On the night of July 19, 1952, something rather strange happened on two fronts in North America.
At Mount Palomar Observatory in Southern California, a pair of photographic plates were taken about
one hour apart, one just before 9pm and the other just before 10pm local time.
In these plates, one showed a cluster of three star-like points, essentially indistinguishable
from stars.
But in the second plate, the points had abruptly and inexplicably disappeared.
Known as transients, these short-lived events hold much promise in the study of astronomy,
in that they show events in much shorter timescales than astronomy normally looks at, a known
deficiency for many years.
What these three star-like points represent is an open question, with potential answers
ranging from gravitational lensing to short-lived astronomical phenomenon we currently haven't
thought of.
They do not appear to be plate flaws or contamination however, those leave telltale signs not present
in this transient, rather they do appear to have been there one hour and gone the next.
Interestingly, it was possible to constrain their distance, which turned out to be less
than two light-years away at maximum and within the orbit of the earth at minimum.
Curiously, on the other side of the country, the time the plates were taken would have
been between 1 and 2 am on the east coast.
At the time, one of the most puzzling UFO flaps in history was happening in the Washington
D.C. area, including multiple radar returns and visual sightings from people in several
locations.
Coincidence perhaps, but all options must be on the table when trying to figure out
what that telescope at Mount Palomar imaged that July night in 1952.
You have fallen into Event Horizon with John Michael Gaudier.
In today's episode, John is joined by Dr. Beatrice Villereal.
Dr. Villereal studies astrophysics and astroparticle physics as a Nordic Fellow at Nordica, the
Nordic Institute for Theoretical Physics.
She has served as the lead on multiple papers, using existing survey data to find examples
of exceptional astrophysical transients, including looking for physically impossible effects
caused by highly advanced technology.
Beatrice Villereal, welcome back to the program.
Thank you.
It's a pleasure to be back.
Now, in our long-running series on transients, you now have a new paper on a newfound transient
in a photographic plate taken in 1952 at Palomar with, I assume, the Hill Telescope,
which at the time that was the most largest and advanced telescope we'd ever built.
It was state-of-the-art.
And yet there's this transient there where in one plate you see essentially three objects
that look like stars, and then a plate an hour later, nothing, they're gone.
Tell us about this new paper regarding this particular transient.
This is a new paper that is actually led by my colleague Enrique Solano at the Center
of Astrobiology in Madrid.
And he has discovered this image where you see three very bright and beautiful stars,
and they are there in that unique plate, but you cannot see them ever again, not even one
hour later.
And these three stars we wanted to find with the largest optical telescope because we thought
maybe they just like got much fainter.
So we used the Gran Telescopo Canarias, which is a 10.4 meter optical telescope.
And we looked there, we went very deep and we found nothing.
So they really vanished and they look real.
And it seems to be like another case of the so-called multiple transients that we've been
seeing before.
Now you've written previous papers on this where there are other transients.
What makes this one, and I actually know the answer to this question, but what makes this
one especially compelling?
It's so bright, so beautiful, so star-like.
Because with the previous ones, like when the first case we found, they were very faint.
We were wondering, okay, maybe it's some kind of plate flaws, some kind of plate flaws that
have some very unusual coincidentally star-like shapes.
But again, they were quite faint and close to the detection limit.
And now you see three super beautiful stars that are there and later vanish.
And that is the kind of thing that we reacted on.
So what magnitude are we talking about as far as brightness goes?
I think like 15 mag, more or less.
Which for that telescope, that's solid.
I think that, I mean, what could a telescope like that...
15-16 mag to be more exact.
Yeah.
But it's solid.
And they all appear to be the same brightness?
More or less, yes.
It's a little bit difficult to get the exact magnitudes of the two ones that are in the
crowded region because they are like overlapping.
But they seem to have more or less the same brightness, all three of them.
Maybe the one in the back is slightly fainter also, but yes.
What strikes me about this is that that does not look like a plate flaw.
That looks like stellar objects.
And that should be there set in stone, so to speak, but that's not what this is, right?
Exactly.
Because when you have something very faint, you can always try to say that it's a plate
flaw.
And then suddenly you have these three like super clear stars and they don't look like
plate flaws.
But of course, we will always find someone who is going to say, but it probably is a
plate flaw.
And I think that is why we need to confirm this phenomenon with entirely different methods
that have nothing to do with photographic plates.
But yeah, they look very authentic.
Now in your work, you look at photographic plates and I'm sure you see plate flaws and
the characteristics of them.
So what does a plate flaw actually look like usually?
No, but plate flaws usually looks like random shapes.
So in order to get to look like stars, you would need to have a very specific, it would
have to, a lot of different factors would have to align up if we say like that to make
it look like a real star.
So I think it's a very, very improbable event.
And now to find several of them that look like stars is even more improbable.
So that's the thing.
And I would also expect that if you have, let's say 10 very bright plate flaws in one
plate, you would see some things that are a mix of different forms, but not that it
would only look exactly like the stars in the field.
So I don't know if this rant made it clear.
It did.
Now what about exposure time?
In other words, how long was the shutter open on the plate that shows the transient?
How long was the shutter open to, you know, sort of eliminate any movement that might
be there?
Because they appear to be point-like.
50 minutes.
Yeah.
50 minutes exposure time.
So if something would be moving in and out of the image, it should be, I mean, it should
be leaving an elongated streak.
It's not going to be, I mean, let's say it moves fast.
If it moves fast during this 15 minutes, so fast that it can go out of the plate and move
somewhere else, you are going to have a streak, not a point source.
Now if it moves very, very slowly, then so slowly that it leaves a point source in the
red image, you would also see a point source in the blue image that is taken one hour
later.
But you don't see that.
What you see is really a point source, only one image and nothing in the other.
So how does that happen?
That is the question.
Yeah.
You have to wonder that.
I mean, stars don't just disappear.
You know, they don't blink out.
Well, at least we, as far as we know, hopefully, hopefully, well, you know, what about things
like a really, really weird event, like a gravitational lensing effect?
In other words, a naked black hole passes by lenses, some normally very dim stars that
are out at the reach of the telescope and you see them very briefly.
What about natural, weird things like that with especially gravitational lensing?
So we've been thinking about it for this particular case because imagine if you have this gravitational
lens that is very, very massive and suddenly behind this lens, you would have a short transient,
something that flared up just for a few minutes.
Maybe what you would see as an observer would actually be that you would see this transient
through the gravitational lens and it would give multiple images.
This is one of the thoughts we were having.
My colleagues estimated like a possible, what would be the possible mass of the lens?
And they concluded something like 10 times the Milky Way mass, sorry, 10 times the mass
of the Milky Way black hole.
And I'm not sure, we are not gravitational lensing experts and I don't know if this is
a reasonable or not reasonable scenario.
It has to be said though, looking at the image, it does look like an Einstein cross, you would
expect, but at the same time, when you see those, it's usually the entire mass of a galaxy
bending that light and making that effect when you see it with like a quasar or something
like that.
And it would seem to me that, you know, that's an implausibly huge black hole to be not at
the center of a galaxy.
But it's, you know, you have to look at all angles and, you know, see what might be there.
Now, what about other options with this?
What other ideas have you guys come up with that might explain this?
Well, I still think that there is an option of that we are seeing something either some
reflecting the sunlight or that you see something with its own intrinsic light that is fairly
close to Earth, why you see it like happening at the same time, because, you know, the speed
of light is limited, so it's not going to come from a galaxy far away, but it's likely
to come from inside the solar system.
Though you got to wonder, though, if it were like an asteroid or something like that that
had varying albedo and you just happened to catch it, but how did it happen that it had
three lobes?
It just seems...
No asteroids.
Well, I'm thinking more about maybe something artificial, possibly, as a possible hypothesis.
Something with either, again, its own intrinsic lights or lamps or something, or maybe something
reflecting the sunlight and let's say something very flat, very like glass or metal or so.
There is an elephant in the room.
This plate is from July 19th, 1952, which is the evening that a massive, massive UFO
flap happened over Washington, D.C. that was caught by multiple radars.
It's quite a fun coincidence, right?
It's quite the coincidence, and it has to be said that that did happen.
And maybe I would dare say, though, if that's what this is, a photographic plate from the
Hale Telescope at Mount Palomar Observatory would constitute probably the best UFO photograph
ever taken, right?
There's something even more fun about this.
When I discovered, or actually I didn't discover it, when my friend Dave Altman pointed out
this date, because it was he who recognized the date when I mentioned 19th of July, 1952.
After he had pointed it out, I was wondering, hey, what about the dates of my other candidates?
And I went to this paper where we had been looking for alignments.
It's a paper called, like, Is There a Background Population of High Albedo Objects?
I don't remember the exact title, but last year we put it on archive and it's a paper
that has issues getting published, because it's a little bit too transparent, I would
say, about the alien angle.
We had five candidates where there were two that were statistically significant and one
that was the best of all.
And in the one that was best of all, you could see five objects in a line.
And it was called Candidate 5.
And if you look at that one, that is from the 28th of July, 1952, which is also inside
this time region of the Washington flap.
It's one day after the second weekend, I think.
I think the second weekend was 26th to 27th of July, and this one happened on the 28th,
and I found it super funny.
I like that kind of funny coincidences.
We have to remember, too, that this is before satellites.
So this is before Sputnik.
So we had nothing up there.
And I mean, at that time, 1952, we were still experimenting with captured V2 rockets and
things like that and developing for the rockets.
And we just didn't have the technology to put something out there that would explain
this as human interference, so to speak, right?
But what if there were some secret military experiments that resulted in the Washington
flyover, but also resulted in that they created some kind of very radioactive particles that
were just captured on the plates that those nights?
Oh, that's interesting.
So there might have been a secret nuclear test that might have done it that we could
do, because remember, obviously, World War II and Trinity testing, and that maybe there
was something thrown into the atmosphere that was...
But couldn't you look at other photographic surveys and look for the same thing, you know,
reoccurring?
Maybe we could actually look for those for the photographic surveys that are from July
1952 and see if we can find more signs of, let's call them UFOs, or any kind of UAPs
or it's a possibility.
Unidentified astronomical object, I'm coining a phrase, and yeah.
It's an interesting coincidence, and of course, it has made me wonder even more.
Now, what other photographic surveys from this time period are there?
I'm sure the Vatican was doing it with the astrograph that they had.
So what other sources of data can you look at?
Maybe the Lick Observatory could be a good, well, it could work.
Unfortunately, the Harvard place don't seem too accessible.
They are photographic plate surveys, I think, from Ukraine, but I don't know if they have
the 1952 year.
Now, what's the future?
In other words, we've got really ideal-seeming survey telescopes coming online soon, probably
the biggest being the Vera Rubin Observatory.
Are you thinking in terms of searching modern data sets like that when we get it?
Actually, we are going to try to go a little bit ahead and create our own project called
Exoprobe, where we are going to place multiple telescopes.
They are all going to be filtering away human space debris and human satellites, and we
are going to search for these kind of multiple transients, but also search deliberately for
signatures of ET probes or unidentified objects that are leaving short transients.
We are going to really focus on transients in these searches, and the goal will be like
if you use multiple telescopes, then if you see some very short flash in several of them,
you directly know that it is a real observation and not something just in one image.
Independent telescope corroboration of a transient would be amazing.
That's exactly what we want to achieve, and then at the same time, if you use at least
two telescopes, you can triangulate and you will directly say it's at this and that distance,
and now if you use ten telescopes, you will get a very accurate distance because you can
get the 3D location much more accurately if you have many more combinations of triangulating.
Within the question of technosignatures, there is a known bias, and Dr. Sankirk Patrick recently
stated it as the orbit of Mars. A technosignature outside of that can be talked about like a von
Neumann probe or something like that at Jupiter, but when you start talking about anything getting
close to Earth, the biases come in even though it's virtually identical. There's no difference
between a von Neumann probe in orbit of Saturn or one in Earth's atmosphere. What's your view
on the stigma and how can we sort of try to get past it? Well, actually, I find it pretty fascinating
that there is such a stigma to search near the Earth because technically, why wouldn't a probe
that can make it into the solar system make it also inside the atmosphere? There's no difference.
There's no difference. So this is just like some kind of social barrier or so, and I think the
only way how we can get past that is by doing these searches and show that, okay, we know there's a
social barrier and we know that it's going to be difficult to publish the papers, but we'll still
look and even if we don't publish them right now, we will probably get them published in a few years
when the stigma is off and people will be kind of much more open-minded. Simply go on and do
your best. That's all one can do. The other thing is that you have to ask another question
when analyzing this sort of thing is that, again, we've talked about von Neumann probes and we've
talked about Benford probes and Bracewell probes and all this sort of stuff that could be in the
solar system, you know, artifacts on the moon or whatever, but we ignore the fact that we might
be living on the most interesting planet in the star system. Yeah, why wouldn't they send it right
to the earth? And I think this is the best place to send any probe to. So if I would be aliens and
they would know that there's an advanced civilization here, I would send all the probes here and I
wouldn't send it somewhere else. The universe is full of gas giants and Venuses and Marses
and things like that, but not so much with civilizations as far as we can tell and study
and that it seems to me that bias, the Mars orbit bias, is just really unhelpful because
the Earth's atmosphere is where you would expect to find a technosignature if there is indeed an
alien civilization here studying us. Exactly, and this is where you could imagine that you would
see things like artifacts and remains on the planet, maybe in geological records even or so.
So I think it's a completely valid way of starting SETI searches here and simply assume that if we
can send something to a different stellar system also can another civilization send something to
us and to the Earth. So I'm totally in favor of this this type of SETI. I also am attracted
to the idea of searching the surface of the moon for any evidence of a past visitation just because
the moon, unlike the Earth, the moon does not recycle its surface constantly and I think that
that's kind of a wide open area for technosignature searches is to start looking at lunar maps and
things like that that might reveal something that was once there. I think that's a really
beautiful idea and I think there are even some searches like AI-driven searches for artifacts
on the moon led by ETH researchers in Switzerland. By the way, I apologize in case you hear weird
sounds from my end, it's my cats coming here and licking my plates that had some ham on. So
sorry for the weird sounds from my end. Oh it's quite okay, we like the cats. I like cats and
one of the reasons why I have a separate Event Horizon studio from my house is that
my cats will try to talk into the microphone. This one might try to, it's a non-human intelligence
that is trying to find her way of maximizing her resources. So yes, a von Neumann cat. Exactly.
So yeah well I completely agree with you on your entire assessment both about the moon and about
the earth and I hope there will be more setting in that direction because we have been doing
60 years of radio searches over and over again always pushing the limit but if you do something
over and over and over again and you don't get any results it's maybe time to open new doors
because new doors will always lead to something unexpected even if it's not what you were looking
for. Well if you're going to look in radio then it only makes sense and this has been
something that's been changing recently is if you're going to look in radio look everywhere
look at every possible technosignature you can think of and see if it might be there or it might
not be and that's one thing that that I think there's not enough work done on is is sort of
the candidates like Jabelsky star or HD 139 139 where we don't exactly know what it is but as
soon as it looks weird and potentially alien all work on it stops and I think that now is the time
to change that and take a fresh look at these weird potential technosignatures. I agree I think
there's an experience that a lot of astronomers have at some point which is like the driving force
let's say you're young and you work on you discover some anomaly and you get super excited like this
coolest thing ever this anomaly and you invest months into exploring it and then in the end you
discover that this was something super mundane and then maybe again some time passes and the
same thing happens and I think what happens is that lots of astronomers develop some kind of
over time some type of experience of that when it's an anomaly 95 percent of the time it's something
mundane and since they want to publish and make good careers and do zero science in quotation
mark it means that anomalies very often get overlooked because people assume that yeah it's
going to be 90% probability of that this is something boring and uninteresting or instrumental
and 10% probability that this is something real I better take a more safe road and I go for more
safe science and in that way a lot of anomalies like remain unsolved while I think the most fun
thing is actually to explore anomalies if we don't do that and stay on the safe side sure we can
learn a lot but it's not going to be as intriguing and as adventurous as the more risky road
it's a high payoff though because if you discover an alien civilization you've just made
probably the biggest scientific discovery in the history of humanity that we are not alone
but what if there is something even crazier than an alien civilization something even crazier to
be discovered that you cannot really imagine right now but you you would discover it and
it would make the alien civilization look like a mundane explanation none of the above
in other words yeah that it's it's something but it's not an alien but it isn't it isn't it isn't
from here well that requires paradigm changes but paradigm changes are common in human history
and for example someone in the medieval world had no idea quantum mechanics existed and maybe
this works like that that we just have no conception of of what might be there and it might be weirder
than aliens in the end yeah and I think like there is some kind of idea that I see in a lot of my
fellow colleagues and that is something like that we have already discovered all the important
physics there is nothing big and new to be discovered which I find super weird the first
question that hits my mind is okay so if you don't think that's anything new can be discovered
and what's the point of doing all this research well of course they will reply that they want
to understand the natural processes and into a finer detail and so on but I find it so hard to
for me it's a point of view that is very different from my own because if you look at
like physics most has been done in the last 200 years and what is 200 years in the history of
humanity it's a short time period and now imagine you have some civilization that has been there
for one million years I think they will they will know so much more about physics than we ever
or that we will do at this point that there is I think there's an immense world of discoveries
ahead of us ahead of the humans and it would be so cool to be part of that and see some of it
the thing is though is that the universe throws curveballs and we see hints right now of a fifth
force you know and things like that and maybe you know another planet in the solar system
planet nine we see all these indicators and things that change our paradigm and we need to be prepared
for that but in defense of science most scientists I've known actually really get intrigued when
there are discrepancies hints of new physics and things like that so at least there still is an
open debate it's not a dogma it's not it hasn't descended completely into a dogma yet I think so
too you're right maybe I was thinking a little bit too dark and I just remember a couple of
conversations sometimes that's stuck in my mind you're right many scientists are very excited
when there's some new anomaly but I remember people were super excited when there was this
neutrino neutrino's traveling faster than the speed of light at cern I remember that yeah
I remember that and well it turned out to be a bad cable or something but
let's see another example of when anomalies turn out to be have some very abundant explanation
it's true that you can have well misinterpretation and knowing that your data may be flawed and you
know there's all kinds of things you got to go through the whole list to make sure you know
confirmation bias all of these things to make sure that what you're seeing is real but that's
what's peer reviews for exactly so what's the future look like on looking at photographic
plates from the past versus looking at new data you know new data sets from telescopes like the
lsst vera rubin observatory that's going to come online can you use computers and things like that
to automatically look for these kinds of transients and see if they're still occurring actually that's
exactly what we want to do but we want to build our own system to look for these kind of transients
because we think that they are quite short from what we've seen with this place that you can only
see them in one plate so what we want to do is to create a system where you have multiple telescopes
where you search for short flashes and you only retain the flashes that are seen in at least two
telescopes to make sure that they are authentic and when you have multiple telescopes you can also
let's say you have two telescopes you can measure the parallax to an object inside the solar system
let's say that this flash comes from something that is blinking or blinking or having some laser
by having by seeing the flash in two telescopes you will once you have the parallax you can get
the distance and now let's say you have 10 of these telescopes and you see the same flash in
all 10 of them then you're going to have a very good accuracy on the distance to that object
at the same time as you are like validating the flash and you know that it's real at the same
time as you get the 3d location you can actually also use a so-called wedge prism in order to
measure like get the spectrum in low resolution of all the objects in that field that is what
we're going to do try to get the real-time spectrum when you get a spectra on a transient like this
say you catch one and you catch multiple telescopes so you know it's really there it's not a plate
floor or anything like that it's really there and you get a spectra on it what happens if that
spectra is not that of a star well it depends on what we actually see because maybe what we are
seeing is some kind of communication laser that looks the same as what humans use in their
communication satellites maybe also the object that we are seeing is in let's say in geosynchronous
orbit and moves just like a human satellite and shoots a laser just like a human satellite
and there is nothing that indicates any kind of anomaly then it's maybe it's not super exciting
but what if that spectrum what if you know that that object is something
that is very close to the earth it moves let's say again at the geosynchronous orbit but
what you see is not any laser and it's some very peculiar type of emission that you've never seen
that would be super cool. Now how would you go about the process of illumination to begin to
ask in other words if it's a technosignature then it could have a signature that is there's no way
that can be natural right and so you say like with a star when you see a star spectrum you see all
the absorption lines and all this stuff and if you don't see that I mean it it would seem to me to be
a very fruitful method of study to start looking at these transients and try to catch spectra.
Well we have our methods that they cannot reveal yet in the exapro program where we will be removing
all the human objects like space debris and satellites and we also have are working on
establishing a protocol where we remove the remaining unknown objects so of course there's
always a chance that you find some very anomalous thing that is some secret some very secret
experiment that some country on earth has sent there but I think we know the boundaries of what
humans can create and produce and we will have to check whether the anomalies are within them
or outside them. Yeah that's going to be a problem because that's a that's a thing in satellite
technology is blinding other satellites meaning you're emitting some kind of light to throw off
the the rival satellites and things like that. Now what about will this research result in other
discoveries in other words might you find when you're looking for your transients and taking
plates with as many telescopes might you find something like I don't know Kuiper belt objects
or planet nine something like that could you catch that with this survey? I think it's there's a very
good possibility that you can find some very unusual astronomical phenomena that are just
happening on these short time scales because in the time scales we are focusing on very few
astronomers have examined it and that's what's what makes it so exciting and that's why it's so
fun for us to explore it and by the way like just a small thing I was thinking about in connection
to the previous question. One more thing by the way in the way how we can separate between human
objects even the secret ones and the non-human objects that we are interested in the artificial
let's call ET probes is that we are going to actually search quite far away from the earth
for starters because in that way we get rid of all these satellites at low earth orbit
and we get rid of the whole belt of human space debris so it's a very good thing to try to start
and the searches further out because there everything that has been or most of the stuff
that humans have sent are very like well known. So in other words we we know what the signatures
of human technology are and we should be able to tell that from alien technology for example if
you were seeing say the light from some kind of a photon drive or something like that it would be
so characteristically weird that it's it can't be something that humans produce right?
Exactly exactly so that's how I'm imagining that you can identify some of the unidentified objects
or if you find let's say something that maybe looks more like a conventional ET probe but in
completely wrong place no country says that they have sent their space rockets and it's too far out
to just be a random object that is there that nobody knows what it is that's also a possibility.
Now you can use parallax to determine that distance right? Of course. When you're using
multiple telescopes and you can determine that this is either close or far away. Exactly.
That's what we want to do. So what is the what where are the telescopes going to be located?
I mean is it globally or what telescope locations are we looking at? So actually we hope to get it
globally but in the first phase it's going to be in California so we're looking to put up a telescope
there in Sierra remote and also two more locations so that's where we are now we are trying to
solve the administrative things with the telescopes. What kind of telescope apertures
are we looking at? What are the size of these telescopes? It seems to me you can do this very
with very small instruments right? Exactly we are going to go for like very professional state of
the art half meter telescopes that have super good tracking and very good mounts that are reliable
and to do this type of work and yes they are pretty expensive so of course we have to
work on that end to make it happen but this yeah we're imagining at least three telescopes
in California and hopefully like within the near future so one is being ordered and there are two
more not equally good as the one that we are ordering and one that also one of them actually
recently had an accident so we need to solve that too. Yeah there was a little accident that
happened with one of them and we will probably we will need to replace it. Now this also seems
like something that citizen scientists might be able to do look for transients because there are
a lot of people doing astrophotography out there and there have been for decades and that maybe
people that have archives should look and see if anything's missing in their photographic plates
that they have and let you guys know about it. I would love if they did that and we also have
a citizen science project that we've been running with the Vasco team where people can go and actually
search for these type of objects that are vanishing. We're now actually wrapping up the
results from there and like we found some thousands of transients we didn't find any example of a star
that is there in five plates and later vanished but we found many of these short-lived transient
things so everyone are welcome to help us with it also or they can also do it with their own
telescopes on their own archives. I think there's a lot of potential when it comes to
transient searches especially in the short time region. Now you recently spoke at the
SOL conference which was put on by Gary Nolan and regarding to UAP tell us about that. Oh my god that
was the most interesting conference I've been to probably in my life. So fun, so nice people,
so brilliant thinkers and minds and like such a diversity in the type of work people are doing
and still there's such a unity because everyone wants to understand the phenomenon or the UAPs
or if there are ET probes and this curiosity people had like there was such a passion for the topic.
Apologies for the sound. Just for the listeners that is the sound of a very active cat. Yes.
All right doctor thank you for visiting with us yet again and I look forward to the next paper
because I'm just fascinated by these transients and legitimately this is one of the things that
really puzzles me these days in science is that is these transients especially this one with the
palomar plate because it just does not look like it looks like stars. Yeah that's the thing it's
like we have several of these cases with the multiple transients all look like stars and some
are even aligned like lying beautifully in a line like if it was satellites moving and tumbling
and of course they are from the early 50s when there was nothing human at those high altitudes
or in space so I find it super puzzling and maybe there's some new physics that I don't know about
maybe there's some completely different type of explanation I'm of course also limited
with my bias but I find it fascinating and I want to understand more what it is with new projects and
everything I can do to solve the riddle. Natural or artificial it's going to be interesting.
I think so too. I'm very curious about where it will lead.