Counterpoints.
With this double interview series, I wanted to do a pair of balanced, fair interviews
probing the differing views within the US government regarding the UFO UAP phenomenon.
In this interview I am joined by Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick, the recently retired former director
of AERO, the US government's all domain anomaly resolution office, tasked with trying
to identify reports of UFOs.
But also to look into the US government's past involvement with UFOs and find out whether
there ever really were retrievals.
More importantly, I asked how those would be classified and a number of other questions
including about the Nimitz event that has made so many waves and a number of other things.
So this serves to show the skeptical side of interpretations within the US government,
something of great interest during a time of continued congressional hearings trying
to figure out just what's going on here, if anything, along with the previous interview
on the pro side.
I leave it up to you, the audience, to decide.
You have fallen into Event Horizon with John Michael Gaudier.
John is joined today by Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick.
Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick is a laser and materials physicist and senior intelligence officer
who served as the first director of the United States Department of Defense's all domain
anomaly resolution office, AERO.
He served in a variety of no-fail roles including deputy director of intelligence, US Strategic
Command, director of national security strategy, national security council, deputy director
of intelligence and the DNI representative for US Spacecom.
He also served as chief scientist at DIA's Missile and Space Intelligence Center.
He is the recipient of several scientific and military intelligence awards.
These include the Secretary of Defense Medal for Outstanding Public Service, the Joint
Meritus Civilian Service Award, the National Intelligence Exceptional Achievement Medal,
four National Intelligence Collaboration Medallions, the NRO Innovation and Achievement
Award, the Cleary Award for Scientific Excellence, and the DIA Director's Award for Excellence.
Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick, welcome to the program.
Thank you.
It's a pleasure to be here.
Now, Dr. the Fermi paradox, and this gets into physics in general, the Fermi paradox
comes from Enrico Fermi back in the day, the 1950s, thinking about alien life over lunch
and saying, well, where are they?
We should be seeing them if they were common.
What is your view to sort of set the stage here?
What is your view of alien life in the universe as a physicist?
Do you think it's probably out there or are you in the camp that now this is rare and
that we shouldn't see it?
Okay, so the Fermi paradox is fascinating in its simplistic approach to the universe.
It's a very apt question.
It's spawned lots of research, it's spawned lots of NASA programs, it's spawned lots of
SETI programs, it's spawned lots of conjecture and a lot of scientific research.
And coming out of that, as you all know, right, was the famous Drake equation, which calculates
at least at first order the probability of intelligent life in the universe.
And statistically, most of the scientific community would agree that, well, one, it
is statistically improbable that there's not life in the universe outside of Earth and
that across all time that the universe has existed, it is statistically impractical to
believe that there hasn't been other intelligent life out in the universe.
But that conversation and that exploration of that question is scientifically grounded
in a lot of the observations that NASA undertakes to probe the different types of planetary
systems throughout the universe as far as we can see today and how that factors into
the calculations for the Drake equation.
And just within our galaxy alone, the last couple of papers I looked at on this was estimating
based on current Webb telescope measurements, somewhere between 30 and 300 planets that
can sustain life and may have some form of intelligence in it.
That's across one galaxy.
So as a scientist, it's just mathematically impractical to believe that there's not other
intelligent life throughout the vastness of the universe.
Where it becomes interesting is carrying that conversation closer to this solar system and
closer to Earth, because those same statistics apply and that the probability of there being
an intelligent life form out in the universe that has found this particular solar system
and this particular planet is just as rare as us finding them.
So I can't see or fathom how that rationally translates to the underlying stories that
pervade public perception today.
Well, there's a plausible way, at least now, space is vast and crossing space is costly.
You know, you're going to need a lot of energy and a lot of time.
And we're constricted by things like relativity and the speed of light and things like that
that really put a damper on the notion of traveling between star systems.
But you can do it as long as you don't care about time and you've got the energy and you
don't care about having any connection to where you left, you know, your time, because
everybody's going to be dead by the time you get back unless they live for ridiculously
long periods of time.
But one plausible way, and I've talked to other physicists about this, is the idea of
a von Neumann probe where you have a machine, essentially a self-replicating machine that
can populate a galaxy inside of a few million years at sublight speeds, at comfortable speeds.
And a machine doesn't really care about the passage of time.
So that is the one way that this could happen, where you could have an alien presence in
most star systems.
And let's face it, 3D printers exist and something could be printing out UAP or atmospheric
probes to look at the most interesting planet in this star system.
Presuming this one is the most interesting one.
So there is a plausible way.
Did you account for that in Aero?
Did you think, well, maybe?
So when we set up Aero, one of the key tenets of setting up Aero and all the processes that
I put in place to do so was to follow the data.
It was to be open to all hypotheses of what could be possible and then look at where the
data led you.
And none of the data supported that theory.
So we did have a range of hypotheses.
I had on one end of the spectrum, you have the alien hypothesis, whether it's probe or
otherwise.
On the other end of the spectrum, you have adversary technology, leap ahead technology
that they are intentionally trying to hide from us.
And then in the middle, you have really all of the mundane known objects that just manifest
themselves in weird ways because we haven't calibrated our sensors against those.
And so what was established was a very rigorous scientific method for how do you test that
range of hypotheses against all of the reported observations is that one, you had to start
with all of those military sensors, all of those ground based or air based sensors or
even space based sensors need to be calibrated against known objects.
Most of the reporting comes from military or Intel, mostly military platforms and pilots.
And what everyone needs to understand is those platforms are purpose built.
They are designed for one thing, and that is to identify large metallic types of objects
coming at them and put a weapon on it.
So if it's a missile or an aircraft or a ground system or whatever it might be to identify
those large, fast moving objects and put a weapon on it, they are not designed to identify,
for example, weather balloons or small drones or other types of objects that have been used
for a variety of different purposes.
And one of the things that one has to do when approaching the scientific method out in the
world is start with calibrating all of your sensors and make sure you understand what
those sensors would see.
And so that was one piece, right?
Set up the calibration program to identify those known objects.
What do they look like in, for example, an F-35?
What do they look like in an F-22?
What do they look like in a ground radar?
And catalog all that, understand what those characteristics are.
Then you take the reported observations and any data that has been collected with that
and compare to the known objects.
That's sort of step one.
The next two steps involve two different communities.
So if you look at that range of hypotheses again, if I go to the end of the spectrum,
that could be adversary advanced technology.
That is the purview of the intelligence community.
And so I had chartered the intelligence community to go and look for what were some of
the research programs that our adversaries were working on and what would happen if they
had a breakthrough and that what we thought they were working towards in a decade they
were able to achieve today.
And what would that look like?
And what were those signatures?
So then you'd have a body of knowledge that involved validated here are the signatures
and capabilities that the intelligence community assesses an adversary would manifest
with. You have the measured signatures of all the known objects.
And then your last bit is, OK, well, what would what would alien tech look like and
how would it potentially manifest itself?
And so that was part of the challenge to the scientific community through NASA.
Oh, all right. Well, we know theoretically how interstellar travel works.
While we may not have been able to achieve it from an engineering perspective, we know
what the basic underlying physics are.
We've seen lots of papers and literature about it.
What does that look like?
What kind of signatures would that manifest as?
And then keep all of that as your measurement stick.
Right. And so when you get different reports and you get different data that we then had
directed to the military and the IC, you know, new reporting requirements to maintain
and transmit all of that data, you can then have something to compare to.
And as you go through that exercise time and time again, it turns out to be in the
middle. It turns out to be mostly the known things that you've characterized and
compared to. Was that frustrating, though, when dealing with that with with instrumentation
that is not ideal for studying something other than a Chinese fighter jet?
Was that frustrating in trying to resolve cases in aero?
In other words, did you wish you had more data?
Oh, absolutely. Always wish we had more data.
And so part of part of what I had done was also design purpose built monitoring sensors
for areas that had high levels of reporting so that we could go out and do persistent
surveillance and monitor on a continuing basis what was passing through the airspace and
what characterize it as best we can to augment the sensors.
There were not designed to do that.
So, you know, what I think a lot of folks fail to understand is that a U.S.
aircraft, an F-35 or an F-22 or an F-4 or 14 or whatever it is that's flying around
and collecting is not a scientific platform.
It is not meant to collect and characterize unknown things.
It is only meant to do one thing.
And that is type a set of known objects, foreign adversary aircraft, missiles,
what have you, and put a weapon on it, not characterize an unknown object.
And so when it sees an unknown object, these advanced aircraft and these advanced
platforms try to the algorithms try to make sense of it.
And when they try to make sense of it, they make mistakes.
The algorithms make mistakes.
I mean, it's just like if you take an AI, you take a chat GPT and you give it bad data
to train on, it's going to give you really weird answers when you talk to it.
It's the same concept.
It's it's just in a machine characterization language.
And so, yes, it has been very frustrating because people then pull on the, well,
somebody saw X and the radar said this, and so therefore it must be an alien.
I'm like, well, no, it doesn't, right?
Because radars make mistakes when the algorithms don't understand what they're looking at.
And a great example of that is how a radar operates.
So a radar sends a series of pulses out to a target and it looks for the reflections back.
And from that, it classifies and characterizes speed and range.
If that object is semi-transparent, like a translucent weather balloon that only has
a few thick wires through it, those reflections are they're not well defined.
They're sporadic and they they tend to give a false range.
They give a false speed because the algorithm is trying to fill in the gaps of the missing data.
And we've shown this time and again in the lab and in the field where we did live
characterization events and tried to get that into our quiver of how do we compare
unknown objects to the sensors.
You know, folks don't understand that and they don't know that that's how these things
operate and they pull on this as as it must be factual.
So, yes, that's a long way of saying it's very frustrating.
Now, biases.
And in science, you always want to try to remove biases and at least recognize them
and your assumptions as well.
But in this case, Arrow wasn't making the assumption.
You didn't go into this saying, well, it's not aliens.
You went into it going with an open mind.
Now, do you think that's a problem with NASA and technosignature searches?
In other words, and you've said it to paraphrase you, the orbit of Mars and views change
the closer you get.
So a technosignature out of Jupiter would be seen as one thing or you co-authored a
paper on that, that that's one thing.
But the closer you get to Earth, the views begin to change and the profile changes.
Now, I have a caveat here.
The thing is, I can't tell you the difference between a von Neumann probe in the orbit of
Jupiter versus one in the atmosphere.
It's the same thing functionally.
So how do you rectify that?
What's your view on that?
That where does that bias come in and what does it mean?
Yeah. So let me let me give you my my actual characterization of this, of the scientific
discussion. And at some point, I think I want to turn it into a political cartoon or some
sort of cartoon. So if I have this conversation about the search for for extraterrestrial
whether that's intelligent or a bacterium, and I'm doing it in the context of the scientific
community and NASA's mission to find it.
And it's as long as we're talking about it out in the universe, across the Milky Way
or even into the vastness of of the universe with all the other galaxies that are there,
then it's a very scientific, objective, data driven, evidentiary driven discussion and
analysis. As I move that conversation closer to Earth, somewhere around my conjecture is
somewhere around Mars ish, it becomes more science fiction.
Right. You're you're now there's a there's a there's an element of science fiction that
creeps into the discussion.
Any number of movies about this have happened.
And then as I get that conversation closer to Earth, somewhere as I cross the ionosphere,
it crosses into conspiracy theory.
And clearly, the government's lying and we've been hiding alien tech that has crash
landed, I don't know, 12 times in the United States, and we're hiding all that.
So these are the kinds of things that that make it very difficult to have a rational
discussion about the evidence and about the data because of that, that transition from
scientific to conspiracy.
Now, that being said, how do you fix that?
I think to your point, how do you get to this?
How do you actually have this conversation?
How do you distinguish between a technosignature of a probe at Jupiter versus Earth?
And the answer is it comes back to the scientific community.
And this was something I challenged them with very early on.
And I was enlisting the help of NASA to help push that is, OK, you know, it's a it's a
valid hypothesis.
It could be a hypothesis.
What is the data that supports that and what would those signatures look like?
What kind of propulsion would be evident?
What kind of signatures would that propulsion give?
What kind of refueling and energy harvesting would need to be done?
Why would one put a probe here?
All right. And we can talk about that a little bit in the context of NASA sending probes
out. Why would we do that?
What would we be looking for?
And put some peer reviewed scientific papers into the into the domain that point to
if there was a probe in Earth's atmosphere, how would it get here?
What are the three most probable ways it would get here?
What are the three most probable ways it would maneuver around the Earth?
What are the three most probable ways it would harvest energy and take all of that
and figure out what the resulting signatures and indicators would be and then
marry that to the data that we have?
And what you'll find is none of that matches.
And so what you what you're left with is, OK, well, then that hypothesis, while
it's still a valid hypothesis, has no data to support it as being the answer to
what you're seeing.
So people, when they don't get the when the answer doesn't when the data doesn't
support that hypothesis in the scientific community, that means that hypothesis is
not correct and that you have to change your hypothesis.
It doesn't mean your data.
You have to change your data in this particular topic area for reasons that are
fascinating from a psychological perspective.
The human condition wants it to be an answer that data does not support.
So scientifically, to answer your question, if I wanted to distinguish a probe in
Jupiter or Earth, you still have the same signatures.
Now it's a matter of do any of the signatures you've measured either in Earth or
around Jupiter match your hypothesis?
Does that make sense?
It does. It does.
Now, I have to ask the point blank question that I'm sure you get a lot.
Just to clarify, did you find any evidence or see any evidence of a non-human
intelligence present here?
And I use that word very specifically because there's ideas floating around, like
the the Solarian hypothesis where it isn't aliens, but it's still weird and things
like that. Did you or did you not see any evidence or even something slightly that
made you go, hmm.
No, I have there was nothing in the over.
I think by the time I retired, I think we were well over 1300 cases or something
like that. And none of them had anything that would give an indication of a
non-human intelligence.
Now, did we see things that were weird within some of the sensors that did
produce data?
Yes. Were any of those alien signatures?
No. Could they have been adversary signatures?
Could they have been commercial signatures?
Sure. They could have been a number of other explanations that we uncovered.
And I think that's the important part is, all right, let's say I have something
that's unusual.
If I can come up with three different explanations, one of them being, OK, it's
an alien and we don't know anything about it.
The second one being, OK, well, maybe it's this commercial product that this
company is advancing and the U.S.
government's not really paying attention to, and it just happens to be there and
we see it. Or the third one being, it's an adversary that's doing something that
we didn't expect them to do.
But there's evidence that they're doing that.
Which one are you going to believe is more likely?
Is it the alien or is it the adversary or is it commercial?
And you don't you don't know right off hand, but logic would suggest that one of
the more common and simple answers like, I don't know, it's a commercial thing
that's just out there and we can go find what it is and here's what it is.
And it could have been this, likely could have been that.
That is Occam's razor, right?
So that would suggest the more simple explanation is likely versus an alien.
But then from a national security perspective, we have to investigate.
And this is where the real rub is.
And this is really what Arrow is kind of focused on is, let's make sure that the
adversary is not doing something.
We need to make sure that the adversaries aren't aren't jumping ahead in a
technological advancement and say, I don't know, propulsion or signature
management that we weren't tracking or else we were tracking, but they had a
breakthrough that we didn't anticipate.
Now, something that was looked at as an evolutionary technology has suddenly
become revolutionary because they had a leap ahead and they're employing it
against us.
Well, that would be bad, right?
From a national security perspective, that's, that's bad.
That's called a, that's called a, it could be a technological surprise and we
don't want that, right?
So you, you, you got to look at all of all aspects of this and it becomes
frustrating and even to the point of maddening of where some people come out
on, well, it can't be that it must be aliens and there's no logical reason why
one can make that known at all other than, than belief.
And that's just frustrating.
Now, methodology to get a little bit deeper into that with Arrow, visual
artifacts and compression in videos, not to, not to frustrate you further and
remind you of frustrating things, but how big of a problem was that when you're
looking at something that just isn't there, it's an instrument error?
Yeah, that, that happened a lot and, and a lot of folks don't understand it.
If you've not dealt with imagery or imagery intelligence for a large part of
your career, you can't understand the types of weird artifacts that show up
in advanced sensors that you just would think is something else.
And there's an example that we put on Arrow's website.
It's one in which there's an apparent UAP that's leaving some sort of a wake
in the, in the video.
As you watch the video, it looks like an atmospheric wake behind it.
And at first, when you look at this, your gut reaction is, wow, that is really weird.
That is so cool.
That looks like what you might see in some sort of advanced propulsion system.
And that must be, you know, evidence of, of an advanced propulsion
system that we don't understand.
Well, when you peel that onion back, and by that, what I mean is you have to go
frame by frame and pixel by pixel with the raw data, not the compressed data.
And what you'll find is that, that, that wake that you see in this video is, it's
a, it's a shadow image of the object from the frame before, and that's an artifact
of the signal processing that occurs frame by frame in this sensor.
And so what you have to do in order to accurately analyze some of this data is
you have to, A, you have to understand what sensor it came from.
And B, you have to understand what kind of signal processing and algorithms
are done on the platform.
And the only way you can do that is you have to go to that particular program
office that, that builds and integrates those sensors on our military platforms.
And you get a surrogate sensor or you get the software or you get the, the
underlying models that are used to validate the sensor performance and you
recreate what it saw and you validate, okay, well, this is actually, you know,
not a wake, a real wake in the atmosphere.
This is an artifact of the signal process.
And we, you can find these kinds of examples in a variety of sensors that
actually show, like we had one in comparison for that particular example of
a predator looking at a ground, a scene, and there were people walking across the
scene and the people were leaving shadows behind them that looked like a wake that
was the cutout of the person.
And so you see the same artifact in other imagery examples, and you really have to
understand that, how those work and how that operates in order to draw a
conclusion.
And in that particular case, I believe that was turned out to be another
aircraft and it was out of focus.
And so it looks like a oblong cigar and it's leaving a wake because it's the
signal processing of the saturated areas of the scene.
So it's a very complex analysis that has to be undertaken for every single one of
these ports.
And, you know, people get frustrated out in the world because they're like, well,
why can't you do this faster?
Because that's why you have to pull apart every frame.
You got to pull apart the sensor.
You got to pull apart the pixels.
And you can't do that level of analysis with a compressed video off the internet
because you lose all of that information.
Compression, to put it onto the internet, gets rid of all of the valuable
information at the pixel level, of the metadata, of the information about the
sensor, which you need in actual to do the analysis.
So if you were to look at a compressed image of the same sort of weird artifact
without having any of that other information to do that analysis, your first
response would be, hey, that's really weird.
That looks like evidence of some sort of atmospheric effect when in fact it's not.
Yeah, that's I mean, technology comes with its problems and with our ever improving
technology, it actually sometimes seems to get worse and new problems crop up.
Now, one of the most famous cases regarding the military and UAP of recent years, 20
years, is the 2004 Nimitz case.
And I know that you've said there was a sort of a lack of data, you know, this
distant from that 20 years again.
But did you see anything?
And I want to ask this a little bit differently than probably most people would ask you.
Did you see anything that indicated that it was our technology and the pilot simply
didn't know about something that we had?
So that, you know, obviously I get asked about that case a lot.
I got asked about that case a lot in Congress.
There are a number of challenges and I'll get to the answer to your question.
There's a number of challenges with that case.
One is it's 20 years ago and 20 years ago there was no requirement to save all of the data.
There was no requirement to process that data.
There was no requirement to even report the incident.
All of that we changed when we stood up Arrow.
And it's important to note that it took however many years that was, 16 years, 17, 18 years,
when we stood up Arrow from the Nimitz event that that's when we changed all of those
policies and made it a requirement that you will report.
And here's what you will report and you will maintain all of that data and you will transmit
it to Arrow and to the service for analysis.
So there, you know, there was no requirement to keep all of that.
So when people question, well, why is there no data?
Well, it's not a big conspiracy.
It's a it's a logistics issue, right?
These platforms don't save the data.
They have a single recording device that is overwritten every mission.
So there's no data off of those platforms.
Now there's allegations that, hey, there was a Aegis around and it collected data.
And, you know, why don't we have that data?
Well, it's a similar argument.
There's no requirement for that.
We don't have the Aegis data for every mission that was ever flown, including
every training exercise, which this was.
And your training in an in a range that is a test range.
So let's now let's walk into answering your question.
I spent a good amount of time talking with one of the pilots to get some descriptions of,
you know, what exactly was being seen and how is it being seen so that we could get a little bit
better understanding of some of the signatures associated with it.
For example, was this something that may have come out of the water versus going into the water?
And if it came out of the water, and what does it look like?
What did it look like as you were flying?
What's the what angles and so forth?
It's interesting to note that there are several programs, both U.S.
and foreign, that could explain that, especially if you're in an experimental test range
where one side of the range doesn't know what the other side of the range is doing.
If you're thinking it's the U.S. technology.
And if it's an adversary, well, you know, they want to know what we're doing in our test range.
There are some ways to do that.
So there's let me give you an example.
There was a declassified CIA program back in that time frame where they would launch
their balloons with retro reflectors inside of them from the water to monitor what responses
would be from ground radars and aircraft responses.
What would they see and how would they respond?
Why would we think we're the only ones that thought of that?
So I'm not saying that I have data to support that that is exactly what it was,
but that is certainly a more logical explanation than it was.
And the problem is I can come up with a couple of hypotheses for what that was,
but we don't have any data to analyze.
So you're never going to answer that question.
We're just not going to be able to answer what that was
because there is no data.
I am glad that I don't work for the U.S. government because that just got me thinking
when I was growing up, my dad was a field test engineer and worked at the Nevada test site,
which is enormous.
And I could just imagine how many different tests are going on.
And the person that knows about all of the tests happening at the same time
and has all the details, which probably is a very few people do,
imagine coordinating that to make sure your F-117 doesn't hit a
weather balloon or something like that.
It's got to be maddening, wouldn't you think?
Exactly.
That kind of deconfliction is what test range managers are supposed to be doing.
And there's no, you know, if a test squadron on one end of the range happens to see
a classified program on another end of the range,
you know, mitigation of that can range from ignoring it and pretending it never happened to
bringing the people in and making them sign inadvertent disclosure agreements,
which is essentially an NDA that says, hey, you saw a classified program
you weren't supposed to see and you're not briefed to and you're not allowed to talk about it.
That is a standard practice of inadvertent disclosures across the classified community,
whether it's DOD or IC or anybody.
So there's no, but again, there's no hard evidence one way or the other.
So we could come up with all kinds of these scenarios and explanations and hypotheses,
but unless I have data, there's not a lot to be done about that.
Yeah, no data then might as well be confetti, unfortunately, you know?
Right.
And I think everybody wishes there were more data, but again, I have to hammer home the point that
you're dealing with sensors or we're dealing with sensors that weren't designed to look for UAP.
They were designed to look for Russian and Chinese aircraft.
That's right.
However, we do have some interesting wild cards and that is the NRO.
Now there was a Freedom of Information Act release that they had seen something that
looked like a tic-tac from orbit.
And I was wondering, did you look into that?
Are you aware of it?
And did you, were you able to do anything with that satellite data?
Yeah, so there were a couple of those reports and we actually worked with them very closely
to do some research into historical imagery and forward imagery and even tasking,
trying to get tasking in real time to when an event may have been seen.
And all of those turned out to be weather balloons, radio songs, and in one instance,
it was, you know, it was another sensor anomaly on basically cosmic ray in the sensor.
So without getting into details about NRO's business, because that's obviously all very
classified, yes, we did look into a number of these things.
None of them turned out to be tic-tacs in the popular sense.
They turned out to be, you know, aerostats or weather balloons or radio songs.
I guess that's probably going to be pretty crazy too is because anybody can launch a balloon,
right?
Anybody and, well, obviously drones, but there's limits on that.
But the balloons, I don't think there are much limits.
And any private individual or group, you know, say you like to study clouds or whatever,
that's your hobby, can launch a balloon.
So there's stuff all over.
But does that worry you?
And then I got another question related to this, but does that worry you about aviation
safety that these balloons are going unchecked?
Oh, yeah.
So that was one of the primary drivers for why the department agreed to stand up aero
was safety of flight, safety of flight issues, not just for the military.
But for FAA and NASA and everybody else associated with it.
So there's a couple of key things to understand that we learned as we were standing all this
up.
There is a, you know, an international community of balloon, professional balloons,
civil scientific balloon organizations.
And they are, they have agreed amongst themselves.
And I think there's some sort of agreement that underlies this to put essentially beacons
on their balloons.
And they launched them.
And you can track them in real time.
In fact, we put the website links on Aero's website.
If you go there and you look under the resources, you can go and look up.
Here's all the balloons that are registered with this community.
Here are the beacons.
Here's where they are today.
Here's what country owns them.
And then there's a hobbyist community that has done the same thing.
So there's another website that you can track hobbyist balloons and you can watch them and
see where they are.
So on one sense, you have a database of overt, legitimate balloon payloads and operators
around the world in real time.
So you should be able to de-conflict with those.
It's the ones that don't have those beacons or are flying in the air spaces they're not
supposed to be that you got to worry about.
And so part of what we established were rules for how to de-conflict that and get that out
with the operators and all of the air spaces to go, hey, if you see something, first thing
you need to do is de-conflict with these two websites and let's make sure those are
not what you're seeing.
And then there's a third place and that's NOAA and NASA have a database as well.
It's not quite as user-friendly as the two websites, but it is complete and tracks
everything that is registered with a beacon on it.
So you can think of these beacons much like aircraft AIS systems and they beacon out here's
who I am and here's where I am and here's where I'm going and you can follow them around.
But it does still worry everyone and it worries me that these balloons don't, while they're
beaconed and they're tracked and they're there, there's not a lot of coordination between
that community and say the test ranges of military or even the FAA on knowing what to do with that
because many of them are at the, of course, the mercy of the winds and the climate.
Some of them have the ability to maneuver, limited though it may be, but they can.
So how do you integrate that airspace in a safe manner and alert the pilots and the
operators that what you're seeing is this balloon from a group in Japan or Norway or
the US and you need to avoid it, but there's a lot of them out there.
I mean, there are thousands and thousands and thousands of these balloons that are launched
daily and are tracked all over the world.
It's just phenomenal to me that we've got that kind of air domain congestion problem that is
increasing and we haven't quite figured out how to deconflict and instead people come upon these
things and don't know what they are because they're flying really fast by them and it causes
challenges, causes problems because if you run into one of those things, especially one that's
got a payload hanging off of the bottom, that's going to rip a wing off if you're flying it,
mock one in a jet and you happen to run into a balloon with a payload hanging off the end.
That's probably not a good day for that pilot.
No, that is scary. I've thought about that at high speed. You're in an F-22 or something like that
hitting one of these balloons and like you say, a payload, not good. It seems like an accident
waiting to happen. Now, all domain anomaly resolution office arrow, all domain,
what are the submarines seeing? Because I know that the hydrophone network has picked up some
strange sounds that took 20, 30 years to come up with a hypothesis as to what they were, which is
usually ice moving in Antarctica, things like that. What are they seeing and is that a lot
harder to deal with than things in the air? Oh, absolutely. So the maritime domain,
integrating the maritime and the space domain was something I had started last,
I guess, the summer a year ago. Space is actually, I think, an easier step than the maritime domain
because in the maritime domain, undersea is noisy and not only is it noisy, but everything is
anomalous because there are so many unknown noises that crop up that people have to try to sort out.
I had one report that turned out to be some guy scraping barnacles off of his boat with a new
type of scraper, two bays away from where the sound was picked up. But it took six months to
figure that out. I mean, these are not trivial events and they haven't in the maritime domain,
at least by the time I retired, we hadn't come up with a good way of distinguishing.
When you hear something, what are the characteristics that would cause you to claim that is
an anomalous technological thing that we need to go investigate versus it's an underwater volcano
or it's a whale or it's a school fish or whatever the things are that while we may know what those
sound like, again, I go back to the way the architectures are set up, a lot of this is
automatic. You record some noise and the algorithms don't know what it is and so they
put it off to the side for somebody to listen to and analyze. Well, okay, how many of those do we
get? And there's a lot of unknown. So we didn't have a lot of, to answer your question more
directly, we did not have a lot of undersea reporting because of that very fact, because
everything is anomalous and nobody knows what qualifies as something we would report. That's
just not there yet. Now in space, it's a little easier. We have a good track of everything that's
in space and we have a catalog that monitors this and we have objects that show up that are
designated UCTs, right? So they're uncorrelated tracks. That's what that stands for. And basically,
it's an object that shows up, could be a micrometer, right? It could be a screw that fell off of
somebody's satellite, it could be anything. And it gets us a couple of returns off of one of the
radars and now we've got a track and well, what is it? And now you've got to figure out what that
is. Well, I hate to tell you this, but space congestion is a really, really bad problem.
When we turned on Spacefence, I want to say, if I remember correctly, we had the number of
UCTs went to 40,000-ish and it was a daily deluge of thousands of objects that nobody knows really
what they are. But the good news is they all obey Keplerian physics, right? So if it's not obeying
Keplerian physics, well, that would be anomalous and that would be easy to pick out and report
and no, there were none of those. But trying to work through the,
okay, well, what's going to be the reporting process and how do we build that into the sensors
and the algorithms so that you can pull those kinds of things out? That takes time, but there
was a good path forward on how to do that. So I think that one is more achievable than the under C
one at this point. Yeah, but the thing is that that problem is going to get worse space with the
amount of launching. I mean, just look at Starlink, speaking of something that could be mistaken for
a UAP. It's just astounding. Thousands, tens of thousands of satellites and constellations,
all full of parts that can get lost. And Starlink is a great example of we had many multiple reports
of UAP and multiple UAP, some of them from very reputable groups, right? And whether it was special
forces or radars or what have you, that it would say it would be a Starlink launch that was
letting loose a string of 20 to 60 satellites. Well, if you look at a string of 20 to 60 satellites
being ejected from a launch through say an infrared system or a radar system, that looks
really weird. And unless you know that that's a Starlink launch, you're going to report it as a
weird UAP thing because that's what everybody was doing. So we had lots of that, lots of UAPs that
turned out to be Starlinks that we had to go back and correlate to a Starlink launch and correlate
to the trajectory of the satellites. And yes, that was just Starlink. Now you had a slide,
and I believe you showed it at your NASA presentation. You had a slide about UAP reporting
trends and it had some interesting stuff hidden in there. One was radio emission section. It said
one to three gigahertz and then eight to 12 gigahertz. How did you arrive at those radio
frequencies as being associated with UAP? So let me be clear about what that section of that
chart said. If you look at the top of that, it should say reported UAP or something to that effect.
That set of characteristics that we put in there, it was taken from all of the various reports
at that time. We've had reports about, you know, they're spherical, we've had reports about
there being possible radio frequencies that might be correlated with it. And those were the
radio frequencies that were reported. We never measured those radio frequencies, but there were,
you know, some, like I want to say it was one or two reports that said that those were potentially
correlated with the observation of a UAP. Now what's important is it just so happens that one
to three gigahertz is also Wi-Fi and the eight to 10 is near one of the X band radars. So there's,
there are other potential explanations for what those radio frequencies were, but that was what
was reported. And we were trying to capture in that chart, here's kind of everything we're looking
for. And how we're trying to go about doing that is, well, yeah, all right, we're going to
put some sensors out to measure those frequencies and we're going to look at, can I correlate that
with any observations of UAP? And we did not, we found none of that. Now the other part of it
that I found interesting was stationary to Mach 2. Did you ever see anything anomalous that was
going Mach 2 because a balloon is not going to do that? Or was that just the, under that same
categorization that you're like, well, this is what we should look for at these speeds,
but why not faster? No, that's what was, again, that was what was reported. The high end of that
range came from some, from a report from a radar that, that seemed to indicate that an object was
going from roughly, I want to say it was around 0.4 Mach up to, you know, not quite two, but one,
one and a half Mach or something like that. And then dropping back down. And what we think that
actually turned out to be was this phenomenon with the radar where the pulses were not all returned
and the onboard algorithm, which was trying to calculate range and speed, was filling in the
gaps with the missing data. And that gave it, that essentially made it calculate this,
this very rapid acceleration. So we think that particular case was essentially a radar artifact,
but again, all of those parameters are things that had been reported. And so we wanted to
capture all of that as a holistic, here is the entirety of what's been reported and we're going
to be investigating each of those. And we're going to see if we can measure anything in a more
controlled fashion with better fidelity that would substantiate any of those characteristics
that were reported. Other countries. Now, we're not the only country in the world and other
countries have looked into UAP. In fact, France has looked into it for decades through their
Gaipin program and they've correlated all kinds of stuff. And there was even a semi-official report
that concluded that aliens were the best option. Was there any international coordination between
Aero and other countries regarding what they see with UAP and in particular France, because a lot
of people associate UAP with nuclear energy and France is the only other country that operates a
nuclear powered aircraft carrier. Did you ever call the French and ask them, what do you guys see?
Yeah, we've, we've, we had coordinated with a number of countries and we were trying to get
kind of a level set of what, what does each country actually see? What do they have data to support
and what kind of framework are they putting in place, if any, to do the same sort of measurement
and analysis that we were. And most all of them, in fact, all of them came back with, we don't
actually have any substantiating data. We, however, like your framework and we would like to leverage
your framework on how we're going to go about collecting and analyzing this. And we'd like to
share data and, and see if we can try to get to the bottom of some of these things. Now
they put into place to my knowledge, many of the same reporting requirements and data requirements,
but they didn't, they, they haven't gotten anything and they certainly hadn't provided
anything to us by the time I retired. Now moving further instrumentation and
mounted on military assets. Now you've touched on this a little bit, but let's go into it deeper.
The idea of classification, and you've said this many times, is not because of what you're seeing,
a bird isn't classified, the instrument is, and you can't tell other nation states your capabilities
and you want to keep that as secret as possible. But can you go out and take, I don't know, off
the shelf stuff, sort of like what the Galileo project is doing and create an experiment to
watch and then mounted on an aircraft carrier in a way that doesn't show anything sensitive
and do a data set like that. Will Arrow try to proactively collect data on UAP from military
assets? So that was the plan. You know, I'd have to refer you back to them to see how far they've
gotten down that roadmap. But let's, let's talk about the classification of data for a minute,
because it's an important aspect that, that keeps coming up. So there are two ways data gets
classified, right? I can have a classified sensor that has state of the art technology.
I don't want my adversary to know what my sensor can do, because if the adversary knows what my
sensor can do, then they can defeat it or they can spoof it or they can jam it or they can do
whatever. But if I have a great sensor and it's on a platform and it takes a picture of a Coke can,
that picture is classified because if I, if I release that picture as it is, then somebody
can take that picture and reverse engineer the picture and figure out what the sensor can do.
And then you've, you've given away a susceptibility of the sensor. That doesn't mean that the Coke can
is classified. It just means that the image is because of that. So to declassify that takes time
because the owner of the sensor and the platform has to do a couple of things. One, they have to
scrub the data down to remove anything that could be exploited by an adversary. And that can,
that can mean everything from reducing resolution to scrubbing all of the metadata and all the
things off of that. And then they have to evaluate it based on where it was taken,
because if it was taken during a sensitive operation, you don't want to give away details
about the operation. And so, you know, the owner operator has to sign off on that. All of that
takes time. And, and the time that it takes is directly proportional to the priority of said
thing. And so, for example, there was the incident last year, I think it was last year sometime where
the, where the Russians, you know, flew at the predator and we had the video, we got the video
declassified. And I want to say it was like 36 hours sent out. Well, that's because there was
a high, high, high priority with international relations with Russia. And the White House was
very interested in making sure we got that out. So under that kind of pressure, that declassification
is going to happen very quickly. Now, there's a whole other way that a set of data can become
classified. And this, this gets to, you know, commercial technology or scientific technology
that isn't, the sensor isn't classified. But if I take a camera and I go out and I,
I take a picture of the back end of the new B-21, that's classified because we're hiding
certain characteristics of the platform, even though the sensor wasn't. So you have to balance
and you have to understand what is being collected. So one of the, one of the,
one of the issues is not imagery, but actual signals. So what signals are being collected
off of say military comms systems or radar systems or platforms that you don't want others to know
about? Because then that gives them access to, you know, command and control and how the,
how the sensor RF might operate. And that's a, that's just as vulnerable as the imagery aspect.
So there's a, there's a wide range of things that affect classification,
but the collection of a UAP is not classified unless it comes from a classified sensor
that we have to then have declassified, unless it's being taken in front of a new stealthy
platform that we don't want anybody to know about. So those are the kinds of things that,
that affect classification and how fast you can get it declassified.
Now, what of agencies within the Pentagon that have a different classification system,
lesser perhaps, or classified for completely different reasons? And I would implicate the
Coast Guard here because they do similar things to the Navy. The Navy sees UAP. What does the
Coast Guard see? And is that less classified? So if the Coast Guard saw anything,
unless they're using a special sensor to collect it, it shouldn't be classified,
but the Coast Guard didn't give us any reports of any.
So nothing from the Coast Guard. That's interesting. Nope.
For comparison reasons, you know, with, with the Navy, but different, different instruments.
They're working with a completely different set of Coast Guard. Yeah. A Coast Guard cutter is
going to have a lot of different equipment related to law enforcement more than the military.
At least in peacetime anyway. Now, as the director of Arrow, now former director,
had you found something in the halls of government? Let's say a frozen alien body
sitting at an Air Force base or something like that, Area 51 or whatever. How would you have
handled that? And would you have disclosed it? I mean, what would you do if you had found something
and then a future director of Arrow? What, what if they find something hidden and they're like,
how do I release this or do I?
So nothing would have made me happier than to be able to actually find aliens, but I didn't.
So I've actually had this conversation with multiple folks in leadership, both my previous
boss, the deputy secretary and the undersecretary INS. And the, and the question was just that,
right? If we find something or we measure something or we collect on something,
what classification is it? What should it be? Is it even classified? And the answer that I think
we all settled on was the discovery of extraterrestrial life is not a department
of defense or IC mission. It is NASA's mission. And so if we had found anything to that sort,
it would have been turned over to NASA for disclosure and announcement and analysis.
Yes. But what if it was technologically advantageous? So you get a piece of UFO
that's very, very high technology that we could back engineer and use. I don't know that you
would hand that over to NASA. So how would you classify that? I don't know that anybody,
I don't know that anyone would actually do so. They might keep the technology to try and understand
how to use it, but the existence thereof would still be turned over to NASA.
So openness, were you happy with the openness that you got with, within investigating branches
of the government and asking around, were they, did you run into anything where you're like, well,
this person's being invasive or anything like that. And the thing is, is that, you know, you can't
read a person into every program, every SAP or everything, because that's dangerous. You don't
want somebody knowing too much. So were you happy with the openness or did you ever hit any brick
walls? Now people sometimes speak about that, that hitting brick walls in government, like the
Department of Energy perhaps, did you run into any of that? No. In fact, everybody across multiple
departments, Homeland Security, DOE, DOD, IC, everybody, NASA, everybody was fully open and
transparent because they wanted to put data to this problem. They wanted to address this problem
because frankly, they wanted to stop having to answer the questions. They wanted to move on with
the missions that were really important to them. I don't know, like a couple of world wars and
some conflicts and maybe going back to the moon and things of that nature. So I never ran into any
hesitation. I was given access across the board on everything that we needed, everything that we
came across. If I came across something that I didn't already have access to, I would get access
to it. And then we analyzed and assessed everything. And it's fascinating to me how folks
try to hide behind that. And I don't know how many ways I can say this clearly. Every program that
people named as being potentially part of this conspiracy, we had full access to hold the programs
out of the archives in many instances, got exactly what they were. And when I wrote up the final
assessment, there was a very classified version that had all of those programs that were identified
in there and what they actually were and what the conspiracy theorists were claiming they were.
And that is with the congressional leadership and with the department leadership and with the
IC leadership. And so going in the future, that will continue. The next director will
finish that analysis with the next set of data that had come in as I was retiring.
We had reviewed all of those programs. Same thing. Nothing extraterrestrial there, but
fascinating nonetheless. Do you think the government sometimes shoots itself in the
foot, however, and creates mistrust? And we have to point out during the Cold War, all sorts of
weird things happened. Things like, for example, the church committee uncovering hidden documents
that were stuck in a warehouse when a bunch of them had been destroyed by, I believe, the CIA.
Or testing radiation patterns by dumping radioactive materials off buildings in St. Louis,
giving people syphilis, all of that. The government has a terrible track record from that period
for openness and transparency and not sticking to government, you know, stuff that, you know,
ethical stuff that it should. I'm not saying that this is going on now, but it did. It did happen.
Could it be that during that period, the US government was perpetuating an alien origin
hypothesis for UAP in order to hide the very programs that you looked into that people are
associating with UFOs? Yeah, that is a very plausible hypothesis. And yes, the government
tends to shoot itself in the foot often. I think one of my windmills that I tilt at is the lack of
really communication and transparent, not transparency, but a lack of communication
in what they're finding and how it was found to try to mitigate some of the narrative and get
control of the narrative that's out there. Certainly that is a possibility. What we found,
and I think, again, what is important to understand from a historical perspective,
is there was no organized Pentagon level concerted effort to perpetrate such a cover story,
if you will. There is some anecdotal evidence of local officers or local commands jumping on that
bandwagon in order to hide programs because that was an easy cover story and it was fun to do.
But it's come back, I think, to really bite them. And now that you've got to be able to
demonstrate that through data documents and people who can attest to it, and that's
going to take time and investigation. And a lot of it, I'm sure, is going to be protected under
the Whistleblower Protection Act that everybody pushed to get forward. And while it protects both
ways, so anybody that comes forward to talk about their knowledge of that kind of a cover up is
also protected. So it's going to be hard to untangle a lot of that. Do you think it's possible
in your position, which everybody knew what you were doing and you were appointed to it and
doing it, do you think it's possible that you were misled by anybody, in the contractor system,
particularly? Do you think that, you know, was there any indication that you thought,
well, maybe I could be misled here? No, I had no indication of that. A lot of these folks,
especially in the contractor communities, I've known for many, many, many years, had working
relationships with. They bent over backwards to try to not only help me find records or evidence,
but also people who had knowledge, you know, kind of firsthand knowledge of story origins and what
was actually happening at the time that this particular event was said to have occurred,
and got them to come in to talk to us so that we could document all of that and write it down and
investigate it and cross-reference it. So we actually untangled quite a bit of one of the
allegations for a contractor, you know, hiding in this technology and where that actually came
from and how it was linked to some of these other stories that don't have any validity either.
So it's an interesting way that the stories propagated, but from a misled perspective,
no, I had no indication I was being misled by anyone other than some of the whistleblowers
that were coming in. Now, there is something burning the internet down, and it's another
FOIA thing, talking about recovery and materials transfer in a document. What did that mean? What
is the story behind that document? Okay, so Arrow is congressionally directed to come up with
not just standard reporting or procedures, but also mitigation and response procedures for,
in the event of a shootdown or a collection of any sort of UAP, keeping in mind that UAP
involves everything from balloons to drones to alleged alien tech. And so to do that,
mitigation and response, as well as standardized reporting, will occur through all of the combatant
commands. And so that particular meeting was to go meet with the J3, who's in charge of operations,
to start the discussion on how we're going to define those procedures and whether or not
we have to provide a flyaway team in the event of any sort of shootdown to collect whatever is there,
because by law, Congress told Arrow it had to come up with mitigation and response procedures,
as well as develop flyaway teams or whatnot to go and collect anything that had to be done.
The problem is, those types of activities are already covered under foreign material
collection and analysis. So there's already a process and procedures in place for many of
these things. And so this conversation was really to start, how do we document that for UAP? And
what kind of procedures do we need to put in place? What kind of processes do we need to put in place?
And I started with space command, because that's where I came from. And that was a kind of an easy
way to get this started to address congressional concerns. So there wasn't an actual thing. It was
a, hey, we need to go have a conversation about how we're going to do this and get the teams
started in documenting that, that goes into the J3, which is the director of operations,
operational procedures and processes. So you literally created a UFO recovery team,
in short, in the event something like that were to happen? It's any UAP recovery. And it was really
more the process and procedure, because they already have people in place that would collect,
if we shot down another Chinese high-optitude balloon, it's that team that would go and collect
it. It's those procedures and processes on how it gets notified and how we go and get it.
And that would be now true for pretty much anything. Does the government have an Indiana Jones
warehouse where they have all of these foreign materials, Russian, Soviet, materials from the
Cold War planes and things like that, that they recovered parts of the missiles and everything
else that are archived somewhere and still kept secret because it's sensitive because of foreign
relations? I wish we had a big old warehouse like that, but that would be fun. But we do,
the IC and the DOD collects foreign material and they exploit it, just like foreign adversaries
collect on us and exploit it. And so some of that stuff is stored in places. I had to ask a question
because obviously it's burning the internet down. So, all right, aliens. I got two more questions
for you. And this one's just aliens in general. Is that treated as a national security concern?
In other words, say you had found something, wouldn't that be really scary to have an alien
civilization of presence here of very highly advanced nature, far beyond anything we can do?
Does the government say that's a national security threat? In other words,
would that have been a high priority? You know, we need to build some missiles or something like
that. Or do they just assume they'd have done something by now if they were here?
No, and this will be a wholly unsatisfying answer. But when we actually, again, when we had this
conversation about if we actually found anything, what would the classification be and how would we
handle it? Most of that apart from, you know, the part of, okay, we're going to get, you know,
NASA will take lead, but it's also going to be, it's got to go up to the president for a decision on,
you know, is it a national security issue or is it a, you know, human, you know, humanity,
civilization issue? And so that's, I think, what would actually happen is it would get briefed
over probably in partnership with the department by NASA up to the president for a decision.
Yeah, and I know certain presidents have thought about it because I believe Ronald Reagan asked
Gorbachev if the Soviets would help us if there was an alien threat and Gorbachev said yes. But
again, you know, that's presidential level. Now, my last question, and this is a fun one.
In looking into all of these programs and past programs and finding, not evidence of aliens,
but did you find weird historical stuff that's eventually going to come out about programs that
we did that's just really cool? In other words, we really did make this kind of a plane or something
like that and it's just not out there yet. Was there anything that you thought, wow, that's amazing?
Well, obviously, I would have to say I am very impressed and deeply proud of both the DOD and the
IC's capabilities that they are developing and building to protect this nation. And I think
everybody should take some solace in that. There are some really, really great technologies that
are coming. Really great. I'm hoping for fusion energy. Well, everybody's hoping.
Everybody's hoping. Well, imagine if you had, I remember Lockheed was developing a compact
or trying to develop a compact fusion reactor that could be launched into space that was the
size of a truck. And I'm like, man, if we had that and we had fusion energy in space, it's
Battlestar Galactica. Oh yeah, that'd be awesome. It would be. All right, Dr Kirkpatrick. Oh yeah,
go ahead. No, I was just going to say there's a fusion energy conference coming up here at the
end of next month. I think we'll talk about the state of the art of fusion community. I think that
would be a fascinating thing to listen to. Oh, absolutely. All right, Dr Kirkpatrick,
thank you for joining us. I've been giving me so much time and good luck in your endeavors from
now on and I will continue to watch Arrow under the new director and see what they find, or don't
find. All right. Now we're not fine. Yes. All right. Well, I appreciate it. Thanks very much.
Let me know if there's anything else you need. Event Horizon and my channel are now available
as a podcast on Apple podcasts, Spotify, and YouTube memberships. Early ad-free episodes,
bonus episodes, and sleep-focused content. Sign up now by clicking the links below to
your platform of choice.