Can we achieve faster than light travel? That's the big question, isn't it? It is important,
though. Throughout the history of sci-fi, it's been explored many times, but usually never backed
up as to how it could happen. That was usually glanced over. And faster than light travel is
something we want. Warping at many times the speed of light to explore our entire universe
is an alluring idea, especially if we want to someday meet intelligent alien life. It's
infectious, even. So how do we do that, speaking in terms of the real universe?
Unfortunately, there have never been very many ways to do it according to known physics.
In fact, it's almost hostile to the idea. Breaking the speed of light within Einstein's
relativity, the best description of the universe at large that we have, would require infinite
energy. Infinite energy isn't possible. Or is there another way? Is there a way to essentially
hack the universe and move at speeds so fast that science fiction generally didn't imagine
until science itself actually did? My guest today explored just such a concept after watching an
episode of Star Trek and thinking about how a warp field could be established that would allow
faster than light travel. It's just an idea consistent with relativity, there's no guarantee
it would actually work. But it's one that so far has stood the test of time. People still wonder
about this idea over 20 years after its formulation. As I said, it's consistent with relativity,
but with caveats. Pretty big ones. But it's important to explore the idea nonetheless.
After all, if we respond to all ideas as inherently impossible,
we'd have never gotten very far as a civilization. So can we actually travel faster than light?
This episode is theoretical physicist Dr. Miguel Alcubierre. Dr. Alcubierre received his PhD in
1994 through the study of numerical general relativity and has since worked at the Max
Planck Institute for Gravitational Physics in Potsdam, Germany and the National Autonomous
University of Mexico. Dr. Alcubierre is best known for his 1994 paper, The Warp Drive,
Hyperfast Travel Within General Relativity, where he describes his theory for traveling
faster than light with what's become known as the Alcubierre Warp Drive.
Welcome everyone to Event Horizon with me, John Michael Godier. If you enjoy what you hear,
fall into the Event Horizon, hit the like button and become an active subscriber by ringing the
bell. Miguel Alcubierre, welcome to the program. Hi, hello.
Doctor, everybody knows you for your warp bubble concept, but you've done a lot of science. That
was 1994. You've done a lot of science since then. What is your work focus on these days?
Well, on these days I've been working on black hole formation and also on something a little
bit esoteric that we call boson stars, which is a model for a star made of a special kind of field
that could mimic a black hole in many circumstances. So I've been specializing
in that area and my work is mostly numerical simulations. So for a long time I've been doing
numerical simulations of black hole space stamps, formation of black holes, collapse of stars,
and also gravitational waves, production of gravitational waves. So that's my main work
and I've been working on that for the last 20 odd years.
We recently detected with the LIGO experiment the formation of or the coalescing of two neutron
stars and I suppose that would be even more applicable to black holes if you have a binary
black hole that's merging. Now, do you study that? I've studied binary black hole formation,
collision of binary black holes, not so much neutron stars. Neutron stars are difficult
for different reasons because they have a lot of matter and you have to do fluid dynamics and
maybe magnetic fields and things like that. Black holes are cleaner and I've been studying black
holes for a long time. So during the 90s and even early part of the 2000s my main work was black hole
simulations, simulations of black holes that collide in an inspiral, they're orbiting and
they do an inspiral collision. And that was actually the first thing detected by LIGO.
Three years ago they detected the first gravitational wave detection ever was a collision
of two black holes which is exactly the problem I have been working for a long time. Now when
black holes merge collide like that, how long does that process take before they become entangled
and gravitationally and they actually collide? Depends very much on how they formed but it could
take tens of millions of years. It's a very very long process. It's very slow. They approach each
other very slowly because they're emitting very low gravitational waves energy. They're losing
energy in gravitational waves but it's very very slow and those gravitational waves in principle
cannot be detected because they're extremely weak but this process takes millions and millions
of years but eventually they get to the point in which they're very very close and they're
separated just by a few times their own radius and at that point the whole process can take just
fractions of a second and that's what we detect. So the final, the detection of gravitational waves
from a black hole collision typically only detects the less than a second, the last fraction of a
second of a collision. That's what we can detect and the first detection actually the whole thing
lasted for about 20, 20 parts of a second so 120 of a second or something like that. It was really
very very close. Neutron stars actually take longer so when two neutron stars collide we can
detect the last minute or so of the collision and that's because they're usually closer by
so the signal is stronger and it's also more in the range of the detector so we can detect for
longer but black holes is a very very fast process what we can detect. So when you have two incredibly
dense objects like two black holes or two neutron stars for that matter, this has to be a ridiculously
abnormal environment. Do you see things like, so you create gravitational waves but what other
radiation comes out of that? Do you see like this perhaps a solution to something like fast radio
bursts where you you just see this mysterious burst of radiation that comes out of nowhere?
Could that be from these kinds of mergers? That's exactly what we think. Not from black holes. When
two black holes merge then nothing else happens. It's only gravitational waves because black holes
are vacuum. They have no matter. The matter has all been concentrated in the center and the center
is beyond the horizon so it cannot nothing that happens inside the black hole can affect us and
no radiation comes out from there. So when two black holes collide all you get is gravitational
waves but when two neutron stars collide that's very different because neutrons are made of matter
they're made of fluids and they have magnetic fields and etc so when two neutron stars collide
essentially you get fireworks you get a huge explosion and and this explosion produces
radiation in all wavelengths and in principle yes we believe that part of the gamma ray bursts
that have been detected for the last 20 or 30 years by satellites come from collisions of
neutron stars. There are actually two different types of gamma ray bursts what we call the long
lived and the short lived and we believe that the short lived are mainly caused by collisions of
neutron stars. The long lived we still not sure but the short lived are probably almost always
the collision of two neutron stars and this is extremely interesting because if we can get
the information from the collision of the neutron stars with gravitational waves and also we can
detect them also with gamma rays and other things then we can learn a lot about the system.
We can even do cosmology. So these types of systems are far more interesting. At the moment
there's only one confirmed detection of a collision of two neutron stars from LIGO
from gravitational waves that was just over a year ago a year and a half ago and there hasn't been
another announced but maybe they they've seen something in the last few weeks and they're a
bit cautious about announcing it there might be some hints about it but that those are the
extremely interesting systems collisions of stars give us a lot more information about the universe.
Now is that due to the fact that nothing can escape a black hole's event horizon so if you
have two black holes coalescing and and falling into each other and becoming a single black hole
you can't get anything except gravitational waves because nothing can escape the the black holes
so you can't get any kind of of radiation other than I guess some maybe some kind of
Hawking radiation off it so is that the case that that they're just simply that's exactly
the case when two black holes collide there's nothing else there's just two black holes
there's nothing can escape from inside the black hole so there's no light there's no radiation of
any kind the only thing you get are gravitational waves so in that sense it's a very clean system
but it's also you can only detect it on gravitational waves and and nothing else
even even the Hawking radiation Hawking radiation is a concept that it's theoretically very well
understood but we've never seen evidence of that because for a black hole the size of a star or
bigger which is the ones we've seen the Hawking radiation is is completely negligible it's just
being ignored completely there's no hope of detecting it so what you detect is just the
gravitational waves coming from the collision still that's very interesting that was the first
system we've seen we saw and we've seen about 10 maybe a lot more now because LIGO's already taken
data again but until the beginning of this year we've seen about 10 collisions of black holes with
LIGO when i when i say seen i actually mean observed with gravitational waves not with light
but so that happens sufficiently often that we see them a lot collisions of neutral stars are not that
easy to see because if they happen very far away you can't see them because the signal is very weak
they have to happen very close by so you might be able to detect them but black holes you can
detect very far away because they're usually bigger and that means that the that the signal
in gravitational waves is much stronger but that's all you get so you get the gravitational wave you
know it was two black holes you can you can measure the distance because of the gravitational
waves and you can get the mass of the black holes and maybe if we're lucky even how fast they were
rotating but it's very difficult to know exactly where they were so we cannot pinpoint the galaxy
in which the black holes collided because there's no light coming out of the system
and the gravitational wave doesn't allow you to locate this in the in space very well so
you can sort of say it came from that region in space but we don't know exactly where
whereas with neutron star is much more different because if you see the light
then you can pinpoint the galaxy exactly what would the hawking radiation of a black hole
look like would it be uh gamma rays well yeah hawking radiation is as i mentioned is a
theoretical idea that came from hawking in the 70s it still has not been confirmed observationally
or experimentally but basically hawking radiation is just what we call black body radiation now a
black body is not the same as a black hole a black body is just physicists terms of saying
something hot so we call it a black body because it absorbs everything that falls into it but and
then emits the light back as just heat so the sun even though it's not black it's yellow but it's
a very good approximation to a black body in in physics terms it's just something that emits
light because of it's hot it is hot and depending on how hot it is it emits light in different
wavelengths so if it's not very hot you can't see it if it's a little bit hotter you see it
red and hotter still than yellow and if it's very hot you see it blue now black holes emit
radiation just like this a black body radiation but the temperature of a black hole is inverse
to its mass that means that very large black holes are essentially very cold and emit very
little radiation and radiation you cannot see with normal light it would come in radio waves
so for a for a black hole the mass of a star the hawking radiation would come in the very very
far radio waves and would be so weak that we wouldn't be able to detect it at all if the
black hole was very small and when i mean very small about the size of a of an atom or something
like that i mean really small with the mass of a few atoms then it would emit radiation very very
hot and it would come out in gamma rays probably but we haven't seen that it's it's very difficult
to detect so so there's no proof yet observation or proof that hawking radiation exists it's just
a theoretical idea now to get into the concept of a star drive that you could use a black hole to
drive the smaller the black hole the more radiation it emits right yes that's correct so if you if you
saw i mean could there be like a technosignature there as they say within astrobiology a technosignature
would an artificial very small black hole low mass yeah would that be visible as something that
you could say that is an alien star drive driven by a micro black hole not really because the
process it would be very very it's very fast a very small black hole with the mid hawking radiation
so fast that it would evaporate very quickly and what you would see essentially is probably
something more like an explosion a burst of gamma rays so some people have actually speculated
the gamma ray bursts are actually black holes evaporating but the idea doesn't fit very well
but you would see some sort of burst of radiation and that's it it would die very quickly
because the black hole as it evaporates as it emits radiation it loses mass and the smaller
it is the faster this goes so very small black hole would evaporate very quickly in a matter
of seconds so you wouldn't see something that just emitting hawking radiation for a long time
you would see a burst of radiation and then it's dead right it would be something very quick
and and also depends on the size if you have a small black hole that's still a few grams in
weight that would still not emit enough hawking radiation for us to detect it it would have to be
something that weighs not much more than a few atoms and then you would see a lot of
radiation and it would happen very quickly so you would see it as a burst but so say you had a
kugelblitz essentially a tiny little black hole that you've artificially created with lasers
it would radiate in a certain way but very rapidly if i'm understanding it correctly so you would
see it evaporate almost instantly exactly yeah now you're also known for the alcubierre warp
field and i call it the warp field because you know a lot of people say star drive but it's really
the idea of warping space time at its most at its most basic what is the alcubierre warp field
well the idea is just the way in which you can deform space that would allow you to travel in
principle as fast as you want in space without actually moving so it's it's as you mentioned
it correctly it's not a star drive it's not a machine it has nothing to do with a spaceship
it's just a model of what you would need to do to space to be able to move very fast and the idea
is to use the fact that space can be deformed and according to the theory of relativity einstein's
general relativity gravity is just a deformation of space it's a deformation of the of the geometry
of space so space can be curved usually people here talk about the curvature of space or space
time but a curvature is a very generic name so you can do many things to space you can expand
it and you can contract it for example and we've all heard about the expansion of the universe
and that happens because space is expanding so people usually don't understand that correctly
because they think that if space the expansion of the universe they think is because galaxies
are flying apart because there was some huge explosion somewhere but it's not like that at
all and galaxies are not flying apart galaxies are just sitting there quietly in their own corner
of the universe but space between them is expanding it's been stretched so you can do that to space you
can stretch space and you can also contract space and then the idea i had back in 94 was that you
can do this in a very small scale so if you imagine that you do a very violent but very
localized expansion of space behind you that would push you away from things that are behind you
and if at the same time you do an opposite contraction of space in front of you that would
pull you towards things in front of you and the net effect of those two things combined is that
you would move you would move through space you would get away from the things behind you and
closer to the things in front of you but you will not be moving yourself you would be sitting in a
bubble of quiet space if you want with a violent expansion behind you and a violent contraction in
front of you and that would apparently you would move through space without moving at all so it
would space doing the moving and this is the idea i had as i called it the warp drive because it
gave me the a similar idea to what happens in science fiction but it's this idea of warping
space to be able to to move fast very fast and there's no limit to how fast space can expand
or contract so in principle you could use this sort of warp bubble to move faster than light
so that was the idea i had in 94 now there's a price to pay and there's nothing is free so the
the theory of relativity tells you that curvature or this geometry of space time can be the firm
deformed but it's deformed through them through the effect of gravity so you need large concentrations
of mass and energy to produce a deformation of space and there's some equations we call them
the Einstein field equations that tell you if you have this concentration of matter you will produce
this deformation of space and that's the normal way in which we go about it we we think okay we
have a star and the star has this concentration of mass and we go through the equations and figure
out what the deformation of space related to the star is and then that gives us the gravitational
field of the star but in this case i did it the other way around i said i want this very specific
deformation of space this warp bubble and you go through the equations backwards and it tells you
what sort of energy density at what sort of mass distribution you need it to be able to
produce this strange deformation of space and when you do that you find that it's something very
nasty because you need something with physicists called negative energy which maybe doesn't say
much to ordinary people but if people remember this famous equation e equals mc squared that
tells you energy and mass are the same thing then when we talk about negative energy we're really
talking about negative mass and negative mass as far as we understand does not exist in the
universe so that's a big problem with the warp drive you need negative energy and even if you
have negative energy you need huge amounts of negative energy because to deform the space is
very difficult to deform space it doesn't like to be deformed so in order to deform space a lot you
need huge concentrations of mass you need planets entire planets of energy to be able to deform space
even a little bit so you would need for the warp drive the equivalent of a jupiter sized object
but on pure energy and also the energy would have to be negative not positive so that's that's a big
problem with the warp drive but the idea was just just this basic idea that you can actually
deform space and it would allow you to travel faster than light if you deform it in the right
way the idea of the of the warp bubble and warp drive what inspired you to think about this was
science fiction as in star trek yeah i was actually watching an episode of star trek the
next generation i don't remember which episode it was but it was some episode of star trek the
next generation sometime in 92 i was doing my phd at the time in britain and watching this episode
they they keep always talking about the warp drive and the warp drive and and i was doing a
phd in the black holes at the time in black hole collisions precisely and i was using ancient
theory of relativity all the time so i started thinking how maybe if they talk about the warp
drive they mean that they're deforming space so how could you really deform space to to be able
to do something similar to what they do in science fiction and i started thinking about that and then
i had this idea of the expansion and contraction of space the expansion behind you the construction
in from in front this sort of bubble and then i went back to the office and i did some quick
calculations to see if the idea could be expressed mathematically in a simple way and i found that it
yes you could express it mathematically in a relatively simple way so i did it and then
eventually i published a paper about that i actually i was doing my my my phd at the time
so i was still a student i went to my supervisor to tell him about the idea and i had already
written something up and i was afraid he would tell me to just stop thinking idiotic ideas and
go back to work but he was actually very supportive he told me that it was a very nice idea and i and
he helped me publish it so it was actually my first scientific paper and on that note we have
to go to break be sure to like subscribe and hit the bell for this channel if you like interviews
like this and we will be back in a moment and we'll talk much more extensively about the idea
of a warp bubble if you'd like to support event horizon you'll be pleased to know we've recently
launched a patreon link in the description below or alternatively you can use your cellular
telephone to scan the assemblage of squares on screen now be sure to like subscribe and
share the video and now back to john and we're back with dr mcgill alcubierre doctor you were
inspired by star trek too which is something that that i think is important because science
fiction tends to inspire the imagination for anybody from scientists down to the common person
you were inspired into thinking about could you create a warp field now yeah tell us more about
this warp field where you could create a geometry i suppose of spacetime where you have one area of
spacetime in front of the ship and the ship is stationary within a piece of spacetime essentially
broken off from the rest of of spacetime so how does it work is it less dense in front of the ship
and more dense behind the ship how does this work well it's it's not so much density is is
it's a dynamic thing is space can contract and it can expand so in front of the ship you would
have a region in which space is contracting very violently and very quickly and behind it you would
have a region an opposite region in which is expanding very violently and very quickly
and it would do this in in a thin shell so the idea is that you would have a sort of relatively
large region of space in which space is quiet and nothing is happening to it and and you're sitting
inside this this region and then on the boundary of this region you have a very thin shell in which
there's either expansion behind you or contraction in front of you and this is a very violent effect
so you would it can move you very fast so that's the basic idea and this is when we think about a
field here we're talking about really what's really the gravitational field it's a gravitational
field is the geometry of spacetime that's how we understand it so it's the gravitational field the
one that's producing this now you can think about another kind of field or energy field or something
that's the one that producing this right so because if you want to deform space you need
some concentration of energy or mass so the easiest thing is to think that it's not so much
mass that you're carrying around with you or negative mass is some sort of energy field that
you're projecting and this energy field has a very large negative energy and this produces this
strange curvature a strange expansion and contraction of space in front and behind you
so that's the basic idea i never went very much or very far into the details i just wanted to
show that this was in principle possible that the equations of general relativity allowed for the
formation of space that looked like this and i also showed very quickly that you would need this
negative energy which is a big drawback because as far as we understand we don't have it in the
universe so that's that's basically how i how i left it and and then i never worked back on the
on that again so a lot of people have worked on that in the past 25 years but i never went back
i i only wrote the first paper and then i've been just looking about what people say about it
you introduced an idea and saw what happened exactly so because of mass energy equivalence
if if you see and you have evidence of negative energy which maybe there is a little bit of
evidence for that there's certainly nothing for negative mass but is there any evidence
that we could create such a material negative energy might be possible in small regions of space
and in very small quantities i'm not sure if that would be useful for the warp drive because
one thing is maybe it's possible but maybe you can't control it very well and maybe it's very
a very small quantity and you need huge amounts of it but still it's it's possible that negative
energy exists we have hints about it quantum theory tells us that in some circumstances
something that like negative energy happens for example a very classic example that comes from
about 50 years ago is something that comes from quantum mechanics quantum field theory
and it's actually called the casimir effect and the casimir effect the idea is you put two
parallel metallic plates very close to each other and the metallic plates conduct electricity and
that means that even if they're not charged they they produce some sort of boundary conditions for
the electric field and it's because they're conductive so inside between the plates then
you can only have a very definite number of of modes of the electric field those that fit in
there it's like a string if you have a string in a guitar can only oscillate in a given certain
ways because of the length of the string so this is the same idea that the separation of the plates
makes the the electric field in the middle allows it only to oscillate in very specific ways
and outside of those plates the electric field can oscillate any way it wants because there's no
nose restriction and we know that according to quantum theory the vacuum is not empty so that
means that the vacuum is actually full of fields popping in and out of existence all the time we
call that the vacuum energy or the vacuum the quantum vacuum or the vacuum energy and it since
outside you have have more freedom than inside the plates that mean that inside the plates you
have less vacuum energy than outside and if you define the vacuum energy outside as zero
then it means that inside the plates you have negative energy because it's less than zero
so that's an effect that we've been we've known for about 50 years it's a completely theoretical
idea it hasn't been measured not the energy there's a secondary effect that all these things would
imply that the plates feel a small amount of force and there will be a force that will try to put
them together to bring them together this is called the casimir force and i understand that
the casimir force has been measured it's very difficult experiment but apparently the casimir
force has been measured but the this negative energy inside has not been measured now if it
does exist and it probably does it would be a very small amount of negative energy so it's not
enough for a warp drive by far and and even then it's not clear how you can manipulate that so
it's very little and not very easy to manipulate so i'm not sure that would help but there's this
hints that maybe in some cases negative energy exists then we also know in a separate case in
which is not so much negative energy but there's something like anti-gravity going on around in
the universe and maybe anti-gravity could also be used for the warp drive it's not clear at the
at the moment but maybe we could and when i talk about anti-gravity we normally think of gravity
as a force that brings things together that planets attract each other and objects attract
each other because of gravity and that gravity would be a repulsive form of gravity that would
make things repel each other and this might exist because we've seen in the universe at large for
the last 20 just over 20 years we've realized that the the expansion of the universe is accelerating
instead of decelerating it's going faster and faster all the time and the only way in which
we can understand this is by postulating some sort of anti-gravity in the universe at large
we normally call it dark energy so if you hear about dark energy when people talk about the
universe is this mysterious form of energy an energy field that produces a little bit of
anti-gravity that causes the expansion of the universe to accelerate and this anti-gravity
might be useful for the warp drive i'm not sure i've tried to do some calculations in the past but
i've never been able to go very far but my hope is that yes maybe dark energy could be used to
do something similar to a warp drive at some point in the future but but still not clear at this point
so because of mass energy equivalence einstein's famous equation e equals mc squared if you can
find some sort of negative energy whether it's dark energy or or casimir effect or what have you
does that suggest that you could create and actually perhaps manufacture negative mass
at you know an object that has negative mass yeah it's a good point and one might think that
it's possible i don't think it's very likely because when we think about mass as such we're
actually thinking of on particles elementary particles we have no hints that there's any
elementary particle with negative mass in this case would when we think about negative energy
would be more like a an energy field and it's the energy would not so much be negative per se but
just less than the vacuum and the vacuum it would define the vacuum as zero then it would be negative
would be more like that like less than the vacuum and and it's difficult to see how you can translate
that into a particle and make a particle with negative mass so even though it might be suggested
by the formula equals mc squared i think in practice there's there's probably not not that
easy or not true at all that you could create a particle of negative mass but it's true that
nothing forbids it in the in the physical loss we know there's no nothing that forbids
to have a negative mass particle it's just it would do very strange things and we have never
seen something like that in other words the the universe does not ban the existence of something
with negative mass say you have a an apple made of negative mass that would be anti-gravity the
universe doesn't forbid it but that doesn't mean it can exist right yeah it's not so much the
universe doesn't forbid it is the loss of physics as we understand them today don't forbid it it
might be very well that the universe does forbid them but we just don't know how right so is the
loss we understand does not forbid it but there's no indication that that's something that can happen
right it's yeah it's not same so there's things that are not forbidden by the loss of nature but
don't happen for example the loss of nature are the loss of mechanics Newtonian mechanics
are reversible so in principle if it can break a glass in the floor the loss of mechanics would
allow the process to be reversed to all the pieces of glass to jump together and and coalesce into
a full-form glass and jump into my hand that's allowed by the loss of physics but it doesn't
happen right because it violates all the things like thermodynamics and things like that so it's
just statistically not not not likely to happen so it might be something like that that the loss
of physics do not forbid negative mass but maybe it's again statistically unlikely in the same
way as a glass reconstruction itself would be unlikely right so very very unlikely say let's
conjecture for a moment say that it could exist is there a way for the big bang to have produced
matter with negative mass if they do exist then they should have been produced in the big bang
the big bang there was so much energy around that essentially any particle that could exist was
created most of those particles don't live very long so that would be another question right you
have a negative mass particle how long does it live so most most elementary particles we know
about are actually unstable and they decay very quickly into other other types of particles and
in the end we're only left with a few stable particles which the ones we were taught about in
high school right the positive right the the proton the neutron and the electron and everything
is made of those three because those are the only three that are actually survived because they're
stable all the other zoo of particles that we know from particle physics are unstable but they're all
produced at the big bang because at the big bang there were so much energy available available that
everything was everything that could be produced was produced so yes if negative energy particles
can exist and in principle they could be have been produced in the big bang but the next question
would be how long do they live if they don't live very long we wouldn't see them around
and it would be interesting if there was some sort of stable negative energy particle but then
we would have seen it that that's what we would expect right if there's some sort of stable
particle then we should see it today because since it's stable it should be around it we should be
able to detect it right and we haven't been able to detect anything like that so if they do exist
they're probably not stable now that's somewhat of a mystery in and of itself within within physics
is if the big bang created antimatter then shouldn't we see what happened to all the
antimatter it should have been an almost equivalent amount to normal matter but yet we don't see it
leading to questions about is the is did did most of the universe annihilate you know as far as
matter goes early on in the universe exactly that's an excellent question it's one of the biggest
puzzles and mysteries of modern physics that we don't know the answer to and we're certainly
worried about that so yes in the big bang as far as we understand physics today an equal amount of
particles and antiparticles should have been produced and then then those particles should
have annihilated each other when they found each other when a particle and antiparticle meet they
annihilate each other and they produce pure energy so we should live in a universe of pure energy
because all the particles and antiparticles should have annihilated each other and should have been
exactly equal amounts of them because of the symmetry and of course that's not the case
fortunately we're around and there's matter around so for some reason there must have been at the
beginning a slightly larger amount of matter than antimatter maybe a very small fraction but a
little bit more matter than antimatter and when the annihilation occurred some matter was left
behind we don't really know why that's a big question people have been thinking about that
for 50 years at least if famous physicists and even soviet physicists like gamma one thinks that
we're thinking about why matter prevails over antimatter and people are still thinking about
that today but we don't have a clear answer yet but it is one of the big mysteries of modern
to ethical physics why there is there's matter and no antimatter around back to matter with
negative mass how would this stuff behave it would be by its nature anti-gravity so
if you were looking for it in nature would it immediately eject itself out of a galaxy or would
it concentrate at certain points in a galaxy where you have this this gravitational equilibrium
going or would it be out in the intergalactic space just it would produce a different type
of gravity so a large object made of negative mass would produce a gravitational field that
would be repulsive so if you were so instead of falling into a lot so imagine you have a star
like the sun but it's made of negative mass so instead of falling into it you would be repelled
by it you would fly away from it because it the field it produces is opposite so it would produce
produce a repulsive field now as far as small particles that that's not true because a small
particle it doesn't matter that's one of the things we know about gravity that the trajectory
of a small particle when it's moving in a gravitational field of a much larger object
the trajectory follows independent of its mass so it doesn't matter the mass is positive or
negative it would do the same thing so if we have the sun and the sun is normal a normal star of
positive matter and we had an earth made of negative mass it would still go around the sun
exactly the same way the earth goes around the sun because the mass is much smaller and doesn't
matter if it's negative or positive it would follow the gravitational field of the sun and
that's attractive so it's more like that it large amounts of negative mass would produce a repulsive
gravitational field but a negative mass particle would not be repelled by the sun it would still
be attracted by the sun because it doesn't matter which side the mass is so yes particles of negative
mass would not be expelled from the galaxy but if they clump together into a larger object that
object would be repulsive things would fly away from that object now with this concept of negative
matter i suppose you could call it this is also important with things like creating stable worm
holes and and yeah essentially any speculative way we could conquer the speed of light so to speak
now the universe doesn't ban it but we have no indication of it how could we detect such matter
which i guess would be the first step in trying to harness its power how could we detect this negative
mass material if it existed at a distance it would be difficult you would have to find some
sort of objects large very large object in space that instead of attracting nearby objects repels
them so but if there was a galaxy with negative mass then we would have seen it because we would
see that the trajectories of other galaxies close to it are repulsive instead of attractive so
maybe we should be able to see it in large clusters of galaxies and if there was a galaxy
there with negative mass if if the object is much smaller then it's very difficult to detect
if you have individual particles with negative mass then we should see those in particle
accelerators and then we should be able to measure it because essentially energy is conserved so in
an interaction with mass with particles with negative mass you would see that you gain more
energy than you put in because some of the energy became negative and you ended up with negative
energy particles so that you you should be able to measure that in the energy balance and in
particle collisions in an accelerator so that which we would have seen an accelerator and we
haven't seen it but as as far as much larger objects in the universe that those are difficult
to detect unless they're extremely large and have a big effect on the surroundings based on
but but i think it would be difficult to see but again there's no indication that they
they exist because if there was negative energy particles we would see those on a laboratory in
the on the accelerators and we haven't so no evidence whatsoever no unfortunately
now back to the warp field if you were in a spacecraft sitting static within within the
warp field and you were traveling across the universe at superluminal speeds what would that
be like what what i mean would you experience radiation i mean what would being inside the
warp bubble be like yeah there's some people that have thought about that and they've even done
some simulations as to how the stars would look like if you're sitting inside a warp bubble so
and essentially if you're going very fast even faster than the speed of light the first thing
you would notice that the the stars in front of you first you would see them in a very small cone
in front of you so you would see stars only in a very small circular region directly in front of
you everything outside that small cone you wouldn't see because the light wouldn't be able to reach you
because you're going faster than the light so you wouldn't be able to see anything behind you
because nothing would be able to catch up with you not even light so behind you it would be
totally black but also in front of you in a large region only on you would see only a small circle
of stars but again if you're going faster than light then any light that hits you from from in
front is going to be blue shifted so it's going it's going to increase in energy we call that
a blue shift it's similar to what happens with with an ambulance when it's coming towards you
you hear a very high pitch and it's moving away from you you hear in a very low pitch
so it's the same thing with light Doppler effect it's Doppler effect so you would see
the light coming towards you blue shifted so again it would be far more dangerous because
something that's normally just ordinary light will probably be hitting you like gamma rays and those
are very dangerous and so you would receive a lot of radiation from the front of the ship
and also anything else that is in in your path if there's a rock in your path or something like
that you would hit it at a huge speed and it would probably be deadly even a small grain of sand
right so yeah it would be extremely dangerous unless you had a very high efficiency shield
to shield you from the radiation coming from in front and also from any small speck of dust that
could hit you and destroy the ship so anything everything that hits you comes with higher energy
because it's shifted right so yeah that's essentially what you would see so whatever
light comes in front of you would be shifted even probably towards gamma rays depending how
fast you're moving it would be deadly and and you would need a big shield but and you would see
also this this deformation only a small region in front of you would be able to reach you
everything else won't be able to catch you and as I said I haven't done these calculations myself
but people have done them and they've done simulations over the years about how it would
look like from inside the the warp bubble and this is sort of the the things you find
so if you were traveling through space at rel you know at faster than light speeds we're not even
talking about relativistic speeds we're we're faster than that and you you caught up material
in front of your ship if you came out a warp in front of a planet you could do some serious
damage to that planet by that material right that's a very good observation and it's also
something people have actually done calculations on everything that's anything that's in your
path and doesn't directly hit you if it was moving forward say but not as fast as you you would you
would catch it but then it would be sort of stuck in the front of the bubble it wouldn't come inside
the bubble because it was moving towards the forward so you it wouldn't actually hit you
but it would be stuck in the front of the bubble so the front of the bubble forms like a barrier
that is sweeping particles and energy in front of you and and you would be accumulating a lot
of energy so any light for example that you catch because you're moving faster than light so if you
catch light that was moving forward but not as fast as you because you're moving faster than light
it would get stuck in the front of the bubble and then you you will catch a lot of light in that way
and when you stop all that light that you caught would suddenly just go forward to whatever's in
front of you so yes it would be extremely dangerous when anyone in front of you when you
well it would be extremely dangerous even if you don't stop it because that way you would hit them
right but but even if you stop then all the radiation would be released and it would burn
anything in front of you so yeah it's it's it's dangerous so and there comes the question of
how do you slow down once you accelerate and we'll get to that in a minute we have to go to break
but never point your warp drive directly towards your planet destination exactly
we'll be back in a moment with dr alcubierre the following program contains imagery from mark
raider maker designer of futuristic hardware and founder of holland space yards what tell him
thanks yes john i'm doing it now thanks mark thanks tell him thanks
and we are back with dr maguella cubierre now doctor it's a big problem with traveling
at these speeds is that you can also bring in time as a problem because such whatever you go faster
than light you always have to ask the question what does time travel have to do with this tell
us about that what what effect here do we have on time yeah well there's separate issues here so
separate issues here so one thing that people might might have heard is about the time dilation
when you're traveling very fast but still lower than light but close to the speed of light then
time it moves forward very slowly for you as compared to to things that are not moving right
so if you go far away from the earth very close to the speed of light and then come back
stay to a distant star a few years away and then come back then you might find that for you it was
only a few years and maybe on earth it was a hundred or a thousand years or even more
depends how fast you were going and how far you were going this is time dilation and it happens
also if you travel slower than light now in the model i did for the warp drive i on purpose put
out this effect so the warp bubble that i designed doesn't have any time dilation but that's by
construction and and since the construction is a little bit just like i wanted to make it and i
did it simple it doesn't mean that if you could do it in real life it would be like that but in
in the model i have there's no time dilation so you wouldn't have this effect but the other
effect that you also have when when when you travel faster than light it is worse you can show and
this is something that einstein showed very early from his special theory and relativity that if
you can travel faster than light in principle you can build a time machine because if you travel
faster than light then from the point of view of some observers you're actually traveling back in
time so if you do it there and backwards you could end up coming back before you actually left it's
not easy it's a special construction but you can do it in principle so and there's a proof
general proof that any method you come up with that can allows you to travel faster than light
can in principle be turned into a time machine that's true of the warp drive i didn't prove it
myself but i hinted at it in my paper and somebody proved it a few like about a year later somebody
actually proved it in detail so you could use a warp drive to build a time machine but you can do
the same with wormholes so people talk about wormholes to travel faster than light if you
can build a wormhole then in principle you can also turn it into a time machine so in a way you
could step into the wormhole today and come out of the wormhole yesterday which again is weird so
but it is true as far as we understand any any way you come up with to travel faster than light
allows you to in principle build a time machine now physicists as myself we don't like time machines
because time machines mean you cannot predict the future because anything you were going to predict
can be destroyed by somebody coming from the future and changing it right so
so in principle it means that physics would not be predictable we wouldn't be able to predict
what happens in the future if time travel is allowed and it brings with it a lot of a host
of paradoxes like the famous brand grandfather paradox and all those crazy logical paradoxes
so we don't like it we don't like time travel to the past and so stephen hawking in the in the
early 90s and late late 80s i think he came up with an idea that he calls in in very technical
terms the chronology protection conjecture but in layman terms it actually means the the no time
travel idea if you want so he argued that the laws of physics do not allow time travel to the
past and if you would were able to try to produce a time machine something would happen that would
prevent you from doing it maybe the time machine would blow up in your face or maybe a black hole
would form and and we came up with this idea it's not just a general argument in words he actually
came up with some mathematical calculations based on quantum theory and he showed essentially that
if you were able to produce a time machine travel to the past and a feedback a feedback loop would
occur it's similar to what happens when they have a microphone and and a speaker close by right
so you hear the feedback because sound is going around and around and it's getting stronger and
stronger because of the amplifier and everybody has heard that when you when you're talking in
microphone you get too close to the speaker so it's the same idea but hawking argues that it
would happen in a time in a time machine energy would be trapped in a loop in time
and going round and round and round it would be amplified it would be focused and amplified with
each loop and eventually these would create such a huge concentration of energy that either the
machine would blow up or a black hole would be produced and that would happen essentially
instantaneously because it's a time machine so from your point of view would be instantaneous
you would switch on the the time machine and it would blow up or produce a black hole and you
would not be able to use it so that's essentially hawking's argument and it's been around for 25
years it's still just that conjecture because there's no formal proof that this happens it's
just an idea but it's a good idea based on very solid mathematical foundations but it's not a
formal proof so that that for me is good right because it that means that it doesn't mean that
you cannot travel faster than light it means that if you want to turn your faster than light
spaceship into a time machine machine you wouldn't be able to do so and i think that's
good that means you would in principle might still be able to produce a warp drive and still
don't have a time machine and at the moment you would try to use it to build a time machine you
would die in an explosion or something so for physicists i think it's a good idea and and even
for the warp drive is probably good news it means that that one of the arguments against it that is
that is you could turn it into a time machine wouldn't be true right you wouldn't be able to
turn it into a time machine so that's that's essentially the situation there in short it
would be isolated in that since you've isolated a piece of space time and you're not moving within
it then you are not actually manipulating time well yeah exactly if you if you just go on a
one-way trip then that's true the thing comes around if you try to do a return trip and if
you do it in a very special way in print way in principle you should be able to do a time machine
but this honking's argument tells you that you wouldn't be able to so the laws of physics protect
us from time paradoxes in this case that's that's that's essentially hawking's conjecture the laws
of physics protects us from from time travel time travel to the past time travel to the future is
always possible sure just can't come back right we're always we're always constantly traveling
into the future we just can't go to the past exactly now how does this relate to einstein
and things like closed timelike curves because some people say that maybe backwards time travel
might be possible through that mechanism what it's exactly that it's exactly that that's that that's
so when when physicists talk about time travel we always mean in technical terms closed timelike
curves so time travel from the point of view of physics is the fact that you have have a trajectory
that you can follow that brings you back around in a circle and and a trajectory that you can
follow it's always a timelike trajectory because you can follow it in your own time so
it's a trajectory that a particle like us can follow it's called a timelike trajectory and
if you can bend on itself and go around back then it's called a closed timelike trajectory so any
time any type of time travel in physics today is always understood as a closed timelike loop
and what hawking is telling you that closed timelike loops cannot exist in nature because
something catastrophic would happen as soon as you can want to produce one but every every sort
of idea for time travel even geddle who had an idea of a strange universe in which time travel
could exist is called geddle's universe and it's from the 20s of the 20th century that also has
closed timelike loops so in principle you construct the geometries you can construct geometries with
these loops that allow time travel and and you can construct them easily mathematically it's not that
difficult to come up with examples but what hawking's tells us is that in practice you
wouldn't be able to do this because this sort of space dance would be unstable against quantum
perturbations that's that's essentially hawking's argument if you forget about quantum mechanics
and you just do a purely classical general relativity calculation in principle you can
always make them it's not even difficult to to come up with little models but in practice
is if you try quantum mechanics would intervene and it would be unstable
which is a big problem with everything you know when you start talking about stuff like this is
instability like a wormhole would you know yes there maybe there's a wormhole at the the
singularity of the black hole but it's going to open and close rapidly and you're not going to
be able to traverse it so and this and this is where the negative mass matter comes into play
because you would need that in order to stabilize the whole thing you know keep it stable yeah a
wormhole on its own it's unstable and that's that even has nothing to do with quantum mechanics
that just pure relativity and pure relativity a wormhole in empty in empty space or with positive
mass it's unstable and you want to stabilize it you need negative energy because the wormhole
wants to close it's it's the equation tells you that whenever you open a wormhole it wants to
close very quickly and you want to keep it open you need that repulsion repulsive field and that's
negative energy that keeps it open so that's the reason why you need negative energy in wormholes
but it turns out anytime you want to do something crazy with Einstein
equations of relativity if you anytime you want to produce some crazy geometry like a wormhole
or a warp drive or something like that apparently always you need negative energy it's some sort of
comes out always right anytime you want to circumvent the laws of the universe it says
you're going to need something special in order to do this and back to the warp drive if you
were able just to speculate to create the warp field and travel at many times the speed you know
relativistic speeds is there a speed limit could is there some barrier that says you can't go
faster than this with the warp field there's no there's no speed limit in principle it's just
to go faster you would need more and more negative energy and the more negative energy you have the
faster you in principle could go you could also use a warp drive to move slower than light it
would be a very inefficient way to do it but you could use a warp drive to move slower than light
but and faster than light is as far as you as fast as you want to go depending on how much
negative energy you have available so there's no limit but there is a problem that I haven't
actually mentioned yet this is the second problem with the warp drive we call it the horizon problem
and it has to do with when you when you use the warp drive to move faster than light
then in front of the this this bubble of deformed space at the at the front region there's a limit
further to which you cannot you cannot actually access anything in front of that directly from
from inside the bubble so if you're inside the bubble you can only reach so far in front of the
bubble but not all the way in front of the bubble so there's a horizon that forms there so there's
a region you cannot reach and this is a problem because if you're supposed to be putting the
negative energy in place from inside the bubble so you're in a spaceship and you have some sort of
energy field generator or something like star trek and you use this generator to put negative
energy at the front of the bubble to be able to move then there's a region you can't reach
and that means you cannot put enough negative energy there and you wouldn't be able to
produce a bubble in the first place so this is the horizon problem it doesn't if you want to
use the warp bubble to travel slower than light then there's no problem but you want to travel
faster than light then it's a big problem and that means that the spaceship itself would not
be able to produce the required field it would have to be produced from the outside and that
again it's it's a big problem right because somebody would have to be there producing the
negative energy as you as you go along as you pass it you could imagine maybe a sort of big
tube like a like a like a subway tube right a big tube through space with field generators
are switching on in time as the spaceship is going through but that's that seems like completely
crazy right to build a tube from here to office and torii so essentially you need to build a
highway before you could use the drive so you would have to build a highway before you send
anything through it yeah so how would you do that if you you would have to do it at sublight speeds
you'd have to have a spacecraft you know and you would have to leave some sort of negative mass
generators of some sort in front so to build a highway to to have it it's sort of like gas
stations actually where exactly yeah to send us a spaceship before slower than light that would
be leaving behind it negative energy generators along the way and they would this would give you
this sort of highway and once it's built something can go through it faster than light but it would
have to be built before and they would have that would have to be done slower than light yeah now
once you had this highway built and you could traverse well at sublight speeds obviously it's
very difficult to traverse the universe but the galaxy say you were able to build a highway over
millions of years and create this this sort of transit system what um with a warp bubble
could you detect that if say say an alien civilization millions of years ago created such
a thing and you were looking for alien technosignatures what what would that look like
this alcubierre warp drive highway system i mean could you detect it or would it just be
not visible i think you would i have never thought about this in in detail but i think
if it was moving directly towards you you should be able to see a burst of radiation when they're
using it but if it's not moving directly towards you then i don't think it would be detectable
i don't think you would be able to see anything but if it's if it's pointing directly at you then
yes you would see a burst of radiation especially when they slow down as we mentioned but yeah that
you should see but but i think it would be difficult because something very localized
and it's not really pointing at you then i don't think i don't see what you would see
so it's probably undetectable you mentioned slowing down once you get going how do you slow
back down with this concept that's exactly what i what i'm saying this is the same problem with
the horizon so you wouldn't be able to slow down on your own somebody would have to do it from the
outside so somebody would have to switch off the highway as you arrive at your destination you
shouldn't you wouldn't be able to switch it off from inside it's the same it's for the same reason
because you cannot reach the front of the bubble so you cannot tell it to switch off at the front
at least and and it's exactly the same problem so initially when i when when i did this paper i
mentioned this also in passing i mentioned that you shouldn't be able they wouldn't be able to
slow down once you turn it on but then i realized the problem was actually much worse you wouldn't
be able to turn it on in the first place right so that's because of this horizon problem but it's
basically the same problem if you're traveling faster than light you cannot reach the front of
the bubble which means you can't manipulate it and you can i you cannot not turn it on you cannot
turn it off you can't manipulate it at all somebody has to do it from the outside that was already
there waiting right so essentially you cannot ever reach the brake pedal basically yes
it's a good analogy but yeah it's essentially this is a brake pedal was so far away you wouldn't
be able to reach it yes you can't ever reach it physically now inside the warp bubble you would
also probably have problems uh people have said that you would you would be cooked by radiation
can you can you get into that yeah well that's what i was mentioning anything coming for towards
you from the front as as as you reach it with the warp double any radiation that was pointing
towards you would actually be blue shifted very and if you're moving much faster than light than
light it would be blue shifted a lot so even something that was ordinary uh radio waves that
was completely harmless if you're traveling sufficiently fast faster than light with the
warp bubble it could be blue shifted towards gamma rays and kill you right because the radiation
would be so intense so you would need a very good shield if you're planning to use this with
traveling faster than light but this is a problem maybe if you move slower than light if you build
a spaceship that could go say 99 of the speed of light then again that's a danger which is
radiation that's coming towards you ordinary light it's blue shifted and it's this blue shifted
towards gamma rays it would be deadly and and if you find a small rock and it's hitting you at 99
the speed of light then it could destroy the ship so this is a problem even at slower than light
speeds if they're sufficiently high right and 99 the speed of light is already a big problem
so it's not a problem that's just related to the warp drive it's a problem of moving at very high
speeds on a scale of one to ten with ten being the most unlikely where would you rate the
possibility of the warp bubble that we could actually at some point in the far future create
this how likely is it oh yeah so ten is the most unlikely yes so i would probably put it at a nine
at a nine yeah i think it's very unlikely if you ask me even though it's my own idea and i like it
for personal reasons i think at this moment it might seem even more likely to have wormholes
and those would have fewer problems still wormholes are not likely at all because we have no idea how
to build one but they have they have fewer problems if you could build a wormhole then you
wouldn't have this horizon problem you wouldn't have this radiation problem a lot of the problems
with the warp drive are simply not there in the case of wormhole but again nobody knows how to
make a hole in space so we have no idea at all how to create a wormhole but it seems less problematic
if you could actually have one but yeah i i think it's unfortunately for myself because it's my own
idea but i think it's highly unlikely at this point still an interesting idea and it's always
fruitful to entertain useful ideas because that's where maybe other useful ideas come
yeah i agree completely yeah and on that we are out of time dr akubir thank you for joining us
it's been a pleasure thank you thinking about far future technologies is a very uncertain thing
vexing at times given what i do imagining something is one thing and actually engineering it and
building it is entirely another but imagination is important that's what starts the ball rolling
and gets people thinking about the nuts and bolts of an idea and while the materials and technology
needed to create an akubir warp field lie in the future perhaps even the distant future for all we
know it is at least a seed for thought on the subject right now that's important and who knows
there may be other ways to defeat the speed of light there are always the possibilities of
wormholes or even ways we may not have thought of yet we do not yet have a complete understanding
of our universe only a partial one so the concepts that spawn out of science and sci-fi
in the coming years centuries or millennia may serve as seeds to push us further who
knows where we might end up john yes i think it's time to talk about getting rid of the car
but wait well i have an idea oh dear this isn't a good sign if
and i stress if if we can get akubir to drive the lebaron we can increase its value tenfold
oh no i can see where this is going wait stop where did you how did you how did you even use
a spray bottle we'll figure that out later and joining me next week will be dr duncan forgen
for a discussion of the fermi paradox and the solutions to it