For many decades, beginning with the purported crash of a vehicle of unknown origin at Roswell,
New Mexico in 1947, there have been many rumors regarding the involvement of the US government
in the field of UAP from crash retrievals to interactions and allegations of a broad
cover-up of their activities in this arena, even making its way to congressional hearings,
of which another one is scheduled.
Amid this, there have been whistleblowers coming forward claiming that yes, indeed,
there have been retrievals, and that the US knows far more than what it admits about UFOs.
I have stated before that I am a skeptic of an alien origin for the UFO UAP phenomenon,
but my mind is open and can be changed.
I am not however skeptical that people see things in the sky that they cannot explain.
That is why we refer to the phenomenon or phenomena as unidentified, but in having an
open mind, I am willing to consider both sides of the question of government involvement
in UFOs.
So this and next week's episodes will be from two differing viewpoints from within
the US government.
This week is whistleblower and former Pentagon official Luis Elizondo on the pro side, ultimately
saying the US government knows far more than it lets on, and does indeed have recovered
materials from Roswell.
And next week, as a counterpoint interview will be Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick.
I leave it up to you, the listener, to decide.
Luis Elizondo is a former senior leader of the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification
Program, ATIP.
Previously, Lou oversaw counter-espionage and counter-terrorism investigations worldwide
for the US Department of Defense, and also worked for the Office of the National Counterintelligence
Executive and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.
Elizondo is a proud US Army veteran and later served his country throughout the world, including
South Korea, Latin America, the Caribbean, and Afghanistan.
Elizondo is a graduate of the University of Miami where he studied microbiology and immunology.
Lou Elizondo, welcome to the program.
It is my sincere privilege to be with you and your audience here today.
Thank you so much for having me.
Thank you, Lou.
I know your schedule is very, very busy with the book tour and everything, and we'll get
to that book shortly.
But I wanted to ask you to start the conversation going.
What is your view on just the question of alien life and the universe in general, and
the science behind that?
Well, I mean, we're living proof that life does exist in the universe, aren't we?
We're living proof.
And not only is life prevalent, it's abundant.
One only has to look at this little rock and realize just how pervasive life really is.
You know, John, I know you're a man of science, and I like to consider myself a disciple of
science as well.
And I'm probably a little older than you, I tell people, this is gray, not blonde on
my face.
I remember a time when at the universities, certainly when I went, there was very narrow
definition of what life is.
And basically, all life had to derive and have to have DNA of some sort.
And we now realize that's not true, because some life forms only have RNA, microbial life.
And then we were told things like, well, you know, life has to survive in a certain Goldilocks
area where there's water and there's oxygen.
And it turns out all that's wrong.
There are these organisms called anaerobic bacteria like Clostridium botulinum botulism
that's actually anaerobic, that actually will die in the presence of oxygen.
It actually thrives in a low oxygen environment.
And then, of course, there's microorganisms that live on the skin of the ISS space station
in a near complete vacuum, right, where the solar radiation is much more intense than
the UV radiation.
You have microbial life living miles beneath the Arctic ice and even even underground in
the highest points of our of our of our natural Earth and in the deepest parts of our oceans.
And so we're constantly having to reevaluate even ourselves what what does life even really
mean? What does it mean to be alive?
And, you know, it's a great observation, because I think one only has to look at this
planet and realize that life thrives virtually everywhere.
It is. And it has things that are related to it, but not quite life.
And I know your background is microbiology.
Look at the viruses. You know, what is that?
And how prevalent is such a thing in the universe?
Well, and a virus can self-replicate, a virus can protect itself, a virus can do everything
that a living thing does, it just doesn't have DNA, it has RNA, right?
And so and there have been actually some, even when I was in college along, again, back
when Moses was around, they were they were teaching us that there were some scientists
who believe that if there was ever a case for some sort of alien life beyond our planet,
a virus would be a perfect candidate for that, that a virus could have hitched a ride on
a meteor, come to Earth and spread that way.
And yes, that there was some serious conversation by some very serious virologists back in the
90s, early 90s, about that very about that very topic and possibility.
So I think NASA realizes that the narrow definition of what life is supposed to be probably isn't
entirely all encompassing, isn't completely accurate at this point.
And it has to be said, the first life on Earth were the anaerobes, as you mentioned, they
know it starts with that.
And maybe there's other ways it can start and maybe it doesn't need water.
Maybe it can use ammonia or any other sort of solvent, anything where the chemistry can
happen.
Sure.
You've got it.
That to me, yeah.
No, you're you're absolutely right.
In fact, you know, people don't realize this.
Water is something that we need to survive.
But it's actually to a lot of minerals, it's extremely destructive.
It's caustic.
In fact, if you put one of the strongest elements that we have in the natural world, which is
iron and stick it in water and see what happens to it.
Right.
So it only works for us because we have evolved where water is is useful to us, both from
a metabolic and catabolic perspective.
But in reality, you know, there are other things that that, you know, water, water is
rather destructive towards.
And so is it possible that life has evolved somewhere in the cosmos off of something else?
Is it possible that you don't have to be carbon based?
Right.
Maybe silicon based.
Look at artificial intelligence.
We are getting close to the precipice where AI could become self-aware, meaning a conscious
sentient life form, but not based in carbon and not based in neurons, but based in capacitors
and circuitry and silicon rather than neurons and rather than carbon.
There's also the, to get even deeper into it, oxygen itself may not be the be all end
all for intelligent life because you've got very highly reactive gases like fluorine that
while they're rare, they would work.
And so you have just many possibilities of alternative biochemistry.
That's right.
Look at methane.
You know, there's how many there's a reason why NASA is interested sending more probes
to certain moons orbiting Jupiter.
That's because of methane.
Now, methane is a it's an organic compound.
And it is we know from life here on earth that methane is produced by the decay of carbon
based life forms, also by the respiration and respiratory processes of life.
Is it possible that we don't have to go searching throughout the Milky Way that maybe life is
just right around the corner here and we're just getting to the point now where technologically
we can we can discover it and begin to understand it.
And you know, Europa, in fact, the Europa Clipper mission just launched.
That's one of its missions is to see maybe, you know, in the plumes coming out of that
moon, maybe, you know, I tend to be a proponent that microbial life is probably ubiquitous
across the universe and that it's nothing special.
And maybe the filters are when, you know, other things happen, you know, to lead to
us.
But at the same time, as you say, we are proof of concept of intelligent life in the
universe.
And that brings us to the topic at hand, the UAP phenomenon, which is, you know, is
everywhere in the news and has been for a very long time.
Going back to rumors from 1947, you know, very early stuff.
What brought you into that world inside the Pentagon?
Well, I was kind of involved, to be honest with you.
I didn't realize what I was getting into till after it was too late.
Some people had met me at my office a few times asking me some general questions.
I had vetted them. They were government officials and they had the blue badge, IC intelligence
community blue badge, which means they had the same, almost the same level of clearance
that I had.
So we could we could have a normal conversation.
And they told me they needed help with a particular program, very sensitive program, and
they needed some expertise in counterintelligence and security, which is what my background
was.
And so after several meetings, still not knowing what the heck I needed to do or what this
office was, I finally met with their director, Dr.
James Lukatsky, who, if anybody knows that name, this is one of the world's premier rocket
scientists. And I don't say that lightly because there's a lot of really good rocket
scientists. But this is a guy who could have very easily found himself several decades
earlier on the Manhattan Project.
That that qualified, that that that intelligent, that elite when it comes to
just intellectual horsepower.
And at the end of our conversation, still not knowing what we were talking about, he
asked me a very straight question.
And he said, Lou, what do you think about you?
Remember him looking over his glasses and asking me the question, he says, what do you
think about UFOs?
And so I thought for a second and I responded truthfully and said, Jim, I don't.
And he kind of rocked back in his chair and he said, what do you mean, you don't believe
in UFOs? And I said, I didn't say that.
Jim, you asked me, what do I think about them?
And I answered truthfully, I don't think about them because frankly, I don't have the
luxury to think about them.
I'm too busy chasing bad guys and worrying about other national security issues.
I've never been a big fan necessarily as a kid of science fiction.
I wasn't a big Star Trek or Star Wars fan.
I was more of a G.I. Joe kid.
And so for me, I never had that luxury really to be involved in science fiction.
So it never really affected me.
I never really gave it any type of serious thought because I just didn't have the
bandwidth to do so.
It was very quickly thereafter that I realized that, yeah, we're dealing with
something very real.
And it's and there's a national security aspect to to to this conversation.
Now, now, in your time and doing that at the Pentagon and I and I will come clean
and open, I am an open minded skeptic.
I don't know what this is.
I am not skeptical that people see UFOs.
Of course they do.
You know, you see things unidentified.
But some of the stuff from the Pentagon, like the Tic Tac incident, are pretty
obviously something a little bit, probably not a balloon, you could say.
And I'm sure you've seen even better stuff in your time.
Would you say that whatever this is, in some cases, it appears to be technological?
It is technological.
There's a piece to this that is very technological, very much nuts and bolts.
And then there's let me correct myself.
People are going to say, well, you said before, there's no nuts and bolts and
rivets. I mean, that figured that there's a tangible physical aspect to this topic.
There's a technological piece to this.
But with every piece of technology, there is a huge history and a tale that goes
with it. You can't just simply look at a car and say that's a piece of technology
because you have to then ask the next question.
Where was it built?
When was it built?
Who built it?
What is it used for?
You know, and all the other questions that come along that aren't necessarily
always going to have a technical response, you know, eventually you ask enough
questions and you start getting into a little bit more, maybe the spirit,
spirituality aspect of this.
When I say spirituality, I don't mean in a in a woo sort of way.
I mean, really in a in a more esoteric sort of way, in a in a manner that that
involves human psychology, human sociology, our ability to perceive and to
to translate information and rationalize information into into into a into a
thought that has a natural conclusion to it.
I know I'm being a little evasive here.
Just I guess what I'm trying to say is that if you want to understand a piece of
technology, you first have to have the capability inside as a person and the
intellectual capability to understand that.
Right.
So it's often like, you know, there's a there's a good analogy.
My my good friend, Steve Justice, used to say, he said, imagine or it might
have been even helped put off.
He said, imagine being Da Vinci back in this in the Renaissance and coming
across for the very first time a garage door opener.
Now, electromagnetic has not been discovered yet.
So we don't understand frequencies.
We don't understand the waveforms.
We don't even understand plastic because it's never been made before.
We don't understand rubber.
And let alone we don't understand why a house would happen to have a garage door
for a vehicle that hasn't been invented yet.
So, you know, it's it's there's a lot to, you know, you learn a lot from nuts and
bolts, which was my focus, but there's a lot more to the conversation, to be
honest with you, like any conversation.
Really? Yeah.
Another analogy would be if you find a piece of a cell phone, a component, a
chunk, a screen, it isn't going to tell you anything about the cell phone network.
You're just you're missing too many puzzle pieces to be able to.
How would you understand what 5G is if the electromagnetic spectrum hasn't
even been discovered yet?
You wouldn't even know it was there.
You wouldn't even know now.
And which is an interesting point, because when we're glimpsing things like this,
now, as far as and of course, everybody's going to ask about Roswell and those
sorts of things of purported materials being recovered, is that the problem in
looking at that kind of stuff if we have it trying to figure it out is you're
like you're you're going blind.
You know, you're you're you're proceeding from a blind position to try to figure
out something presumably far more advanced than anything you've ever seen.
Right. And look, one thing is if you recover a Russian aircraft that crashed,
chances are they might have some advanced technology, but it still works the same
way as the technology we're familiar with.
It's not necessarily new technology.
It's just advanced technology.
But when you come across something that is fundamentally new and requires a new
understanding of science and a new understanding of the physical world, where
do you start with that?
Right. It's a pretty it's a pretty big leap of faith to just jump off in any
direction and say, OK, this is what this piece is used for.
Most components, like you say, in a cell phone, right, have all sorts of other
components that they rely on a screen by itself that can't do anything without a
battery and a battery can't do anything without a charger.
And the charger can't do anything without being connected to the electrical grid.
And the electrical grid can't do anything without, you know, electricity being
supplied by a dam or perhaps a wind turbine somewhere, you know, in the state
or a nuclear reactor.
So it's it's it's not just that simple as picking up a piece of material and
saying, aha, you know, it's far more complex than that.
I always wondered if there was a warehouse somewhere where the U.S.
government keeps things like Russian aircraft and that submarine that they
recovered from the ocean floor decades ago, if they if they still have that
stuff. Right.
We would not, unfortunately, be able to to elaborate on that.
But it's a very good, very good, insightful question, for sure.
Call it the Indiana Jones warehouse.
But anyway, back to the topic at hand now, internally speaking, what did you guys
discuss as far as possible solutions as to the origin of this?
Did you get into scientific ideas like the zoo hypothesis, for example, that this
could be, you know, an alien machine or something like that that's, you know, here
to keep us bottled in and keep an eye on us?
Or some other sort of, you know, what were those discussions like?
And this is just all open science speculative stuff that, you know, is out
there. Well, there was a lot of speculation.
I never had one particular narrative.
Some people suggested that we were merely a gas station, that water was being used
as a form to power their propulsion units.
Others said that they suspected there was some sort of monitoring of our nuclear
capabilities and to see our development and evolution as a species.
Others suggested that they're here for a far more malevolent reason, some sort
of ISR, intelligence surveillance and reconnaissance and preparation of the
battle space. Others had speculated that they may be here just out of curiosity.
Why do we go to the Serengeti and and watch the wilder beasts migrate?
Because we do, because it's part of nature.
There's a lot of different theories.
I was never necessarily wedded to one or the other.
I think we need more information.
I think we need more data.
And I've always been, although I've been tempted a few times, I've always tried to
resist the urge of trying to trying to figure out what their intent is.
You know, intent is something, John, intent is something that tends to be very
uniquely human. There are motivations.
All animals have some sort of motivation.
When a shark bites the surfer, his motivation that he's hungry, but his intent
isn't to hurt the surfer.
He's not even kidding.
Shark isn't even calculating that it's a human being, right?
Living, breathing human beings says, oh, something on the water looks yummy.
I'm hungry. I'm going to eat it.
But intent is something a little different.
Some of the more advanced primates and humans have intent, meaning we do things
deceitfully. We do things to manipulate in order to get some sort of self gain
out of it. Most of the animals in the wild don't do that.
They have motivations, but not real intent.
Humans are one of the only real species that have that higher order of thinking.
And therefore, that complexity of thinking and intent is a uniquely human
and advanced ape aspect of our being.
Artificial intelligence doesn't have intent.
Artificial intelligence has input in and data out.
Very simple. Is it possible what we're dealing with is also like artificial
intelligence, meaning it just does what it does?
Or maybe it's binary.
Maybe it's just things on ones and zeros, right?
Yes or no. Very simple, on and off.
We simply don't know.
And from a national security perspective, to determine if something is a threat,
it's a very simple calculus.
It's capabilities versus intent.
We've seen some of the capabilities, but we have no idea the intent now, do we?
Or even if there is an intent.
So it's very hard to even, from a national security perspective, even determine
whether these things even are a threat.
I think one of the more spooky scenarios is that it may not know why it's here.
It may have forgotten.
It may have never been told.
You know, it may, it's just like sending out Voyager 2.
We never told it what it was going to go do.
We just programmed it to...
Well, how about the trip to, you know, at some point when mankind or humankind
decides to go to Alpha Proxima, with current technology, it would take us
about 10,000 years to do it.
You know, that's only three and a half light years away.
Do we, are we sure that the occupants of that, let's say that starship we were
to send out, that notional starship that doesn't exist, but let's say it does, by
the time they get to Alpha Proxima, would they even understand what their mission
was all along, or would they have forgotten it?
Well, you can also apply that to machine civilization.
If you have a von Neumann probe that has been sitting out there for millions of
years, taking cosmic ray hits, it may be so corrupt in its programming that it has
no idea what it's doing.
It's just 3D printing out probes that are appearing irrational, you know, in
the atmosphere of an exoplanet.
Glitches in the system, so to speak.
Yeah, glitches in the system.
Now, did you ever see any indication that it might actually be multiple
different phenomena that are being mistaken as one and that we're just
lumping it all together, perhaps unwisely?
Yeah, yeah, that's always a possibility too.
You know, we do understand the morphology of certain crafts.
You have lenticular or disc-shaped craft.
You have cigar or rod-shaped craft.
You have triangular-shaped craft.
And you even have large boomerang craft that are often reported.
And then you've got some of these outliers like the jellyfish, right?
And these orbs, if you will, or whatever you want to call them, right?
These luminous balls of light as well that are often lumped into the UAP
phenomenon, interestingly enough, when I went to South America, the Mapuche
people, the indigenous people, Aboriginal people of Patagonia in Argentina, in a
little area outside of Bariloche called Las Lajas, they see these orbs, these
luminous balls of light all the time, but they actually have a different conclusion.
They believe that they are the spirits of their ancestors coming in to take a
peek at them and make sure that they're okay and everything, everybody as well.
So, yeah, I mean, there's always speculation that this could be multiple
different types of variants, probably using a similar type of technology, kind
of like an internal combustion engine, whether it's a Ferrari or a, you know,
Chevy Impala, the physics is still the same.
There's, you know, one may look a little different, one may behave a little
different, but at the end of the day, it's still a piston's internal combustion
engine, transmission, power to the wheels, and away you go.
So, you know, that's a great question.
And I think a lot of people have speculated that we're looking at different
types of morphology of vehicles, probably even different occupants, perhaps,
with probably, probably similar technology.
Was there any indication of how the propulsion systems on these worked?
And was it common?
Did you see the same characteristics from different types of UAP morphology?
Yeah, great question.
So that's correct.
We did.
And in fact, talk a little bit about it in my book, I actually give a
presentation on it that's a little bit more comprehensive, but yeah, there
was in 2015, this proverbial aha moment within ATIP where the senior
scientists came in kind of barging through the skiff's door and said,
we need to talk.
And after about a three hour conversation, it was kind of this Eureka moment
where a lot of the observables that we were seeing, both from a performance
and even a human biologics perspective, could all be explained through very
simple physics.
Now, when I say simple physics, I don't mean easy physics, but I mean simple
physics.
Now with simple physics comes very complicated technology sometimes to
master physics, the simple physics, right?
Look at gravity.
If you want to break gravity, we have to come up with either a helicopter or
plane to do it.
And we've only been able to do it maybe the last century or so out of the time
that homo sapiens, sapiens been scratching on the floor.
So by no means am I saying it's an easy thing to do, but the physics seems to be
fairly straightforward and that what is happening is that whatever these are
have created some sort of ability to create a bubble around themselves that
insulates themselves from the external effects of the warping of space time.
As we know, massive objects, there's two ways to warp space time.
Thanks to, thanks to Einstein and his famous equation, E equals MC squared.
Now, most people don't realize this, but that is a very interesting equation
because energy and, and mass matter are really coefficients of each other in that
equation, meaning you can think of energy and matter as fundamentally the same
thing in two different States.
So what do I mean by that?
Think of imagine ice being matter, solid mass, and now imagine steam being energy.
Both are made of water, right?
Both are almost identical.
It's just the fundamental state in which they, they, they, they, they reside.
One is extremely energetic while the other is condensed and consolidated.
Cause it's cooler.
Very much the same thing.
If I take matter and I annihilate matter, what do I get?
I get pure energy.
And if I take energy and I go to the CERN and I start cooling it down and slowing
it down, I start getting at the subatomic particles.
So the two ways to warp space time or to, to battle space time.
Cause we do know space time is flexible.
That's a fact.
We've already proven that one only has to look at their cell phone and look at a
GPS signal and realize something through the phenomenon called atomic drift, where
the atomic cesium clocks on board the GPS spacecraft, even though the, the exact
same clocks here at the ground station and have the exact same half-life, atomic
half-life, they still run at different rates.
Now, why is that?
Because the clocks that are on the ground here on earth, the warping of space time
is more extreme.
And so time literally goes by at a slightly different rate than the atomic cesium
clocks are experiencing on board the spacecraft.
So we know space time is flexible.
And in some extreme cases, you know, with mass earth warps space time.
The sun warps space time because of its mass.
And if you're a super massive enough, you make a black hole and you warp space time
to the point where, where it almost becomes nonsensical.
Now, are they using mass, whatever they are to, to propel themselves across the
vastness of the cosmos, if that is where they're coming from, chances are not,
because that mass would perturb the very massive here on earth and it would be
very destructive and we'd all, we would all see that and feel it.
So the other way to warp space time is with a tremendous amount of energy.
And it turns out that if you have enough energy and potentially the right material,
you can create at a localized area, a bubble that insulates yourself from
the external warping of space time, meaning inside this bubble, the way you
experience space time would be fundamentally different than the
observer standing outside the bubble.
And what would appear like magic to me, standing outside the bubble to you
is just a walk in the park.
What I consider extreme acceleration and hypersonic velocities for you, you're
not performing anything unique or extreme.
In fact, to you, you're just operating like normal and to, and, and your
observation of us outside the bubble is that we're actually all going in slow
motion and it's, it's, it's a little interesting.
It's kind of a trick off of Einstein's relativity, but we believe that
potentially that these UAP, their, their, their propulsion units are a little
bit different than what we are used to.
You know, we have a car or an airplane and you've got an engine inside the
car that propels a car.
This is a little different.
In this case, the car itself may be part of the engine, meaning you have an
energy source in the middle of the craft and you then have a reaction with the
skin of the vehicle, which happens to be a certain material type of material.
And when you have that interaction, all of a sudden, interesting things start to
happen, things that shouldn't be able to happen, but, but do happen.
And it might even explain the, when people see the strobing lights, different
multicolored lights, they say, it looks like a police car sometimes.
And that could just simply be a Doppler redshift blue shift.
You could be seeing something that is going in, in, in one frequency that gets
shifted up into the visible light spectrum.
And now you're, you're actually seeing, uh, it's propulsion units, the triangles,
for example, that have the lights on the apex of the triangle, um, chances are
those are not actually lights.
Um, it's, it's quite possible those are part of potentially the propulsion
system on board the craft.
Well, the descriptions of the lights, at least in the really good accounts,
you're right, they're not lights.
They're, they're something to do with inherent with the UFO because otherwise,
you know, an alien doesn't, they're not interested in, in following FAA
conventions or things like that.
Yeah, they, they, they don't necessarily have the handbook on board with them.
So it's probably not used for the same things we, we, we would use it for.
Right.
It's kind of like, I always tell people, imagine if a, if a 747 crashed in the
middle of the Amazon jungle and, and, you know, an Amazonian lost tribe of the
Amazon find some of the wreckage and, you know, they pick up a piece of glass from
the cockpit and now they can use it as a tool to, to skin their meat a little
easier, but are they really reverse engineering the technology?
No, they're not.
They're just exploiting it for whatever current paradigm that they live in and,
and exploiting it for those purposes.
Now that gets into a rather puzzling question that's vexed me for a long time.
So there are reports that these things crash, but they can't have been doing
that for very long because whenever a human throughout history finds a piece of
metal, say a meteorite, they use it.
Even if you don't even know how to smelt metal, you still use the meteorite metal
because as you know, you haven't seen anything like that before.
And there are, you know, archeological examples of, of, you know, nickel iron
meteorites hammered into points.
And this was even done into, into historic times.
Massai warriors in Namibia had access to the Gibeon meteorite and were hammering
it into spear points into recent memory until they realized that the meteorites
were worth something on eBay.
Same thing with in, in Greenland.
There was the Cape York meteorite that was used by local peoples for harpoons.
I mean, John, let's not forget, you know, King Tut's tomb and the famous dagger.
Yep, the meteorite dagger, but what we don't have is an aluminum one, you
know, or, or a piece of titanium done like that in an archeological context.
Well, we believe that the crashes are more recent and, and may be due to a
vulnerability and particularly in the way the propulsion systems work.
And that is to say that electro certain electromagnetic pulses, think of an EMP,
just like they can disable my cell phone or this computer can also interfere with
the propulsion units of, of these vehicles, because of the way they operate.
So radar or some sort of EMP or something like that.
They're susceptible or the, or, you know, the detonation of an atomic weapon or
the testing of an atomic weapon, there is a very strong EMP that is released.
Electromagnetic pulse that interferes with all sorts of conventional
technology and it's quite possible.
And there's also a huge burst of neutrinos as well, and, and, and neutrons as well.
So, you know, I'm not going to bore you and your audience with, with the science
lesson on atomic and nuclear technology, but it does seem to be a correlation
there that the U S government has recognized.
Lou, that means that we've recently become some kind of a threat to this phenomenon,
right?
In other words, we are dangerous now.
Well, certainly we are not as susceptible, you know, willing subjects.
It means that we have an ability to, to potentially interfere with, with
whatever they are.
And they seem to recognize that.
And, you know, we can, we can ascribe all sorts of intent behind it.
Um, but, uh, it does appear that at least superficially that they have a vulnerability.
Now, certainly someone within the government noticed that because I can't, I
do not buy it when, um, you know, a government official comes out in a
hearing or whatever and says that whatever it is, it does not appear to be
a national security threat.
Of course it's a national security threat.
When you don't know what it is.
And given that we can't, apparently sometimes can't even see gigantic
Chinese spy balloons, uh, we may have a problem here.
What's your take on that?
Yeah.
Um, look, uh, we're getting into a part of a conversation here that I find, um,
interesting, some people may find disturbing, but look, governments are no
different than religions or any other type of institution where the citizens
have given, have placed their faith and confidence into a particular organization.
Um, again, whether it's a government or religion or anything like that.
And governments in particular have one job and that is to protect
their citizens from threats, whether it's environmental threats or military
threats or ecological threats or financial threats, um, it is not a good
spot to be in as a government to identify a problem for which you don't have a
solution for it.
Okay.
And the people say, oh, well, that's nonsensical.
Look, we do it all the time.
Let me give you a case in point.
Uh, when we first developed the U2 spy plane, when, when, when the CIA had the
plane commission with locking skunkworks, um, we did it in direct contravention to
the peace treaty we had with Russia at the time, which was we would not fly manned
reconnaissance missions over mainland Russia, but we did because we were afraid
they were building nukes and we wanted to keep an eye on them.
So what was, what was our choice?
Well, we would build a plane that would fly higher and faster than anything else.
And the Russians would never be able to detect us.
And you know what?
It seemed like that was a case because for the first few missions we flew over
Russia, the Russians didn't react.
And so we thought, holy crap, we did it.
That was to say until the Russians developed the SA-2 surface to air
missile and successfully shot a U-2 down and then went on to parade, uh, Captain
Powers and the aircraft bits and pieces of it in front of the United
Nations and the world, right?
They did not even admit to their own Russian people that we had this capability
until when, until we, they had a solution to, to, to negate that threat, right?
It wasn't until they could shoot down the U-2, did they ever admit that
they even knew about it.
And this is very common for, for all governments, uh, because governments are
supposed to be solution focused.
And when you don't have a solution to a problem, it creates great anxiety and it
also creates distrust, animosity, fear.
And, and that's not what, that's not what we want our citizens to feel.
So, um, therein lies part of the problem that we, we don't like to admit problems
that there are no solutions for until there's a solution.
Now question, we briefly mentioned this, but I want to get deeper into their
interest in our nuclear, uh, capabilities, aircraft carrier groups and things like
that, and you know, they seem to be, especially if, if such a thing can
actually produce an effect on them, well, of course they're going to be interested
in it, but were you able to figure out, and this is part one of this question,
where you were able to figure out why they were so interested in, in, uh, you
know, nuclear reactors and things like that.
And then I got a part two after this.
Sure.
Um, what you're saying is correct.
There is definitely interest in our nuclear equities, not just ours.
Um, other, other world governments, nuclear equities as well.
Now, when I say nuclear equities, I don't just mean nuclear weapons.
I mean, nuclear weapons, I mean, uh, nuclear energy, nuclear technology,
nuclear triggering devices, anything and everything nuclear, uh, there seems
to be a very keen interest by UAP.
And furthermore, they have the ability to interfere with that technology.
Now, some can speculate, well, it's like, you know, parents taking
matches out of the hands of kids.
Well, that's fine if you think that, but let's, let's look at the actual
evidence and see if it's, see if it exists, um, where we have issues here,
where we had anecdotes of these UAP taking our nuclear weapons offline
here in the United States in Russia, the opposite occurred.
They actually turned them on.
Um, so think about that for a minute.
Secondly, um, in the 1940s, mid 1940s, there's only one, it'd been one country
that's ever used an atomic weapon and it was us.
And we vaporized nearly 800,000 human beings off the face of the planet with
dropping of two bombs, uh, Hiroshima and Nagasaki with a, a, a yield of roughly
13 kilotons and then only I think was about 21, 22 kilotons, um, nowhere did
UAP come and stop that from happening.
In fact, when we were the only country with an atomic weapon, nowhere did
UAP stop the proliferation of a type of technology getting into the hands of
the Russians and then ultimately North Korea and Pakistan and potentially Iran
and India and everywhere else.
In fact, UAP didn't stop, uh, anything from happening when we were testing in
Nevada, all our nukes or Zarbamba from being detonated by the Russians.
It didn't interfere with Three Mile Island or Chernobyl or Fukushima.
So to suggest that they're trying to prevent us from hurting ourselves, I
mean, that sounds nice, but there is no empirical evidence to suggest that.
What we do know is that they're interested in our nuclear carrier strike groups.
Now, what is that?
Well, you're talking about a nuclear footprint that when, when all is said
and done in the middle of the Atlantic ocean can be bigger than the entire
nuclear footprint of the entire state of New York, right?
Um, you have nuclear powered vessels, nuclear capable vessels, nuclear armed
vessels.
Um, and that's a pretty big, uh, that's a pretty, pretty big target, if you
will, for, for UAP, and we believe that may be why they have a keen interest in
our nuclear carrier strike groups, simply because of the nuclear footprint.
Part two, there is an elephant in the world that also operates a nuclear
powered aircraft carrier group, and it is France.
Did you ever have any contact with the French and do the French see the same
things from their aircraft carrier bases?
No, I can't speak on behalf of a foreign nation.
Um, I, it would be very inappropriate for me to do that, whether we have, or
we have not, um, that's, that's a question you'd have to, I would need permission
from another government to answer that.
Um, and I don't have that.
So unfortunately I'm going to have to do a polite pass on that, but, but look,
France has their own organization called Japan and they have been very interested
in the UAP topic for some time as well.
Um, talk to Jacques Lallet, he can give you more details about that.
But as far as what the capabilities are or what the interactions are with
another foreign country, unfortunately, I can't, I can't elaborate on that.
Now, the other question regarding, um, nuclear, you know, interest, does it
appear that they're trying to harvest energy?
In other words, I mean, could there be a neutron flux or something like
that, that they find useful?
Could be, but there's easier ways to get it.
Um, we don't see any, what appears to be any type of bleed off effect where
they're reaching any type of anything from it.
Um, it appears to be more, they're just interested in our development.
Um, and, and there may be a reason for that.
Uh, look, if you look at it at a scale.
And you, I don't know if your viewers are going to be able to see me on screen
here, so I'll be, I'll be trying to say articulate as I can, um, cause I don't
know if I'm actually going to be on screen for you guys.
We can make it happen.
So if you were to take a line on a piece of paper and you start with, with two,
start with two, two lines here.
So if you look at a chart like this, energy versus mass, and you start
way back here and you look at a glass of water, glass of water sits over here.
Um, that is a, when you convert that into steam, that's a, uh, you are
separating the molecules from each other.
It's still, you're not breaking the molecules up.
You just separate the molecules and that's a one times 10 to the third
yield of energy and you can go there and go now to an exothermic reaction
like gunpowder and you get now one times 10 to the fourth, uh, yield of
energy, an exothermic reaction.
Then you get down to splitting an atom.
The smaller you go in mass and you break apart those bonds, the
greater your energy yield goes up.
And, and it turns out that long story short, um, any species, any
civilization that finally cracks the code of how the atom works and that
there's a whole nother universe, subatomic universe, smaller than that
with infinite amount of potential for energy.
Um, it's probably a matter of time, maybe feta can play that, uh, within
a couple hundred years, they will understand the technologies themselves
to bend space time, to warp space time and basically perform the same type
of maneuvers that we are seeing with each UAP is it possible that things
are just interested in us and our development that the, that the funny
little monkeys are getting to a point where in the next couple of centuries,
they may be able to travel the cosmos like they can, and now no longer
distance is no longer really a problem anymore.
Um, and if that's the case, what would the impact be?
You know, if you've got some, some noisy neighbors that are pretty, you
know, they keep a sloppy yard and there's dog poop all over the place,
but they keep it to their yard, you know, and there's a big fence around
it and you rarely see them, you're probably not going to be as bothered.
But what happens when your noisy neighbors start doing the same thing
around the entire neighborhood, right?
And they start knocking on people's doors.
Well, that's a different problem.
And so it could very well be that they are just watching us very carefully
because the funny little monkey is about to get out of his cage.
It could be, and that again, that's the zoo hypothesis or subset of it, which
is the alien police action scenario where they, they're, they're watching
you until you do something like develop artificial generalized intelligence
that can be a threat to the rest of the galaxy.
Right.
I mean, look, we're, we're doing it now with the tribes in, in, in Brazil
and in the Amazon, right?
We, we, we, we fly into the helicopter.
We take pictures and we monitor them.
What are they doing?
You know, and there's going to come a point where we're going to have to say,
okay, well, now's the time for contact.
You know, now, now it's either they're getting violence or they're starting
to raid a local village and they're starting to steal things.
Um, you know, who knows?
So it could just be a monitoring mission.
It could be, or it could be like, you know, we were talking with a shark,
but in this case, like a grizzly bear, it's just staring at you with a
half hearted interest until it gets hungry.
And then it just does something that, you know, it's what a bear does.
Yeah, that's what a bear does.
And, you know, or, and polar bears are worse in a lot of ways
because they don't have as much food.
Um, so it may be that way for an alien civilization is they're like, well,
that planet may be useful someday.
We don't need it right now.
And the monkeys can have their planet, but when we need that, you know, and
it could be something very predatory like that.
That's right.
Oh, by the way, can the monkeys defend themselves?
So what are we going to have to do to take, you know, take a little blue planet
if we need it, you know, these monkeys can be pretty violent sometimes.
Absolutely.
Well, the good news is if they, you know, people have pointed out, if
they were going to do anything, they'd have probably already done it.
So we must not have that important, but I don't know if I believe that.
I don't, I don't know if I believe that, you know, we're, we're, we're
talking off human timescales here, but that's relative, you know, um, a
tortoise lives 200 years plus maybe even older, right?
The oldest tree right now is what?
Several thousands of years old.
Time is relative.
You know, they don't, they don't, we don't, they're not on our timescale,
whatever they are, a timetable.
They've got time on their side.
They can do whatever they want, whenever they want.
And so, you know, say that way, we've already done it.
I'm not convinced.
Maybe there, you know, some folks in the Pentagon have speculated they're
doing a preparation of the battle space, maybe a 100 year, 200 year mission
to do reconnaissance, figure out what resources are on this planet and what
type of fight that they're going to have, and then be prepared for that.
Um, do I believe that?
Not necessarily, but some people in the Pentagon do.
It's interesting to think about the idea that, you know, time to them,
because we perceive time with our clocks and our calendars and our lifespan.
Ultimately, you know, we think a hundred years is a long time, but it, it really
isn't, it's not geologic time here.
But if you have something that lives, you know, on the scale of geologic time
or as part of a hive mind or something like that, that just is effectively
immortal, 10,000 years to it is nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
You know, we get out.
Sure.
I mean, it's, it's, it's not that big of a deal.
It is to us because, you know, our lifetime book, you said, are very
compressed, you know, if you live to 85 years old, you're doing pretty well.
Um, but that's, that's nothing.
That's a blink of an eye, right?
In, in, in real terms of, of, of time.
For now, in the future, 300 years from now, people may live a
considerably longer and they won't be.
We already are, aren't we?
I mean, look at the way we were back in the middle ages,
lifespan was what, 38, 39, 40 years old.
Unless you were royalty.
Um, now most people are living into their seventies, eighties, and even nineties.
Um, and now with the, you know, this, this new development of gene therapy and
some other stuff where you can, you know, biohack the system, it is very possible
that the next generation or two may be living to 150 years old.
Um, and, and, and that's still nothing.
Once you understand why, why people age, why animals age, right?
There's a genetic code that switches and all of a sudden, you know, the
system starts to eat itself.
But if you can turn that off and suppress that from occurring, then, you
know, who knows how long we could actually live.
True.
And I mean, that is the future.
But next question is a little bit more, um, in depth about the Pentagon.
Were you able to uncover the basic reason for the secrecy?
Now we all know that, that the Pentagon wants to protect the capabilities of
its sensors and all that stuff.
And they don't want to, you know, tell the Russians what, what the Raytheon radar
can do, you know, and things like that, which that's obviously national security
stuff, but they always say, you know, it's, it's not, it's not, it's the
instrument that's classified.
It's not the bird we photographed, you know, but in this case, that does
not seem to be the case.
The UAP seems to have some kind of classification of its own.
Am I, am I getting that right?
In other words?
So there is a UAP security classification guide.
Um, I'm not at liberty to discuss much of it.
Um, I was aware and, and familiar when it was being developed.
Um, there are very specific aspects of the UAP discussion that are indeed
classified, some of it is very classified.
Um, why they chose to classify certain aspects and not other aspects.
I couldn't answer that for you.
Um, I think some of it has to deal with sensitivities of the topic.
Look, the Dead Sea Scrolls, when they were first found, you know, how many years it
took before the translations were released to the public and do you know why that
they were kept secret for so long?
These are the Dead Sea Scrolls that they found in the, in the forties.
Yeah, absolutely.
Um, well, they were obviously worried that there were religious concerns.
Let's say that even though there really wasn't that much there, but
they were afraid that it would contradict the, at the time, the present understanding
of the Judeo-Christian belief system.
Um, that's not that uncommon.
We do things like that all the time to, to protect the American mindset
and other countries do it as well.
Now, is it right?
I don't think so, but that's not my decision.
Um, you know, there are, there, you don't want to, there were several studies that
were done in the past that the Pentagon and the intelligence community commissioned,
uh, through formal channels, think tanks, and they all came back unanimously saying
that if you, if you were honest to the American, with the American people about
this topic, it will cause great panic and pandemonium, you'll have runs on Wall
Street, people won't want to pay their bills anymore, and you're going to have
complete mass panic on your hands.
So the government decided not to have a conversation.
Um, you know, I tend to look at it the other way.
We're having the conversation now and guess what?
Everybody's still paying their mortgage.
Everybody's still paying their phone bill.
Everybody's still going to soccer practice and going to PTA.
So, um, I don't think those studies were accurate.
Now at the time, at the height of the Cold War, maybe, but we're not in the same
timetable anymore, or we're not in the same circumstance or in the same
situation that we were in.
And so I think we can have the conversation.
And I think America particularly can handle the truth and deserves
the truth about this topic.
Well, I think we're sufficiently conditioned by the pop culture and the
presence of UFOs on, you know, things like the History Channel and everything,
all that constantly, people know what it is.
You know, they know that it's a possibility.
Um, my last question for you is this.
Now, could there be an even more insidious reason for the secrecy?
In other words, if they have recovered technology from these, I can't imagine
they would hand that over to NASA.
They would want to know how it works so that we can use it, you know, and have a
leg up on, on, uh, you know, adversaries.
But even if we can't figure out how it works, keep it around and keep it secret
because maybe someday we will, although these things we tend to understand.
I understand, you know, you know what it is after you develop it yourself.
So not a lot of hope for, you know, back engineering, very advanced technology.
But is that the reason it's being kept secret?
And is it under like nuclear secrecy or something like that?
Well, um, you're not far off on the nuclear secrecy side.
Um, there are some, during the atomic, uh, regulatory committee time, they, they
had some very interesting policies, uh, that anything that gives off a certain
amount of radiation falls under those guidelines, period, full stop.
And then you have the U.S.
Espionage Act of, I think it's 1903 and some other, other laws on the books that
really were used to enforce secrecy about this topic.
Um, there are potentially more insidious reasons to keep this secret.
And it could be because of what we've done.
Uh, and I'll give you a case in point, you know, there were experiments with the
United States have done in the past.
And by the way, let me just make this clear.
I love my country.
I love my citizens.
I love my government, but we haven't always been honest brokers in the past.
People say, oh, our government doesn't lie to you, but lie to us.
Well, okay.
Unless you talk about, but they, I don't know, the Afghanistan withdrawal
and, uh, Iran contra and all the Pentagon papers, right?
Um, MKUltra, MKUltra syphilis experiments, right?
Where we allow human beings to die, die.
Think about that and allow syphilis to go through its natural progression
just so we could study it, right?
Even though we haven't cured at the time, um, we have done
a volatile things to each other.
Just, just look at the indigenous people here in this country and the way they've
been treated and the way the army started to, to basically conduct mass genocide
and get rid of all the buffaloes so they couldn't hunt and they were forced to,
to ultimately, um, force to their knees and then subjugate themselves to this
new government called the United States.
Um, you know, we can all look back in hindsight and say, well, you know,
we're all better off for it, but are we really?
And is it an excuse to treat people the way we have and keep things secret
only later on to find out what we did and go, yeah, sorry guys.
Well about that.
Maybe we shouldn't have done that.
Yeah, you're damn right.
We should have done that.
That was long.
And are we still doing things like that today?
Sad to say that we are.
And that's why this is why I do what I do.
Look, I'm a disclosure advocate, but not just for UAP.
People think, oh, you're the UFO guy.
Actually, I'm not the UFO guy.
Uh, I'm a disclosure guy.
Um, I've been part of some very interesting things that this country has
done in the past, some of it, not very good, some of it, very good,
some of it, not so good.
And the only way we, we stopped from ever making those mistakes again, is being
open and honest and, and being held accountable for those things.
And that is why I think this topic is just one example of many, why the
government needs to come open, come on about what, what, what we have known
all this time about UAP.
Now I'm not saying necessarily give up, you know, the crown jewels and say what
we've been able to exploit from this and reverse engineer from it, if anything
at all, but what I am saying is the mere fact that we're not alone in the
universe, you know, let's learn from the, the, the, the mistakes of the Catholic
church back in the days of Galileo.
You know, when he first proposed the idea of the heliocentric solar system and not
an earth centric solar system, it almost burned him at the stake.
They made him recant.
They even refused to look through the very telescope he had to prove his observations.
Now at the end of the day, did the, the truth about earth really hurt religion?
No, of course not.
What it did was just challenge our ideas at the time about religion, but it
never actually challenged religion.
And I think we're kind of in the same boat here.
I don't think this topic is going to hurt or threaten anything with our government.
Um, it may force us to recalibrate our thinking on some things, but I think,
I think we can handle that.
I think we're grown up enough.
And I think the new generation of people, the younger folks that are my
kids age, who are very responsible, very intelligent, they have what took me
having to go to a library, reading an encyclopedia, an encyclopedia that was
written 10 years before me even getting there is now all available on this
phone worldwide in any language in the world, instantly touch of a button.
Think about that for a minute.
We are, we are, we are smarter now than we have ever been before.
We have evolved more in the last 120 years than we have in the last 120,000 years.
So that's my, that's my take.
That's my perspective anyways.
I think, I think we can handle the truth.
And I think, I think we deserve the truth.
And we must always remain vigilant in this democracy.
You know, keep the country honest, keep the government honest, because
the government isn't the problem.
It's the people in the government.
That's right.
Look, sometimes to be a patriot, you have to do things that don't always
necessarily seem patriotic at the time.
Absolutely.
But, um, I could not agree more.
Now everybody should check out Lou's book, uh, Eminence, which is absolutely
fascinating, but I got a special plug because I got the audio book version and
Lou actually read it and did a fine job, even better than, you know, a voiceover
artist could normally do.
So that was just very nicely done, Lou.
John, thank you.
I don't have the, uh, sexy, smooth voice, uh, like you do.
You have a natural voice for radio.
I have a voice that's more akin to a, a cement truck, uh, hurling down
a country road in high gear.
Uh, um, so unfortunately you had to endure that.
I apologize, but thank you for the compliment.
It suits, um, it's very heartfelt.
Oh, I enjoyed it.
It was very personable and really added a, uh, you know, a personal touch to
the story and it was very good book.
So everybody should check that out.
Luel Elizondo, thank you for joining us today.
It was a pleasure and I hope whatever happens, we, we eventually get an answer.
John, my, my sincere honor and privilege and a big shout out also to your partner
there, Ross, who's helping make this happen.
And, uh, and of course a very good mutual friend of ours, Rob as well,
probably, so just wanted to say thank you.
Shout out to Rob.
Event Horizon and my channel are now available as a podcast on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, and YouTube memberships.
Early ad free episodes, bonus episodes, and sleep focused content.
Sign up now by clicking the links below to your platform of choice.