Oh, yeah, you can sing for us. Are you a singer? I used, I mean, in college, in high school,
in high school, you were singing in college, you know, just in the choir, but you know,
just like everybody, everybody likes to sing it as long as nobody's listening, right? Yeah,
that's for sure. Yeah, I like music. That's like hum along in the shower. What's your
favorite kind of music? I don't have, I'm not very specific. It's more about like emotional,
the emotional palette that it's playing with. It's different genres of music have the different
emotional palette. Exactly. I'm interested in which kind of palette I like, but I particularly
like sort of glorious music, glorious music, Vangelis, right? Like sort of like epic orchestras,
like as if there was like grand big things. Yes, like, like a big battle scene in a movie,
the kind of music you would see behind that, like just Brian Eno, for example. I don't even
know what that means. He's a musician. Sorry. Oh, he's a guy. Oh, person. Right. But obviously,
I could play you some. Oh, yeah. Are you a musician? Do you play any instruments? No,
I mean, I played a recorder a long time ago. That's okay. Like in college, I would relax by
going into like stairwells in the university and playing my recorder in the stairwell.
And I really got into, well, somebody, somebody told me I was doing that near their class and
they said they were hearing this music from the like air ducks in the classroom that couldn't
figure out where I was coming from. Interesting. That's very interesting. Okay. Well, let's
officially get this thing going. Mr. Robin Hansen. It's great to meet you. First of all,
nice to meet you, sir. For our listeners and our viewers, can you give me a brief description of
who you are, your background and your areas of interest? That's going to be hard because I've
just been all over the place. I know you really have. But if you could give me some sort of a
synopsis. So long ago, I started out in engineering in college. I switched to physics, got an
undergraduate degree in physics, and then I decided I wanted to understand what the hell science was.
So I went off to University of Chicago to study philosophy of science, but then I kind of answered
the questions for myself and switched back to physics. And then I saw cool things happening in
Silicon Valley and heard about AI and hypertext. And so I left school with two masters in physics
and philosophy of science to go off to Silicon Valley where I did AI research and Bayesian
statistics as a job. And on the side did hypertext publishing and a bunch of other stuff for nine
years. And then I went back to school to get my PhD at the age of 34 with two kids, age zero and
two. Wow. Just in a four years in your out program, because they guarantee, you know,
that basically everybody gets kicked out after four years. That was good. And I got my degree
in PhD in social science from Caltech. And then I went on the market and did better in political
science than I did in econ, but I didn't get a job. I got a postdoc in health policy for two
years at Berkeley. And then I went on the market again and got my current job as a professor of
economics at George Mason University. And since I got tenure in 2006, I allowed myself to spread
out a bit more. And I started a blog called Overcoming Bias. And I've since written two books,
one a futurist book called The Age of M Work, Love and Life When Robots Rule the Earth, and then a
psychology book called The Elephant in the Brain, Hidden Motives in Everyday Life. And I'm still
pretty much all across the map. I've done a lot of different things. The thing I'm most famous for is
the idea of prediction markets, which I was working on when I was that computer researcher,
but back before I went back to school. And that's why I picked Caltech because they did
I thought that would help in these institution ideas. And I have a wide range of like, big
institution ideas I'm into too. But as you know, recently, I went back to my astrophysics work,
and I did this gravy alien stuff picking up on the great filter stuff I did while I was a postdoc
doing health policy at Berkeley back in that long ago. And so I think most intellectuals are just
naturally broad. And in fact, that's probably one of the main failure modes when people want to become
an academic, is they don't focus enough. And I was at risk of failing in that way, by not focusing
enough, because the academic world really wants you to be the best at one thing and stick with it
for the rest of your life. And doing a lot of different things, it doesn't reward so much. So
I slipped by I managed to sneak by being a little too broad. The Future of Humanity Institute at
Oxford. You're a researcher there. I have an affiliation there. When they were starting up
long time ago, they wanted to collect prestigious affiliations so they could, you know, credit
everything who there was listed associated with them for what they did every year. And so it
happy to be included in that when they first got started, when they were small, and now they are
big and don't need me anymore for that purpose, but I'm happy to still be affiliated. So the
purpose of that was to look at the big picture questions about humanity, right? Absolutely.
And what, to you, what are the fundamental big picture questions about humanity?
Well, there's where we came from and where we're going.
So the Future of Humanity, of course, focused on that future. But, you know, I think the first job,
as always, is diagnosis before you do prognosis. So the first thing you need to do is just have a
foggiest idea of what might happen, when and how. And then you can start to think about how could we
move it a little. So I think people start way too quick to say, what do I want the future to be?
What do I want the future to be like? And sort of map out their ideal case. And actually, it's
pretty hard to actually just figure out what's likely to happen if you do nothing. And you're
probably not going to be able to do a lot. So figure out what's likely to happen if you do nothing,
and then maybe nudge it a bit. So people thinking about the future, they of course think about
things like global warming, they think about population and fertility, they think about
the future of innovation, technology, like space travel, energy, but innovation of social
institutions too. I've been especially interested in forms of governance, ways that you can interact
with the economy. And people are usually focused on the future in our era mediated by technology,
that is people imagine particular new technologies coming, and then they think about how that will
affect the future. So that's been true for a while. And so obviously, artificial intelligence
is one kind of technology. I mean, since I did AI research for nine years, that was especially
salient for me. Obviously, people think about future energy sources, they think about
space travel, they think about environmental impacts. But there's just a lot more to think
about really, if you get creative about it. So I always thought that there was a neglect of the
intersection of social science and tech in thinking about the future. So most futurists that you hear
about are tech people. They know about some kind of a tech, and they want to tell you where they
think that tech is going, and then what social implications that will have. And like myself,
when I was a physics student a long time ago, they were probably taught that social science
doesn't exist. Most tech people are told that basically, that hard sciences like, you know,
physics or computer science or chemistry, even biology, those are real sciences, and people
really know stuff there. But over in those social sciences, that's all fluff and made up, and there's
really nothing there. So when tech people go to try to figure out the social implications of the
technologies they're imagining, they kind of wing it with their intuitions. They don't really use
expert social science. Whereas the social scientists who do understand social science,
when they think about the future, they tend to be skeptical about all those tech projections.
They look at the world around them, and they figure the technology of the future couldn't
possibly be that different from the technology they see around them, and science fiction-y
projections must just be fantasy. So they don't really take seriously the tech, and therefore
they don't really project, you know, what future tech might be, and then what the social implications
are. So there's this missing intersection, right? On the one hand, we have tech people who can
envision future technologies, and on the other hand, we have social scientists who can project
social changes as a result of whatever perturbations come, including technologies, but they don't put
it together much. And that's what you do. That's one of the things I've tried to do. So my highest,
most meta-level principle is to look for important neglected things. So, you know, that's
neglected there, right? You find a way that people are neglecting something that's important, and then
you can have it all to yourself. So what is the future of humanity and artificial intelligence
if we look into the near future and the distant future? There's a lot of people who have very
dystopian views of how this might look. What are your views on this? Are they dark or dystopian,
or are they optimistic? So, first of all, in terms of ordinary artificial intelligence of the sort
that most people see and have seen for a long time, of the sort that I did as a researcher,
I see that as accumulating gradually, improving steadily, and having a long road still to go.
So that sort of process looks like it will give you plenty of warning before you have bigger
problems to deal with. So we're a long way away from machines being able to do most everything
humans do, perhaps even centuries. And, you know, as they start to become more capable,
then they will basically take up a larger fraction of world income. The key signature of AI getting
more capable is you pay it more money instead of people. So because most income goes to pay
people today, you can be pretty sure that people are the main valuable thing today. But later on,
with time, we will pay more and more for the machines and the software,
because they'll be doing the important things, and then eventually they'll do most things.
But there's a long way to go before that, and that process will be pretty gradual. That is,
I don't foresee a sudden change where all of a sudden, you know, humans were doing, you know,
half the jobs yesterday, and next week they're doing almost nothing, right?
The scale, the timeline isn't necessarily linear in a sense that the exponential growth of tech,
the growth of technology becomes exponential, right? Like what we did in the last 100 years
compared to the next 100 years will be extremely sped up. Well, I actually think you should think
in terms of a log normal distribution over task difficulty, which is a mouthful, I guess. So
the idea is the difficulty of tasks in automating varies enormously. So, you know,
they are spread across a very wide spectrum in terms of how difficult tasks are to automate. So,
you know, as you know, Moore's law for a while, you know, computers got twice as cheap every two
years. But we didn't see an exponential displacement of humans from jobs, even as
technology was increasing exponentially. That is, we've seen a relatively linear steady displacement
of jobs, even though technology is increasing exponentially. And a way to understand that is
to imagine there's a distribution for each job of how hard it is, how much computing power does it
take to automate that job? And think of it in terms of many, many orders of magnitudes, right?
So if it was a number like some jobs take one and some takes 10 and 10 take 100 and 1000 and a
million and a billion, and that jobs are spread really far across this really wide range of
difficulty. So the very first machines automated some very simple jobs that people were doing.
And then over time, as computers have gotten better and cheaper, we've been able to automate
more jobs by moving up that spectrum. Like first, it was the jobs that only had a difficulty of one
and then the jobs have 10 and then the jobs that have 100. But the idea is the range is really wide.
Like there's jobs up at a trillion and the jobs at a quadrillion, right? And so that's why even
as technology has been improving exponentially, the fraction of jobs that the machines do has
not been increasing exponentially because the difficulty of job is just really widely spread.
And at the moment, we are, you know, automating a new set of jobs that we couldn't automate
10 years ago. But we have just a little still really long way to go. And so that would be my
picture for the ordinary kind of AI that we've seen so far. Now my book, The Age of M is about a
somewhat different kind of AI. And that different kind of AI has more of a threshold effect where
nothing happens until something happens and then a lot suddenly happens. And that's the idea of a
brain emulation. So you have a brain in your head and it has a whole bunch of cells of different
types which are connected to each other with little wires. And there's a system by which when
signals come into your eyes or your hand, it goes to the brain and they go signals go through the
cells and each cell takes signals in and send signals out. And we could in principle copy that
whole system in your brain and make a computer model of a brain like yours that has, you know,
a substitute for each cell and a model of how each cell works that send take signals in and send
signals out that sends it to the other cells just like in your brain. And if we could make a brain
emulation of your brain, then it would behave just like you in the same situation. And that would be
powerful human level artificial intelligence. We are a long way from being able to do that,
but we will sometime in the next few centuries be able to do that. And we might,
I think, be able to do that before we can do other kinds of human level artificial intelligence.
And this kind of AI has a threshold. That is, when we make this emulation of your brain,
say we get it wrong, like this cell models are off or the connections are off. If it's wrong enough,
it just won't work. It'll just be mush. It'll just be a mess. But once we pass a threshold of
the model being close enough to you, then it'll basically work. And so that's this threshold
where brain emulations before a certain point, they're just not really valuable at all.
And then after a certain point, they're really valuable. And then that would have more of a
sudden transition into this world where brain emulations were cheap and common. And that's what
my book is all about, is what that world looks like. Have you ever seen the movie or the show
Westworld? Yes, of course. Yes. Yeah, that is almost exactly what Westworld is about, right?
It's about a park. Can you explain? Right. Well, so the, I mean, initially it was a movie long ago
when I was a kid. It was also a movie long ago. Yeah. Right. And so the idea is it's an amusement
park where there are robots to entertain the guests and they don't really specify how the
robots are designed. So in fact, in the TV show Westworld, they also have brain emulations later
in the show as a different thing. And so the robots in Westworld are not brain emulation robots,
but they are AI that are as very effectively similar to humans. So they present them as very
human-like AI, even though they're apparently not designed that way. And of course, it's crazy
stupid. Like a lot of fiction is if you could actually make those robots as they made them in
that show, you wouldn't mainly use them in an amusement park. You choose them everywhere in
the economy. I mean, so the key thing is human workers are get more than half of world income.
So if you could have a substitute for human workers, you can make trillions of dollars,
basically replacing human workers with it. So the idea that you would just use that in an amusement
park and nowhere else is kind of crazy. Well, the idea of the main incentive for Westworld,
correct me if I'm wrong, I may be misinterpreting it. That's been a while, but I believe the main
incentive of it was to longevity, right? To live forever, to be able to learn enough from these
real humans that were interacting with them, to be able to copy them, to copy their minds. So when
their biological body dies, they can take that copy and put it in a cyborg or a robot.
There were three main lines of business that I recall from Westworld TV show. The first main
line of business was the entertainment of the amusement park. Right. Okay. A second line of
business was they were trying to make uploads. And I believe they showed that as failing. That is,
they just didn't work. And then the third secret line of business that they reveal later on is
that they're watching the visitors to the park very closely and therefore learning to predict
human behavior. And somehow the idea is that that was much more valuable than just having
human level robots. Because somehow you could market to them, right? You could send them
advertisements and predict what they do. And so in the later seasons, they have these big
spherical computers that are predicting the world. What will everybody will do, right? As if that
was some enormously economically valuable thing compared to the robots, which that seems crazy.
Because people predicting future behavior, the moment that doesn't command much income in the
world, there's not a lot of demand for that. There is some, but it's not that big. But people working,
there's a huge demand for that. The world is full of people working. And if you can substitute for
people working, you can make trillions. I don't think you can make trillions just because you can
predict what TV show somebody will watch next or which way they will turn on the street. There's
just not that much money there, but it sets up this dystopian thing. Oh my God, they can predict
what I'll do. I just feel dehumanized now, right? So the show went for this emotional threat of you
feeling threatened by the fact that a machine can predict you as the emotional anchor of the show,
as opposed to these machines can take your jobs. Pardon this brief interruption, but I want to take
a minute to talk about this incredible supplement that I've been using for over a year now after it
was recommended to me by nutritional scientist, Dr. Dominic D'Agostino on this podcast. I take
Dom's advice when it comes to anything related to nutrition, diet, and longevity, because as we get
older, these things become more and more important. That is why I started using Verso. Verso is a
company that is dedicated to translating scientific breakthroughs into products that
hold the potential to increase longevity. I take cell being this one right here, which contains
nicotinamide mononucleotide, or NMN-based supplement, paired with naturally derived
micronized trans resveratrol and TMG. These two chemicals are actually precursors to what's called
nicotinamide iodine dinonucleotide, which is commonly known as NAD. And NAD is essentially
the precursor to energy, cell repair, and longevity. If you've ever tried fasting,
or even intermittent fasting, and you've gotten that feeling of super high energy or mental
clarity, it's because your body is activating these genes called sirtuins, which are actually
longevity genes. The downside is as we age, NAD declines. When I found out I could naturally
increase my body's activation of sirtuins and naturally activate my body's production of NAD,
I was sold. And it is so much more affordable than doing NAD IV drips.
Head on over to ver.so and use the coupon code concrete at checkout to save 15% on your entire
order. That's K-O-N-C-R-E-T-E at checkout and get 15% off your entire order, or you can just go to
ver.so slash K-O-N-C-R-E-T-E. It's linked below, back to the show. Right. It's more of like an
advertising type thing, right? Right. They can predict it. They can make money with advertising
to you or selling to you. Right, which is tiny compared to work. Right. Like advertising is like
two or three percent of GDP, right? Whereas work is like 70% of GDP. Oh, wow. Right. So,
you know, if you can take over the advertising industry, you can take over the work industry,
take over the work industry. Right. Do you imagine those little pearls, they call them,
do you imagine is that like a realistic physical form of what a brain might be uploaded to?
I mean, that's just to have a dramatic physical thing to look at. I mean, obviously almost all
computers these days have wires by which they transfer files by wires from one computer to
another. Sometimes when they want to like send a file physically, they have them on a tape and
they mail them. But I mean, the fact that have these little shiny silver balls doesn't make much
sense. But that's not forgivable because that's also not terribly wrong. I mean, you could do it
that way. Yeah, that you would. It seems like we're at least beginning one of the first steps
towards that with, for example, the Neuralink that Elon Musk is producing that directly interfaces
with the brain. I mean, it's essentially like a super evolved version of the iPhone, you know,
but it's in your it's actually attached to your brain. You would think about things and be able
to communicate without speech. In principle, it would just have a higher bandwidth. Right, exactly.
Your brain could talk to a machine and back and forth with a higher bandwidth. So I mean, obviously
bandwidth is valuable. The key question is for what? What is exactly the value of high bandwidth?
So well, I mean, your brain was designed for high bandwidth through your eyes and ears, right? So
your brain really wasn't designed to take high bandwidth input in through other channels. That
is your brain, you know, has a whole system there for what it's where it expects to get input and
then has a whole system for processing that input. So it's not obvious that we can actually usefully
give your brain a lot of input other than through the input channels it was designed to take.
Interesting. Yeah, because I always think about it. The first thing that I think about when I
think of things like Neuralink is being able to like the advantages that you would have
over other human beings, like being able to, for example, download a book into your brain and know
it in 30 seconds or, you know, the advantages you have in the economic world if you have that
technology. That would be hard. So the brain emulation scenario is a scenario where, you know,
you equivalently have Neuralink, you know, easy because they're just on computers anyway, so it
would be easy to send information in. But it's not clear you could just, you know, download a book
and they would know it because that requires that you restructure the brain. So. Oh, how so? Well,
you know, so if you imagine like having files on your computer you could download a movie and then
the movie's on the computer and if you hit play you play the movie. You need software. Right. But
if you have a large, say a library, right, a large library full of books and now you want all those
books to reflect some new insight in math, right, you don't just like put the math book somewhere
in the library. Right. All the other books don't update on the math book sitting in the library.
You'll have to get all the other books to change in response to this new thing, you know,
so that they've integrated into the rest of the books, right? So taking any large library and
getting it to reflect some new math insight would be hard, would be time consuming. You'd have to go
find all the books that actually are related to that. Understand them and rewrite those chapters
in order to reflect the new insight that you were trying to get in. Right. That makes perfect sense.
Um, so one of the most memorable quotes from that movie to me, which I've talked about on this
podcast many times, and I think about a lot, which I'm fascinated to hear your opinion on it, was
when Ford, the man who developed the theme park with the AIs, he said that human intellect is
like peacock feathers. It's an elaborate display to attract a mate. All of the best of Mozart,
all the best of Shakespeare, the best of Michelangelo, even the empire state building,
just an elaborate mating ritual. Um, and maybe that all the things that humanity has accomplished
doesn't even matter because it was done so for the basis of reasons. Even the peacock can barely
fly. It lives in the dirt and it picks insects out of the muck. What are your thoughts on that quote?
Um, I do expect that peacock feather kind of drives were an important drive in human
mind evolution, but it's also clear that human minds are spectacularly capable compared to most
other animal minds. It's clear that human civilization together with human minds has
been able to accomplish amazing things. Now it could be it's only accomplishing them with
10% of the brain and the rest of the 90% is peacock feathers, but still something in there
is amazingly capable compared to all the other animals that that's just obvious.
Yes. So then you might want to understand like which parts are which try to disentangle the
fundamentally, you know, more useful parts from the others, but certainly something in there
is useful, but the brain is huge, so it could well not be most of it.
Mm hmm. Well, it goes back to the main, one of the main or the main theory of your book,
the elephant in the brain, right? Where there's explain what the that that book is and what the
the basic idea of it is. So the idea is that you are wrong about why you do many things, right?
That is, if I asked you why you do most of the things you do, you'll give me a reason.
And it turns out most of those reasons are wrong. That is, it's the reason you have in your head,
it's the reason you can sort of explain and justify and to some degree your behavior is
driven by that thing, but not mostly. So, but most of the things you're doing
instead, the motives you have are reasonable motives to have, they just don't look as nice
as the motives you'd like to point to. So, for example, you go to school not to learn the material
because you don't actually learn much material. You go to school to show off, to show that you
are capable and also to sort of learn sort of modern workplace habits. You go to the doctor
not to get well, but to show that you care about people and let them they show they care about you.
You vote not to help the nation do better, but to show your allegiance to your political tribe.
Each of these things is a useful function for a social animal, it's just not the function you
claim. Now, some of these functions are more zero-sum or have waste at least, so many of these
functions that you don't like to admit that you're not really aware of are showing off.
And showing off is often wasteful, like going all those years to school just to show off how smart
and conscientious and conformist you are is a lot of waste, but it's not all waste.
It is important for people to be able to judge who's how capable and to sort them into different
kinds of tasks and roles based on knowing about their features. And, you know, large social
worlds, we do need to show and judge loyalty. And a lot of these signals are to show and judge
loyalty. So like the peacock feathers are just showing that you can put up with the feathers.
That is, you have enough, you know, other capabilities that if a predator comes after
you, you can usually survive even though you're carrying around this big wasteful set of feathers.
But those feathers aren't really useful for much else. But many of the capabilities that humans
have acquired that we show off are actually more useful for other things. Now, maybe evolution just
got lucky and didn't realize how useful they would be, but clearly something in the human brain,
the capacity the human brain has, has allowed us to do enormous things compared to most animals.
Like acquiring wealth would be an example of something that would be impressive and
also has many other right. Exactly. Sure. Or language. So for example, most people use a
larger vocabulary than they really need to because they show off how much they know to do a larger
vocabulary. And I noticed I use the word vocabulary instead of just saying, you know, many words. So I
was showing off that I had a bigger vocabulary, but words are useful. So you are learning things
like that. Many, you know, ancient societies, people who are rich, what they show off by
getting things from far away, strange, you know, things that local people wouldn't have,
that they would have an unusual thing. And that encouraged trade and long distance travel
interactions. War has actually been one of the largest drivers of innovation over the last 10,000
years. War is terribly destructive. Nevertheless, the drive to improve war technology has in fact,
you know, driven a lot of technological improvements. Right. So the key thing is once
you open some new territory of learning and expanding, even if you're wasting most of your
effort there, the remaining effort can just produce huge returns. Yeah. One of the most absurd
examples I've thought of when it comes to the idea of the elephant in the brain is Elon Musk.
You know, you think of him as this just crazy, flamboyant, you know, the richest man in the
world. And he also builds rockets and wants to make our species interplanetary. Or does he? Or
does he just want money and women? I'm not sure I care. I'm not sure I care. Right. Because at
the same time, whether that is his drive or not, the things that he's accomplishing are
valuable and very important to us. I mean, I think if you're going to pick one person on the
planet today that you want to be really impressed with, with what they've accomplished, it would
have to be him. That's true. So, you know, I have to give hats off. I mean, and he's going on to
accomplish more things, no doubt. Many of them will fail. But yes, we, humanity is on a tear
and we have a bright future ahead of us if we so choose, even if we are now wasting enormous
fractions of our civilization on peacock feathers. And in some sense, that makes the prospects even
brighter. If we could cut the waste, we could get even more. Right. Simulation theory. How far do
you go into simulation theory in your books and what are your estimations of the probability of
simulation theory? So many decades ago, the idea that we might be living with simulation was a
common theme on some of the mailing lists I was on. And then at one point, one of the people was
on the mailing lists, went off and wrote a philosophy paper based on that, Nick Bostrom,
and then that got more attention. And then at the time that inspired me to write a paper on how to
live in a simulation because that was neglected. So there are many of these topics where, again,
people want to mainly focus on the technology itself, when it might happen, is it possible?
And they rarely, they neglect the social implications. So I thought, let's just think
about the social implications of a simulation. If you were living in one, how should you live
your life differently? And so I do have that paper on that. But the key idea here is that
in the future, things like brain emulations will be possible and therefore it will be possible to
create creatures who are in a world that looks completely real to them, but is in some sense,
not. It's fake. So like in the movie The Matrix or things like that, it'll be possible to make
such creatures. And some of those creatures would be set in a world like the past of that world.
Just like today when we make movies, some of our movies are set in our past and some of our games
are set in our past or something like that. And so if there was a creature set in some, you know,
fictional world who doesn't know they're in a fictional world, and if that fictional world
is in the past of that symbolization, then if you are sitting here in your world, you could ask,
how do I know I'm not that creature? Exactly. I could be in principle, you know, in fact,
that future creature who thinks they're in this current day, but is actually in the future
in a simulated world made to look like their past. So the relative chances that I am a simulation
like that really comes down to a numbers game. Like how many people are there here today really?
And how many people would there be in the future simulating my time now? And that's, you have to
come up with estimates of those relative numbers in order to guess, could I be in a simulation? So
if you think there are relatively few people in the future who would be simulations of the past,
then you think it's not very likely that I'm in a simulation. But if you think there's enormous
numbers of them in the future, then you would have to think, well, then it's pretty likely, right?
Now, we should first notice, like, if you were simulating the past, you're not going to equally
randomly select from the past to simulate. So when we do movies or we do games, right,
we do Caesar all the time or Napoleon all the time and all the other people not so often, right?
So that means your chance of being in a simulation does depend on how
photogenic your life is in the sense, is your life the sort of life somebody might want to simulate?
Right. Would you be an interesting player? Right. Or are you a famous person? Did you
have a big impact on the future, right? So we'll often pick famous people in the past.
Who we see as having had a big historical impact as the people we simulate in our past when we do
novels or games or things like that. So then, you know, that would modify your estimate for
yourself. If you're a random person, that's different than if your life seems to be especially
good story, especially story that the future might. So Elon Musk himself
should assign a higher probability than the rest of us to living in a simulation because it would
be more likely somebody would simulate his life compared to ours. Right. Okay. But let's set that
aside and let's just think about an ordinary average person today and ask what's the chance
they're living in a simulation. Well, I'd say we're going to basically do an integral where we
multiply two numbers. So basically there's all these different years in the future and each year
in the future will have a certain size economy which has some amount of past simulations that
are happening in that economy. Right. So in each future year, there's some percentage of that
economy that they spend doing these past simulations. Right. So we could count that now in terms of our
how many historical novels do we have or historical games or something. Right. And
we could also have which past they're interested in, you see. So as the future,
as we get farther in the future, we expect the future to get bigger, the economy will get bigger
and then even if there's just a constant fraction of that future economy that spent thinking about
the past, that amount gets bigger. Right. Right. So the farther we go into the future, the more
past simulations we expect to be happening at that moment in that distant future time.
Okay. But we expect those simulations to be spread out across their past according to how
interested they are in their past. That is, which past are they interested in. Right. And so now
when we're thinking about the future, we're asking, you know, it's an integral over the future.
For each future year, one number is how big is that economy and, you know, what fraction of it
is devoted to historical simulations and the other is how large a fraction of that would we count
because we are competing with all the other dates at which they could be trying to make
simulations. Wow. That's complex. Right. But there's a simple answer. Okay. Which is that
if interest in the past fades faster than the world grows, then most of the simulations of you will
be in the relatively near future. So say if, you know, interest in the future doubled at the moment,
sorry, the future economy say grows by a factor of two every 15 years at the moment. But if interest
in the fact falls by a factor of two every 10 years, then as you can see, even though the future
gets much bigger, it's even less interested in you. Right. Simulating your date. Right. So
they'll be much more interested in simulating things nearer their own date in terms of their
history. So the final bottom line is what we want to ask is how fast does interest in the past
or decline with time compared to the rate at which the population of the economy grows in time?
And there's something called Google n-grams and you can just type in a year like 1900 into Google
n-grams and it will show you how the interest in that year rose with time up until that year and
fell with time after that year. Really? And you can just pick all sorts of dates and see that.
And so you can see how fast does interest in the past fall away as you move away from that year.
And in fact, it falls away faster than the economy or the population grows.
But there are certain years that are way more interesting than other certain times in history
like the ancient Egyptians when the pyramids were built. Sure. Or World War II. But we're
just trying to do sort of the overall average first. Okay. Okay. So the overall average seems
to be that our interest in the past fades faster. And that also is roughly true. That is, say,
in the last 10,000 years, the world population doubled roughly every thousand years up until
recently. But I think it seems to me obvious that interest in the past falls faster than a factor of
two every thousand years. So, right. Okay. I mean, so if you look at most historical simulations,
you know, a thousand years ago, you know, almost all the simulations, the percentage of historical
simulations that are past the year 1000, probably well over 90%. Right. And you go back another
thousand years and it falls even faster. And, you know, the fraction of historical simulations that
are of 1000 BC, almost nothing. Right. Look on Netflix or some other thing. Find me a historical
story that took place more than 3000 years ago. Right. It's just almost nothing. But 3000 years
ago is only a factor of eight reduced population because it goes by a factor of two every thing.
So according to the, if it were proportional to population, then one eighth, say, of historical
simulations should be more than 3000 years ago. Right. But far fewer. I see. So here's the bottom
line, right? We should only expect the future to simulate us when it's relatively soon, but actually
we can't do simulations yet. It'll be a while till we can do simulations of the past. It'll be a
while before we can create creatures who are in a simulation that don't know they're in the past.
We're not able to do that yet. Right. And so by the time they can do it,
it'll be far enough in the future. They'll be hardly interested in us at all. Right. And then
they'll only be able to do a few at first. And as they get able to do more, they get even less
interested in us. Right. Why would they be? We're just too far in the past. We're too far in the
past. Unless we are somehow special. So some people have claimed that we are in the special era,
that the future will be unusually interested in us, especially because we are different.
Why would they be interested in us right now? Well, many people are attracted or tied to this
idea that this is a pivotal moment in history. And that's what motivates them to do a lot of
things they do because this is the moment that matters. And of course, it's a bit of arrogance.
Yes. It sounds like something that every... Obviously, it could be true in principle. I
don't actually think it is that true. I mean, some important things are happening now, but important
things happened a century ago and a century before that. What would be the social implication
of everybody being aware that they are in a simulation? If human beings being aware that
we're in a simulation, what would change? What would be the social implications?
Well, you have to ask what's the purpose of the simulation. So clearly somebody who made a
simulation could have told people in simulation that we're in a simulation, right? If they had
wanted to do that. So clearly they didn't want to do that, right? So if people in a simulation
figure out they're in a simulation against the wishes of the people who set up the simulation,
the question is, what can the people who set up the simulation do in response? And they have
enormous powers to deal with that. So I don't think they're actually going to suffer that problem.
So they wouldn't let us allow us to figure it out?
If they don't want to, it doesn't seem like they want to. Unless they want to do a simulation of
a world that finds out and see what they do. But that's going to be a kind of unusual special
thing to simulate. No doubt they do that sometimes, but not very often.
So one of the main things you can do in a simulation is you can sort of have noise and
error in how you do the simulation. And then if something happens that wasn't supposed to happen,
you just back it up and you do it again. So simulations don't have to just run forward.
They can back up. So that's just the nature of the way we do computer simulations, all sorts of
systems today. So that means if there's anything you don't want to have happen in a simulation,
it's relatively easy to prevent it. That is, if you see the thing go wrong, then you stop,
you back it up, and you take that, you know, you change something and then you roll it back forward
and you keep doing that until you get the thing you wanted. Right. Right. That makes sense.
So, you know, if you're in a simulation, you are very much at their mercy and you will not know
things they don't want you to know. What if they did want us? What if they did decide to let us know
we were in a simulation? Well, then we're in a simulation where they want to find out what
happens when they let us know. And of course they will try that different variations on that. And
then, you know, they will see the different variations. Wow. That's fascinating. And people
like Elon Musk, people who have more interesting lives, who have made a greater impact on him,
who have made a greater impact on history. Those are people that are more inclined to believe.
Well, they should be more inclined to believe that for them it is in fact true that they are
more likely to be living in simulation. Right. The great filter. What inspires you to write this
paper on the great filter? I believe you collaborated on it with a few people. Is that
right? And then what is the basic idea of the great filter? So the great filter is something
I did over 20 years ago, 25 years ago almost now. And 1996, right? It started. And that was about
just reframing the great, what they say, Fermi's question, where is everybody? So we look up in
the universe and looks empty and dead. And we look at our future, we see this prospect for us to be
lively and invisible. And there's a bit of a conflict here. We don't see around us the things
we expect to be in the future. So I reframed that question, just asked a different way. And I said,
well, big visible things of the sort that we hope to become soon, they will have to appear
by going down a path. They start with simple dead matter early in the universe, and then they're
on a planet, say, and life appears and then life goes through stages. And eventually it gets to our
stage and eventually goes from our stage onto this big visible stage. And going down that path,
it must be very hard to go from the beginning and get all the way to the end by this point in the
history of the universe, because almost nothing has done it. So that would be to say there's a
filter on that path. Things start in at one end of a pipe and almost nothing comes out the other end
of the pipe. Because look, this whole universe started on the pipe. Every piece of rock anywhere
could have started down this path to evolve life and spread. But we're the only thing we can see
that's farther down the pack. We don't see anything that's farther beyond where we hope to be.
So that's the claim that to get all the way to where we hope to be is very hard. There's a very
large filter between, you know, that final destination and the initial stage of simple
dead matter. And when you say filter, what specifically are you referring to? What would
a filter be? What's an example of a filter? So, you know, you could have a planet where it never
evolved even life in the first place, right? And then it failed to pass that first step. And then
you could have some place with simple life but didn't become more complicated life, like with
sexual reproduction, say, or photosynthesis, or, you know, a whole bunch of multicellular
things, right? So on Earth, life went through a bunch of stages. And we could say each stage,
when it made a key change, it passed through a filter step. It succeeded in accomplishing
something that maybe most planets never do. And that's the great filter is the difficulty
of going all the way down this path to the place where we are now and then on forward. So
the fact the universe looks dead and empty says that filter is big. And it also raises a question,
how far along the filter are we? Because we're not all the way. And so clearly it's a huge filter.
And even if just a small fraction is ahead of us, that says bad news about our future.
A small fraction is ahead of us. What do you mean by that?
So it could be say the total filter is maybe 10 to the 24, for example, like only one planet out
of 10 to the 24 ever becomes reaches advanced life that becomes visible in the universe.
Well, it could be that we've gone through 10 to the 22 of it so far.
And we only have 10 to the two left. But that would still mean we only have a 1% chance
of getting from here to that final destination. That is 99% chance we won't probably by dying,
which is kind of scary. Yes. What are the chances that we've already made it through the great filter?
Well, that's again about how much of it we have passed. So
you could look at our history and try to guess which things were hard. But the problem is
actually the timing doesn't tell you much. So it turns out that if we were very lucky on Earth to
get as far as we did, then even if the different steps before us had different difficulties,
the timing would be roughly equally spaced. And therefore, we do see roughly equally spaced timing
between major transitions. And so that actually doesn't tell us much about how hard those steps
were. If we were to find other life out there in the universe that had gone independently
down this path, that would be big information about how hard the steps were. So if we found
some other life out there, say that was just primitive life that didn't share an origin with
us, well, that would be big news about how hard that first step was. And it would suggest it's
easier than we might have feared. So paradoxically, any evidence we see of independent life out there
in the universe that's gone anywhere along the path to where we are is bad news about our future.
If we discover any sort of life out there, that's bad news for us. Because it would suggest that
maybe these earlier steps aren't as hard as we thought. And therefore, the later steps we still
have to go are harder than we thought. So that's all the great filter stuff. We were talking about
the work I did with some other people that's in the last two and a half years. Yes, like the
that's what work we call grabby aliens. Right. And that's basically giving numerical estimates
for the great filter. Right. Telling you just how big it is. And therefore saying more specifically
the distribution of aliens in space time. And we claim that we kind of have the answer to that.
So what are grabby aliens? So there's two kinds of aliens in the universe, the kinds you can see and
the kinds you can't. So we just postulate there are some kinds of aliens that would just be pretty
obvious. That is, they started somewhere, but then they expanded and kept expanding. And in the volume
they expanded to do, they changed things. They did stuff. We don't know exactly what they'll do, but
just like humans and life on Earth has changed stuff for it, wherever it goes, they would change
stuff. And if they do that to a big enough volume, they would be noticeable. And so we can think about
what our data says about the obvious ones in a much easier way than we can about the other kind,
the quiet ones. So we can come back to the quiet ones, but we're first going to focus on the big
obvious ones. And the key point is we don't actually see them, right? They would be big and
obvious and we don't see them. But if we think carefully, we can figure out a lot about what that
implies. You might not realize that it says a lot that we can't see them. So what we have is a
three parameter model of where aliens are in space time. And each of the parameters can be fit to data
and then you kind of need to believe this model to explain why we're so early in time,
which is one of the key data points, our current date. And so, you know, I'm happy to walk through
if you want. Yes, absolutely. Each of these parameters. Austin, you should be able to pull
up some sort of graphics that represent this concept and the study. Yeah, let's go through that.
We are here at 14 billion years into the history of the universe.
That sounds late. 14 million years seems like a long time, but it's actually pretty early.
The average star will last for five trillion years. Now, the peak of star formation in the
history of the universe is like a four billion years after the initial. So we're well past the
peak of star formation, but most stars will last for trillions of years. And so we are early in
terms of when most stars will exist. And we have a simple theory of when advanced life should appear
that says that the most likely time for advanced life to appear would be much later in the history
of these stars. So I've told you about how life on earth had to go through a number of difficult
steps. Yes. And that earth is probably lucky in having gone through all of those steps in an
unusually short time. That is most planets out there never get to our point before that planet
ends. Right. Certainly by now in history of the universe. So that suggests that it's just hard
to do each of these steps. And perhaps each of the steps just has a crazy long expected time,
but that our planet got lucky. So an analogy is cancer in your body. You have many billions of
cells and to produce cancer, a cell needs to go undergo like six different mutations
in that same cell in the entire history of your life. Now, these mutations are so unlikely that
most of your cells never have any of these mutations and only a few have a couple of them.
But by the end of your life, typically one of them will get all six mutations.
And that's analogous to all these planets in the universe who need to go through a bunch of steps
to produce advanced life. And most of them never even get to the first step and hardly any of them
get to, you know, four steps. And maybe our life got through all six steps to get to where we are
before the deadline of life closing on planet Earth. So that's like a cell in your body getting
cancer before the deadline of your lifespan ending. In other words, planet Earth has developed
malignant cancer. Right. Although this cancer is great. Depends on how you look at it. Sure.
But I'm going to take that stand. This life is great. But so what we know is that the
chance of you getting cancer as a function of time goes as a power law in time where the power is
the number of these mutations that have to happen. So typically around six. Okay. So you are far more
likely to get cancer near the end of your life than the beginning. It's not constant in time.
The chance just increases dramatically toward the end of your life. It goes as this power law of the
power of sixth of time because there's roughly six mutations. Okay. So similarly for planets,
if advanced life like us is going to appear on a planet like Earth, it's not equally likely to
appear at any moment in the history of that planet. It's far more likely to happen near the end of
that planet's life. And it actually seems like there's roughly six hard steps that need to
happen on a planet like Earth for us to produce life at our level as well. So that means
over time, the chance of advanced life increases with time. Right. Now,
now, but longer lived planets, they've got a lot more time for all these hard steps to go in.
And so the actual chance of life appearing on a longer lived planet also increases by this power
of six. So we are a planet with say five billion years long life and say the typical planet out
there will have five trillion years of life. That's a factor of a thousand more. And if there's six of
these steps, the chance that life would appear on one of those planets till the end of its life
compared to our planet at the end of our life is a thousand to the power of six or 10 to the 18.
That is, it's crazy unlikely for life to appear on a planet like ours so early in the universe
compared to on a longer lived planet later in the universe. So there's something wrong
with this analysis because our analysis is saying we are just crazy early. Sorry, pull that thing
just a little bit closer to you. You can adjust. You can pull it like this. Pull it closer. There
you go. So we're just crazy early compared to when we should expect life to appear. But the key
assumption we made of this analysis is that the universe would just sit empty and wait
until we appeared. And that's the assumption we're saying is wrong. So what's actually happening is
life is popping up and appearing in various places in the universe, advanced life. And then
sometime it becomes grabby. It becomes visible. And when it becomes grabby, it expands at some speed.
And then these civilizations appearing at different time expand. And then they're expanding
waves eventually meet each other. And then at that point, the universe is full of grabby aliens. And
then it's too late after that for life like us to appear. So there's a deadline in the history of
the universe. First, the universe starts out empty and then advanced life starts to appear.
And then it expands and then fills everything up. And then too late. You can't appear anymore. And
that's the explanation for why we are here so early in the history of the universe. We are now
at a period where the universe is filling up with aliens. And in a billion years or two, it'll be
all full. And we couldn't appear five trillion years in the future because it will have long
since been full then. So we are just extremely early compared to other solar systems and other.
We're extremely early compared to when we would have appeared had the universe just
waited empty for us. The universe is not waiting empty for us is the key point. There's a deadline
and that's why we're appearing so early. So that's the first thing to say is this is why you need to
believe in this theory is that we are crazy early otherwise. You have to believe there are
aliens out there and they are filling up the universe right now. And in fact right now roughly
half the volume of the universe is full of alien civilizations that we can't see. And in another
few billion years it'll just all be full. And we have we may well soon join them i.e. going out
and expanding and becoming a gravity alien civilization. So this model of aliens appearing
has three key parameters. First we're going to assume they just appear at random places in space
on the large scale of the universe. The universe is pretty similar. They just appear in a random
galaxy say. And then they expand at some speed after they appear. So that's one of the parameters.
How fast do they expand? And then the other two parameters are when they appear in time. So I
told you there's a power law that is the number of hard steps makes them appear later in time
more rapidly according to a power law. So a power law has two parameters. It has the power and has
a constant. And so these are the three parameters that we can fit to data. So the power comes from
the history of life on earth. That is the timing of when life appeared on earth and how much time
we seem to have left from now include. And other data we have suggests there's roughly six hard
steps on earth therefore a power of six roughly somewhere between three and twelve or something.
But roughly a power of six. The constant of the power law comes from our current date
because we are a random sample of when a advanced civilization appears. That is we're not advanced
enough to become gravity yet but if we do so it'll be within a million years or so. So a million
years which is relative short time on the on the scale of 14 billion years. So relatively short time
from now we will either become gravity or not but that makes our data random sample from when
these things happen. So that gives us the constant in front of the power law. So we have the constant
in front of the power law. We have the power of the power law and all we need is the speed of expansion
and then we've got the whole model. So how can we get the speed of expansion? Well if you run this
model and simulate it you find that when civilizations are born and they look in the universe we ask can
they see other civilizations in the universe? And what we find is if they expand slowly when
they're born and they look out they see lots of other civilizations. Huge you know spherical
volumes in the sky much bigger than the full moon full of aliens. Spherical volumes in the sky? Well
because they start at some point and they expand spherically away from there. Okay. And so you
would look in the sky and you basically see vast spheres of alien civilizations if everybody grew
slowly. That's what the typical civilization would see. Okay. But if they grow very fast
most of them won't see any others when they're born because they don't see them until they're
almost there. Because there's a selection effect you you couldn't appear within the volume of a
different alien civilization because they would preclude you. That is if they had born and using
the volume you would no longer be able to evolve there. At least if they so chose. So the fact that
we don't see any aliens in our sky is the evidence that they must be expanding at a very fast speed.
Say roughly half the speed of light or even faster. Which is extremely fast. What explains why we
wouldn't see them coming until they're actually here? Until they're nearly here but it might I
mean it might be millions of years before they're here you can see them but still
at a typical birth date you won't see them yet. Right. Okay. And now what is this what is this
model? Explain. Austin is this there's no video? There's a video farther down. There you go. Yeah
that's the video. Following is a simulation of the grabby aliens model of alien civilizations.
Civilizations are born and then expand outward at a constant speed. A spherical region of space
is shown. By the time we get to 13.8 billion years this sphere will be. So this is you know a random
place in space civilizations appear they grow and then they meet each other and then eventually the
volume is full. And so you up the upper right hand corner you can see the date of the simulation so
we're past our current date now. Okay. And it's showing that the universe is expanding and it
counts how many of them. We're just gonna see the same thing again but now we can see through the
volumes maybe see more what's going on. So you can see up on the upper right we're before today at
the moment the universe is expanding. We show how many civilizations there are. There's there's
roughly you know four times ten to the eight galaxies in this volume so it's a very large
region of space and then it's all full. So that's the idea. Okay. So it's a relatively simple model.
Things just appear at random times and then they expand at a certain same speed but the time at
which they appear goes as this power law. That's the key thing here right. Right. At the beginning
hardly anything was happening and later till the end everything was just going. Everything goes crazy.
Right. Okay. What now what makes a civilization grabby? So the definition of grabby is that
it expands and changes the appearance of the volume it's in so that you wouldn't you would
notice it. That's the key idea. Now we could ask why would that happen and you know in some sense
you could just imagine it's like life on earth just once there's some competition of different
parts trying to colonize things eventually it all gets colonized. We will in our future perhaps
face a choice to become grabby or not and that may illuminate better the issues involved.
So if you just imagine technology just arbitrarily getting improved then eventually people could leave
here and go places and eventually they would then you know compete to grab things and when they grab
things they'd use them in some way and then they would change them and that would just be a naturally
way that they could become grabby. Of course they have to be capable enough to actually
do interstellar travel. Right. Which we are not yet but you know within a million years it seems
like we would. Yeah. So the simplest argument for being grabby is just to say if technology
and abilities just keep improving then eventually there'll be a point when interstellar travel is
possible and then it would be done and then people would move in different directions and then they'd
land somewhere and they'd colonize that and grow there and expand out. So just in the way you know
life expands across the earth when it's possible then it would life would expand through the
universe. Now of course you know there's that prerequisite you have to be advanced enough to
be able to do interstellar travel and then you have to not be dead at that point. Right. That's
important. And you have to allow it. So I actually think it's not clear what fraction of them will
allow. I think there may be in fact most civilizations don't allow it. That's a plausible possibility
but even so the universe is big enough that some of them will and so the grabby aliens model. So
the key idea is you start out as a quiet civilization and then eventually have the
choice to become loud. And there's this key question of the ratio between the quiet and
the loud. What fraction of quiet eventually give rise to allow? And that fraction matters for two
different things. One is our future. If say only one in a thousand quiet become loud then
until we know otherwise that's the best estimate for our choice was that only one in a thousand
chance we would become loud. And the ratio also matters for SETI the search for extra terrestrial
intelligence. This statistical model I was just telling you about we can fit each of these
parameters to data and I didn't tell you the actual final numbers which are roughly loud alien
civilizations appear roughly once per million galaxies. Okay. And right now is sort of the
middle of the distribution of when they appear and if we start to expand at the speed you know half
the speed of light like the rest of them are then we would meet them in roughly a billion years.
Okay. So that's the answers but those are the statistics for the loud ones. But if there are
a ratio of quiet to loud then the higher that ratio is the closer is the nearest quiet one.
Because we know the loud the nearest loud one is like once per million galaxies away.
Okay. But if say there was a million to one ratio of quiet to loud well now the nearest
quiet one might be in our galaxy. Whereas if it's only a 10 to 1 ratio you see the nearest one is
one in a hundred thousand galaxies away which is a long way away. Yes. It seems like if we were to
become that advanced and be able to achieve interstellar transportation it seems like we would
be based on what we are like now we would become a loud civilization because that's just human
nature now we expand we influence we grab things and the way economics are involved.
But there are contrary forces at play and so that's worth thinking through.
So as you know the world is pretty integrated at the moment. It's once upon a time empires were
separated across the globe and didn't interact very much distances were too far to communicate
or travel. But as we've made travel and communication easier the world has become
more integrated over the last century. Right. That integration has made an integrated economy
we trade across the globe and integrated society people meet and interact across the globe and
create communities across the globe and the size of nation and empires has also been increasing
over centuries. That is we now have things like the European Union large coordinations of nations
on large scales. Yeah. Now you know for a long time people have thought doesn't that mean we'll
have a world government soon. Won't we merge these into an even larger unit and people have
been concerned about that. Yes. And wary of that and so far we haven't. But what they haven't
noticed is that we have created something like a world mob or world community which we did not
have a century ago. So if you look at many different areas of regulation say nuclear power
or medical ethics or organ sales or electromagnetic spectrum or plane safety or things like that.
It turns out that the world does it pretty similar everywhere.
So we have a world community that talks to each other about these things and people want to be
respected in those world communities and there's some conformity pressures in those world communities
and those conformity pressures basically induce a pretty high level of convergence of regulation
all around the world. It was especially dramatic in Covid if you recall at the beginning of Covid
at the very beginning the usual health experts had their usual recommendations which were against
mass and against travel restrictions and then elites around the world talked about the subject
a lot and came to a different conclusion and then the whole world did it the different way.
That is almost everywhere people follow the new consensus about how to treat Covid which was
different than what the elite consensus had been a few months before because we just have this
large world community where people talk a lot and then they feel some social pressures to go along
with what everybody else thinks in the way that most communities do but now we have a world level
community. We have world level communities of many kinds of topics especially with regulation
and other sorts of business practices where we have a whole world where we do things together
in that way and I think a lot of people like that. That is instead of having a world a lot of
first world people like yes right instead of a world at war and in conflict around the world we
have a world where we have a lot more peace because we talk things out and decide together
rather than fighting and competing them out and that's been going on for the last century and
I think we have to predict that will continue and so the obvious prediction is that we will have
even stronger world communities that limit variation even more in the future. We may have
a stronger world government we may not but we will have the stronger world community
and we will correctly credit it and maybe incorrectly also for many advances like
dealing with global warming or dealing with inequality or dealing with overfishing.
That is these world communities have been trying to tackle those sorts of problems
and they have often had success so I think over the coming centuries we will have a more strongly
integrated world community that likes the fact that they can talk together and decide what to do
and in fact prevent destructive competition that they don't like i.e making the regulations
everywhere in the world the same including preventing war and that's the near-term future
that we should expect given recent trends but now project that forward and imagine the point in time
a few centuries from now when interstellar travel becomes possible and imagine the choice to allow
that. People will know that as soon as they allow an interstellar colony to leave earth and go off
to another star that will be the end of this era when we could all talk and decide together and
exert enough social pressure to make sure we all do it together the same way. Once you send those
colonies out they are beyond your control for to regulate you cannot stop their competition
and you cannot stop their evolution they will evolve and become strange things so one of the
things I think over the next few centuries people will like is that they will prevent evolution they
will prevent our descendants from changing to become strange descended creatures. Wait wait wait
explain that again that last part how would they why would they want to stop evolution
why would they want to stop us from evolving so you're saying they would want to stop us
from becoming different? Yes so we've I mean as a futurist there have been many conversations over
the last few decades about the possibility of say genetic engineering or other sorts of changes
to people including artificial intelligence and a consistent theme is a fear even horror of the
changes that might happen and the ways that our descendants might be weird. People have been
pretty against allowing substantial genetic engineering to make our descendants genetically
different they are wary of allowing AI descendants to be mentally different
and they are often just wary of say population competition that is people have often been
worried about over worried about overpopulation and one of the fears they've had is that even
if most places limit their population the few places that don't eventually dominate the
population and so people have wanted to and talked about having regulation of fertility
to prevent overpopulation which is competition by population size. Okay so all of these themes
together are showing a wariness of allowing evolution of allowing our descendants to become
different from us that is we are human in a certain way and we like being human and we are wary that
our descendants might just not be very human they could have very different mental styles that are
in conflict with ours right and that scares people but when we have this world community
they will just stop those things that they don't like right just like today they would we have
like basically stopped nuclear power of the sort that scared people. So are you saying if we did
become a well integrated world community or if there was a one world governance somehow that
we would decide not to become interplanetary or interstellar? The key choice at that point would be
to continue to have a unified community world community now by world I mean the whole solar
system so within a few centuries right they would be spread across the solar system but still the
solar system small enough to allow this centralization and coordination. Our solar system so if we had
communities on mars right all these planets we would still be able to control it within the sun
right and anything right anything in the solar system you can throw a rock and smash it if you
misbehave okay okay basically yeah wow so so the solar system is still small enough to be within
the reach of central you know control okay so if we continue to enjoy this world community by which
where we have reduced war and conflict and harmful competition and you know things we are scared of
like genetic engineering or nuclear power or whatever by having this global community that
agrees on what things to stop and then at one point we have the choice to send out an interstellar
colony and we know the consequences of that that will be a hard choice I predict that is the
consequence of allowing interstellar colony is that we no longer regulate
behavior out there we'd be just letting go they would allow to do whatever they want they were
allowed to change however they want to adopt technologies however they want and then they
could come back here and destroy and test us test here control air right whatever they develop out
there whatever advances they produce out there they can come back here wow and the question is
would we then allow that so I can see it going either way but the point is I can see it going
either way right it's not a crazy thing for people to want to do to enjoy to continue their community
that they understand like versus allowing strange evolution and competition and perhaps fierce
unchecked competition right so the idea of panspermia is that a rock came here a long
time ago containing genetic material from somewhere else in the universe and then we
derived from that I've heard you explain even in more depth the idea that when the universe was
created the same life forms or biology that was on one rock expanded into everywhere so that the
idea is if there are aliens out there that are expanding or not that they all came from the same
source so the motivation here is that the simple grabby aliens model we just described again has
the nearest aliens being a million galaxies away right once per million galaxies so it has
almost no prospect of any aliens nearby under that simple model
but you might ask well but couldn't there be aliens closer than that might that not make sense
and you could ask me try to come up with the story where that makes sense and then I realize I can
as the simple model has things appearing independently randomly and independently
but what if they appear in a correlated way what if clumps appear appear together
together that would then allow the nearest aliens to us to be much closer even if on average aliens
appear only once per million galaxies if we're here and they're correlated then they could be here
too so the question is what sort of correlation process could there be that would make aliens
appear together in clumps rather than appear independently around the universe and panspermia
is a process that could create that correlation that's why panspermia is interesting in this
context is it would allow there to be aliens much closer than they would otherwise be
so the panspermia story would be that life appeared somewhere on another planet not earth
and then that actually allows life to have had a much longer time to evolve so
if you actually look at the earliest life we can see on earth it looks really complicated
making it hard to believe that evolution could have produced that complexity in such a short time
so postulating an eden another planet before earth gives a much longer time scale for
much simpler life to have slowly gotten more complicated on eden and then maybe the life we
see on the beginning of earth is like halfway down the whole path so it jumped jumped to another
place to evolve right so it wouldn't do it on purpose of course but as you know rocks are
falling from the sky all the time and when rocks hit the ground they often knock rocks from the
ground back up into the sky right and inside those rocks is often life so that's the obvious
route by which life could move around in the universe is in rocks now at the beginning of
our solar system when the solar system started was born in a nursery where say a thousand other
stars were all being born in the same place at the same time and at the beginning of our solar
system there were lots of rocks flying back and forth you know enormous numbers of rocks flying
back and forth in that early solar system so if a rock came from outside that nursery
into that nursery it would have plenty of opportunity not only to land places but to get
you know smashed and knocked around and spread around so it would be plausible that life that
seeded earth at that early point of time in our stellar nursery would have also seeded many other
planets in that nursery at the same time so now we would have the scenario life appeared on some
eden many billions of years ago maybe lasted five billion years there then a rock you know hit that
flu maybe maybe that rock drift drifted for millions of years actually um and then eventually
landed in our stellar nursery where it seeded not just earth but many other planets and then
that makes the correlation so these stellar nursery only lasts for you know a few million
years and then it drifts apart these planets that were all born together drift away and they
basically form a ring around the galaxy right and we can actually find them in the sky that is they
all have the same mixture of chemicals because the stellar nursery was an integrated mixture
of chemicals so they just all have the same proportion of chemicals that you can see in
a stellar spectrum so we can actually find them in the sky find our stellar siblings
and they could find us so if life started on a whole bunch of planets
that was seeded in this nursery then over the last four billion years they would have all been
trying to advance and evolve and if the advancement of life from that stage wasn't
terribly hard then it might be that other planets also went a long way down that path
and that one of them might have reached our level before us
and then there could be aliens nearby this would be the best explanation for like the modern ufos
that we see today right right if you're trying to if you're trying to ask how could ufos be
aliens how could that make any sense at all then this is the best story i can come up with
because remember otherwise if they're you know once per million galaxies they're just crazy far
away and you know they would just be very unlikely for them to be anywhere near here this puts them
close now but we can go farther in trying to come up with a scenario to explain say ufos
by thinking more about the scenario i just described so if another alien civilization
appeared as a panspermia sibling there's another thing that we know about it which is that it did
not get grabby right right because otherwise our galaxy would be full of them right right
so we also know the timing would be they would have appeared say roughly a hundred million years
ago would be sort of a random time not not in the last thousand years of a hundred million years
would be roughly when they would have appeared so the scenario would be they appeared a hundred
million years ago somewhere in our galaxy and then in that hundred million years they did not
colonize the galaxy they did not expand and things so they must be one of these civilizations that
chose not to expand they chose to prevent it and succeeded at that so you have to realize that's
actually a pretty impressive achievement they're a big civilization and if any one part of them
ever left with an interstellar colony that's the end the era of this unified thing ends and
competition returns so for a hundred million years they managed to stop that
right now couldn't an explanation for if there are aliens here if these ufos are aliens
couldn't they just be sort of like hall monitors or security guards making sure that
we could just list a large number of logical possibilities but it seems more useful to walk
through what we do know about them and then collect those implications because we we we can
draw some conclusions from the things we do know to limit the space of theories right so one thing
we know is they did not colonize the universe right therefore they had a rule that they
successfully enforced for a hundred million years against that in their civilization
so that's the thing we know about them right we know how old they are and we know they've
chosen not to allow expansion and then we know that they could find us that they could easily
see where their panspermia siblings were and they could look at them in telescopes and track them
so they could have been tracking us all that time and we know that they would know that
we threaten to break their rule they've had this rule against expansion and we don't
haven't been told about the rule and we with if they did nothing we might well break their rule
and then the thing they were trying to prevent would happen right the universe gets colonized
nearby by something else so that creates a plausible motive for them to be here right
so i mean the keith question is like if they've had this rule against expansion that's probably
a rule against a lot of travel too right they probably prevented people from traveling very
far from their home be a risk because every traveler becomes a risk to create this interstellar
explosion right so now now we have a reason why they would want to be here and take a chance
an unusual chance to actually allow someone to come here because this is a high priority like
we are at risk of breaking their rule a rule that kept success for for 100 million years
and a rule that's obviously very important to them because you know they've paid large costs
to to keep it right so so already we can see that they have chose we have a reason why they
would be here and why they wouldn't be other everywhere else those are the key things we're
trying to explain right and we could another thing we conclude is they didn't just kill us
that would have been really possible right so they must feel some affiliation some reluctance
to just kill us so they have some other plan to prevent us from expanding other than just killing
us right which goes against well didn't Stephen Hawking have a famous quote on this subject
about another civilization coming here he said if it did come here it would be the end of us they
would come they would use farm us or they would consume us or something like that are you aware
of right right but it's certainly if you just took random past you know connect places when
humans met each other in the past as your data set you might well say yes those don't usually
go well right so which is fine but but we know more things here you see so so we we aren't just
making an analogy to a random path earth thing we are drawing step by step conclusions from the
things we know that is you know we know that they would be a panspermia sibling therefore
they would be even though they're near here the nearest other alien could be a million galaxies
way right right so they're near here but hardly anything else is right so it's not a galaxy
populated full of alien civilizations it's just them and us and maybe one other or something
like that that would all be all there is do you how deep do you i know you're very uh science
based analytical cold calculated person um when it comes to this stuff but how how much attention
do you pay how much attention do you pay to the stories of like interactions with other beings
that are accounted for i mean there's books and movies and documentaries about this kind of stuff
how much tend like ufos and nukes being around nuclear weapons weapons shutting them down
there's a store famous story of a ufo landing in africa in front of a school and communicating
with children telepathically about the environment and taking the dangers of technology what do you
make of those stories and how much how much credibility do you give them so this entire
topic is in disrepute in general among elites elite academics and elites of all sorts
so if i'm going to venture into this subject i want to do it very carefully so that my thoughts
won't be wasted if i am sloppy about this then i will be tainted with the same disrepute that
everybody else has been who touches the subject right so i'm i'm very eager to be methodical
and careful here and exactly how i do this right so um that means i want to sort of logically lay
out the space of possibilities and then lay out sort of the general inference task and then place
myself somewhere in that set of tasks and say which things i'm doing which things i'm not
i'm not going to present myself an expert on all the tasks that are relevant we're thinking about
this topic but i will venture into some of them and say for some of them i have relevant expertise
and i will speak to those okay so first of all we just say look there are things people think
they see right and they have to have some explanation and we can categorize the kind
of explanations they could be right so for example they could be aliens sure or they could be just
some other hidden earth organization who has capabilities beyond what they've advertised
um or it could all just be mistakes and delusions drunk drunkards and blowhards and you know people
trying to get attention right or there could be some organized hoax behind it all somebody's like
planning and purposely may having people lie and putting things up there that look like things and
just trying on purpose to write us think of something right right those are the four main
categories of explanation right and we're interested in judging which is the truth
so in general what we want is what's called a Bayesian analysis here that is we for each of
these categories of explanation we want what's called a likelihood and we want a prior a prior
is what's the chance of that scenario ignoring all this evidence just a priority what would be
the chance you would think of something like this happening and the likelihood is given that this
theory was true how likely is it that you'd see the sort of things you'd see that's and then you
basically once you have a likelihood and a prior for each of these then you multiply those two and
you do a weighted average and you get your posterior i see which theory you believe so
that's our task we need likelihoods and we need priors okay um so i am more of an expert on the
priors that is the likelihoods have to involve looking at these cases in particular in some
detail right because we're talking about how likely is it that these theories would account for
the particular things people see whereas the prior is just about what kind of things could have
happened in the universe what kind of things do ever happen you know that's and so my expertise
as someone who's done physics and astrophysics and economics etc puts me at i can speak to the
prior at least at least for some of these and less so to the likelihoods now i'll just say
i've looked at enough you know ufo reports to say it's more compelling than the data i can find for
fairies and ghosts i go look up online what's the best evidence for fairies and ghosts and
they don't impress me very much right by comparison okay i can also say in the past
there were things that were equally just similarly disreputed to ufos that in fact
turned out to be true so once asteroids people thought rocks falling from the sky was crazy
ball lightning is something people thought was pretty crazy except they made it in the lab and
they decided it must be true even though the actual like evidence of it outside the lab still
looks pretty weak but they made it in the lab so they figured okay i guess that must be true
and then there were these very high level lightning pink lightning that looks kind of like an octopus
that people said they saw a long time the first pilot said they saw and people thought that was
crazy and then a couple decades ago nasa took pictures they said oh like okay i guess it's real
so that would be my context is to say like just because this is in disrepute doesn't mean
it couldn't be because we've often thought things were crazy and then changed our mind about them
so and that um you know the actual evidence i can see i think again it's it's better than
ghosts and fairies okay okay but how much better is what you need an expert to go into those details
for but what i do want to say is the prior is high enough that you should be taking the data
seriously so think about a murder trial okay okay in a murder trial they claim a murdered b
right now if the prior on that was crazy low you would just say no that's crazy i'm not even going
to think about that right so how low is the prior in a murder trial well let's say roughly on average
one out of a thousand people's killed and they might have a thousand other people nearby who
could plausibly be the one who did it okay so i'd say the prior is roughly one in a million
for any given murder accusation okay so a one in a million prior is something that evidence can
typically overcome that's not so crazy unlikely it's not like one in a quadrillion prior where
you'd say you know go away that's silly it's high enough that you got to take it seriously
so my rough guess for the ufos is aliens prior is roughly one in a thousand now that's quite a bit
stronger than typical murder trial which means you got to look at the evidence you can't just
dismiss it just like you would in a murder trial right now if you have an accusation in a murder
trial you don't stop there you don't just say okay you accused and so they're guilty right you have
to look at the evidence right yes and so similarly here just because this is in the realm of high
enough plausible probability that it could be true doesn't make it true it just means you got to look
at the evidence so i could walk through my calculation for one in a thousand prior but i
might also just mention one of the other categories i think has an even higher prior
which is the hoax category that is the u.s government and other governments have at times
organized big hoaxes of capabilities of the sort and um i would give that a one percent chance
that's still like 99 chance no right but i'd still say that's the sort of thing that does happen at
times and so you got to take that seriously as well as a possible explanation and then again
it comes down to looking at the data like how plausible is it that you know they could pull
it off for the particular things we see i'm not very impressed with these delusion you know
mistakes theory that seems to me it's hard it's just harder to to account for all these stories
as all delusions and mistakes something more systematic would seem to be going on i would
judge but again to several other candidates what do you think the the probability is that
that there are private organizations aerospace organizations companies um that hold information
knowledge or technology that they are withholding from the public or academia that could explain
some of these anti-gravity sightings so i mean if you combine a theory of saying there really are
aliens and then some people really got that technology now you're you're you're basically
combining the two of these theory categories right if you just want to say there are advanced
organizations out there that have advanced technology they didn't get it from aliens they
just made it up themselves then then it's hard to understand how they could be much more advanced
than everybody else because we know a lot about technology and how it advances in the world and
how you know it happens by diffusion and people hearing of other things so we just almost never
see enormous advances by some sides compared to others right it's usually within a range of the
kinds of things we expect so um the kinds of abilities reported for ufos do seem to me
substantially beyond the sort of things you might expect at least you know for several decades ago
now more recently there's this technology whereby you might say send a laser to some place in space
in the sky in the atmosphere and say heat it up and then make a little plasma there and then like
be able to draw that and then basically like on tv screen draw a image in space and then move it
around and you could move an image that you drew around very quickly so that seems to be an ability
that's near feasible now that could explain ufos but that wouldn't explain ufos seen in 1960 or
something right that would have to only be explaining very recent ufos because that's a very
recent capability that apparently people have now is the ability to draw like a laser pointer
right basically but except it doesn't go against a wall that stops a place in space and draws
something there right um that's exactly how some of these pilots have been describing the things
that they've been seeing like commander graver and ryan graves so from from very recent observations
that becomes a more plausible story but not for more ancient observations aerospace organization
similar to lockheed martin containing some sort of technology that could explain this stuff
would have to be directly it would have to be because they discovered some sort of alien
technology it wouldn't be something that was just created here if it was far more advanced than
the stuff that everybody else has which it is right i mean i i mean i don't know if it's true
if it is true it would it is clearly way more advanced than the kind of propulsion that we
have so i didn't finish describing the most plausible scenario so there's another thing
we know about ufos that you would need to explain to explain ufos as aliens
it's a crucial thing many people have noted which is they could have either been completely
invisible or completely visible those were i mean 100 100 million you know year more advanced
civilization than ours they could have just been completely dark orbiting and seeing everything
without being at all visible or they could have just shown up on the white house lawn as they say
and just been completely visible so apparently they are not doing either of those things
so we need an explanation for why they're doing this weird thing of hanging out at the edge of
visibility to sort of make themselves be somewhat visible but not more visible that's weird so
you know if i weren't trying to explain that part i might give a higher prior
to ufos as aliens but i need to explain that part too because again the the other weird
thing about aliens is like why aren't they in the rest of the universe right why didn't they
take over the galaxy why are they only here nowhere else that's the first thing to explain
and so we postulated for that that they have this rule against expansion and then that's why
they're here but then we also need to explain why are they hanging out at the edge of visibility
not making themselves aware to everybody right but also not completely hiding exactly right why
be partially visible what's the point right because they clearly could have chosen anything
else if they wanted um so we want to explain that and we want to do that in the context of
what we know of their motives to be here right right they're here to convince us
not to expand without killing us right because they could have killed us those are the other
things we know so they somehow are going to use this method of hanging out the edge of our
visibility to convince us not to expand and not kill us that's that's the purpose of this so how
does that work so the thing i notice is that humans have domesticated other animals primarily
by being the top of their pecking order if we make dogs do what we want it's because we are the top
dog okay we go into a pack of animals and we convince them we are in their status hierarchy
and we are at the top and that's how they do what we say that's how we domesticate other animals and
it's how we domesticate ourselves that is all through histories emperors have convinced people
to obey the emperor because they showed they were the top person in the society they had a big crown
and a big palace and a big army right and they displayed themselves as the top of the pecking
order to convince others to go along right so the hypothesis is that's what the aliens want to do
here they want to be the top of our pecking order how do they do that they show that they are better
than us they show very impressive abilities but not violent confrontation with us they are they are
they are not hurting us but they are better than us just like you can't really make a bunch of dogs
obey you if you kill half of them right okay you have to be in their tribe but they're not being
like benefit threatening right not threatening but better better clearly better right right
and we should be smart enough to figure out why they're here and what their agenda is they don't
even have to say anything they just have to show themselves as very impressive better creatures
nearby now you might think well yeah but why don't they show a little more what's the harm
in that well why would it be a problem if they were to give us a little more detail and then
you realize well think of how much humans have hated other humans for pretty minor differences
between human civilizations right right right humans are pretty similar to each other nevertheless
we find these reasons to hate each other based on what to an alien must seem like a pretty minor
difference right so they would know that they would know that if they showed us details of their
lives and history something about it could really put us off right maybe they eat babies they don't
think that's a problem but we hate eating these maybe they have tentacles we hate tentacles some
who knows right right point is they don't want to take that chance so they're just gonna not
ever show us much detail about us about them but just clearly show they exist and that they are
much more capable than us and that they're peaceful that's it that's all they have to do
and that's a very simple strategy they could have approved from the beginning so remember
another constraint in this whole process is they're scared of any expedition getting out of control
and you know ending their era of no interstellar colonization right so when they authorize this one
expedition not only do they only authorize it but they have to ask how are we going to keep control
of it how do we limit its behavior how do we make sure it only does the thing we want it to do
so they have they would want to pick a very clear strategy a simple strategy that they could
authorize it to do and only do not be creative and come up with a bunch of new ideas when it got here
they don't that's taking too many chances right they want to say let's have a plan they're going
to go there execute the plan that's all they're going to be authorized to do that's all they're
going to be capable of doing hopefully and then we are taking the minimal risk with this expedition
out there to to you know go convince these people not to expand right and so you have to think what
would be a plan they could think of ahead of time without knowing much about us like they can't wait
till i get here and like learn a lot and then make a plan based on that because that would give too
much discretion to the local team they say from a distance what we could what can we know that will
make a plan that they could execute it seems it's interesting though like if you look just in the
last 150 to 60 years how the stigma of the subject has become less and less it's still pretty high
it's it's but now that the government is talking about it and the new york times is talking about
it still pretty high that mean if you talk to other intellectuals i think you'll find
doctor professors of various sorts right astrophysicists you know let's talk to
just all sorts of prestigious people i still think you think that stigma is still pretty high
where does it go if it keeps going on this trajectory of less and less stigma more people
entertaining this conversation that you and i are having right now right and the world everyone
every a larger percentage of human beings on earth being aware of this idea and being
understanding it what how does that affect us if say the u.s government's new willing to flirt
with the idea produced more concrete evidence that then persuaded other people that would make
a big switch but if all they do is just release the sort of thing they've released so far
and they don't release anything more that's more persuasive i don't think it'll tip the balance
for a long time i mean it's basically just going to be the slow accumulation of more and more solid
evidence that tips the balance because people are just not that willing to accept this so that's
but it'll just take a long time but of course that's fine from the under this theory that's
fine for the aliens they're not in a rush we're no long we're nowhere near threatening to do
a learning style colonization yet and what would human beings do if they did discover it like if
a small group of human beings discovered this somehow well i mean many people claim they already
have right yeah problem exactly small groups discover but they can't convince the rest of
people yet right would they even want to convince them some do some don't but where would they want
to just find some economic benefit for it and try to find some leverage of competition between
nations or between it's hard to see much benefit here i mean the whole point is like look they're
not like handing out christmas goodies or something yeah but like they're just off in the
distance being impressive right but i'm saying like if we did if if we did find evidence of this
like like the story of bob lazar is the most famous one of i'm i'm i'm sure right yeah sure
yeah where he just claims he worked on back engineering these anti-gravity crafts and the
government had has been has been working on it for decades but we haven't been able to figure it out
and we want to use this as sort of leverage against other nations for weapons and war so again
there's this vast space of possibilities but i have to sort of stay anchored on the possibilities
that make sense right i understand i can make sense of so in the simple theory the the aliens
are just here to impress us and like convince us they exist and that we should do what they say
under that simple theory they don't have any particular reason to hand out goodies to some
people or to like reveal our their technology to us yeah it seems kind of crazy that they would
just accidentally crash their vehicle and leave it behind i mean again 100 million years more
advanced it's like and so so we can be able to capture and similarly i gotta say abductions
still don't make that much sense in this story right what they need to do is just be visibly
impressive why they would need to pick some people up and like study them personal experience yeah
there would be no need for that again 100 million more advanced they could study us just fine from
orbit they don't need they wouldn't need to physically pick us up and poke us no exactly
no that that would be crazy that they would a very primitive civilization would need to do that
really so if they had that if they had the technology to to traverse so light years to
get here they they would let's talk about what we can roughly guess about very advanced civilizations
actually so the first thing we should be able to guess about very advanced civilizations is they
are just artificial like they are made in factories they're designed you know they
can swap their parts out you know just like we make artificial cars instead of growing horses
right they are just artificial creatures that that and they are their minds are even artificially
designed like and you know there's a new product line that comes out from some source and they're
all the same in the product line and then they have some they just the modern economy where you
make things in factories and you have firms that make them at scale and distribute them that's the
kind of way they're made in the kind of way they run everything basically so they aren't you know
made they don't reproduce with cell mitosis or whatever the way right they found a much more
effective way surely that's how they would be so there was long since become artificially so
they've long since like been able to be any physical form they want to it's not like they
have a certain shape body that they have to fit into a craft or something right they can
they could move into any kind of body they want to make right just like on a construction side
we make different kinds of trucks and different kinds of shovels or whatever it's not like the
nature of a construction worker to have a certain kind of shovel it's like you have a bunch of
different things for whatever purpose you want to make make them right so there's not going to be
the size of the aliens right or or even their lifespan or how many eyes they have none of that
makes sense they are artificial creatures who can have as many eyes as they want to in any given
circumstance and they can add eyes and take them away just fine right just like we can add a
headlight to a car so that's one thing i think we can say robustly about aliens is that they are
artificial the other thing we might want to say depends on how much they've controlled
their competition so you know they prevent interstellar colonization and they probably
prevent some other kinds of evolution but how much evolution do they prevent how how restrictive are
they about their evolution so i think we can imagine two extremes one extreme is they are
minimally restrictive like they prevent people from leaving their solar system but
most everything else inside their solar system they just allow relatively free evolution and
competition right all they do is just prevent stuff from leaving right under that scenario we
should expect evolutions to continue and then we can ask what do we expect evolution to produce
in the long run for various features of creatures the opposite extreme is where they have a very
restrictive very centrally controlling society that has prevented and most competition and
evolution under that other extreme their technology may have stagnated at some point
when they could no longer if you know innovate more because they were being so restrictive
and even worse their society might have come to rot rotting is a feature that we see consistently
in large complicated systems that humans have built and even observed and rotting is the sort
of thing that central control risks and it becomes a big issue for a long-term civilization that
has maintained central control for a long time um i think most people don't know enough about
rotting can you give me an example of rotting in today's our world so i'll send hold on austin can
you turn the air down it's getting hot in here
sorry nope don't pause while he does that or uh you know we can keep going it's okay
unless you want to take a bathroom break i'm fine okay cool so most
large software systems are these not tiny systems rot think of the apple operating system or google
operating system or the system that runs any large bank or anything like that large software
systems over time become harder to usefully change they become more fragile and eventually
they are thrown away and replaced with brand new systems this is the consistent software practice
at enormous cost if you think of any big company most large companies have a big software system
somewhere in their process that they developed and it's a big part of their value that they have
compared to their competitors and all of these large software systems rot with time and are
typically just thrown away entirely and started over from scratch this is because they're
overlooked because they're so large and complex they are looked at carefully but still the key
thing is the process of changing them makes them rot so if you have a large software system and
nothing changes then you never have to change anything it can just keep going but typically
you're trying to add features the environment that's in changes maybe the kind of hardware
it connects to changes and so slowly over time things are changing and you need to adapt it to
those changes customers may change customer preferences because things like firmware updates
right all sorts of changes but the key things you have a big complicated things and stuff is
changing so you constantly have to adapt the system to deal with these changes and the key
thing that happens is you have dependencies between different parts of the system so if you
if you if you don't have any dependencies then you'll just change one part of the system
and you don't have to change anything else but when you have to have dependencies when you change
one part you also have to change the other parts that are connected to it in a matching way
otherwise it's broken and the problem is when you take a system with two parts that are connected
to each other and that you change both parts to to manage something you tend to make that
those things more fragile that has become harder to change in the future this is sort of tied to
what we were talking about in the beginning of downloading books to the human brain right exactly
so in fact the human brain rots too not just the cells rot your mind rots in the sense that
you start out with what's called fluid intelligence and you end up with what's
called crystallized intelligence crystallized intelligence means you know many specific things
but you can't learn new general skills very easily not compared to when you were young and
had fluid intelligence so your mind over your lifetime becomes harder to usefully change
old dogs in fact find it hard to learn new tricks that's actually true about brains so human minds
rot with time just like software does and plausibly even large rule systems like legal systems or
systems of organizations they rot with time corporations rot that is most corporations
eventually die and are replaced by new ones even when they try to you know prevent that it
consistently happens right rot and the the only solution we've ever had as a robust solution to
rotting is dying and replacement right so human bodies rot and are replaced with new organisms
our minds rot and die are replaced our software has to be replaced our firms have to be replaced
and all at great expense we have make enormous investments in things that slowly rot and then
have to be thrown away now but so so far like that's been the nature of history but now we
are starting to create global structures that we don't want to replace at a global level
like these global communities and these global habits of regulation and so now we're entering
a new era what happens when the world as a whole coordinates on say how we regulate nuclear energy
we regulate nuclear energy and nobody is allowed to do it different and then that system
rots with time what will happen then will we be willing to throw it out at some later point
or we just deal with it slowly getting less efficient because like systems that rot typically
can function just at a lower efficiency like the old software was working it just got harder and
harder to change but you could just change it less and gain fewer advantages from changing if
you insisted on sticking with it the reason why we throw it away is because the new thing will be
cheaper and easier to change and we want to change things yeah but don't we just
install like now we have these firmware updates for everything for all these systems are constantly
being updated improving fixes that's part of the rot the firmware updates are part of the rot yes
absolutely they are changes that are trying to make other things fit each other okay the reason
why you have the firmware update is because something changed and this is the strategy
to do that but in the process what is becoming crystallized or hardened or or becoming i don't
understand so the key idea is that it's harder to usefully change so like the bits of the software
don't disappear right they stay there but still it gets harder to change them okay i mean i don't
know think of the marvel universe or something right the marvel universe is rotting in some
sense that like they keep making new assumptions and new characters but they are limited in how
many new things they can do because it has to be consistent with all the old things they've done
i understand slowly over time they will be more limited what they can do in the marvel universe
right um i mean it may still be a fun universe but it would be you know but eventually it will be
thrown away and replaced with other universes right right so what is this rot i forgot what
this was in context to so first it's a rot that say the aliens would suffer if they had a central
government that limited their changes and it's a rot that we may suffer in our future if we
you know have a strong central government or global mob that makes us all do everything
together the same but it's a very difficult choice because you know the alternative is
competition and therefore conflict and what do we do right so say think of nuclear power slow you
know apparently we could have had a vastly more powerful nuclear power industry than we did now
we were scared and we overregulated but now we kind of overregulated everywhere similar ways
similar degrees what if someplace wants to not be so heavy regulated nuclear power are other people
going to be scared of that will they allow it or will they just insist that everybody keep on with
the current program right to prevent the things they're worried about and that'll be true for
lots of different ways we're organized so the key thing to notice is up until recently the world has
competition at the highest level empires competed species competed right the fundamental thing that
happened was empires rose and fell and empires fell in substantial part because they rotted
but humanity could go on because humanity wasn't tied to any one empire
we were the thing that lasted past the empires but once humanity becomes tied to an empire
and then the empire starts to rot well then what happens then and that would be like a like a world
civilization right with being tied to with where we agree together to do things the same way and
collect more and more rules about such things and that begins to rot what happened the question is
what happens then yes are we willing to allow competition enough to drastically replace big
parts of such things or do we just slowly get less competent and less capable you've mentioned in the
past that uh you plan on doing something with your body after your physical being passes away
right so i am a cryonics customer cryonics yes holding this neck tag here up if you're not
watching and basically it says that if there's a medical emergency they should call this number
and the plan is then to freeze my brain in liquid nitrogen and once it's frozen it won't change
basically for centuries if they keep it frozen and then that would give me a chance to come back
as a brain emulation later if the world i describe in the age of m comes to pass so
um that's a chance i have at immortality i'd say another thing we can know about
you know advanced civilizations is they are immortal
but immortality doesn't necessarily mean what you think it does
the civilizations are immortal or and entities within them are in principle immortal that is
immortality is just another robust feature of advanced civilization meaning their consciousness
is immortal it's capable of being immortal that's the key distinction so today being immortal
today houses and cars are immortal in the sense that if you keep maintaining them and repairing
them they can go on indefinitely but we don't always choose to keep repairing and maintaining
them that is they over time become more expensive to maintain and the value goes down because new
things are more competitive or you know more capable compared to them so that will also happen
for our descendants who are immortal or aliens who are immortal that is in principle they could last
forever but it will cost to keep them going and their value may decline because new things are
just more capable where they are right so that would be an issue for me wanting to be immortal
that is they could bring me back in the future but will they and even if they do how long would
they keep me and so that's an issue i describe in my book the age of m about a world where
everything is in principle immortal but it's still a matter of choice right right what would be the
incentive to bring you back or to keep me back if i had been brought back temporarily right this kind
of is the same thing as why would aliens abduct human beings and poke them problem right to try
to say what's the point right because it's so out of date now i do expect that because there
are so few of us cryonics customers like only maybe 200 people have been frozen so far that's
it maybe you know 3000 people are signed up for it wow even though it's had free national publicity
for many for a half century so if unfortunately if it continues that very few people do this then
the few of us who are available later on would be celebrities of sorts and so they would almost
surely bring back the few of us however if what i prefer is like a large fraction of the earth's
population we're crying customers well now it's much more of a question how many of those billions
would be brought back if you're relying on the generosity of the future to help your future self
out you may be taking a needlessly large chance you know what we often do is protect ourselves in
the future that is when you retire you often retire on the basis of assets you've saved yourself
rather than throwing yourself on the mercy of your grandchildren or something right to help you when
you retire right so similarly i might think well the best thing would be for cryonics patients to
pay for their own revival to set aside assets that are available later to cover their own
case and this is not done it is often done yes oh it is often done yes oh wow who are the type
of people what type of people typically do this cryonics brain freezing so many friends that do
it well yes but it's a very small fraction as i told you there's only like 200 people have been
frozen so far and maybe 3000 people have signed up or something yeah so far that very tiny fraction
so basically first of all contrarians right country yeah obviously you have to be willing
to sort of put up with the social pressure that disapproves and do it anyway what um what is the
process like so they actually take your brain out of your skull and they put it in like a bag
or they freeze it in carbonite like uh what does this look like so the usual approach today
there's the there's the option of whole body where they would freeze your whole body or there's
their head only where they would just freeze your head and not freeze the body with all of this
yeah it was with everything so i mean the key thing is they're just trying to
get you cold fast without too much damage happening while they get you cold so then
the main thing is just they basically pumped anti-freeze through your blood veins okay right
and so they don't want to rip off any skin or anything they just want to pump you as fast as
they can with anti-freeze so the least amount of damage right with the least amount of damage so
that you get cold as fast as possible and then they just want to preserve you in that state
where uh again so the usual approach is through liquid nitrogen now there there is an alternative
technological approach that seems feasible which is sometimes called plastination basically where
they would fill your body with plastic in essence and sort of freeze the the the chemical reactions
that way not not just by being cold but by just basically putting stuff in between stuff that
prevents the reactions and then that could in principle be preserved at room temperature
which would make it easier to preserve these things but the problem is that that's a whole
separate technology that would have to be developed there's just too few customers here to justify
having separate technologies many of the customers today would not like the plastic approach
because they're hoping that their current bodies will be revived i'm skeptical about that but
again the key problem is just not enough customers here and i mean honestly i think this is a terrible
shame in the sense that it seems to me that most people today don't need to die that is
the main risk about cryonics is that these organizations can't last because they don't
have enough customers so if they had lots of customers this would just be much cheaper and
more reliable so if millions of people use this stuff then the price would come way down and the
chance of you not surviving would go way down what is the name of the company that does this
is there only one there are several there are several okay my my suppliers called
alcor but alcor okay there's also cryonics institute which is an alternative and several others
but again the key thing is they just hardly have any customers what is the price of doing this
um you know i'm sure it ranges a few tens of thousands of dollars up depending on how much
you want and you know which firm you go with right basically it's quite accessible via life
insurance for most people at least first world people right uh wow so a similar an interesting
comparison that often strikes me is there are some people who when they die have their ashes thrown
into space into space yes some people are turned into ashes and have their ashes thrown into space
and beautiful that costs a similar amount and a similar number of people do it that's pretty wild
it is so and that causes a lot less marital problems so cryonics customers do actually
have a lot of problems where their family and friends or spouses are upset that they are
going to use cryonics interesting and people are not upset about ashes into space
isn't that weird similar amount of money but but i mean so obviously one would seem to have a
chance of working ashes into space is not going to bring you back but it's in fact the fact the
fact that you think it might work that bothers people that is it's like betrayal and abandonment
like you're willing to leave them to go to this future world without them right right that bothers
people whereas ashes into space doesn't so that's one of the main obstacles to cryonics is often
people who are inclined in that direction face resistance from family and friends who not only
find it weird but find it like it's somewhat emotionally threatening in the sense that you're
willing to leave them go somewhere else yeah no it's uh i mean the idea of wanting to preserve
your body after you die to be saved for potentially thousands of years to be brought back by a future
civilization it's uh it goes back to something that you've talked about before of wanting to
create more descendants of yourself or more versions of yourself to last into the future
how how does that idea relate to us compared to potential alien civilizations
the main way in the past our ancestors have influenced the future is via descendants
right even in the last 10 000 years with a lot of cultural evolution still i'd say the main way
most people have influenced the future is via descendants that's because biological and cultural
evolution have just been powerful forces in the world um so the question is for any one person
how how do they want to be involved with that process that is do you want to influence the
future and if so how do you expect to do that um you know if you imagine a corporation or something
right it has a large structure that plans and then it creates future version of itself more in many
ways through planning than through sort of random variation and selection right so sometimes firms
have spin-off firms and then new firms are based on that but firms influence their future selves
more through planning in some way that's right they decide to make a division and they decide
to build a factory and they decide to promote somebody and things like that right so there's
there's a sense in which we we influence the future at least in short terms often through planning
and then you might think of that sort of the main alternative to
evolution as a way to influence the future right and that's very popular in the sense that when
people think about how do we want to influence the future they often think in terms of plans
they say global warming how are we going to solve global warming let's come up with a plan and
implement it or something right or war how are you going to stop war let's come up with a plan and
implement it right so i would see you know planning versus sort of some sort of competitive
adaptation as the two main forces that we know about for influencing the future and up until
recently planning only ever had much impact on pretty short time scales you could plan your short
your lifetime near in your near future right you could plan a town plan a firm but over longer
time scales it was evolution and adaptation that had most of the impact on change if if those are
the only two processes i guess aliens would have to choose between them too right right um and
you know planning has become ascendant right in recent centuries we are doing more planning
that's in the past we didn't even have large firms right most people were small artisans working
on a small scale firms are a new thing or large government agencies those are a new thing
uh large longer term projects building a huge dam things like that those are all relatively new
things so planning is ascendant right more of the world today is structured by plans
than was true in the past but still even so at the larger scale of our society most of it isn't
planned right new firms arise old ones go away you know new technologies arise mostly not through
long-term planning right but planning is growing and i think that tempts people to think what if we
could do everything with planning and then we wouldn't need competition and that's i think
what's happening with these world mobs or world government i think that's sort of the key choice
when we're thinking about which future we're going with the quiet or the loud aliens really
that is in some sense the quiet aliens are likely the ones that liked planning liked
collective decision making liked having a world community that decided things together
and chose consciously what to do and controlled things consciously and the loud aliens are the
ones who allowed competition allowed evolution and allowed adaptation and all the conflict
and strangeness that would produce right so the the loud aliens are the ones that
cared more about descendants or they failed at the other approach i mean or they just failed
with the other right they could have wanted to do the other one and just failed at it right
remember just it just takes one colonist whoever leaves through the entire history of civilization
and goes off to another star that's all it takes to end the era of the central control so it's a
it's a high bar right so quite likely they never intended for it it was the outcome they you know
happened because they failed to achieve the other one you talked about how humans today are becoming
more and more like foragers because we are the the way society is structured in the last few
centuries compared to and this is something that you've written extensively about how are we more
like foragers foragers are the way humans live for a million years before say 10 000 years ago
roughly right and we lived in small groups and these small groups were governed sort of informally
by collective decision making where we sat around the campfire and decided things together and if
people didn't like it they could leave and that's how we did things for a million years and we had
a lot of cultural flexibility that allowed us to enter a lot of different regimes some of us became
eskimos and some of us lived in the rainforest etc but we still mostly had the similar social
structure of these small bands who lived collectively and then basically you know they
had a lot of things that are different must they were relatively promiscuous they didn't so much
have marriage they shared a lot of food made decisions collectively they had a lot of leisure
time they had a lot of art and travel and then at some point farming became possible which i'm
including herding and farming and farming just requires a very different social organization
and sort of attitudes toward life in the world farmers lived in higher densities for example
maybe communities of a thousand instead of communities of 30 they had to plant seed and
save for the future and they had to have self-control they had property instead of sharing everything
they were living close enough to each other they could have war and trade
they needed to manage self-control for war and they needed to deal with inequality because they
had these large groups that would produce inequality and farmers were just very different than foragers
and you might think it just couldn't happen that foragers could become farmers but humans had enough
cultural plasticity that we could change over maybe 50 000 years slowly changed to become
farmers and and farmers then accept more slavery inequality marriage property war trade working
harder less nutritious less travel all sorts of ways in which farmers were just different than
foragers but that's the way the farming world lasted for 10 000 years under this new
economic thing which was much more productive in the sense that people could just live much more
densely much more people per square mile living as farmers than they could as foragers so farmers
won in that sense of just displacing foragers and then in the last few centuries we've gotten rich
as we found ways to generate wealth faster than we grow the population so the wealth per person
has gone up and in that time period as we've gotten rich the cultural pressures that turned
foragers into farmers have weakened that is a lot of what made foragers into farmers was cultural
pressures that was mediated by the threat of poverty that is so if you take so foragers were
pretty promiscuous okay they didn't really marry they stayed with the partner for a couple years
and switched okay farmers were supposed to be monogamous right for a lifetime and um so if you
take say a young farming woman who is tempted to be promiscuous what makes her not well she is told
over and over again at great expense and clearly if you break our rules about promiscuity you and
your child may starve and we can show you examples of people to whom that's happened and that tended
to be persuasive farming young women and men learned enough self-control to follow the farming
norms that were different than the forging norms because they would die otherwise and they had
substantial threats that were powerful but when you get rich and somebody says you know if you
don't follow the rules then we're going to disapprove of you and you say yeah but i'm rich
i can afford this then that doesn't work so well so in the last few centuries as we've gotten rich
we have been felt less inclined to go along with the forager norms and rules we've looked inside
ourselves and said yeah but what do i feel like and we've done those things and we continue to
move in that direction of doing those things that we feel like doing because we can we're rich enough
that we can so today a young woman is told hey if you have a child out of wedlock then you and your
kids may have problems they go okay but i've seen other women they have kids they seem to do okay
i think i'll do okay so you know don't bother me and so we've been moving back to forager values
outside of work now work is different in the sense that work is the goose that lays the golden egg
it's the reason we are rich so in fact at work we are hyper farmers
we put up with domination and ranking and stuff at work that most farmers will put up with and
certainly not less foragers so we are a schizoid in the sense at work wait what do you mean by
that last part we put up with more dominance and ranking so at work most people at work
in the modern workplaces are told what to do all the time and they're told they're doing it wrong
and they're shown they are worse than somebody else who's shown to be higher than them even if
they they don't agree with that people and most farmers would never put up with that
most farmers were relatively independent farm you know farmers or cobbler or fisher or whatever
they worked in small groups as relative equals and they didn't have a boss telling them what to do
all the time and after an initial apprenticeship they were in charge of how they did things and
they could just do it that way for the rest of life because things hardly changed
and so and even that so most foragers again are very egalitarian they're hyper egalitarian they
just they refuse to do they won't tolerate any sort of implication that anybody's better than anybody
else they're really sensitive that and they were really squashed that very is this also because
there are way less people and it's not that's not central to it it was more just the norm that
nobody should stand up so compare it to chimpanzees in a chimpanzee group there's
a dominant set of chimps who rule over the group and are unequal okay and humans didn't want that
to happen so humans are consciously and purposely preventing themselves from having a dominant
group like chimps do and making sure everybody is treated equally but that means they're constantly
wary of somebody thinking i'm the big chimp and i'm gonna i'm gonna take over here and so they
have to be wary for that and stomp it as soon as they can okay because foragers are very egalitarian
and they enforce that vigorously and so part of that is nobody tells anybody what to do in part of
the forager groups and even children are not told much what to do in fact children are basically
you know raised in a forager group by children get bored and then they follow an adult around
and maybe the adults will show them what they're doing if they're nice and that's how children
learn to do what adults do and so farmers have more ranking because farmers have classes right
there's the king and there's lords and maybe slaves but it's usually only a limited range
of classes and most people interact mainly within their class so most farmers still have a relatively
egalitarian world where most of the people are at their level and nobody's giving orders
and that's how most of the farmer life is and so at work but we put up with a lot of domination
and ranking at work and it seems like school is a big part of why that's possible school seems to
make the modern worker in a way that non-school doesn't so we've we have many stories from around
the world when modern you know companies would go into some local area and try to put up a factory
or some modern workplace and try to get the locals trained to work in the modern workplace
and that often failed badly because the locals would just not do what they're told even if
they're offered large wages and would be fired if they wouldn't do what they're told they just
won't do what they're told so like one classic example was in India and England at the same time
they had the same factory for you know spinning making clothes whatever you know making textiles
right and in England the factory was six times as productive
than the Indian factory because an Indian worker would you know have a machine and they would sit
next to the machine they would tend that machine and the English worker would have six machines
and sit next to them and tend them if you told the Indian worker to tend six machines he'd say no
no that's not what I'm going to do I refuse and quite consistently across a wide range of stories
that I've heard it's just hard to get local people to do what they're told in a workplace hard to get
them to show up on time and especially hard them to just tell them that they're doing it wrong that
is workers just are typically very proud and they think however they do it is right and they don't
want this foreigner person telling them wrong especially commonly like I've told this story
someone I knew worked like near a United States Indian reservation and basically people off the
reservation coming into a workplace they would have this sense of status in their work from their
reservation and they insisted that all their work tasks in a job reflected that relative status
they would not want to do a task that was lower status than somebody else they thought was lower
status than them right in the workplace and so I mean for example I understand why like when the
United States went into like when United States goes into Arab countries and like tries to train
militaries say in other parts of the world what they often has if they have a room full of people
are training and some of them are higher than others in the room then they can't do anything
in the room that would ever make a higher person look lower than somebody else in the room in terms
of their ability on any task okay right and so they either have to only train people all at the
same level or train them in a way that they never actually do anything because they might look worse
and this is just a very common sort of thing people around the world are just very sensitive to
the status they think is due to them and then the tasks on the job might threaten that status and
make them look worse than somebody else who's supposedly lower status so but the key thing is
that school changes this because the main thing that happens at school is every day you are ranked
and rated many times in a way that most adults wouldn't put up with like on most jobs most people
get an annual evaluation right and that's a big sensitive thing you're not ranked every damn day
constantly but students in school are ranked every day and in fact we know that that level
frequency of rating and ranking of students makes them learn slower that's actually a thing we know
we know they would learn faster if they weren't rated so often but we do rate them so often
plus because that's the product that's what we're trying to do we're trying to produce
kids who will accept a modern workplace why are we trying to do that though because that's actually
more productive that is because it makes us rich that's the thing that makes us rich we get rich
because modern workplaces require a high degree of organization a high degree of specialization
and they change fast and so people have to be told what to do and told how to change it
and that's the goose that lays the golden egg that's how we can be more more agreeable or
people that are more willing to take orders right and we want to produce people like that
because it makes us more rich and it makes us more productive wow at the beginning of the
industrial revolution people saw this and they were terrified many people so you can see like
famous movies and novels around say you know in the year 1900 as people were seeing the
industrial revolution spreading and they were seeing this degree of regimentation and structure
in workplaces and they were terrified that that would spread to everything and that was plausible
in the sense that they could see that in a factory or a shipyard or one of these very structured
modern workplaces people did not have much discretion about how they did things or what to
do they were told exactly what to do and how to do it and when and that seemed inhuman compared
to prior workplace habits and then they thought that'll spread to everything and so people wrote
science fiction novels in the late 1800s describing what would happen if everything were regimented
that way what if society told you who to marry and where to live what to eat for breakfast and
what clothes to wear all the time always right and that was this terrifying vision of the future
that people were imagining because they were seeing how regimented work was
and they were thinking that will happen to everything right and it could have happened
everything if we hadn't gotten rich but well as we got rich we could spend our extra wealth on
not having that happen outside of work so you know in in a modern world living in a big dormitory
with a big cafeteria where you all wear the same clothes is much cheaper to supply so like i visited
a commune and there are communes out there that are you know living very poorly because they're
basically supplying their own food and clothes and stuff but they can do it by having just a
high degree of regimentation and structure where people live in communal housing and have communal
food and clothes and that is much cheaper than the way we do things but as we got rich we decided
instead of living in big communal housing and things we would have personalized housing and
personalized kitchens and personalized clothes because and in fact that's what we've spent most
of our wealth on in the last century so a century ago people were looking ahead exactly variety
individual variety that's what we've spent most of our wealth on we could have say vastly more
food we could say maybe work two hours a week or something with all this technology we have we don't
need to work very much if only we would be willing to accept very standardized communal food and
clothes and housing etc but we weren't we chose we'd rather work a lot more and have a lot of
personal individual variety that is what you're explaining when you're saying we're becoming more
like foragers the individuality individual as part of the forager trend i think but so a whole bunch
of trends are explained by this forager so we say over the last few century we have less slavery
less religion less war more of the less less less marriage more promiscuity
more leisure more travel more art less overt domination of all sorts at workplaces
and in all sorts of contexts these are all trends that are explained by this
moving back to forager styles outside of work and many people have painted science fiction futures
where this trend continues and they love this idea like star trek is partially like this or the culture
novels where basically in the future people work less even less than they do now they have even
more variety they have even more promiscuity they have even less religion they have even less war
um so where does that go where does that fertility where does that end up oh less fertility is part
of that yes fertility is also for foragers had lower fertility than farmers why is that
and why would we why would our fertility be declining so i have a more detailed theory
but the first thing to notice is in fact foragers are lower fertility than farmers so farmers are
farmers are often in a situation where they can have a lot of kids and they do
whereas foragers are usually in a relatively stable environment where they control their
fertility in order to make sure that they can stay in that stable environment so farmers have had
just more variety in the size of their environment where they they go into a new area and they can
just make a lot of farms etc and they can just expand a lot whereas foragers haven't had that
same ability but it is basically also just true that foragers just tended to have lower fertility
the space births say you know farmers might space births once a year and foragers might space them
every three or four years or something okay um but i have another theory that also can try to
explain this lower fertility because this is a central fact about our civilization today that is
if you want to complain about our civilization it's like one of the biggest things to complain
about you can say well any any decent civilization wouldn't do this in terms of if it was hoping to
survive and reproduce right it would it would just why would it have such a lower fertility so
i do think there's a serious puzzle to be explained and why we have low fertility and i do have a
favorite theory but it's not just the forager theory actually it's a a variation but i mean
but i do have to admit the forager correlation does at least predict the sign of the effect
okay well please expand on it okay but um so the idea is that over the last 10 000 years we lived
in these larger groups which often had things like kings and queens right like king and queen
of a thousand people isn't quite the same thing but still you had somebody at the top of a hierarchy
who had much better long-term success for having grandchildren say so over the last 10 000 years
and and the prior 50 000 say as people were adapting to this we evolved to ask should i
take a shot at being king or queen that's a new strategy option that didn't exist before foragers
didn't really have kings or queens but now that we have king or queens you might ask well should
i go for that so i could go for that or i could have my kids go for that right should i try to
raise king kids in a such a way as they might be king but only certain people would have that
option only people that was in yes in their lineage no so well the question is what are
the conditions for having a shot at being king or queen so evolution cultural evolution and
biological solution had to find a way to code that that is you know there's a lot of different
variety of civil of groups they have different practices everything what would be a robust
indicator that you had a good shot at being king or queen and the hypothesis is relative wealth
would be a good indicator that is in almost all societies if you were higher status you would have
more wealth so you're seeing that you had more wealth than others would be an indication that
you had a shot at being king or queen you lived in a bigger place you had more food more clothing
more leisure just all sorts of indications of wealth would be a robust indicator that you had
a better shot than most of being king or queen so first let's ask what would you do if you had a
shot of being a king or queen so in most societies there's an elite culture and then there's signs
of being a member of the elite culture and what you're trying to do is acquire those signs that
show that you deserve to be a member of the elite culture so you might do embroidery or poetry or
learn to do balls or like the different societies have different things but almost all of them will
have a set of cultural practices that elites have or rich elites have that others don't that mark
you as a valid member of elites such that you are a valid candidate for being king or queen
right right so now the story is if i or my child has a shot at being king or queen then i want to
invest in them in developing these cultural markers i want to teach them poetry to dance
to embroider to sing play the piano whatever it is that in anyone's society is a marker of the
elites maybe read more fiction know how to you know etc but it will take time to invest in that
right and so the idea is that if i have a shot at being king or queen a better shot than most
for me or my child then for me or my child i want to invest more in these cultural markers
and the key point is that will come at the cost of fertility that is it'll take time away from
other things and that if i want to invest more in each child i can't have as many children right
okay so the idea is if i had a shot at being king or queen i would have fewer children
or they would have fewer children because they have a better shot at being king or queen and if
they do then that will more than compensate for the current fertility loss because king or queen
will have lots and lots of grandkids so now the question was you know what would be the indicator
that said i did have a shot the indicator would be relative wealth that would work so
that's the simple story but that story doesn't work yet because in fact over the last few centuries
we haven't had an increase in relative wealth we had an increase in absolute wealth
so the strategy i've just described says look around yourself at your relative wealth to the
people around you and if you have a high relative wealth then you have a shot at being king or queen
then you should lower your fertility now invest more in the signs of cultural markers that would
make you an elite qualified to be king or queen but the story doesn't work yet so i have to add
one last mistake to my story i have to say well up until the last few centuries
the average wealth never changed societies pretty much always had the same average wealth which was
pretty pretty near subsistence people varied within a society about their relative wealth
compared to the average but the average almost never changed so this heuristic look at my relative
wealth was perfectly fine as a heuristic look at my absolute wealth because my absolute wealth
always told me my relative wealth until the last few centuries so why bother to do this relative
thing just look at absolute so the story is evolution culturally and biologically encoded
in us this habit of looking at our absolute wealth as an indicator of whether we had a shot at being
king or queen and if we did we would lower our fertility in order to invest in the cultural
markers of eliteness such that we would then be a valid candidate for king or queen
and then the problem is in the last few centuries all of a sudden absolute wealth did vary
absolute wealth did vary we got rich consistently the whole world not just temporarily but
persistently and that threw off this heuristic so now everybody thinks they have a shot at king
or queen and everybody's cutting back their fertility to collect cultural markers of eliteness
so that they can all be king or queen which is not working very well because they can't all be king
or queen what is happening it seems like right now in society especially with young people
is that people are investing more and more in their education or their careers people my age
in particular they they are especially you know young men and women they are putting way more
value into their finances their education their careers and i would say these are markers of
eliteness that is the things they're collecting instead of kids are markers of status in our
society right and this is part of the reason that fertility is going down because we are
we have less value on producing more children and more value on gaining eliteness for ourselves
and my explanation is that's executing this strategy of trying to have your kids or you be
king or queen right so by the time you do have kids you have developed this wealth or you have
accumulated enough you can train them to have high cultural markers so that they have a shot
of being king or queen so except neither none of you have a shot of being king or queen
anymore i mean in the past you would have but now you don't so why why did we how did we end why
did we end up here how did it get like this so the key idea is that evolution evolves strategies
that are heuristic and that use the cues available in in a crude way right so evolution can't can't
look at the world you're actually in and tell you exactly what to do in your world right it
can only find markers of the world you're in and then find correlates between things you should do
when those markers exist that's how evolution tells you what to do it can't look at more detail
right so it evolves this connection between the cues you see and the behaviors you should
do to respond so and the way it encodes those is going to be opportunistic it's going to be
based on what happens to be stable or not so so for example imagine there was things like water
except they weren't water okay right so imagine there's something like water that tastes like
water it isn't water or something else that smells like water that isn't water right now in
our world everything that smells and tastes like water is water it's not a problem right
so in our world evolution could have taught you when you're thirsty to get water based on the
taste or the smell either one it would work fine or just the way it flops when it when it moves
or something right when evolution wants you to go get water it has a whole bunch of cues to work
with that are all go together in our world so it doesn't that much matter right so you know maybe
you queued off the smell of water and then that smells good and now i'm going to drink water right
so now imagine a world where okay there's a thing that smells like water it isn't water that isn't
really isn't actually healthy for you right well now if you appeared in that world all the sudden
where you had been trained in the prior world then you would start drinking the stuff that
smells like water and and that would hurt you because it's not actually water right but you
know that's because you moved into a new world right you moved from a world where all the
different cues about water all went together so you didn't actually need to use them all you could
just pick any one of them you moved into a world where all of a sudden it makes a difference
and now you'd be making a mistake so the key idea is evolution has this general task of figuring out
what cues in the environment should trigger what behavior but it's only going to bother to like
look at the actual variation in the world you're around not all possible variation
in order to figure out what to get you to do so the story is that out for our ancestors for a
million years our ancestors lived in societies whose average wealth never varied so there was
no point in evolution coding you with this way of checking your relative wealth to other people
was much simpler to have you just check your absolute wealth all right that was the perfectly
fine cue up until recently to decide whether you had a shot at being king or queen but all of a
sudden the world changes and now this heuristic that worked fine in the old world doesn't work
so well in the new one and that's why fertility is declining we're just executing a heuristic that
is misfiring because it's in a new world and there's projections that show birth rate
where it's going and i think elon musk is one of the most vocal people about this
so which is why he's having like so the question is like how will this problem get fixed
and you might think okay eventually say evolution would fix it but now we have to ask well how
exactly would evolution fix it so i think the key question is how much cultural conformity pressures
are involved here that is you know so for example we've seen societies like you know the mormons say
or orthodox jews who have an unusual culture that promotes fertility right but nevertheless their
fertility has also been falling at a similar rate just at a delayed time and even those societies
apparently aren't failing to resist the larger cultural pressure to adopt the larger cultural
attitudes toward fertility right so that is your attitude toward fertility is a combination of like
your genetic unique attitude toward fertility plus the cultural attitude toward fertility around you
that you're being taught right right so biology can only fix this when that if that cultural
that biological attitude got so strong as to overwhelm this cultural attitude and that doesn't
seem to be true most people today that most people are pretty culturally influenced by the people
around them some people might have more of a biological inclination toward fertility but they
all seem to be pretty influenced culturally by the people around them so either over i mean so if
you think about i think i did the numbers like in 1500 years humanity would go extinct if the
population went down by half every two generations or something like that so that's kind of the
time scale we have to work with wow so the question is well first of all can biology
create humans who resist cultural pressures enough over that time scale which i'm doubtful
for more likely scenarios can culture create a new culture that resists outside cultural influence
over that time scale and that seems more plausible because we have seen cultures that are somewhat
insular in the past right cultures that train people in that culture to follow that culture
and to ignore outside cultures say forget all of them they're evil they're wrong just just listen
to us right so then the the win scenario seems to me is that we end up with a especially insular
fertile culture that as a culture arises which has a strong value of fertility and
insularity that is it teaches people to not listen to outsiders and to stay away from outsiders
and to just listen to people in the culture this has to be more insular as i said than the
mormons are now because they are failing they are in fact have you know responding enough to the
outside cultural influence that they are on track to all with everybody else so this new insular
culture is going to have to be pretty damn insular and that's going to cause a lot of costs right
that is you know that insular cultures have caused wars and a lot of things and you know
especially they're going to limit innovation right this insularity is probably going to
resist other things from the outside culture not just fertility attitudes or it's going to
resist technology maybe all sorts of things it might resist right and so and who knows what
it'll be but unless we can like engineer it'll be kind of random right which insular culture
appears that manages to to persist and of course it'll have to not only arise as an insular fertile
culture but also resist the outside's world trying to crush it right because the outside world may be
very offended by their insular fertile culture i'm less i'm less assured of biology solving the
problem than culture that is i'm less assured that like some humans will just evolve a biological
inclination to just want to have a lot of kids regardless of cultural pressures or we can start
genetically making our own kids in test tubes i'm not i don't think that helps that is it's about
again how much you invest in each child right getting pretty far it's about how much you
invest in each child not so much about how mechanically you make the child in the first
place right most of the cost of raising children isn't the first year or the pregnancy the cost is
all that time it takes to raise the child to be a elite cultured child and the time it takes to
put into them and to teach them things right so if you'd have to imagine a future where people
are willing to like hand all that off to robots or something right well people are selfish too like
i feel like right now people are are they're not they're inclined to produce more kids but it's
the time they're willing to spend on the kids because you're taking time away from yourself
and putting it right towards this other human and you have to have enough faith and enough belief
that you're going to right so so you have to imagine something like uh you know where where
the kids the elites kids send their kids off to boarding school or something right where now the
elites aren't spending the time the boarding school does now you have to imagine a very
efficient cheap boarding school right right because somehow it's going to be able to raise
these elite kids at a low cost to the parents so that they're willing to have a lot of them
right that's that seems a tough game i i would more predict the insular fertile culture
and the faster than that well robin we've hit three hours um thank you for doing this man
hey it's been fun uh thanks for letting me spout and ramble and i'm gonna have to watch this over
so i can understand it better but it's been quite educational i appreciate it very much
where can people watching and listening find more of your work find your books
find you on the internet etc well i have a website hansen.gmu.edu i on twitter at robin hansen
i have these two books the age of m and the elephant in the brain and just google my name
of course we'll find it a lot or even videos on youtube google my name well thank you very much
again um it's been a pleasure i very much enjoyed it