The first time I learned about you was when I was watching a John Mack documentary.
Oh, far out.
Yeah.
And you were talking about John and he had a lot of interesting things to say and I thought
that you would be a fascinating person to talk to.
So I'm glad you're finally here.
Yeah, I've gotten only more fascinating since then.
Lou Elizondo retained me and then we get to do the help with the legislation and things
are really hot right now.
Things are very hot right now and you're being very outspoken.
Why have you all of a sudden decided to start doing podcasts?
Well, because once we got the attention of Congress, you know, the Congress pays attention
to people around the country when they start knowing about stuff.
And so our people now, what we've put together, the New Paradigm Institute to actually mobilize
people to educate people, to get them past the supposition that, well, somebody says
they're there, you can't really tell, they don't ever have any real pictures of them.
You know, they got buzzed over the December 2017 videos, you know, that Lou Elizondo and
Chris Mellon brought to the New York Times and they're going, whoa, okay, then they've
seen those a hundred times, you know, but the fact is there's a lot more, a lot more
information in firsthand witnesses that are extraordinarily credible, there are deep insiders
that have been coming to the Senate Intelligence Committee now and testifying under oath, you
know, and giving them a documented proof and other references to corroborate what they're
saying.
I mean, you know, it's rolling right now.
And so we all, people put together the Senate Intelligence Committee and the Senate Armed
Services Committee staff, you know, Armed Services Committee under Jack Reed and the
Intelligence Committee on the Senate side, you know, under Mark Warner, who's the chairman,
and also Mark Rubio, Marco Rubio, you know, they've all been on board this thing and they
crafted this 64 page bill.
It was just like comprehensive in how we would go about undertaking a really responsible,
controlled disclosure of all of this information, giving the president ultimate authority to
recommend that a certain piece be, if he said one piece of information to be postponed from
immediate public release, but he has to give reasons and he has to have a written report
on why he's doing that.
And there can be a classified portion of it that he can provide to the Intelligence Committee,
but there also has to be a public document acknowledging that he's withheld a particular
piece of information and explain why he's doing it.
So it was a really comprehensive bill that was put together by people who were definitely
in favor of disclosing virtually everything that's more than 25 years old, which is the
kind of a standard rule for even intelligence information, as long as you don't disclose
anybody's particular identity, et cetera.
You know, but so we got into the bill that presumably everything is 25 years old or more
going all the way back to January of 1945 has to be revealed to the public.
And we set up a time schedule for it.
You know, they got 300 days to gather everything all together and put it into digital form
with an outline and have it be retrievable, computer retrievable.
And then they had to turn it over to the National Archives.
And then the National Archives was directed by Congress to, within 180 days, release it
all to the public, you know, unless the president personally intervened and made a provision
for a particular piece of information to be postponed.
It was really comprehensive.
And there was a nine person board that was put together to review all this permanently
with staff, had a 20 million dollar budget, you know, to put together all the information
and to comb through it.
And we were one of the groups that was to nominate people to that board, that our New
Paradigm Institute was the citizens group that was to be nominating people for the president
to appoint to this board.
And, you know, it was the majority and minority leader of the Senate, the majority and minority
leader of the House of Representatives, the Secretary of Defense, the head of the National
Archives and us as the citizens group that we were referred to as the UAP Disclosure
Foundation.
That's one of our domains.
But it's the New Paradigm Institute that's set up as a 501C3, it's a wholly integrated
project of our 40 year 501C3, you know, that did the Iran-Contra case, that did the Karen
Silkwood case, you know, that I did the Pentagon Papers case for the New York Times, all that
Hey guys, I want to ask you a quick favor.
Over the last few months, almost 70% of the viewers of this podcast are not subscribed
to the channel.
The most important common denominator that allows me to keep creating these podcasts
every single week is you hitting that subscribe button below the videos.
I want to thank every single one of you who watches and supports these podcasts.
I would not be able to do it without you.
Please hit that subscribe button if you enjoy it.
Now back to the show.
You know, we did all that through the 501C3 and so we've set up a full project under
our 501C3 tax exempt organization to act as the citizens watchdog on this process.
So that we're in Washington DC, we're the only civilian office right within the federal
enclave on Capitol Hill with all the Senate and House buildings and the United States
Supreme Court and the Congress building.
We're right there.
So we can have regular meetings with the staff.
We have lunch with the staff, you know, and are going through the details of what was
in the bill.
And when it went over to the House side, you know, we knew, for example, that there was
a 17-0 vote in favor of the 64-page bill in the Senate Intelligence Committee, all eight
Republican senators, all nine Democratic senators, you know, we had all the major heads of all
the committees in charge of it, and it passed overwhelmingly in the Senate.
And we sent it over to the House side and it had of the 435 members, you know, like
420 of them, you know, were instantaneously supportive of the whole 64-page bill.
And it was actually called the UFO Controlled Disclosure Campaign Plan.
I mean, it was a full-scale mandate from Congress that there be a plan put in place to disclose
all of this information, and it had a seven-year period that was covered.
So that we had a seven-year period within which to disclose all of it, but there was
a 300-day period that they had to gather up all of the information that's 25 years old
or more and get it made public.
Now, that's a huge thing because actually from the date of the enactment, which was
December 22nd of last year, of 2023, that would have fallen on October 18th of 2024,
right this year, like two weeks before the election.
Oh, that perfect timing.
Yeah, I mean, it was just that we had it all set up so that this information is coming
forward so that people will have it, you know, in helping to make their decisions as to who
ought to be their senators, who ought to be their president and vice president, et cetera.
This is an extraordinary event.
I mean, when you have, when you have, and everybody knows now about Colonel Grush testifying
in the House Oversight Committee under oath that we are in possession of a non-human extraterrestrial
spacecraft and the bodies that are non-human.
The DNA tests have shown that they're non-human, and now that's a big story.
The DNA tests have shown, but have we seen any DNA tests?
They've got them.
The Senate Intelligence Committee's got it.
So with Grush, how many total witnesses did he bring forward?
There are 40 of them.
Forty.
So I was just talking to my friend Jeremy Riss on, we do a little Patreon pre-show before
this, and I was asking him, because he's a historian in the UFO thing, you know Jeremy?
He's a great guy.
I was asking him about you, and he had a great way, a great question.
I'm going to try to, I'm going to botch this, but he basically said, Danny Sheehan's a Harvard
lawyer.
Ask him this.
If I broke into, or if anyone broke into anybody's house, if I broke into your house, right,
and there were two witnesses that were neighbors, and they both said they saw you, saw me breaking
into your house, you would go to jail, right?
I wouldn't go to jail.
You'd go to jail.
I own their house.
That's what I meant, right?
So whoever broke in would go to jail based on those two witnesses who saw you breaking
into the house?
If the jury believed the two witnesses.
So we have 40 witnesses with this whole UFO dog and pony show.
And is the issue that the jury doesn't believe the witnesses?
No, it's that the jury has been the Senate Intelligence Committee, and they do believe
them.
That's the whole point.
That's why they passed this law, you know, saying, look, okay, now it's time to have
a full disclosure of this information to the American people so that we can formulate what
to do about all this.
So why can't we get, based on those 40 whistleblowers or witnesses, why can't we get a search warrant
of the blue room at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base or Battelle Memorial Institute?
That's basically what this statute was.
This statute was basically a search warrant that was issued by the Senate Intelligence
Committee ratified by the United States Senate, saying that there is subpoena power that they
have, that they're commanding them to turn over the information to the Senate Intelligence
Committee and specifically to the National Archives, okay?
So they're ordered to cough it up, and if they don't cough it up, there is subpoena
power.
And they have the power to subpoena them, to make them cough it up, and they have the
power to undertake sworn depositions so they can subpoena people to come to depositions
and interrogate them under oath subject to perjury charges against them if they try to
pretend they don't have the information or, you know, their dog ate the homework, you
know, whatever they want to come up with for their lame excuses as to why they haven't
produced it, you know, and they, very importantly, had the power of eminent domain, which was
to actually seize, order the seizure of the crafts to take them back into the possession
of the United States government.
Or any material, right?
Or any material, any biologics or anything.
They had the power of eminent domain to take them back.
So this was a real search warrant, subpoena, that was issued by Congress, basically, to
take this stuff into possession for the Congress, because it's an absolute violation of the
Constitution to deprive the Congress of the United States, which is actually the fundamental
government, the elected government of the United States.
The other people are appointed, you know, these are employees, the people in the Defense
Department, you know, they're not elected by anybody, you know, and so they don't have
the authority.
You know, the President has the authority, and under the statute, the President had the
authority to review this, because we've discovered that a number of the Presidents were not briefed
in on this, even when they tried to get it.
They were, that's how I got started in this whole thing, back in 1977.
Jimmy Carter got elected in November of 1976, November 4th.
On November 19th, he sent the message to the CIA director and ordered him to come down
to Plains, Georgia, to his home.
Was that Bush?
That was George Bush, Sr., and ordered him to come down and demanded that he turn over
the information to him about UFOs and what connection they had to extraterrestrial life.
George Bush refused to give it to him and said he didn't have a need to know.
And so what President Carter did is he went to the Congress and got the House Science
and Technology Committee to issue a directive to the Congressional Research Service to gather
all the information together and provide it to the President.
And that's when I got called.
I was at the Jesuit headquarters at the time, and I got contacted by Dr. Marsha Smith, who
was the head of the Science and Technology Division of the Congressional Research Service
of the Library of Congress.
And she called me and asked me if I would be special counsel to the investigation, the
research, initially to see if we could get the Vatican, because I was at Jesuit headquarters,
to see if we could get the Vatican to agree to allow us to have access to the archives
of whatever information they had on UFOs and the ET phenomenon.
And so that's how I got involved in it back in the early spring of 1977.
What made you guys want to go to the Vatican?
They wanted to go to the Vatican because they thought that given the fact that there's a
thousand, two thousand years almost, of records that have been kept there, they thought that
they suspected that there may be information in the Vatican archives about the issue of
extraterrestrial intelligence, mainly because the Vatican was, for many centuries, one of
the primary sources of intelligence gathering for the Roman pontiffs.
They had intelligence services, which were primarily Jesuit, actually, since 1547.
Yeah, it's wild.
The Vatican has a space observatory.
A lot of people don't know that.
Yeah, they do.
It's a pontifical observatory at Castel Gandolfo, just outside of Rome.
So what did they say to you when you asked them for access to the archives?
They said no.
They just said no?
Yeah, they said no.
So I sent them a second letter saying, let me make clear, this is Jesuit headquarters
in Washington, D.C., we're contacting you, as the largest order in the Catholic Church.
We've been contacted by a person who's been designated by the president to get this information.
They'd like to have the information.
And they just said no, that we couldn't have it.
And so I contacted Dr. Marsha Smith and told her that they were not willing to give it
to us.
And then she asked me if I would go and brief the top 50 scientists at SETI, out at the
Jet Propulsion Laboratory, JPL, out in Pasadena, if I would go and brief them on the theological
implications of contact with an extraterrestrial civilization, which I did.
And I got clearance from the Jesuit order to do that.
And so then I was, we went to the National Council of Churches and met with the leaders
of the 54 major religious denominations in the United States and proposed to them from
Jesuit headquarters that they agree to set up a task force to look into this, to get
out ahead of the power curve so that we wouldn't have another, you know, Copernicus and Galileo
kind of event of people, you know, freaking out and thinking that somehow science was
somehow going to be contradicting basic theological tenets.
So we said, look, we ought to get busy on this.
And then the National Council of Churches didn't want to do it.
So that was what we were doing there at the headquarters.
And then I was contacted later after that by Dr. John Mack to represent him when he
—
What year were you contacted by him?
1994.
I was contacted in 1994 by John Mack to represent him at Harvard because I'd graduated from
the college and the law school and had gone to do my master's and Ph.D. work at Harvard.
And so he figured that, you know, we'd kind of wave the school tie at them and get them
to lay off him, you know.
So that's the next kind of major event that I was engaged in.
And John and I had gone to see Lawrence Rockefeller and Rockefeller had agreed to finance an entire
Grand Rounds at Harvard to present all of the information and evidence to them.
And so I was actually in a position of interviewing virtually everybody in the field on behalf
of Dr. John Mack to prepare them as witnesses to be part of this Grand Rounds at Harvard
in 1994.
So you interviewed the people that were in his abduction book, the people that —
I met some of those people, yeah.
But I also interviewed all the major researchers, you know, I got to meet Stanton Friedman,
I got to meet Bud Hopkins, I got to meet David Jacobs, I got to meet virtually everybody.
I got to meet Stephen Greer, I got to meet Linda Moulton Howe, I got to meet all the
folks that were researchers.
And then I got to meet all kinds of the direct experiencers because I also became legal
counsel for the Project for Extraordinary Experience Research.
That's the peer group that John Mack put together in Cambridge.
So I got to meet the people in that context.
And so that's why Stephen Greer ended up asking me in 2001 to be legal counsel for the Disclosure
Project.
And I was legal counsel for the Disclosure Project for 20 years.
So I got to meet a lot more people in vetting the witnesses that we were going to present
at the National Press Club in 2001.
Yeah.
So going back to John Mack, when he first reached out to you, what was — he wanted
you to represent him for the stuff that Harvard was coming down on him for, for the research
that he was doing.
That's right.
What did you guys end up doing when you first met with him, and how did you approach that
case with him?
Well, it was interesting.
I actually got contacted initially by Ron Robertson.
Ron Robertson is John Mack's best friend.
He was his best man for him and Sally at their wedding and everything.
He was out in Santa Barbara, and I was teaching at the University of California in Santa Barbara.
And Ron Robertson contacted me.
He was the head of the art department at the Santa Barbara City College.
And he had come to a number of my lectures on the Ron Contra case and the Karen Silkwood
case and Three Mile Island case and other cases that we had done.
And so he was kind of a follower of the Christchurch Institute at the time.
So he called me and asked me to come and see him and then asked me, you know, what I thought
about the UFO issue.
And I told him I thought it was extraordinarily important.
It was probably one of the most important public policy issues that one could be involved
in.
And he said, oh, well, look, I should tell you that my best friend John Mack has just
been dragged up in front of this kind of tribunal at Harvard University that's completely secret
right now, but that they're excoriating him for having written this book about his
interviews with people who held sincere beliefs that they'd had direct contact with extraterrestrial
spacecraft, et cetera.
And he said, would you be willing to take a call from John and consider representing
him?
And I said, yes, absolutely.
So John called me, had me fly to Cambridge, and we sat down to talk about this.
And we looked into it, and this was not an AAUP panel, it was not an Association of American
University Professors authorized panel of any kind.
It was just this kind of rump gathering that they put together.
And then I found out that what had happened is that the United States Air Force and the
Defense Department and the Central Intelligence Agency had been engaged for decades in a covert
program of trying to smear people inside the military or inside government offices who
tried to actually do anything about the UFO issue.
And what had happened is that one of the first things they would do if a high ranking officer
insisted upon filing an official UFO report, one of the first things they would do is order
him to go get a psychiatric exam, which is not a career builder in the military.
And so that a few of these guys who would actually pushed all the way through and insisted
upon filing an official report.
For example, Arne Arnoldson, Colonel Arnoldson was the commander at the Molestrum Air Force
in Montana back in 1968, when the UFO came up over the over the Minuteman site and shut
off all 10 of the Minuteman missiles.
And Arne Arnoldson was the guy that called NORAD about it and said, you know, that we've
got this the craft of some sort that's come up over our site and has closed off all of
our missiles.
And they said, Are you trying to file a UFO report?
And he said, Yes, yes, I am.
And they said, Well, that's interesting, because both the Minuteman site to your west
and to your east have both reported the same thing.
They've had their missiles shut off too, which people don't know about, don't talk about.
But I talked to Colonel Arnoldson.
But it was fellows like that who insisted upon going forward, they would be ordered
to get a psychiatric exam.
And so a number of them had been sent to Harvard Medical School to get this kind of top level
psychiatric exam.
And John Mack, being the chairman of the department, was actually tasked to do that.
So he did that.
And he says he told me later, he said, you know, I did all the interviews with them and
did all the tests.
This wasn't by choice.
No, no, no, no, they were ordered to do it.
And so when John said, I mean, I mean him, but it wasn't his choice to interview these
people.
Well, no, they were they were sent there to be to be tested.
My guess is that that he, as the chairman of the department, had some discretion in
who would be assigned to actually do the exams.
And so he chose to do those.
Do you do you know if before he started interviewing these people, these military people, if he
had any sort of interest in this topic?
No, no, he did not.
He did not.
He had no he assumed it was all nutty, actually.
And he actually suspected that these guys had something wrong with him.
And he did the interviews and then he said, you know, but each one of them tested out
to be within the normal parameters of normalcy.
And yet they had this story that they kept insisting upon going forward with and they
felt compelled to talk about it and were ordered to be silent about it.
And so he he actually called his mother, John, John, who was like, I don't know, probably
60 years old at that time.
He called his mother, who was like 90 years old, and tells her about this.
And she said, oh, well, you should you should go see the Hopkins boy.
You know, they were the family friends.
The the the Mac family were family friends with the with the Hopkins family.
And she said the Hopkins boy has got been interviewing a lot of people who believe that
they've seen these UFOs or had direct contact with the pilots or the occupants.
And so he ended up calling Bud Hopkins and getting to talk to Bud and Bud sent some other
people to him, police officers and, you know, teachers and lawyers and librarians, people
who were in kind of positions in the community that it would not have been in their interest
to make up something like that.
And so he started interviewing them.
And as he started interviewing them, he got so fascinated by by the stories that he began
actually conducting like an investigation.
What he would do is he never hypnotized John, never hypnotized anybody.
He didn't want to do that.
He never did.
No, he did not.
What he what he does is he did a thing called holotropic breathing.
Holotropic breathing was a method that was developed by Stanislav Graf to actually get
people super relaxed.
And they would do like sort of like Hindu breathing through the different nose things.
And they would they would get into a kind of an elevated state of consciousness and
get very, very relaxed.
And that was the key for them to remember things that any kind of anxiety that they
had that was blocking into their memory.
So he would do the holotropic breathing and interview the people.
And what he would do, what he would do is he he would actually start asking them kind
of ancillary questions, you know, they would tell what was happening.
OK, now, are you you're you're where they say, well, I'm inside some kind of a room.
You know, I'm on this table and I'm getting examined.
And he said, now, will you look around a little bit?
Tell us, do you what do you see?
Then he would have them describe like the equipment in the room.
What type of equipment do you see?
You know, what does it look like?
And he would get like details of some of the stuff that they were seeing.
So that when he had another person who was in a similar situation,
he would ask them things that nobody would have ever asked him about.
But like particular little details about what was happening.
And it started being correlating.
And so he started to suspect that this was something that that was extraordinarily
strange because it seemed like it was real, what was happening to them.
And so he wrote an article.
He wrote an article for the New England Journal of Medicine.
How many people had stories that were very similar that like
and what kind of objects did they talk about seeing?
They would talk about some of the instruments, for example,
that were being used to examine them.
He would ask him to describe in detail what the instruments looked like.
Was there any kind of equipment in the room?
You know, what what kind?
Did you see any kind of navigation equipment in there?
Any kind of, you know, computers?
What did you see?
You know, and they would describe in some detail some of the stuff that they were seeing.
I had a guy on here named Randall Nickerson.
Yeah, Randy Nickerson.
He explained to me something about some sort of like like pole or stick.
Yeah, it was a rod. A rod.
There's a rod. There's a rod that a number of them reported having them.
It was usually the tall, tall grays, they call them, that had this rod
and that they would they would seem to actually give them control over people.
Actually, it was like it seemed to like amp up kind of their telepathic capacities,
which were quite considerable to begin with.
But it was like that.
So John, so John ended up sending the sending in this this report
that he did for an article for the New England Journal of Medicine.
And after several days, it got sent back to him
with a note saying they weren't going to publish this.
Well, he was kind of taken aback by this.
You know, he's the chairman of the Department of Clinical Psychiatry
at Harvard Medical School. This is a very professional piece.
So he decided what he would do is he would would beef it up.
He would put in more footnotes and more details
of the stuff to make it really full scale professional.
Then he he sent it back to him.
And within two days, the executive assistant
for Arnold Relman, who was the head of the who was the editor in chief
of the New England Journal of Medicine, sent his executive assistant
back to Harvard to go into the office of John and hand it back to him
and to tell him to note that it had not been opened.
And they weren't going to open it and they weren't going
to even consider publishing it.
And John got upset about it.
And so John called a publisher.
He'd won the Pulitzer Prize already. Right.
For the writing Lawrence of Arabia, the T.E. Lawrence thing,
the psychobiography.
And so he contacted a publisher and the publisher agreed to write it,
to print it, and it was published.
And then, like within a couple of days of it hitting the stands,
the dean of the medical school came in and said, John,
you know, I hear that you've published a new book.
And he said, yes, he said, this is a very interesting topic.
You know, why don't you why don't you come by, you know,
and let's talk about this?
It's very interesting.
And he said, look, and as long as you and I are going to be talking about it,
why don't we invite some of the other faculty people to come on over
who might be interested in this?
So John was excited about this.
John thought that was a cool idea.
So he was going to he went he went to the where the assigned place
was to go and meet the dean.
And he comes into the room and here's this tribunal
sitting there that there is not only the dean himself,
but it turns out that that Arnold Relman,
the the editor in chief of the New England Journal of Medicine,
was chairing the committee.
And then there was the legal counsel for Harvard University sitting there.
And then there were three other professors,
all of whom John thought were people who really didn't like him
for some reason in the faculty.
He had some experience with them.
And they were all there.
And they began to excoriate him
for besmirching the name of Harvard University,
writing about this ridiculous thing, that it was clear that these people
were mentally ill, you know, and that if he had written an article,
you know, about this weird mental illness,
then that would have been OK.
But he seemed to give the impression that he was attributing
some sort of dimension of reality to this whole the whole experience.
And so he was taken completely aback by what they were doing.
So he called his mother again and his his mother said,
Well, why don't you just go to the family lawyer?
You know, they were a fairly wealthy family.
And, you know, and his his father was a doctor
and his grandfather's a doctor.
They were kind of wealthy family.
So he goes to the local lawyer in Boston, the family lawyer.
And the lawyer says, Oh, just give them anything they want.
You know, if you want the recordings of your sessions, did you bill them?
Did they get insurance?
You were were you doing this as a clinical treatment to them?
Or were you doing research?
You know, just tell them whatever they want to know.
And he was kind of surprised.
He said he wasn't expecting that kind of advice.
And then he checked and found out that the lawyer, the law firm
Ropes and Gray was the lawyer for Harvard University.
Oh, no.
And he felt betrayed by the whole thing.
This episode of the podcast is brought to you by Bubs.
I've recently gotten into collagen supplementation
because after the age of 25, your natural collagen production
dramatically drops off, which severely impacts your skin.
By supplementing with collagen, you're actually increasing
your body's natural production of collagen.
This increases your skin health, your skin elasticity,
which improves the overall quality of your skin.
Secondly, if you're someone who's into lifting heavy weights,
collagen is one of the major building blocks to joint and connective tissues.
Collagen protein can help reduce joint inflammation and improve joint function.
And finally, collagen is amazing for your hair growth
because it increases the production of keratin,
helping to promote stronger, healthier hair.
Bubs is a tribute company to Glenn Bubs Dority,
who was a Navy SEAL and CIA contractor
who died defending American freedom in Benghazi, Libya.
Plain and simple, Bubs makes the stuff to help you get after it.
With nature derived nutrition to help give you that edge on life's adventures.
Bubs collagen peptide packets are easy to use as a daily supplement.
It's flavorless, easy to mix nature, makes it easy to mix in anything.
I like mixing it in coffee.
Check out Bubs today by visiting bubsnaturals.com
and using my promo code DJP for 20% off your first order.
That's bubsnaturals.com promo code DJP.
It's linked below.
Now back to the show.
And so he called his best friend, Ron Robertson.
Who called you?
Who ended up calling me, saying,
why don't we get Danny and see if he's interested in helping you on this?
And John said, oh, no, no.
He did like the Ron Contra case and the Big Silk Road.
He's done all those other big cases.
He probably wouldn't even be interested in this subject,
because that's why Ron Robertson called me, asked me to come to dinner
and asked me, what do you think about this?
You know, and so that's how that's how I got to be on the case.
So I go with John to the next session of the tribunal.
And we come in, we sit down, right?
And in there's there's Rellman up there with all the
the the dean of the medical school and the lawyer and all these guys.
And so Rellman just starts in trying to interrogate him.
And so I said, well, excuse me.
I said, excuse me here.
You know, you know, I don't know, you know, I didn't do the potted plant routine
that I'm not just a potted plant, you know.
I said, you know, look, I said, look, I don't know what the nature of this
this tribunal is.
It's certainly not an AAUP convened tribunal.
I said, but whatever the nature of it is, can you tell me, you know, are
are any of the either one of the two following fact questions
going to be at issue here?
Number one, whether or not extraterrestrial life exists.
And secondly, whether at least some of these sightings of the UFOs
might actually be a vehicle from an extraterrestrial
civilization. And Rellman says, well, the two of them are
absolutely going to be relevant.
He said, and it's totally ridiculous to think that either one of those things
could be true. That's what he says to me.
You know, 1994, Harvard University says it's completely ridiculous
to think that there would be life anywhere else in the universe.
I mean, that's where they were.
So I said to him, well, I said, in that case, you know, in the spirit of cooperation,
let's let's just tell me who is it that called the dean?
And there was this big, dead silence over the room.
And he looked around like this and the lawyer for Harvard University looks at him
and goes like that, shakes her head no.
And he says, well, I'm sorry, we're not we're not at liberty to discuss that.
And I said, oh, OK.
I said, well, look, in the spirit of cooperation here, you said
they ask a bunch of questions and he wasn't really able to to answer the question.
So what were the questions?
Another big, long pause.
He looked at the lawyer, the lawyer shook her head no.
He said, I'm sorry, we're not at liberty to discuss that.
So I said, all right.
Well, then, look, let me just tell you in the spirit of openness
that that John and I have just spent the weekend with Lawrence Rockefeller,
and he's agreed to finance a complete grand rounds here on this subject
at Harvard University that we'll bring in the chief investigator
for the Federal Aviation Agency, we'll bring in military personnel,
we'll bring in police officers and things that have filed these reports
in the lawyer for Harvard University just leaped to her feet.
And she said, absolutely not.
She said, we're not going to allow this procedure to be turned
into some kind of a circus, she said.
So I said, well, I said, you know, we've made the offer, you know,
we're perfectly willing to answer your questions and stuff.
But we're going to present the witnesses to support these two fact questions
that you think are at issue here.
And so we're ready to proceed.
And they said, no, we're not going to do any of that.
So I said to John, that's it, John, we're out of here.
You know, this is not an official tribunal of any kind.
You don't have to be here.
So I reached out and kind of help pick him up
out of the chair and walked out on him.
You know, and so I went around doing all the interviews of all these people
that we could present.
We just kept going straight forward, saying, you know, I kept saying,
this is a great opportunity, you know, to present to Harvard University
what the evidence is and the information is that we have.
And so I had to have a local council
because I was admitted in the Southern District of New York
and in Washington, D.C., but I wasn't admitted in Massachusetts.
So I went to I went to Dershowitz, Al Dershowitz,
who was one of my professors at Harvard,
and said because he I had the course with him on
psychiatry and the law.
He and Stone, Professor Alan Stone.
So I'd taken a year course in that at Harvard.
And so I went to see him and I said, you know,
who should we have to be just local council for me here?
So he recommended Harvey Silverglate.
And Harvey was in the middle of a trial and he couldn't do it.
So he recommends this young guy, Eric McLeish,
who had just gotten into the bar in Massachusetts.
And so he could just, you know, be there to be local council.
So we brought him on board.
And then he right away started working at trying to figure out
how to settle the case.
To say, well, look, why don't we just do whatever they tell you to do?
Why don't you just? Right.
And I said, no, stop it.
You know, we're not going to do that.
We're not going to turn over all the tape recordings of these things to them.
I said, you know, that we're going to do the grand rounds.
So he kept on figuring out how to solve this thing and settle it
and make him leave him alone.
And John's wife was upset.
Sally was really upset because he was being ostracized.
You know, at Harvard, he wasn't invited to any of the social events anymore.
And she wasn't getting invited to any of the women's things.
And so she was getting really upset about what was happening to him.
And it was all secret, you know, because they kept saying,
you know, we want this kept secret that we're doing this hearing.
I kept saying to myself, why the hell should we keep this secret?
This is ridiculous.
They don't have any right to be doing this.
But so what I was doing is I was respecting John's wish to keep a secret.
So what I did is I was reaching out to all these different potential witnesses
to come in and start preparing.
And one of the people that we reached out to
that had been in the University of Colorado,
because they were very, very familiar with the Condon report
that came out of the University of Colorado years earlier.
And so and he got terribly upset that this was going on.
And he called the newspaper and told them that this was happening.
Condon? No, no, no.
It was this other guy. It was a professor there that just knew all about the condon.
Oh, I understand.
And so I was going to have him testify all about it.
And so he told somebody about it.
And so they threw a big fit.
You know, the committee threw a big fit over the fact that it had been made public.
And so that the this fellow, Eric McLeish,
kept getting in there trying to get it settled.
And it turns out this Eric McLeish is later on
after this, after they stopped and left, left John alone.
I I was the one that initiated the first litigation
against the Catholic Church for the pedophile priests in Boston.
And I got a hold of Eric McLeish to to do the case for us. Right.
Pull that mic back.
And and he and he ended up starting settling all these cases.
He was the guy in Spotlight, the the movie Spotlight. Right.
That that Ruffalo, Mark Ruffalo was in where they played
told all about the Boston Globe in the the
the investigation they conducted about all the priests.
And they discovered that this guy, Eric McLeish,
was the guy settling all the cases for the Catholic Church
and getting a huge portion of the the settlement that was given to the people,
but making them sign statements that they would keep completely secret.
Any of the accusations they made against the church,
you know, which totally pissed me off, you know.
So was he like working as like a double agent with the church?
Yeah, he was. That's what he was doing.
Yeah, he was he was settling all the cases and he was basically engaging
in covering for the church and but getting money for all the people
that had filed complaints against these pedophile priests.
But he was getting a share of the money, you know.
And so I was really mortified by that.
But but it started, you know, it started with him, you know,
successfully settling the case for John Mack and making them leave John alone.
But it stifled our ability to bring all the witnesses on.
You know, it's just it's a little known fact about a well-known subject.
But the bottom line is that that's how I ended up after they
they apologized to John and left him alone.
He had me become legal counsel for his project on extraordinary experience
research, the peer group that he had there in Cambridge.
And John and I started working on trying to set up
what we were calling the New Paradigm Institute
that was going to be examining the worldviews clash that occurred,
that this is an entirely different worldview that Harvard University has.
It's the scientific, logical, positivist, materialist worldview
and that the assertion that it was completely impossible to believe
that that any spacecraft could actually come from a distant star system
and come to our planet just couldn't be true because, you know,
they can't go faster than the speed of light and therefore they can't get there.
What did John think about all of this?
Did he really think that this was like
spacecrafts coming from another star system or did he think
this was something like inside the human mind?
No, it wasn't inside the human mind.
What he started thinking about was that he thought it was quite clear
that there was evidence that that some of these events
involved a spacecraft from some other planetary system.
For example, the Betty and Barney Hill case.
Betty Betty Hill actually got one of the people on the craft
that she believed that they'd been abducted and brought on to to show her a map.
You probably heard about that showed in the star map. Right.
And she did get hypnotized by a guy in Boston, a professional hypnotist.
And she re-drew the star map that was shown to him.
And nobody could figure out where it was.
And it turns out that it wasn't later until they had the computers that could do it,
that they reversed the star chart to figure out the perspective
from which the star map was drafted, was drawn,
that came from their planet, which turned out to be Zeta reticuli.
And when that happened, that was kind of a further confirmation
because there wasn't any way she could have drawn something like that.
She didn't know anything about stuff like that. Right.
And so John said, OK, now there's there's some solid evidence
that at least some of this is coming from an extraterrestrial civilization somewhere.
But he thought that there was other stuff going on as well,
that it wasn't that this was a delusion on their part,
but that in fact, there was something going on
that had to do with what is normally considered to be religion.
And apparitions of the Saints see and the apparitions of Mary,
you know, that these kind of things that are happening in the.
And so he started exploring it and going to interview indigenous people
around the world who who believe that they have direct encounters with star people.
You know, in the Lakota tribe, for example, the Lakota people
believe that they come from the Pleiades originally
and that they came down from the Pleiades in this in this light chamber,
came down into the the Black Hills, into the wind caves
and came up through the wind caves.
It's a very specific tradition that they believe in their other indigenous tribes.
So John started interviewing people and put together this thing
called the Project on Extraordinary Experience Research.
Just one of the extraordinary experiences was these encounters
with what they experienced as being an extraterrestrial being,
you know, in a spacecraft.
But there were other experiences that people had that made it appear
that it was like interdimensional, that they thought that these beings
were coming from some other dimension.
In fact, in fact, we got called,
John got called by Bob Bigelow out from the Skinwalker Ranch.
This is back in nineteen ninety five or so. Right.
And he got a call from Bigelow and Bigelow said,
ask John to come fly out and see him right away and bring your lawyer
who helped you at Harvard.
So we flew out to see Bigelow.
And when we arrived, even like a day later after this event had taken place,
we arrived and met with him and he didn't want to talk about it anymore.
He decided, I don't want to talk about it.
And Colm Kelleher was there
and Colm took me aside
and stepped into the room next door and told me all about what had happened
there at the ranch and had to do with this kind of portal
that was like at the ranch and that this portal had opened.
And one of their people had seen this other this person,
you know, a big, tall, seven foot tall being,
you know, that had big kind of shaggy hair,
looked almost like a yeti kind of character.
And Colm told me all about it, you know.
And so I went back out and was talking to to Bigelow
to see whether he wanted to do it,
because what happened is Bigelow brought in a scientific team
right away to try to see what it is that was going on here to measure.
And these two helicopters flew in, two helicopters flew in
and landed in and ordered the scientific team to get away.
And they couldn't come to where this event took place.
And the scientists kept saying, no, you know, we're here from Mr.
Bigelow, he owns this place.
And they said, they don't care. You get the hell out of here.
They were American guys. Black helicopters.
They were unmarked helicopters.
But they, you know, they were just regular jumpsuits,
all black jumpsuits, no insignia on them, no names on them and anything.
But they were American guys talking.
He knew that they were they could recognize they were American military guys.
You know, and when when the scientists kept trying to assist upon
going in and setting up their equipment, they began to get beaten up
by these guys and breaking their equipment and broke their cameras
and scared, scared the crap out of them.
This is on Skinwalker Ranch? Yes. Yes.
Yeah. And I was I was right there, like within two days of when this happened,
you know, of them beating up the scientists and stuff.
And so that originally he was so upset that Bigelow wanted to sue them
and wanted John to bring his lawyer out to do something about this.
But by the time we got there, just a couple of days later,
he just was not going to do anything at all.
And as I say, it was Colin Callagher told told me all about the details
of what it is that had just happened.
Who do you who do you guys suspect these people were?
I I don't get paid to guess.
You know, if people want to investigate it and want to do it
so I can retain professional investigators and the proper people
to do the investigation, we do it.
Does anybody have any ideas?
Does Bigelow have any clue? Does anybody speculate?
Oh, all kinds of people speculate.
I mean, what do people say?
This whole field is filled with speculation in private contractors.
Are they it's it's it's, you know, that I'm assuming that I'll be in position
since we've set up the new institute, the New Paradigm Institute,
that will be funded to investigate things like this and do it professionally
full scale, you know, with psychological stress evaluators
and professional investigators that are licensed gun toters.
We that's what we work with.
You know, that's what we did in the Karen Silkwood case.
That's how we found out who killed Karen Silkwood.
It's how we found out that they were smuggling the plutonium
out of the facility to Israel.
You know, it's how we did the Iran Contra case, how we caught them
smuggling the weapons to the Contras and smuggling the cocaine.
We had we had we had where they were smuggling the cocaine, too.
And, you know, put the refrigio de fico, the Punta Arenas,
these little shrimp boats, they were bringing it into Miami.
We had the house where they were bringing it.
We had the unlisted private telephone number for the house.
We had the code words you use to be able to call and get an order of the drugs.
We knew that it was Gambino's daughter that was running the place.
That's what we do.
I mean, that was what the Christic Institute was for 20 years in Washington.
That's what the Romero Institute has been for 20 years out in California.
And that's what our New Paradigm Institute brings to this.
That's what we brought to John Mac.
It's what we brought to the review of the vetting, the people
that were going to be witnesses for this closure project.
So with John Mac, all of those people that you guys interviewed
and all the people that he did this holotropic breathing with
and had them kind of recount these experiences, things like
what Betty and Barney Hill encountered.
How many of those people were foolish?
A few of them.
There had to have been a few of them.
Yeah, yeah, there were.
But some of them were foolish.
Some of them were foolish.
Some of them were were mentally ill,
you know, which is different than being foolish.
Yeah. But there were others that were just fakes, you know,
they just wanted celebrity or wanted to be involved in it.
And so I vetted these people out, you know, that was what I did
for the for the peer peer group.
You know, that was part of my responsibility.
And that's what I did for the for the disclosure project.
As I said, no, these are not people that we want to vouch for.
Right. You know, right.
And so that we could we could call through the people
and present just the most credible people
with a kind of verifiable evidence that you would you would
conduct a rule 11 preliminary investigation
before you would be willing to file a complaint, you know,
asserting that the facts are true to the best of your belief.
You know, that that's what we bring to this this whole field,
which is new, is a rule 11 standard of professional investigation.
And the fact of the matter is that we can, in fact,
bring adequate numbers of witnesses who are completely credible,
completely verifiable, who've got corroborating evidence
and documented proof, you know, and those are the kind of people
that are being presented to the United States Senate.
Are you familiar with the guy who he was a Air Force officer,
I believe, at the what was the name of that base in California?
Vandenberg. Vandenberg.
There was a story of a rocket that went up with a dummy.
Oh, yes. Clear warhead on it.
Oh, yes. This guy was like arguing with Bill Nye
on live TV about it. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Was he one of your witnesses?
No, he hasn't. He hasn't gone in front of the Senate yet.
He did. He came to the National Press Club, though.
He came. He came with with Bob Salas.
Bob Salas came in who was the captain
at the Maltstrom Air Force base with the Minutemen.
And there were there were two other guys who came with him.
One of them was that guy and he presented the entire information about
and showed showed a mock up of the video that he took.
He was mock up of the video.
He showed what it looked like.
What it was is that he he was he was actually videoing
the the the launch and watched the launch go
with the big gigantic telescope that they had.
He had it mounted to be able to watch the whole ascent of the rocket.
Yeah. And he saw the thing.
And what he did is he he drew a a reenactment of what it looked like
and where was the original video?
Well, it was it was top secret.
It was it was kept by the people.
He was working for Vandenberg Air Force base.
He was actually part of the team that was monitoring the flight, you know.
And so he was in an official position to be doing it.
And so he's the one that saw the video
and turned it over to the officials in the Air Force about what it is
that had happened.
But and he waited for years.
This was just let's see.
We're in February of 2024.
Now, this was like in, I guess,
early June, probably a little earlier than that.
May, May, perhaps May of 2023.
He came with Bob Solace to the National Press Club
and actually had a press conference and in showed his
re-creation of what the video looked like.
You know, so he he did talk about that.
Yeah, there's been lots of recreations of that video online.
You can find on YouTube.
Yeah, it's it's for people that aren't familiar with it.
Apparently some sort of a saucer came up around this fake nuke
that was being launched in the atmosphere and it like shot laser beams into it.
And then it just fell into the ocean.
Yeah. And they just showed it like a beam of light coming out of it.
And then it went in the rocket was going up.
I mean, it was accelerating, you know, like, I don't know,
a thousand miles an hour or something in this this craft, whatever it was,
was just doing circles around it and zapped it with these three
different beams of light.
And then the whole thing just, you know, went all off course
and ended up crashing, I guess.
Yeah. And we were talking a little bit earlier about
like the misinformation and what the military was trying to do
with some of these people at these bases by, you know, giving them
these psych exams by John Mack, because obviously, like you put it,
well, it's not it's not good for a career builder.
Exactly. Yeah, right.
So are you like I wonder how much of that is going on now
with people that come out and or are publicly talking about
like witnessing UFOs or having these sort of abduction experiences?
How many of these people are being contacted by people in the government
or people in the military and being fed
disinformation so they can basically be a conduit to the media,
giving them sort of like like a limited hangout type thing?
Well, it's it's a it's an important fact question,
but it's one that we have to investigate.
I mean, all kinds of people speculated about it.
And there's a mixture of people who are who are making stuff up.
There's a mixture of people who are speculating.
There are people who are getting third hand reports
and then embellishing them.
What we're what we're doing at the New Paradigm Institute,
in addition to organizing and educating people
about the kind of really concrete cases that are really verifiable,
that what we're going to do is investigate some of these other cases
to vet them and decide which ones of those that we can vouch for.
OK, because we're in the process of presenting people to the Senate,
you know, into the House Oversight Committee.
So we're we're trying to make sure that, you know,
you could have five really absolutely credible witnesses.
But if you let one real ringer get in there, you know,
who's mentally ill or just faking it, you know, like this guy,
Corey Good, you know, that was going around, you know, pretending that
he was on, you know, interstellar spacecraft that we'd back engineered
and he'd been to other galaxies.
And who's this guy?
This guy, Corey Good, that he was around for about two years.
And Dave Wilcock was, you know, flogging him all around
and putting him on Gaia and everything.
You know, there are people that are just complete phonies
that have Dave Wilcock. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
That guy's that guy's a wacko. That's right. That's right.
But these two guys were all the rage.
I mean, they were they were showing up at, you know, going on Gaia television.
They were going to the International UFO Congress.
They were going to the, you know, all these different events
where people are gathering together and they were attracting big, huge crowds.
You know, and it was just this totally sensationalist stuff.
I mean, and I just I ended up refusing to go to any.
I refuse to participate in anything that they were at.
That guy Wilcock was like in the beginning of the trailer
of one of Stephen Greer's documentary is calling Greer a genius.
Well, he was like, Stephen Greer is a genius.
Well, as I say, people are say all kinds of things, you know,
and this this area has been rife with people who are hoaxing
and people do it just it's just like the kids who use to cut people's clotheslines
on Halloween, you know, or poop in a bag and light it on fire
and put on people's porches. Right.
You know, I mean, there are people who are just reckless.
Well, are you I'm sure you're I'm sure you're familiar
with the the Paul Benowitz case, right?
There's a movie there's an amazing documentary called Mirage Men.
And it's about this guy named Paul Benowitz.
I believe this was in Steve.
You could probably find this, but I think it was in the 70s,
mid to late 70s.
He was living in Nevada.
And here's the yeah, here's the document.
It is one of if not the best UFO documenter I've ever seen.
Shout out Jeremy Rees told me about this.
Anyways, he was living near an air force base right over the hill in Nevada.
And this guy was a devout UFO guy, right?
He was he was in the community going to all the talks.
And he was seeing these crafts,
these UFOs flying over the mountains
near where this air force test range was.
And he was sharing them with the UFO community in the area.
Anyways, the Air Force got wind of the people at the base got wind of this.
And they sent a counterintelligence guy over to his apartment
to check it out, see what he knew.
And the guy they sent over what his name was.
This is Rick Doty of Doty.
Oh, yeah.
And he went over there and he found out what he had.
And Doty was Doty was feeding him fake information.
This is right in line when they were testing the stealth bomber.
And Doty saw what he knew and asked him what he thought.
And he said he thought there were UFOs and Doty said, you know what?
I think you're right.
I think these are aliens.
And he used Benowitz
as a conduit into the UFO community to disseminate this misinformation
because they knew there were Soviet spies embedded in the UFO community
that were trying to figure out what sort of military or like blue sky
research that we were testing and developing over there at those air force.
Yes. Yeah.
This episode of the podcast is brought to you by Rocket Money.
Do you ever feel like money is just flying out of your bank account each month
and you have no clue where it's going?
Well, I do. It's to all those subscriptions you have.
Think about it between all your streaming services,
productivity tools, fitness apps, meditation, guided apps.
It's endless. And I'm guilty of this.
So I ended up using Rocket Money to figure out which subscriptions
I'm still paying money for every month.
And they helped me cancel all the ones I no longer use.
If you're unfamiliar with Rocket Money, it's a personal finance app
that helps you cancel your unwanted subscriptions, monitor your spending
and helps lower your bills.
And it's not just about canceling subscriptions.
It's about monitoring and controlling your spending.
You can see all your subscriptions in one place.
No more digging through bank statements or suffering these long,
grueling calls with customer service people.
They'll even work on getting you refunds on subscriptions that you haven't used.
They're very skilled negotiators.
Rocket Money can potentially lower your bills by up to 20 percent.
Just snap a photo of your bill, send it to them, and they will handle the rest.
The bottom line is Rocket Money has already helped over five million users
save an average of seven hundred and twenty dollars per year.
That's over five hundred million dollars in cancel subscriptions.
Stop wasting money on things you don't use and cancel all those unwanted
subscriptions by going to RocketMoney.com slash DJP.
Again, that's RocketMoney.com slash DJP.
It's linked below. Now back to the show.
I remember I met Dodie before, you know, and I always thought Dodie was a phony,
you know, and people didn't like me because saying I don't I don't attack
people as a rule unless I become just completely convinced that they're lying.
And that they're engaged in active disinformation and in trying to discredit
the whole movement. And Dodie was one of those guys.
And there have been a handful of others like Wilcock and Corey Good and a couple
others that we've we've been involved in exposing.
There was some one guy, I can't remember his name or nobody.
He had this whole cockamamie story where he and his dog were out walking in the woods
and they came upon this craft that was crashed in the woods.
And it shot out a ray and froze his dog.
And so he got really angry.
And he picked up a big branch and clubbed this little UFO guy
and put him in his freezer and was keeping him there.
And he had this big mechanism that he put on his wrist and could shoot rays.
It was just total lying, you know, and one of my professional
investigators actually followed this guy around and finally caught him,
you know, reporting to some friends of his how he was bullshitting everybody.
Yeah. And and I told John Mack about it.
And John then issued a statement discrediting the guy.
Yeah. And then. What is that?
Someone driving that was a loud car driving.
There's also like when on Groom Lake, when the Air Force
or the CIA was testing the first jet propelled, you know, the first jet airplanes,
they sent up the pilots with gorilla masks in the cockpit.
So in the case where they flew within visual distance
of a civilian airplane, they would put on gorilla masks
so that when this pilot goes to the bar to tell his buddies about this jet airplane
he saw, he's going to say he saw a gorilla flying a jet airplane.
So it's like it's like purposely planning these false,
these fake seeds to cover up top secret information.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, they definitely were doing it.
And they they very definitely consider the whole UFO issue
a major top secret program and that they've been actively engaged
in sowing disinformation and discrediting individual people
who who have genuinely seen things.
They've destroyed people's family lives.
They destroyed their professional careers.
You know, they've just they've destroyed their military careers.
You know, there's a very active, aggressive counter intelligence program
that's mounted to stop people from reporting genuine UFO incidents.
And I connect all of this to to Bob Lazar in the fact that in his story,
specifically when he talks about walking past a window and seeing an alien body,
like if they were going to bring him in
to potentially try to back engineer some sort of technology, they dug up.
It would make it.
It really would make sense that let's walk him through a room
with a little alien in it.
So that way, if he ever tries to blow the whistle on this program,
people aren't going to believe him.
No, that's that there's there's dozens of individual cases
where it bears analysis, professional analysis.
You know, for example, all you have to do is is is get him Bob Lazar
and put him on a psychological stress evaluator, which no one has done.
They put him on lie detector tests and he's passed the lie detector test.
But those are pretty crude.
You know, you know, I mean, the little things on your fingers
and the little belt on your chest.
Those are those are not even close to the precision of a psychological
stress evaluator that measures tension, involuntary tension in your vocal cords.
It's it's a very professional way of going about this.
And I was in F. Lee Bailey's office this developed this.
We used it in Bailey's office when I was there in seventy four, seventy five.
So but but not very many people knew about him.
You know, I mean, Bailey also had a had a briefcase,
satellite phone, et cetera.
We discovered only later that he was actually on the index four for the CIA.
He was one of the four lawyers in the United States
that the CIA is supposed to contact if one of their people is caught
engaging in domestic covert operations, which is totally forbidden
by the National Security Act in 1947.
So I was one of the three trial lawyers in his office and we didn't know it.
And as soon as we discovered it, you know, I left and had a number
of the investigators leave with me because we didn't want to be associated with that.
Can you break it down for people listening?
What the Pentagon Papers were and how that led into the Watergate
burglary and how you got involved in it?
Well, it's it's it wasn't.
Well, what happened is the they were separate cases that the Pentagon Papers.
I had initiated the case.
I was the co-founder of the Harvard Civil Rights Law Review in 1968.
I was taking doing constitutional law with Lawrence Tribe and others.
And and we set up the Harvard Civil Rights Law Review.
And I wanted the law review to be something more than just writing academic
thought pieces.
And so I wanted to have a provision in the Harvard Civil Rights Law Review
where we were helping young lawyers figure out how to become civil rights lawyers.
And so we sent out letters to around to a lot of the major bar
associations and things, letting people know that if the if any lawyers
had really important civil rights cases, they could contact us
at the Harvard Civil Rights Law Review.
And we would get a bunch of little eager beavers at Harvard
to work on those briefs. Right. Right.
And so the bottom line is
I ended up being contacted by a guy
in the name of Pappas, John Pappas, who was a NBC television journalist
in New Bedford during the riots that followed the assassination
of Martin Luther King in April of 68.
And the the
riots broke out in New Bedford after the assassination of Martin Luther King.
And the white mayor issued a shoot on sight
order to the police to shoot any looters
that were engaged in looting in the context of those riots.
So the Black Panthers had set up barricades
around the ghetto area to keep all the police out of there.
And their big standoff occurred
because they built barricades.
And then the police came in and they brought in the helicopters.
And, you know, they thought there was going to be gunplay that was going on
because they were armed, the Panthers.
Bottom line is, long story short,
that the the Panthers agreed to give an interview, an off the record interview
to the John Pappas, who Paul Pappas, I'm sorry, Paul Pappas
would give them an interview if he would keep it off the record.
And he went in and interviewed them.
And then the district attorney subpoenaed him to make him cough up
the confidential interviews that he'd had with the Panthers.
And then he contact they contacted us at the Harvard
Civil Rights Law Review through a guy by the name of John Flynn to write.
So I asserted the First Amendment right of journalists
to protect their confidential news sources in the case,
went all the way up the United States Supreme Court right away.
And so I was only a second year law student.
So I got recruited by the Wall Street law firm that represents NBC
to come down to do the briefs for the United States Supreme Court.
And in doing that, I also wrote the amicus briefs
at the Supreme Court level for CBS and ABC
and also for The Washington Post and The New York Times.
They all filed amicus briefs on that important issue, right?
In the Supreme Court, because no one had ever asserted the right before.
And so it had never been litigated.
So we were litigating it in front of the Supreme Court.
In that context, I got to meet Jim Goodell, who was the general counsel
and vice president for The New York Times.
So when they got the Pentagon Papers
brought to them, their firm, Lord Day and Lord,
it represents The New York Times most of the time,
threatened to turn them into the FBI if they didn't give them back right away.
And so Jim Goodell called me over at the Cahill firm.
So I got the call.
And then Jim Goodell came in to talk with with me and us,
and we agreed to represent them to publish the papers.
So we went ahead and did the Pentagon Papers case
for The New York Times and won the case in the United States Supreme Court
and got to publish all 47 volumes.
But what happened is I got to read.
I was one of the few human beings on the planet that actually read all.
You read all of the 47 volumes of this is we were trying to determine
what we were going to publish and what we weren't.
We're vetting what we're going to publish.
Why would you publish all of it?
Well, because you didn't want to reveal names of people.
For example, the thing that Snowden gotten all the trouble for. Right. Right.
So so so the bottom line is I was doing all that.
And Bailey had already contacted me earlier before I went to the Cahill firm,
wanting me to join his firm.
But all he wanted me to do is write legal briefs
on behalf of constitutional rights to protect fucking criminals.
Did Bailey have anything to do with the Pentagon Papers?
No, I would imagine that he would not want nothing.
No, he did not. He did not have anything to do with it.
But he knew that I was doing all that stuff.
And he had asked me first to be the good guy to recruit.
And so the bottom line is when he got retained by by McCord
to defend McCord in June of 1972,
June 17th, when the burglary took place, Bailey gets retained
because he was on index four, along with William Bennett Williams
and two other attorneys that he was on index four.
What do they call index four?
It was just a code name they had for the list.
CIA code name. Yes, the CIA code.
There were four lawyers that were on retainer by the CIA
so that if they got caught, engaged in domestic covert operations,
which is illegal, that they would call these lawyers. Right.
And so Bailey was one of them.
And so Bailey called me and asked me if I would come out of the Cahill firm
and come to his firm to be on the case.
So when we got there, when we got there,
I realized that these three of these Cubano guys
from our interviews with McCord, that they were Traficante guys.
So I was kind of saying, look, I'm responsible for trying to monitor
the hearings that are becoming at the Watergate hearings.
Who is Traficante?
Santos Traficante was the Don of the Mafia in Havana.
And in January of 59, when Batista was overthrown
by Fidel Castro and Che Guevara, et cetera, that Traficante fled
and came to Tampa, actually came to Tampa and was here.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
And that was Santos Traficante, the mob boss, you know, for for all of Havana,
which was a key area because it had the gambling casinos.
It had the the houses of prostitution, et cetera.
Was it Meyer Lansky big shot down there?
Miami. Miami National Bank is a Lansky bank.
It was a mafia bank.
You know, but he ran a bunch of the casinos and whorehouses down there.
That's right.
And they had the heroin.
The main heroin trafficking was coming in from Southeast Asia,
coming in through Traficante was also partners with Vang Pao
and over in Laos.
And they were bringing in the heroin into Havana.
And the the three person partnership was Batista,
Santos Traficante and this guy, Paul Helliwell, for the CIA,
are the ones that handled all the heroin coming in through Havana.
From Laos, from Laos.
That's right. Through Vang Pao.
Yeah. And so.
So the bottom line, the bottom line is I came into the office
and we ended up, you know, participating in getting McCord
to blow the whistle on them.
He wrote the letter to Judge Sirica
explaining to him who they who the burglars were and what they were doing,
because he thought that they were actually coming in to try to protect.
They thought that, well, the story that he told
was that they thought that the Democratic Party
was coddling people that were illegally
opposing the Vietnam War, which they thought was undermining national security.
That was that's what James McCord was talking about.
But the bottom line, as it turns out,
we found out through our interview of Traficante directly
that the reason they'd gone into the Watergate Hotel was because Larry O'Brien,
who had just been made the new head of the Democratic National Committee
in the Watergate Hotel in Washington for 25 years, had been the previously
was the chief lobbyist in Washington for Howard Hughes.
And Howard Hughes is the guy that Richard Nixon
contacted to set up the assassination team to kill Castro in Che Guevara.
And the bottom line is that's the group that killed the president.
And that's what the Watergate burglar was all about,
is Nixon was terrified that that they were going to find out that
because Larry O'Brien had worked for for Howard Hughes,
that Larry O'Brien may have found out that Nixon is the one who who created
the assassination team that ended up killing the president,
and that if that ever got out, that nobody would believe that he wasn't behind
killing the president, which he wasn't.
But he was behind trying to kill Castro.
And it was that same unit that killed the president in sixty three.
All right, we're going to have to rewind a little bit.
Yeah, we're going to have this off the UFO subject.
We're going to have to go a little slower over this for a second.
Oh, yeah. So the guys you interviewed.
Traficante. Yeah.
And found out that the Cuban guys were going into the hotel to find they were
hired by who?
I'll take it from the top and I'll tell you, so you'll know the details of it.
What happened when I realized that there were
Traficante guys that were in the hotel and I was saying,
what the hell has that got to do with anything?
Why are they there?
So I get a hold of Bill Taylor, who was my investigator,
assigned to me in the firm of Bailey.
And Bailey gets a hold of bad Andy Tooney,
who was the chief investigator for Moriarty and the Social Security Department.
Who was the chief investigator for Moriarty and Associates,
which is Bailey's investigation firm. Right.
And he interviews he interviews Traficante at
Hank's house, Henry Gonzalez, at his house here in Tampa.
He sets up an interview and interviews him at length.
And he explains what's happened here.
What happened is back in in early
late May, actually, of 1960.
This is the 1960 presidential campaign.
And Richard Nixon is the vice president under Eisenhower. Right. Right.
And he is campaigning to get the Republican Party nomination in 1960.
And in late May of 1960, Nelson Rockefeller
withdraws from the campaign in Michigan.
And therefore, Nixon knew he was going to win the nomination
because Nixon was now because
Nelson Rockefeller was out of the competition and Nixon was going to be
the nominee. And they were certain they were going to win because, you know,
there was this kid, Kennedy, that had been was going to be the nominee for the
Democrats. So they were all convinced that he was going to win.
What Richard Nixon did is he was the head of the 5412 committee,
which is the subcommittee of the National Security Council that does covert
operations under Section 5412 of the National Security Act of 1947
that authorizes the CIA to engage in activities from time to time
at the request of the president to protect national security.
And so they he Nixon ran.
He chaired the 5412 committee of the National Security Council.
So he knew that Howard Hughes was a secret consultant
to the National Security Council.
He was running special operations.
He, for example, had designed and created the the Goldmar Explorer,
which was the ship, special ship that was able to pick up submarines
off the bottom of the ocean, the Russian machine.
He also did the C5A cargo plane out of the Suma Corporation.
And he was also doing other stuff for the National Security Council, 5412.
We're talking about Howard Hughes, the guy who plays an aviator.
This is this is Howard Hughes.
And he's living in Las Vegas, you know, at the the one of the major
mob hotels. And he's living in the penthouse suites up there.
Right. Right.
And so the bottom line is Richard Nixon contacts him.
As soon as Richard Nixon knew that Nelson Rockefeller had withdrawn
and he was going to be the nominee and he contacted Howard Hughes
and on the the secret phone for the 5412 committee,
talked with him by phone and asked him to set up an assassination team
to kill Fidel Castro, Raul Castro in five of the commandantes
that they wanted assassinated.
And he said, but you got to keep it completely away from the White House.
So that if you could get that done,
that I would deeply appreciate that when I become president. Right.
But if Howard Hughes, why would Howard Hughes set up an assassination team?
Well, when you know the nature of what some of the things were
that Howard Hughes was doing with with the 5412 committee,
it was the deepest, darkest, most secret stuff that they were doing.
And he was part of it.
It wouldn't help for me to go into what that one was.
But there was an extremely, extremely supersensitive program
that Howard Hughes was working on with them, in addition to the Glomar Explorer
and the C5A and all that.
But because of the the depth of the darkness of that relationship that he had,
he knew that he could go in under that umbrella of that super dark program
and to get Hughes to do this, Hughes doesn't agree
or disagree with with Nixon on the phone, whether he's going to do it or not.
He's not that's not done.
So but what he did is he got one of our one of his lawyers, Bob Mayhew.
And Bob Mayhew, he assigned to go get this done,
see if they could put this team together.
Bob Mayhew meets with Johnny Roselli.
Johnny Roselli is the bag man at the Sands Hotel
that's owned by the mob.
And Johnny Roselli is in Las Vegas, where where Howard Hughes is.
And where Bob Mayhew was.
And so he so Bob Mayhew gets a hold of Johnny Roselli
and says, look, use guys, you know, have every reason in the world
to try to get rid of Castro.
You know, he shut down the whorehouses, he shut down the gambling casinos.
And very important, he's cut off the heroin supply
that's coming in to the to the C Supply Corporation.
So if you guys would do this, you know, the president would be really grateful.
And they started referring to Nixon's president
because everybody assumed he was going to win.
Right. And so so what so Frank.
So Johnny Roselli says, look, I'm going to have to go and see Giancana.
You know, who's my principal here? I can't do this.
So I have to clear this through Giancana.
So so Johnny Roselli goes back to Chicago and meets with Giancana
and says, look, here's the Nixon who's going to get to be president now.
Well, it's this assassination team put together.
Can we do this?
And in in Giancana says, well, that's Traficante's territory.
That's he's the Don of Havana, you know, and even though he's fled
and he's up in Tampa now, he said, we're going to have to go meet with him
to see whether he would OK this.
And so what they do is they set up a meeting and Sam Giancana goes
and Johnny Roselli goes and Bob Mayhew goes.
And they meet down at the Fontainebleau Hotel in Miami
with Traficante, and they hold two meetings.
They're to persuade him to do this, to set this thing up.
And then Traficante says to us, you know, he said,
but I didn't fall off in the melon wagon.
He said, he said, so I'm going to I'm going to check to make sure
that this is coming directly from Nixon, not some, as he said, brain fire,
you know, of Giancana or of of Howard Hughes or anybody else.
I wanted to so that they the third meeting, they send a guy
using the nom de guerre of Mr. Ed.
And it was Sheffield Edwards.
Sheffield Edwards was the chief of security for the Central Intelligence Agency
under Eisenhower and Nixon administration.
And so he comes to the meeting and gives them the green light
to put this assassination team together.
So they put the assassination team together.
And Traficante is the guy that's going to put together the team.
And Traficante picks 15 guys
that are former shooters for him out of Havana.
But he gets guys who have been recruited by the CIA
to participate in a thing called Operation 40,
which is a covert operation that they were running guerrilla raids into Cuba,
burning bridges and blowing up, you know, burning sugar fields.
Right. And doing that stuff that they were doing.
That's Operation 40.
And they had recruited a whole bunch of former Traficante guys
to participate in that, who had fled from Havana and were up in Tampa and Miami.
This was the anti Castro Miami right wing hardball,
anti Castro Cuban refugee community, Alpha 66, you know, the 2506 Brigade.
You know, that crowd.
Do you know Felix Rodriguez?
I sure do know Felix Rodriguez.
I've taken Felix Rodriguez's deposition.
You took his deposition. Yeah.
Can you tell me about Felix Rodriguez?
Felix Rodriguez is a shooter.
He's one of the guys on the team that killed the president.
He and he and Rafael Chichi Quintero.
I'm going to interview him tomorrow.
Oh, well, that's who he is.
You know, Felix Rodriguez, he'll know exactly who I am
because he was he was he was the number he was the number one guy
at Ilepongo running the the contra weapon supply operations,
along with Rafael Chichi Quintero.
He and he and Rafael he and Rafael Quintero were in the security division
at Pemex in Mexico City where all the assassins hung out in Operation Condor.
He's a cold blooded fucking killer.
You know, that's who he is.
Yeah. Felix Rodriguez.
He was so he was on.
Yeah, he was one of the Cuban assassins.
That's right. That's exactly right.
That's exactly right.
And just ask me about Rafael Chichi Quintero.
Tell him we've interviewed Rafael Chichi Quintero
so we know exactly what we're talking about.
You know, so ask him who Carl Jenkins is.
You know, say, tell me about Carl Jenkins and tell me about how you got trained down
in the the down in Oaxaca, Mexico,
at Clint Murchison Jr.'s ranch as part of the Triangular Fire Team to kill Castro.
Tell us about that, Felix.
That's incredible how the universe just like falls into place.
He says about that. Yeah.
Oh, my God.
So a lady we just had in here by the name of Annie Jacobson
is how I learned about Felix.
She wrote a book called Surprise Kill Vanish,
all about the like the creation of the Title 51 CIA assassination teams.
And she followed a guy named Billy Wah around different countries,
who was like he started out in Vietnam.
Really, he got just passed away.
But he was a CIA paramilitary guy
who was like doing some brutal stuff in multiple different countries.
And he was the guy who captured Carlos the Jackal.
And one of the guys that she interviewed in that book was Felix Rodriguez.
And, yeah, she talks about how like some of the things he did
didn't say anything you said, just none of the stuff you just said.
But she talks about some of the operations he did during the Bay of Pigs.
Yeah. And how he captured Che Guevara.
Yeah. Ask him about a wristwatch when he's sitting there.
Ask him. He took Che's wristwatch? He's got Che's wristwatch.
He wears it. Wow. Yeah.
He wears it to this day.
One in five Americans has learning a new language on their bucket list.
And if that's you, make 2024 your year
by checking that off your bucket list with Babel.
Babel's quick 10 minute lessons are handcrafted by over 200 language experts
to help you start speaking a new language in as little as three weeks.
I always binge Babel's courses when I'm gearing up to go on a trip.
It helps me to prepare my conversational skills
so I can deal with real people in real life situations
when I'm ordering food or asking for directions or dealing with merchants.
And to me, what helps set Babel above the rest is their speech recognition
technology, which helps hone in your accent and pronunciation.
Studies from Yale, Michigan State and others continue to prove Babel is better.
One study found that using Babel for 15 hours is equivalent
to a full semester at college.
Babel has over 16 million subscriptions sold.
Plus, all of Babel's 14 award winning language courses
are backed by their 20 day money back guarantee.
And here's a special limited time deal for our listeners.
Right now, get 50% off a one time payment for a lifetime Babel subscription,
but only for our listeners at Babel.com slash Danny.
Again, get 50% off at Babel.com slash Danny.
It's spelled B-A-B-B-E-L dot com slash D-A-N-N-Y.
Rules and restrictions may apply.
It's linked below.
Now back to the show.
So, OK, how did you learn about Felix?
Like initially, how did you find out who he was?
Here's what happened is that is that here's Traficante telling us
explaining how they did this. Right.
So what they did is is Traficante takes 15 of his guys,
all of whom had been shooters for him down in Havana. Right.
Gun guys. And they are all he takes guys that are all been recruited
by the Central Intelligence Agency to work in Operation 40,
which is running the raids down into Cuba. Right.
And they've got five paramilitary bases.
They've got one out on Swan Island, one at No Name Key,
one of them in the Everglades and two of them at Lake Pontchartrain,
one on the southern border and one on the northern border.
The northern the northern base at Lake Pontchartrain
is where Lee Harvey Oswald was working, you know, with the guys in New Orleans.
Right. OK.
And so so the bottom line is they put 15 guys on this assassination team.
And the way they do it is they they're all spread out
in these five paramilitary operations. Right.
And what they do is they send private planes around and pick them up
individually and they fly them to Fort Huachuca in Arizona.
And they sign them in and then they all disappear.
And they take them down to Oaxaca, Mexico,
at Clint Murchison Jr.'s ranch down there.
And they have a triangular fireteam base down there.
And a guy named Carl Jenkins is training them.
What does triangular fireteam mean?
They're they're high powered rifles.
They set up a triangular crossfire to to get three different angles
coming in to shoot and kill a target, a moving target.
OK. OK. And and they were trained down there.
And they were they were tasked to kill Castro.
And that was that and they were called the S-Force was their code name.
You know, say that to Felix and watch how he responds to that one.
The S-Force. The S-Force. That's who they were.
And and and so that they they were tasked to try to kill Castro.
And what what happened is that they they were put together.
They were assembled.
He picked the guys who were also in Operation 40 working with the CIA
so that if any of them got caught,
the agency would have to move in to protect them
because people would think they're the ones that did it.
But they weren't. But they did.
I mean, but it was it was Nixon that was asking to have it set up.
But it was set up by Howard Hughes and then Traficante set it up.
But he got to go ahead from from Sheffield Edwards,
who was chief of security for the CIA under Nixon. Right.
And so that's that's how the thing was set up.
And they but lo and behold, it turns out Nixon didn't get elected.
And Kennedy got elected.
But Kennedy was not briefed on the existence of this group.
OK. And what they did is they they set up
going to love this part.
They they set up a mechanism for funding them.
And what they were doing is they were to to fund the Triangular Fire Team
base down in Oaxaca at their at the ranch at Mercheson's Ranch.
What they did is they skimmed cash off the casinos in Vegas.
They would put them into these brand new suitcases.
They put them in the trunks of brand new Cadillac automobiles,
and they would drive them from Las Vegas through New Orleans,
where all the money would be audited, you know, by Marcelo's people. Right.
And then they drive the money all the way to Miami
and deposit it into Meyer Lansky's National Bank of Miami.
And then what they would do.
Here it comes.
What they would do is they would wire some of that money
down to the Banco Internacional down in Mexico City.
And there was a lawyer there by the name of Ogario,
and they put it into his account.
And that's where they wrote the checks from to pay for all the costs
for the Triangular Fire Team base.
And that was the bank on which the money that was caught
found in Bernard Barker's pocket in the Watergate Burglary
came directly from that account.
And that's where that's where Mark Felt was headed for.
Mark Felt was getting set to go down to the bank to find out
what the hell the story is with that account.
When when Pat Gray, who had become the new head of the FBI,
instead of Mark Felt,
freaked out about the fact that he was getting set to go down
the next day on the 23rd of June,
following the 17th of June break in. Right.
So he goes on the 21st of June.
Pat Gray goes to the White House
to meet with John Dean
and says to Dean, you know, we got a problem here.
You know, Mark Felt is getting set to go down to Mexico,
to this bank down there to track them,
the sequentially numbered bills that were in Bernard Barker's pocket,
one of the Watergate burglars.
And and so so John Dean goes in and tells
tells most of the chief of staff.
What was his name?
The guy with a crew cut anyway,
tells him about the the fact that Felt's getting set to go down to the bank
and he needs to find out whether that's going to be a problem.
And so so the what's the guy's name?
Talking about the Mexico City Bank, right?
Yeah, the Mexico Bank Banko Internacional. Right.
And and so the the bottom line is the chief of staff comes in
to talk with Richard Nixon in the Oval Office.
And he says, Mr. President, he says, I think we've got a problem here.
And Nixon says, what is it, John? Right.
And he says, you know,
Pat Gray has just come in, has talked with with John Dean
and said that this guy, Mark Felt, is getting set to go down to this bank
down in Mexico City to track these money that was in Bernard Barker's pocket.
Says he wants to know if that's going to cause any trouble.
There's a big long delay on the tape.
And Nixon says, look, you've got to go.
You've got to go and get a hold of Ericman right away.
And you've got to go on over to the agency and you've got to sit down.
You've got to talk to Dick Helms and to Vernon Walters, both.
Make sure they're in the meeting and tell them both that they've got to contact.
They've got to contact the FBI.
The agency's got to contact the FBI.
Dick Helms is the head of the right.
Because you've got to contact the FBI and tell them to get the hell out of that
part of the investigation.
And so the chief of staff, I'm trying to remember his name still,
says to him, well, what is it?
What am I going to tell them?
What am I going to tell them to say to make them get out of there?
He says, just tell them if you you can't tear off that scab,
if tear off that scab, it's going to it's going to reveal an awful lot of things
that can't get revealed.
So you just tell Dick Helms and Vernon Walters
that if they don't get out of that right away,
all the Mexico stuff is going to come out about the Bay of Pigs guys.
That's what he said.
That's the smoking gun conversation that nobody can figure out what it means.
Nobody can figure out what it means.
But that's exactly what he said.
Because as it turns out, the the the guys, the guys in the Watergate Hotel,
in addition to the Cubans were Howard Hughes and Frank Sturgis,
as you may recall, along with G.
Gordon Liddy. OK.
But it turns out that Frank Sturgis was in control of one of the five
paramilitary bases on no name key. Right.
No, on Swan Island.
He was on Swan Island.
And the other one in the Everglades was the Howard Hunt.
These were the CIA liaisons to those Cubano groups
that were doing the assaults into into Cuba.
And they were the liaison to the team of people that were put together
to be the assassination team. Right.
And so these are Castro for Castro. Right. That's right.
And so what happened is is that it wasn't the Bay of Pigs thing.
People think, oh, the CIA must kill them because the Bay of Pigs,
they were so upset. That wasn't it.
It was the Cuban Missile Crisis.
The Cuban Missile Crisis in October of sixty two, that what had happened
is the the the Khrushchev and Kennedy had become so totally traumatized
by the fact that they'd come within minutes of a complete
total nuclear annihilation of the planet,
that the two of them started having these secret communications.
And they were actually they they exchanged 18 letters
that people don't know about through through cousins.
His name was that was moving, was delivering the letters back and forth
between Khrushchev and Kennedy.
And what they were doing is they were the two of them were discussing
disassembling the nuclear warheads of the entire nuclear arsenal
of the United States and Russia.
And they just freaked out when they found out about this
and said, this guy's got to go.
Kennedy, Kennedy's got to go.
We can't wait for the election.
You know, this is this is November of sixty two or sixty three rather.
You know, it's a whole year before the election.
He's going to exercise his executive authority as the commander in chief
to order the disassembling of the nuclear warheads.
And Khrushchev is going to do the same for the Soviet Union.
And it's going to be brokered by John the 23rd.
Pope John the 23rd is going to be the broker of making sure they both comply
with this because Khrushchev liked him and trusted him.
And of course, Kennedy did, too.
And that's the process that was underway.
And so what happened is the the Cuban guys wanted wanted to kill
wanted to kill Kennedy because when when the when the Cuban
Missile Crisis had happened, that he was so freaked out
that he ordered the shutting down of all five of the bases.
And it was freaked out that that Kennedy was so freaked out
about how close they had come to having nuclear war that he promised Khrushchev
that he was because what happened is after the Bay of Pigs,
Kennedy apologized, right, for for having authorized the attempted invasion
at the Bay of Pigs.
Yeah. And there was also there was declassified.
There was there was two operations.
I think one was called Northwoods and there was another one.
Maybe it was just Northwoods where they were going to have Northwoods.
They were going to have they were going to fly a plane,
a remote controlled plane and blow it up and say the Cubans did it.
And they were also going to have some attacking Cubans
killing people in Miami and three things.
They were going to blow up an airplane and say that it had been done by Castro.
They were going to attack Guantanamo base.
They were actually going to dress up a number of
Cuban refugees in Cuban military uniforms and attack and kill
personnel at the Guantanamo military base.
And they were going to blow up shopping malls in Miami,
is specifically targeting members of the Cuban,
anti Castro Cuban refugee community to blow them up,
to totally make them hysterical so that they would then be able to blame it on
Castro. Right.
So all of that all that stuff was going on.
But after the after the the Bay of Pigs
fiasco, Kennedy apologized and took responsibility for it.
Right. And then what he did is he promised Khrushchev
that he would stand down Operation 40 that was running the attacks
under Nixon that had been running the attacks on the island.
Right. And against Cuba.
And so Kennedy said he was going to stand them down.
And then he went down to Miami and in the Orange Bowl did a big presentation
to the Cuban community that he gave them his solemn word
that the flag of a free Cuba would fly over the island by the end of his second
term. He gave them that promise, that solemn promise.
Right. And the problem is he didn't he didn't order them shut down.
He had lied to to Khrushchev and they just transformed Operation 40
into a thing called J.M.
Wave and they ran it off the Miami base.
They had a great big base called J.M.
Wave and they they changed it from Operation 40 to Operation
Mongoose was the code name for it.
Right. Right. OK. But he continued to run it.
And so what happened is when when Khrushchev realized that Kennedy had lied to him
after the Bay of Pigs and he was not standing down the operation,
that's when he started sending the missiles in.
Right. OK. And so he put all those missiles in.
And when Kennedy later in October of 62 found out about it,
that's that's from April of 1960 when they actually had the Bay of Pigs thing
happened. There was almost two years later in October when they discovered that
the missiles were there.
But in the interim, what had happened is is that when the missile crisis
came down in October of 62,
Kennedy and Khrushchev, I said, were so freaked out by it that they started exchanging
these these letters and that they were trying to have a detente.
And they were going to be not only not only was Kennedy going to
to agree to shut down the bases, but he ordered the shutting down of the bases.
And he said, this is for real this time.
You know, he had lied before saying they were going to close him down and they
didn't. But now he ordered him to close down.
And Frank Sturgis from Swan Island, after receiving the order from the president
to shut down all those bases, Frank Sturgis launched another attack against
Cuba and sank a Russian ship in the harbor of Havana
that could have caused a total shit storm, you know,
and would have caused Khrushchev to think that Kennedy was lying to him again.
So Bobby and John sent in six helicopter gunships
filled with U.S. Marshals and burnt out Swan Island,
the base and arrested the people there, including Frank Sturgis and the guys.
And they arrested them and charged them with the Violation Neutrality Act.
And the guys were furious at him. Right.
And then he released them after three days saying, that's a shot across the bow.
Knock it off. Right. But then E.
Howard Hunt over in the Everglades started planning a second attack against Cuba
in complete defiance of the orders of the president to shut down those bases and
cease and desist from that program.
And Howard Hughes was getting set to do it again.
And Kennedy and Bobby and John sent in the helicopter gunships and burnt out
the base in the Everglades and arrested them all and charged them.
And these guys were dedicated. They're going to kill this asshole. Right.
And so that was that was all in October, November, December,
actually, December of 1962. All that happened. Right.
And and when Kennedy was then mounted,
he was exchanging these letters with Khrushchev. Right.
These 18 letters with Norman Cousins delivering the letters back and forth.
And they were planning to do this thing.
And one of the things that Kennedy was going to do as a show of good faith is on
June 5th of 1963,
same day that Walter Sullivan ended up reporting to Bobby that there was an
assassination team that had been fielded to kill Castro,
which they didn't even know about. It's all total bullshit.
People trying to lie and say that the Kennedys put together the assassination
team to kill Castro. Totally untrue.
It was Richard Nixon and we've got it directly from Santos Traficante that gave
us all the details of how it was done and when it was done and who was in it and
everything. Right. And so what,
what Kennedy did is on June 5th of 1963,
Walter Sullivan tells Bobby Kennedy about the assassination team.
Kennedy orders them to stand that operation down and what they do is in
defiance of the, of the order,
they put together one last attempt to go into the Island of Cuba and assassinate
Castro. That took place between June 13th and 19th of 1963.
You know, and it was guys from the assassination team, guys from the S force.
And they, they were under the, under the leadership.
We know exactly who ran them all.
One of my investigators was on the boat with them.
Actually, when they went down there,
when they went down to the assassination. Cause he, at the time was the,
was the head of the Miami office of life magazine.
And, and what's it said? The, the guy, the loose,
Henry loose, who's the head of a time magazine in life magazine,
wanted to have a person on board when they got it so they could get the pictures
of the people that went and assassinated Castro. Right.
And so Dick Billings is on the boat assigned to go on the boat with them.
And so we know perfectly well that they tried another assassination attempt
against Castro on, on the fifth of,
from the order to stand down on June 5th of 1963.
And on the same day, Kennedy, you know,
demanded from the CIA all their UFO information.
Wanted to have all the UFO information cause he was going to give that to, to,
to Khrushchev because they wanted to show,
of show good faith and they wanted to join together in the space,
the space program.
Kennedy offered Khrushchev partnership in the joint U S Soviet
space program and was going to send to him the information about the UFO stuff,
which has caused all kinds of people in the UFO community to go, Oh,
that's why they killed him.
The reason they killed him is cause he was going to give up the UFO.
That wasn't it.
You know, John Newman?
Yes, I know John.
He was just sitting here a couple of days ago. Yeah. He is,
he's got a, I mean, he's written, like he's written the books.
He's written all the books on, he's read all the documents,
all the documents. I know he hates when people talk about daily Plaza.
He's like, it's the daily Plaza water cooler.
It's all a distraction from what really happened.
He talks about the, the Colonel Lemitzer and Maxwell Taylor,
who were the joint chief of staff who had the sire and Curtis,
and Curtis Lamey, Curtis Lamey. Yeah. Big Curtis, big Curtis Lamey.
Absolutely. Right.
And they had a big plan for a total and nuclear annihilation of the Soviet
Oh, yes. Oh, yes. Oh, absolutely. Oh, absolutely.
No, that whole operation is going down and they were almost completely out of
him under control of Kennedy, you know, and, and, and so, so the,
but the bottom line is, is that what happened is that when,
when they learned of the exchange of these letters and what Kennedy was getting
ready to do, the team was all ready to want to kill him. In fact, on the boat,
on the Flying Tiger, which was William B. Pauley,
William D. Pauley, big honcho owned the big sugar mills
down in, in Cuba and owned the private bus transportation lines in
Cuba. You know, William D. Pauley,
it was on his boat that they went down to try to do that assassination in the
middle of June of 1963.
And Dick Billings is standing on the deck of the boat, the Flying Tiger II,
along with William D. Pauley in Johnny Marino,
Johnny, Johnny, Johnny Martini,
Johnny Martini is standing on the boat with him. And
what was the guy's name? Rip Robertson was the guy's name.
Rip Robertson was the actual field commander for the S-Force. It wasn't Carl,
Carl Jenkins didn't, wasn't the field commander. He was the trainer for them.
But Rip Robertson was the field director for these guys, right?
And so, so he's, he's, Rip Robertson is standing on the boat.
William D. Pauley is standing there and Johnny Martino, Martino,
his name was, and Dick Billings are all standing there.
And, and Johnny Martino is just raging about the Kennedys,
about what rotten bastards they are and how they lied.
And they gave their word that they were going to have a free flag of Cuba flying
over there, over the, and he was raging like this.
And William D. Pauley turned to Johnny Martino in the presence of all
those guys and said, don't worry, Johnny, we're going to kill that motherfucker.
And that was, that was on June, that weekend of June 13th,
14th, 15th of 1963 on board the Flying Tiger II with Dick Billings
standing right there next to him.
And Dick has told me the entire story in detail and the first person
proof of it being there, you know? And so that, that's,
so when, as soon as he heard that the president had been killed, he knew,
he said, I knew exactly who had done it.
And he became the chief of staff for the house select committee on assassinations.
So do you think that these,
these Cubans really wanted, I mean,
do you think that had anything to do with the actual assassination of Kennedy?
Or do you think it was the military just using these guys?
No, I mean, they're the ones that did it. I mean,
they're the ones that pulled the trigger, but it was, it was Alan Dulles.
It was Alan Dulles, not because he was disgruntled because he'd been fired as
the head of the CIA.
The reason he was the head of the CIA is because he was general counsel for
Brown Brothers Harriman. Brown Brothers Harriman is the key to this thing.
Yeah. It's going to sip us up liquid death. Murder your thirst.
Yeah. Brown Brothers Harriman is the key to this thing.
Because Brown Brothers Harriman was the group of like 20 of the richest
families in the, in the country.
The robber barons all came together and this informed this group called the
Brown Brothers Harriman. They were based in New York city.
And the heads of all of the, you know, the, the,
the Carnegie's and the Rockefellers and the, the
Harriman, they owned the rail lines and they owned the steel mills.
They owned the agribusiness corporations. They owned the cattle association.
They owned these key elements of the major economy of the entire United States
during the robber baron era. You know, openly, I mean, that's who they were.
And they sat and they made policy together.
And the bottom line is the chief,
the CEO for Brown Brothers Harriman was George Herbert Walker.
That's who he is.
That's the maternal grandfather of George Herbert Walker Bush and the great
grandfather of George Herbert W or George W Walker Bush. Okay.
He's the guy and they, and Alan Dulles was the legal counsel for Brown Brothers
Harriman.
That's why he was appointed to be the first civilian head of the CIA and the guy
who wrote the original memo to Truman recommending the creation of the CIA was
Robert Lovett, who was the senior partner of Brown Brothers Harriman.
This was the crowd in the, just so you,
just so you'll know that George Herbert Walker in 1924 stepped down as the CEO at
the end of World War I.
He stepped down in 1924 and handed over the CEO position to his brother,
his son-in-law Prescott Bush. Right.
And then he went and set up the union bank of New York,
which was capitalized by the major corporate guys that were the funders and the
supporters of Brown Brothers Harriman. Right.
They were the members in the investment group.
They capitalized the union bank of New York.
They set up a foreign subsidiary of the union bank of New York in the Netherlands
called the bank of shipping and commerce held up by Fritz Theisen.
They completely financed the construction of the international headquarters of
the third Reich. Right. Absolutely stone cold verified.
Right.
Because there was their intention to have the Germany rise to power again after
the end of World War I.
And then they would become the bulwark against Bolshevism in Europe because the
Bolsheviks had taken over in ousted czar Nicholas II at the end of World War I
and withdrawn Russia from World War I.
And the secretary of state under Wilson,
whose name was Robert Lansing,
Robert Lansing was married to the oldest daughter of John W. Foster,
who was the grandfather of John Foster Dulles and Alan Dulles that he was the
secretary of state in 1893 that that overthrew the Hawaiian islands and the
or through Guam.
Their whole plan was to have Germany stand to stride all of Europe is the
bulwark against Bolshevism and they would go westward out into the Pacific and
they would develop the entire Asian market.
That was what Brown Brothers Harriman was all up to.
That's what they were going to be doing.
They were funding the rise of the third Reich to control Germany.
And what they did, you love this one.
What they did is Robert Lansing, who was his son-in-law, right.
Of John W. Foster or yeah,
that that he is secretary of state under under Wilson is the one that dispatched
the foreign missionary for the foreign expeditionary force into Russia to try to
crush the Bolsheviks.
There was a straight up military operation run by the United States to send a
foreign military expeditionary force into Russia to try to crush the Bolshevik
revolution in the cradle, which you almost never hear about.
The reason I know about it,
because I had Gov 122 from Henry Kissinger at Harvard college.
He was my professor in foreign United States, American foreign policy.
So we know about this.
Right. And so John W.
Foster, his son-in-law,
Robert Lansing is the one that ordered them in to try to crush the Bolshevik
revolution. And he is the guy that supervised the treaty,
the treaty of Versailles in 1918. Right.
And he took his two nephews who were John W.
John Foster Dulles and Alan Dulles, who were the grandsons of John W. Foster.
He was their maternal grandfather. Right. And he put them into,
they were on the staff of the Versailles treaty negotiations.
They're the ones that drafted into the Versailles treaty,
the reparations demands against Germany. Okay.
And so they imposed the reparations demands on Germany had lost World War I.
And then what they did is they turned around and negotiated loans from
the people that were in Brown Brothers Harriman, the investors, to pay,
give loans to the German government to pay the reparations,
which were being paid to corporations who had lost property in the war.
Okay. And then what they did is in exchange for the loans,
they took stock in their major war industry,
the Krupp ball bearing factories and IG Farben chemical core. Right.
So these guys ended up owning major shares of the war industry in
Germany.
And what they were doing is financing the rebuilding of the entire military
machine of Germany.
At the same time they were actually funding through the union bank of New York
in the bank of shipping and commerce in the Netherlands,
building and financing the entire rise of the third Reich to establish them as
the bulwark against Bolshevism in Europe.
When they turned their attention westward to go out into the Pacific and take over
the Hawaiian islands and Guam and the Marshall islands, et cetera,
marching their way onto Asia so they could develop the Asian markets there.
That's what they call the China lobby.
That's the group that was at Brown Brothers Harriman.
And the reason it's so important is because when Kennedy was talking about
disassembling the warheads of the nuclear arsenal of the United States,
along with Russia's,
that totally freaked them out because they knew that they needed to
have the nuclear weapons, not against Russia,
against China because China could put a billion men in uniform in
the field against them. As they showed them at Incheon in Korea,
they had already showed. And so that's, that's what they were worried about.
Okay.
But also this was the time,
this was a specific time when we had the most nuclear weapons in Russia,
Russia had the least.
That's right. And Russia was willing to disband all the Russian missiles.
And China was agreeing to never build any missiles if the United States would
just stop building them and would disarm.
And just like with poison gas at the end of World War I, the mustard gas,
don't do this anymore. It's completely, you know,
a violation of all the rules of war. You know,
it's a complete violation of the just war theory.
Nuclear weapons are inherently designed to destroy civilian populations by the
millions. You know,
it's a complete and total violation of the just war theory.
And we wrote about this at Jesuit headquarters when I was there as general
council in their social ministry office,
Brian Hare wrote a major piece about their just war theory.
And we got the Jesuit order to agree to condemn the mere possession of nuclear
missiles as a mortal sin,
because it's inherently designed to violate the premises of the just war theory.
Oh, this is a little more complex than you need, but the bottom,
the bottom line is that we've been on top of this for years of monitoring what
these people have been doing. Okay. And that's what they did in that.
So that whole operation, when,
when Kennedy was being so traumatized at the coming right to the brink of
thermonuclear Holocaust started exchanging the letters with Khrushchev to
disassemble the nuclear warheads of the United States nuclear arsenal and all of
Russia's, these guys said, that's it. This guy's got to go.
We can't leave him in place because he's going to have another whole year to do
this. And that's why they ordered the killing.
And the fact is the team was there. It was fully prepared, fully trained.
They had maintained a, an arm's length relationship from them.
It wasn't tracked directly to the white house unless somebody ratted out Richard
Nixon. Right. And so,
so what happened is when Kennedy ends up getting killed and people said,
holy shit, it's the S force that killed him.
The agency rolled right into place and started covering up everything,
started destroying evidence, started lying,
started doing everything because they were terrified that they'd be blamed for
killing the president. And Richard Nixon did the same thing.
He was terrified that he was going to get blamed for killing the president.
You know, and so what happened is Lyndon Johnson,
Lyndon Johnson reached out to, to, uh, Warren, Earl Warren,
the chief justice of the Supreme court and said,
we need to have you head up the Warren commission to investigate the
assassination.
But the one thing you can't do do not reveal the fact that there was an
assassination team that was in the field to kill Fidel Castro.
Because if that ever leaks out,
people are going to think that Castro found out about the assassination team,
that the Kennedys put together to kill him and probably killed him.
And if they do that, we're going to be into world war three.
And that's how he got real foreign to agree to chair the Warren commission.
And who he put on it to run the commission is Alan Dulles.
Yeah. Why did they get Alan Dulles to run the commission?
Because you would be able to totally total, keep it locked down. Right.
Absolutely. And that's what, and that's what they did. You know,
Felix Rodriguez wasn't a part of that team that killed Kennedy though, right?
Yes, he was. Stop. That's what I just got there telling you.
He was on the S force. It was the S force there in daily plasma. Yes,
he was. Yeah. As was Ed Lansdale, as was,
as was a rip Robertson or photographs of rip Robertson standing right there.
Are there photographs of Felix there? No.
Then how do we know for sure he was there?
Because he was a major part of the S force.
Yeah. But we have no proof. He was actually there. No photos. No.
If you don't have photos, it doesn't mean you don't have the proof. I mean,
the fact is no, no. Oh wait. Oh, you need, but you need other kind of evidence.
You need other evidence, paper trail, all kinds of evidence of who the S force
was, you know, and there's one guy remaining living who could tell everybody
about it, you know, but he hasn't done it yet.
What, what evidence do we have that he was, that Felix was actually there though?
Cause Rafael Chichi-Quintero told us so. Oh, oh.
Rafael Quintero.
Cause Quintero was there too in the Morales.
The Indian was the guy that pulled the trigger that killed him from the,
from the Noel. That was Roger Morales.
He was the, the, a shooter for the, for the S force, you know.
What did Felix say when you deposed him?
Well, he wouldn't talk about it. All the, all they ever said,
all they ever said is, you know, I take the fifth amendment.
Has he ever acknowledged anything about the, uh,
the team that was sent to Cuba to kill Castro or?
He's never even admitted that he was in charge of the Ilopango operation,
providing weapons to the Contras. Really? Yeah.
Are you aware of the, uh, the Kiki Camarena case? Oh, sure. I am. Sure. I am.
Do you think Felix was part of that? Was there?
Well, the, the, it was operation Condor that killed him in Condor was based out
of Pemex out of the Mexican national oil corporation. It, uh, uh,
Jose Diaz Sorano. Yeah.
Jose Diaz Sorano who was the head of Pemex was the former business partner
with George Bush senior in the Zapata oil corporation. Uh,
and they, they hid out the assassination team in Pemex's security department.
That's where I feel Chichi Quintero and Felix Rodriguez, you know,
ask Felix about that, you know, ask him, what,
what were you doing in the Pemex security department in Mexico city?
You know, and that's Condor. That's that whole operation.
The assassination teams that were deployed in South America were all run out of
Pemex, you know,
and the reason they wanted to get a Kiki Camarena is cause he was like being
really loud about Iran Contra.
Well, no, the drug was the, the drug smuggling stuff. I mean,
Kiki Camarena was a major DEA guy. He was a close,
he was a close friend of Michael Levine's Michael Levine was one of the,
the top undercover guys in DEA, you know,
and Kiki Camarena was killed for that reason. But there, there's a,
there's a guy because, but B because he was stopping the drugs, right?
And we wanted, we didn't want that to be stopped.
Not that we didn't want them to be stopped. They were running them. Right. Right.
I interviewed face to face the deputy CIA station chief,
Joseph Berkholder Smith,
who sat right there and told me all about the details.
He had been actually brought to a meeting, you know, in Mexico city,
by, by, what's his name? The guy that was head of the DFS in Mexico.
Nasser Haro. Oh, pull your mic closer. Yeah. Yeah. He was, he was,
he was the Joseph Berkholder Smith, Joseph Berkholder Smith was
brought to a meeting actually by, by Nasser Haro,
who was the head of the DFS in Mexico and sat down right in,
I've been a place called Salta in the Northern Northern tip of,
of Argentina, you know,
sat in the meeting with these guys sitting right there and talking about the
you know,
sat in the meeting with these guys sitting right at the table,
this big open table with the big stone fireplace behind them with the swastika
on the mantle, you know, in there and said, look at, he said, you know,
there's, there's been some discussion that Tom Polgar has just been made the new
head of the station here in Mexico city.
And it's not clear whether you're going to be left on Joe Joseph Berkholder Smith.
It's not clear you're going to be left on as his deputy.
So what we wanted to do is have a talk with you. You know,
we have spent a lot of time and energy creating a major cocaine cartel down in
Columbia.
And we're going to be moving the cocaine into the United States and a portion of
those funds are going to be used to help finance our war without boundaries
against your enemies and ours.
And we want to make sure that if you're going to be left in place,
that you aren't going to do anything to interfere with that.
Joseph Berkholder Smith said to me, look, Danny, he said,
I don't know what I'd ever done in my life that would have led them to believe
that I would have gone along with that. And I said,
how about being the deputy CIA station chief in Mexico city for a start?
And he turned to Dick Billings, who was sitting there with me,
who was the chief of staff for the house select committee on assassinations by
that time. And he said, Hey,
I thought this guy was going to cooperate with us. And Dick said, look,
I just met the guy. You know,
so that's, those are all detailed stories of people with firsthand knowledge of,
of what it is that they've been doing, you know, now they are,
that they feel perfectly righteous about it. You know,
I don't doubt that the Rafael Chichi Quintero and Felix Rodriguez and Morales
and Rolando Martinez and, and Ricardo Chavez,
and all the guys that were on the shooter team thought that they were totally
righteous, you know, and doing what they were doing. They were,
they ended up stopping the guy who was a, in their mind,
a total whoremonger, you know, and a lying sack of shit who was president,
you know, basically father bought him the, you know,
the offices that he got. That's how they viewed Kennedy. Yeah.
That's how they viewed Kennedy, you know?
And he was getting set to use his power to disassemble the nuclear warheads of
our entire nuclear arsenal, you know? And so that they, they said, you know,
button, put the button on this guy.
Wow. You are like,
you're like a, a walking historical information machine.
Well, I was at Jesuit headquarters for 10 years, you know, I mean,
they didn't get their reputation for nothing.
The amount of knowledge you have is incredible, man. It is,
it is amazing to sit here and listen to you talk about some of this stuff.
There are very,
there are very few people who have got direct firsthand information directly
from Santos Traficante, you know,
about the details of putting together the entire assassination team, you know,
and what his direct relationship is to the, to the Watergate burglary, you know,
nobody, nobody knows about the, the,
the sequentially numbered bills in Bernard Barker's pocket coming from the
Banco Internacional, except for, except for Mark, Mark Flint,
you know, that he knew, he knew it, you know,
and he's deep throat. Wow. That's who he is.
You know, Mark felt, you know, that's the guy. Why they call him deep throat.
That was the nickname that Bob Woodward gave him.
Cause he was the, he was the source of deep throat in the Watergate burglary.
He's the one that kept meeting with Bob Woodward in the garage and,
and pointing him towards, I said, follow the money. He said, follow the money.
And as soon as they got to the money and they discovered the money,
that, that had been deposited into the committee to reelect the president,
had been deposited down in the,
the Ogarrio account in Mexico city and the Banco Internacional, you know,
they said, Oh, bingo. We've got, we've got Richard Nixon's president,
a committee to reelect the president funding the people in the Watergate
hotel. That's it. Bingo. They were stopping right there.
And they never went in deeper and discovered what the hell's the story on that
particular fund that's down there.
It would lead right back to the assassination team that killed the president,
you know, and they, and they, and they settled for it.
Bob Woodward and Bernstein settled for the half a story.
I mean, it was a big hat, a big story that they,
they got funds that had been given a check from, what's his name?
He wrote the check that went into the bank, into the,
into the Banco Internacional down in Mexico city, you know,
from the committee to reelect the president.
Now McCone was the head of the CIA.
Yeah, he didn't need no shit. They didn't, they wouldn't tell him anything.
But was Helms before Cone, Richard Helms?
No, Helms got, Helms got, got indicted, you know,
for lying, for lying to the, to the Congress for that.
He, he was lying and saying that, that,
that one of the things he lied about is that they,
the Phoenix program only killed 20,000 people,
whereas they killed vastly more than that.
Remind me of the Phoenix program.
Phoenix program was the political assassination program that was run by
Theodore Shackley, who was the CIA station chief in Saigon that,
in that they were using money from the Vang Pao,
the drug money from Vang Pao to finance the Phoenix program.
In Helms, Helms, the man who, who guards the secrets, you know,
he's the one that committed perjury to the,
to Congress to hide the family jewels ended up getting ousted.
He was also the guy who burned all the MK ultra documents, right?
Well, the, it was under him. It was under him personally. Yeah.
Just, just like,
just like the CIA burned all the videos of the Abu Ghraib torture sessions.
You know, they were ordered by Congress to cough them up and they burned them all.
Right. You know what I mean?
So that what we're dealing with is a national security state that's out of
control here, you know, and they're,
they're completely self righteous about what it is they think they're doing,
you know, and, you know,
that any anybody who grew up in the same way that Felix Rodriguez did and
Rafael Chichi Quintero and those guys, you know, their,
their whole world is, you know, is,
they're knowledgeable about the,
what they view as the corrupt nature of Kennedy, you know, I mean,
and they were all sharing the stories about, you know,
I'm fucking anybody who would bend over and, you know, and he was on drugs and he was,
you know, he, his back was out and he was half on drugs. You know, that's,
that's the kind of stories that are going around inside all about them, you know,
and Chichi Quintero and, and, and these guys were sitting at the kitchen table
with my guy, Gene Wheaton,
who was the chief of security for the US military mission in Tehran and who was a,
who was supplying airplanes to the Contras to fly the drugs and guns around,
you know, sitting right at the table listening to them talk about the plans that
they had to kill the president.
That is nuts, man.
Yeah, but it's not, that's the problem.
It really is, man. Like, like, how do you,
your, what is your worldview of the United States of America and the security state
and like the whole military industrial complex and where we're headed?
Are you at all optimistic with all this information that you know,
and the people that you've talked to and the cases that you've been involved with,
like, and, and even going back to like the, the,
the Pentagon papers, like, look at where we're at now in the media.
Like, I'm sure you're familiar with the Twitter files, right?
Oh, yes.
Where do you think all this is headed?
Well, that I think to be pointed,
I think that the UFO issue presents the greatest possible opportunity for
unveiling the lengths to which the national security state has gone in taking
over the control of the government of the United States,
in that they're fascists, you know,
I mean, that the people who created the central intelligence agency, you know,
they're fascists.
And they believe that the most effective way of running the government is to
deploy the instrumentalities of the state on behalf of the interests of the major
corporations.
They believe that what's good for General Motors is good for the country.
And that if you can, and they've got a,
you ought to get a copy of the 1992 United States Defense Department policy,
planning guidance document that was put out directly after Gorbachev stood back.
You know, Gorbachev disassembled the Soviet Union on March 30,
on December 31st of 1991. He released all of them. The following Monday,
you know, Paul Wolfowitz, you know, under Dick Cheney,
who's the secretary of defense for, for George Bush senior, you know,
convenes his group of people in the West wing of the White House.
And you got Paul Wolfowitz and it's under Dick Cheney.
You got Scooter Libby. You got Doug Fife. You got Richard Pearl.
You know, they're all there and they're all the special group inside the
defense department, right? Under Dick Cheney, under Bush.
And they draft up the 1992 United States Defense Department policy,
planning guidance document. And they're saying, oh good,
the Soviet Union has stood back out of the cold war. They've stood down.
And now we're going to have all kinds of pressure put on us to try to cut the
military budget because for the last 50 years, you know,
we've been justifying spending now up to $700 billion a year on the
military because we have to stop the Soviet Union from taking over the world.
Right. And that's the rationale that's been put forth for all this time for
this massive military program. You know, the United States,
the United States spends more money on the military every year than the next 10
countries in the world. It's insane. Right.
We've got 800 military bases all around the world, you know,
and we're invading places all over the place.
Most people don't even know about, like everyone focuses on Ukraine and what's
going on in Palestine, but there's so many other wars that are going on.
And what I'm saying is, is that the, that this,
this operation has this, this,
from the age of the robber barons in the age of the robber barons that began in
1868 after the American civil war, right by 1872,
they had actually come up with this concept of creating this new private,
private shareholder owned corporations in that this,
this business entity actually immunizes the owners of the
company from any personal liability whatsoever for whatever the corporation
does.
That that's an essential element of the creation of the new business vehicle of
the private shareholder owned corporation.
So that the corporation itself is the only thing that's liable for anything the
corporation does is the shareholders are completely immunized and the,
the, the board of directors are personally immunized. Okay.
And even the management people are personally immunized.
You can only sue the company itself because the company itself is a person,
you see. Now it wasn't the citizens United was the first time that they came up
with that idea. You know,
that was what the whole fight was about back in 1934 when they,
the whole court packing issue with Franklin Roosevelt,
when he was offering to,
was threatening to appoint more people to the Supreme court.
It was because the United States Supreme court kept ruling consistently that
corporations were persons who were entitled to fundamental rights under the,
under the constitution. And therefore you couldn't interfere with, you couldn't,
you couldn't regulate their advertising because it's free speech, you know,
and you couldn't interfere with their right to contract,
which is a constitutional right that people have the freedom of the contracts
right in the constitution.
And so therefore you can't support labor unions because it's interfering with
the right of the corporation to negotiate one-on-one with people for a contract
for their employment. And they were ruling this over and over again,
all right after the 1929 crash, you know,
by 1932 when, when Franklin Roosevelt was elected,
Franklin Roosevelt started issuing all of these executive orders,
trying to get control over the excesses of the corporate investors
in the corporations that had run rough shot over things. Right.
And so what he was doing is issuing all kinds of federal executive orders.
And this group of people, Brown brothers, Harriman people, the Duponts,
particularly were engaged in planning a military overthrow of
Franklin Roosevelt in 1934. That whole thing with General Butler,
that he, he was,
they tried to recruit him to mount a major military coup against the
against the United States government. So, I mean,
this thing comes right out of the robber barons who had created this particular
device, this business vehicle of a private shareholder owned
corporation that was deemed to be its own independent person.
And liability ran just to the corporation and all the rest of the people were
immunized against any personal liability. And their,
their mandate was to maximize the short-term profits
for the purposes of giving shareholders, you know,
income from the income that they made.
And that vehicle is a sinful structure.
That's what we designated as a Jesuit headquarters.
It's an inherently sinful structure because it's driven by greed and self-interest
and avarice. In fact,
you can be dismissed as a member of the board of a corporation.
If you take into account the public interest,
it's called the doctrine of ultra various. It's called, you know,
and it's a specific doctrine. It's in the books of the law over corporations.
And so what happened is those corporations between 1872,
when they first established that as a new business vehicle,
between 1872 and 1898 when McKinley
came to power in 1898 and his,
Mark Hanna was his, his,
his kind of major advisor. And Mark Hanna
said that the greatest ambition that any human being could possibly have to is
earn as much money as he possibly can before he dies. That's,
that's the quote from Mark Hanna and that's, that's, that's McKinley, right?
And they had, they had risen to the power in 1898 where it became the age of the
robber barons, right? And it was also not coincidentally,
the age of American imperialism. And it's called that in history books.
It's the age of American imperialism.
And it was the person who sort of supervised that whole age of American
imperialism was John W.
Foster, who was the secretary of state.
And he's the one that, that, as I said,
overthrew the Hawaiian islands, Guam, the Marshall islands,
all moving out across the Pacific. That was what their whole objective was.
And they were operating right out of Brown brothers Harriman who were in charge
of organizing the Versailles treaty, you know, under Robert Lansing, you know,
who was the son-in-law of, of John W.
Foster, who was the grandfather of John Foster Dulles and Alan Dulles.
And Alan Dulles was the legal counsel for Brown brothers Harriman,
where these families were all together cooperating in planning how to take over
the American government and how to put the instrumentalities of the government at
the behest of the interests of the private corporations.
That's why they sent the United States military expeditionary force in 1903 into
Nicaragua to overthrow the government down there on behalf of United Fruit,
who was a client of Sullivan and Cromwell.
Sullivan and Cromwell was the law firm that Alan Dulles and John Foster Dulles
were members, were partners in, being legal counsel for Brown brothers Harriman.
That's who these people are. I mean,
these people get up and put their pants on one leg at a time,
just like anything else. If you investigate them closely enough, you'll find it.
If you can remember the names of everybody,
if you can remember the pattern of where they are, they go, oh yeah,
there they are again. You know, oh, here they are again. Here's the bank.
That's they're the ones doing it, you know? And so we know who they are.
We know what their lineage is. And we know that these are the people,
for example, that in 1945,
in 1945 December after the dropping of the atomic
bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki, remember the, the,
the Nazis in Germany had surrendered in May of 1945,
but the Japanese had not.
And so the Japanese knew that the entire allied forces were going to turn their
attention to Japan, right?
And so they started removing all the gold and silver and platinum and jewels and
stuff that had been garnered over a 30 year period by the
Japanese empire had been sweeping all through South Asia, you know,
in taking all the gold and silver and platinum and everything and bringing it
into Japan as their war chest for the major imperial war
that the Japan was getting ready to mount. Okay.
And they had all of those riches that were there.
So what they did is they smuggled them out and they moved them into the
Philippines and they buried them in 176 separate
tranches in the Philippines, like, you know,
like 700 feet deep, the huge mine shafts that they built,
you know, and they did it with slave labor.
And the people who dug the mine shafts and they buried a hundred.
The Japanese were doing this.
Japanese are doing this a hundred, a hundred billion
dollars each, each trove,
176 troves of a hundred billion dollars each
in gold. I mean, the photographs that you can see in the, they're,
they're shoulder high stacks of gold bullion, as big as football fields.
You can see them and they buried them under the, in the Philippines. Right.
And in the G two,
the G two for the United States army in Manila was Ed Lansdale.
Edward Lansdale had been an OSS guy and Truman disbanded the OSS as
soon as the Nazis surrendered in May of 1945.
So he just, he distributed everybody from the OSS out around the world. Right.
And Ed Lansdale ended up being the G two in Manila.
And he knew that the guy who was in charge of gathering all of
that gold and silver together was a guy named General Yakushima.
General Yakushima was the guy who ran a thing called the golden lily was
the Chinese code name for the,
for the unit that was into pilfering all the gold and silver and platinum all
through Asia and bringing it into Japan.
And he supervised the burying of these 176 troves in the Philippines.
And what happened is Ed Lansdale,
when General Yakushima turned himself in surrendered after the Japanese
surrendered,
he kidnapped the driver for Yakushima
and torch had him tortured to find out where some of these treasures were.
And they actually,
they actually found 12 of these out of the 176,
$1.2 trillion at
$32 an ounce of gold, which is now like $1,400 an ounce. Right.
And what they did is they, they punched one of those, those, and he,
yeah, there they are. That this, this is the people, people,
people don't understand it. Yamashita.
Generally Yamashita is the guy that, that stored all this gold there.
And Ed Lansdale got his hands on 12 of 12 of these troves for
$1.2 trillion in true. He had Truman McCarthy,
MacArthur, General MacArthur set up a private,
they set up a private trust under Truman that was run by
Brown Brothers Harriman for $1.2 trillion.
They, they, they took the 12 of them, the $1.2 trillion,
and they shipped it all out and they put it in the international credit and
international credit bank in Geneva,
Switzerland and issued gold certificates on it to pay for covert operations,
you know, completely independent from Congress.
Never told Congress about it at all to this day.
I've never told Congress about it, you know,
and they've been using it as covert operations.
You know, they got, they've got all of it still.
Because what they did is they issued gold certificates. They didn't,
they didn't have to do anything with the gold. They left it there.
What they did is they issued gold certificates that are just like bearer bonds
and they use them for cash.
And it's a, it's a major source of funds for the covert operations.
You know, I mean, that's what we've been dealing with all this time.
That's how people kept saying,
how in the world did these people know all this stuff? You know,
they were going crazy because we set up,
we set up the Christchurch Institute out of Washington, DC,
out of the Jesuit headquarters.
We set up the Christchurch Institute as a 501c3 public interest law firm.
And I had access to all these investigators out of Bailey's office. You know,
we had, we had like 30 class a licensed gun toters that were investigators for
us, you know,
and we're in the public interest domain because most all of these guys want to
be good guys, you know, and that they gotten, they've gotten perverted. You know,
they, they come in to try to, try to do,
do right and they discover that the people they work for major corporations,
you know, CIA or government agencies that they're corrupted.
And so we set up the Christchurch Institute,
which gave everybody a chance to be good guys, you know,
and try to just find out what's going on and what they're doing, you know,
and if you disagree with what they're doing, you know, then tell us, you know,
so that, you know, so,
so the bottom line is we've been doing,
we've been in this business now for like 50 years, you know,
and we ran the Christchurch Institute for 20 years in Washington, DC.
We've run the Romero Institute, you know,
for 20 years in California because George H.W.
Bush ordered the revocation of our 501c3 tax exempt charter for the Christchurch
Institute because of our bringing the Iran-Contra federal criminal racketeering
charges against the off the shelf enterprise.
And we just exposed everything about them and their drug smuggling and the
assassination programs and everything. And and when the judge in Miami,
dismissed our case because he,
he excluded four eyewitnesses who in the case who could verify this case we
brought under the federal criminal racketeering act, he dismissed the case.
And George Bush contacted his politically appointed head of the internal
revenue service and directed him to yank our 501c3 tax exempt charter on the
grounds that nobody had been ultimately criminally convicted of the charges that
we made against them,
even though six of them had already been indicted by the special prosecutor,
Lawrence Walsh, right? For exactly what we charged them with.
And then he pardoned them after he was beaten in the 1992 election in November
by, by, you know, Bill Clinton,
but more importantly by Ross Perot who took 19% of the vote away from George Bush
because Ross Perot was a guy I was flying around in his Learjet with him telling
him all about this.
And in Ross Perot was the guy that brought the complaint to the FBI,
to Bill Webster. And that's why,
that's why they initiated the investigation of the Iran Contra people.
And so,
so Ed Meese caught his hair on fire and freaked out and ran in and held an
immediate press conference going, Oh, what do you know? Faith and Bogota.
We discovered that there's this young renegade Lieutenant Colonel Oliver North,
who's run off and basically gone recruiting old retired military people,
you know,
on the golf courses around Virginia and set up this kind of off the shelf
enterprise. Oh, you know, we better have a special prosecutor appointed.
And I, Ed Meese,
will draft up the charter to limit their investigation to whether the president
directly authorized the transfer of the profits that were generated by the sale
of tow missiles to the Hezbollah, to the Contras, you know,
under Adolfo Calero, whether he did that, you know,
and whether the president authorized that in writing. And if he did,
then he could get in trouble. But if he didn't, then we're all okay.
And so he crafted the, the, the, uh, he,
he crafted the charter for the special prosecutor in the, in the, the, uh,
Iran Contra case so narrowly that he thought he was going to get away with it.
And not only that,
but the person they selected to be the special prosecutor to investigate it was
Lawrence Walsh, you know, a noted repug,
and it turns out Lawrence Walsh was the Lawrence Walsh was the senior partner in
Crow Dunleavy, which is the law firm.
We kicked the absolute out of in the Karen Silkwood case for 10 and a half
million dollars.
And they thought that he was just furious with us because we destroyed his
reputation as a law firm.
And we just mopped the floor with them in that case because we had everything on
them. You know, and the,
and they picked him to be the special prosecutor and it backfired because he
knew we were right. I mean,
he'd already paid the price for not understanding that we knew what we were
doing.
And so we were the very first ones contacted by Lawrence Walsh to fill him in on
what was going on. And he indicted the shit out of these people.
I was going after all of them and he was going after George Bush,
senior because who was totally involved in it. You know, George,
George Bush, who was the vice president under,
under Reagan is the one who coordinated the whole off the shelf enterprise
as the head of the 5412 committee, just like, just like Nixon had been under
Eisenhower.
He was the head of the 5412 committee as the vice president in Nixon's,
Nixon's national security or Bush's national security advisor,
Donald P. Greg was having direct face to face meetings with Felix Rodriguez.
Okay. Who was running the Ilepongo air operations,
delivering the weapons and smuggling the cocaine right on the same airplanes.
In fact,
the head of the DEA took photographs of them loading the cocaine onto the
planes and gave them to us, you know, so that we had them.
Another guy I've had on here who I have, I'm nervous.
You might know who he is. Is Rick Prado.
I've heard of Rick Prado, but I don't, I've not interviewed him.
Yeah. Okay. He was not working directly with,
I don't think he was working with Felix, but he knows Felix. Yeah.
And Rick was sent down to Honduras to train the Sandinistas or the Contras.
No, the Contras. The Contras. The Contras. Yeah. He was sent down under Jack
Singalow. Right. Yeah. He was sent down there to train the Contras. Yeah.
And that's Prado. Yeah. And yeah. And he, and he was, you know,
part of that whole paramilitary operation. And after that,
he was actually sent back to CIA and put through the whole spy class,
spy school. And then he went down to Costa Rica.
Yeah, for sure. To be on the southern border of Nicaragua and like doing all
kinds of... That's where Hull's Ranch was.
That's John Hull's Ranch in Costa Rica where they flew the stuff in and out of
all the time. That was the guy. Yeah. He was there doing all kinds of crazy shit.
Yeah. No, he was. I've done his deposition too.
Oh, really? Yeah. Yeah. Oh my Lord.
You've been everywhere. Not everywhere,
but just enough to be able to tell what's going on. Yeah.
One of the things I think about a lot is
if the military or some of these military
contractors had information or had
technology that would render
them useless, or render,
that would render any sort of nuclear weapon or any
sort of war machine completely useless, right?
Like if there was some sort of technology they had that they didn't
fully understand how to use, that we knew was real, right?
Not even... I'm not even going to talk about where it was from.
Like say it was... Who knows where it was from.
Yeah. Let's not pretend it's from the UFOs. Right. Let's pretend it.
Let's just say they found it washed up on a beach somewhere and we
had multiple of these things and we knew other countries had these things too.
What would they do if they had the
technology and they knew if whatever
is behind the technology would completely change the
world and it would completely change the dynamic of
nation states, right? Like if war was no longer a driving
factor and it would destroy their business model,
because that's how they survive is from developing weapons and doing all this
blue sky research on how to do all this sci-fi shit that DARPA is doing.
It makes sense that they would want to keep it a secret.
And I don't know what it would take to
make that stuff come to light. And I don't see,
I don't see them letting go of it.
Well, the problem is it's even worse than that.
It's one step worse than that.
That in the 1992 United States Defense Department of Policy Planning
Guidance document that I told you about, that they drafted up, you know,
starting on the Monday morning after the dissolution of the Soviet Union,
what they did is they put this document together and they said that the reason
that we don't want to step back and reduce our military budget,
just because the Soviet Union has been disbanded now and that we've been
rationalizing the $700 billion a year on the grounds that we had to protect
ourselves against them. The reason that we want to have,
we want to increase the military budget because now we have the chance to
establish full spectrum dominance over the planet.
And the purpose of this will be to maintain, quote,
to maintain our continued privileged access to the strategic raw materials
needed by our major corporations. Okay.
Cause that's what they do. And they view that as they are Rome.
They are the aggressor. You asked me what,
what my idea about the national security is.
They are the aggressors on the planet. Okay.
And what they're doing is they're working at the behest of the major
corporations and the wealthiest families that own the shares of stock.
It's just as bad as you think it is, you know, is that they view their,
they view their job as securing their continued privileged access to the
strategic raw materials.
I've sat and had direct conversations with the people that'll tell you that if
there's some third world country that is sitting on some sort of major resource
that turns out to be of real value economically or militarily for us,
if we don't go get it first, China or Russia, we'll go get it.
So we'll go get it first. And that's aggressive war.
That is a violation of every single premise of a just war theory.
You are the aggressor. You are the bad guy, you know, that, uh,
that's I had the experience when I got ready to leave to go to college,
I grew up with my aunt and uncle and my uncle was the head of the Republican
County committee up in Warren County, up in Northern New York, right?
And I'm getting set to leave to go down to Boston to go to college.
He brings me out. He's the head of the civil,
he's the civil defense director for the whole County.
And he goes out and we stand in our front yard and from our front yard,
you look North into Canada and for a hundred miles,
all there are is forest, the Adirondack forest preserve, right?
And uncle Jim says to me, Danny says, you're going down to college now.
I don't want you to become a communist, you know, going down there. He said,
you know, I want you to look out here now.
There's going to be a day we'll come when the Russians are parachuting into our
hometown.
And I want you to commit to me right now that if they're in the rush,
when the Russians parachute into our town, that you will fight against them.
And I said, look, Jim, I said,
Russians aren't going to be parachuting into our hometown. I said,
but I'll tell you what I will do.
I will take an oath to protect the constitution of the United States against
all enemies, foreign and domestic.
And then I left. Okay. I go back down to go to college, right? I'm in,
before I get to Harvard college, I'm in special forces, right? For two years,
right? In fifth special forces. And I'm out at Fort Devens.
We're getting set to do the halo jump, you know, the high altitude look,
we get set to do the halo jump. They bring us back four from a fifth army.
Special forces. And he's sitting there telling us to look, okay,
now you gotta, you gotta remember now, uh, you know, when you're,
you jump into the night, you know, you're up at like 38,000 feet.
You jump out, you know, you time your drop. And he said, when you drop in,
he said, uh, you gotta make sure anybody who sees you come in,
you gotta kill them immediately and bury them with your shoot.
Cause they were trained to drop in behind the lines in Vietnam. Right.
And he said, and I said, I'm standing there with our unit. And I say,
what if it's women or children? Kill them. He said,
and bury them with your shoot.
We're the Russians. I said,
that's exactly what uncle Jim was hypothesizing of them jumping into our
neighborhood. Right. Uh, and here we are going 8,000 miles away,
jumping into the neighborhood of people that have been there for 5,000 years.
And we're jumping into their neighborhood and I'm sitting here being told at Fort
Devon's, you know,
in special forces that you jump in and you kill the women and children if you
have to and bury them with your shoot. And I turned around right then,
and I walked right out of the place, turned around, walked away.
And Captain Campbell, our commander said, Sheehan, where the f**k do you think
you're going? I turned around. I said, look it,
somebody around here is f**king nuts. I said, and it ain't me.
And I turned around and walked out and never went back.
You know, they freaked out and drafted me and, and you know, all that s**t.
And I ended up going to Harvard college. F**k you. I said,
I go to Harvard college and I studied American foreign policy under Henry
Kissinger. I studied all about the Vietnam war. You know,
I got to be one of the point briefers from Harvard law school to the United
States Senate,
briefing them on the Cooper church amendment as to how they could
constitutionally cut off all the funds for the Vietnam war. Right.
And I ended up being the lawyer for the Pentagon papers case to reveal all of
this so we could stop the war. Right. And so I,
I took this personally, you know,
this is a violation of everything that we've been taught. You know,
what these people are doing is a violation of everything that we've been taught.
They are the bad guys.
They are the bad guys and they're decent guys that go into the military because,
you know, they need a job or they need training and they get tasked to do all
this stuff. And by the time they get buried into this, this military culture,
you know, all they're doing is blindly doing whatever it is they're told,
you know, and they invade places and kill people, you know,
and then they end up justifying killing somebody because they killed my buddy,
you know, and here you are 8,000 miles away. What are we doing?
Invading the middle Eastern oil fields. It's just completely obvious.
We invaded the middle Eastern oil fields based on a complete absolute fabricated
lie. This Saddam Hussein was in possession of nuclear weapons and we go ho hum.
Oh, well, okay. I guess that was a big fat lie.
We've been in, killed tens of thousands of people, you know,
it's spent hundreds and hundreds of lives of American men and women, you know,
for what? To occupy the middle Eastern oil fields. Why?
So that we could control the middle Eastern oil for our country and keep China
from getting it. Okay. So, I mean, that's what's happening here,
you know? So that's the answer to your question.
What do you think about all this national security state?
I think the national security state is fascist.
I think that they are devoted to the proposition that the entire
instrumentalities of the state should be put at the disposal of the private
interests of corporations, you know? And that is fascism.
That's exactly what Mussolini wrote his major essay about on fascism. You know,
that is exactly what the idea of fascism is. Okay.
And that's what they're doing. And they're justifying aggressive wars, you know,
to go get the resources because somebody else will do it.
And they keep on buffaloing everybody that the Soviet Union was planning on
taking over the world. You know, that's our job. As,
as George Carlin used to say, you know, that's our job, you know?
And that's what they're doing.
They're attempting to establish full spectrum dominance over the planet through
800 military bases through over a trillion dollars a year now,
a trillion dollars a year in major military operations.
You know, with, with, with young men and women of complete good faith that are,
Americans have been raised believing in the fundamental rights of the
constitution and liberty and democracy and all that stuff.
And they're being deployed to go kill people, you know, uh, over oil,
you know, that is so that Donald Trump and the guys say,
we are the number one producers of energy now in the world.
We are producing more oil than Saudi Arabia, you know,
and who's there are allies, Saudi Arabia, you know?
So it's, uh, you know, that's what I think, you know,
and that's why I went to the Jesuits to have to be legal counsel for them
because they,
they're the ones that are devoted to trying to instill the fundamental Judeo
Christian social ethics that we've all been taught as young men and women,
you know, in our high school civics courses and everything else.
Our job is to make that stuff real, you know, and you can,
you can hold them up to it. You can confront them with it, you know, uh,
to say, look, here's the promises that we've been made.
Here's the promises we've been made all through our raising being raised in
high school and college and everything else, you know, and we intend to do that.
And, you know, and that's why we're still alive is because the guys say,
wait a second, you know, these kids actually believe this stuff. You know,
that's, that's who they, that's who we are. And they say,
who the hell are these people? You know, they're getting all this information.
It was Felix Rodriguez. They said, how, how, how,
I hate that we keep bringing him up.
No, they said, they said, they said that they catch this, uh, Oliver North,
Oliver North believed, and I know this because he told,
he told, uh, Ross Perot of this, that they believed that the source of our
information in the Iran Contra case was Felix Rodriguez.
Really?
That's what they thought.
And they were going to have to try to get rid of him as the head of the
Ilepongo air operation. Cause we had such good information about the,
we knew the flight numbers. We knew the tail numbers. We knew,
we had the shipping invoices over the serial numbers on the weapons,
those people, man. I mean, we had these guys dead to rights and they said,
it has to be Felix. Okay. It wasn't, it was Chi Chi,
who was his number two, who was just giving us the,
Pantero. Yeah. Cause he was talking all the time to, to, uh,
to Gene Wheaton and Gene Wheaton was working with us because he got really
pissed off. He'd given him his airplanes.
He gave him like a dozen of his, his airplanes to fly, uh,
weapons down to the Contras. He said, you know, fuck the Contras, you know,
they're fucking, you know, they're the fuck the Sandinistas, you know,
they're all communists.
So he let them use his airplanes until he found out that they were flying
cocaine back into the United States on his airplanes. Uh, in the,
in one of them crashed on the way back and he got ready to file an insurance
claim. He says, no, no, no nurses. Don't do that. Don't do that.
Cause if they send investigators to try to find the plane and they'll find it
and it's filled with cocaine.
And so Gene got really pissed off, uh, and came to us, came to us.
Paul Hoeven brought him to meet with me.
Paul Hoeven was a copter jock in Vietnam, you know, and he ran the,
the project on military procurement, which I chaired the fund for
constitutional government in Washington, DC. Uh, and we had,
we instituted the fund for, uh, for military spending, right?
And we were overseeing the whole project on military spending to go after the
$500 coffee pots, the $300 hammers, you know,
the $800 screwdrivers that they have all that shit, you know?
And so we were doing,
we put together the project on military procurement and Paul Hoven was one of
the consultants we had because he was an expert on military
hardware, right?
And so he would tell us exactly what the, like the Bradley fighting machine,
the Bradley fighting machine, you know, if,
if it took a direct hit a midships,
it would totally blow up and kill everybody all around it. Uh, because,
because, because it was,
it could be defeated with an armor piercing shell and it was loaded with,
with the military, uh, uh, uh, uh, what do you call it?
Anyway, provisions, they kept, they kept the shells inside the tank,
you know? And so you hit the, you hit the Bradley fighting machine.
It could go 60 miles an hour on the open highway.
But the fact is it could, it could,
it could be penetrated by one armor person shell and blow up and kill everybody
all within like 150 yards of it, which all the guys who were around it,
you know, would get killed, you know,
and still they just kept pushing it forward because it was a multimillion
dollar project, you know? And so that I was, I was, uh, uh,
there is the, is the head of that program. We put that together.
We put together the, uh, the, uh, uh, Institute for corporate responsibility,
which was the original whistleblower protection group for the fund for
constitutional government.
We did all that out of the fund for constitutional government.
When I was at the Jesuit headquarters, I got recruited by the people to,
if Stuart Mott helped fund that, that thing.
So they asked me to become the chair of it because they knew I was a serious
person when it comes to the constitution. And so we, we,
we set up all those different programs then, you know, and that's how I got to,
that's how I got to meet Paul Hoeven and Paul Hoeven was at a meeting of the,
uh, the heritage foundation. If you know what that is,
the heritage foundation is somewhere to the right of Attila, you know, uh,
and, uh, they've got this foundation in Washington, DC, where they're all, you
know, they're, they're the ones that built the, the entire, uh, was it a mandate
for leadership, that great big 500 page, uh,
book that they gave to Ronald Reagan when he became president. Uh,
and he instituted all those beliefs and stuff. And, and, uh,
and Hoeven was at one of these soirees they were having there and there,
and there was Gene Wheaton standing there at the bar drinking and they got
talking back and forth.
And Wheaton started crying in his beer over the fact that his airplane had been
shot down filled with cocaine. And so, so Paul Hoeven knew me,
cause he was our consultant at the project on military procurement.
And so he came to me, he said, Danny said,
I know that you guys have been looking into this, uh,
weapons smuggling operation going on down to the Contras,
which everybody's denying is happening. Uh, and you're sure it is happening. Uh,
but I've got, I've got a guy who I think may know something about it.
So he sets up the meeting to in a safe house out in Virginia.
And I go out and sit down with, uh, with Gene Wheaton, uh, in, you know,
after probably half an hour, 45 minutes,
he realized that, uh, I knew a lot.
I knew a lot, uh,
and then he became convinced that I was serious about this and I was no spy for
Cuba or, you know, Soviets or anybody.
I was just an absolute American who believed in the constitution and had been
given the privilege of getting to go to Harvard college and Harvard law school
and Harvard divinity school.
And I had all kinds of contacts cause I'd been in Bailey's office and I knew all
kinds of stuff from being on the Pentagon papers.
And so he agreed to work with us cause he was pissed off about what they were
doing. Uh, and that's how we learned that Theodore Shackley,
who was the CIA station chief in Saigon,
was also the guy who put together the off the shelf enterprise.
It wasn't Oliver North at all. It was Theodore Shackley,
who was the handpicked head of covert operations for the CIA
worldwide by George H.W. Bush.
When he was the director of the central intelligence agency.
And this guy was the fucking protege of Reinhard Galen,
who was the head of the Waffen SS third Reich anti Soviet and anti Eastern block
intelligence for the third Reich. And this guy, Theodore Shackley,
was his protege in Europe and the 101st counter intelligence core.
When, when Galen turned himself in at the end of world war two and Shackley was
his translator and he went with him and translated stuff and brought him to Fort
Hunt at the end of world war two and help persuade everybody to let him become
the head of West German intelligence. And so Reinhard Galen,
who was the head of the Waffen SS third Reich anti Soviet and anti Eastern
block intelligence was the head of West German intelligence for 26 years and
provided,
was the primary source on intelligence against the Soviet Union to our,
to our United States central intelligence agency.
And Theodore Shackley was, was his protege.
It was in the original class of the central intelligence agency,
along with Michael Harari,
who was chief of security for Noriega and his drug smuggling. You know,
these are the guys that, these are the guys that we're talking about here,
you know, and, and, and what I'm saying is the,
I think that the UFO issue is,
is it's got the widest constituency of any issue of public policy.
Everybody, everybody wants to find out about the UFOs.
Everybody wants to find out about the fact that there's extraterrestrial
intelligence and they're coming and going from the planet.
All the Republican senators are in support of our bill.
All the democratic senators in charge in support of our bill, except for,
except for McConnell, Mitch McConnell, in one guy from Alabama,
you know, one, one of the senators from Alabama, all the other senators,
you know, all 98 other senators are supportive of our 60 page bill, you know,
and virtually all the members of the house, you know,
I've got meetings with AOC sitting there with, with Gates,
with Matt Gates sitting,
having cordial conversations about how they agree that the Congress has the
right to have all this information because it's rotten and unconstitutional for
this, the, the unelected people in the,
in the military and in the intelligence community to be secreting this
information. What do you think about the, the story?
I don't know if you've heard, I'm sure you've heard of it,
but Annie Jacobson talks about in her book Area 51, she has a source,
a major source for her who was an EG&G engineer.
Yeah, I know EG&G. Yeah. He, he told her,
he was like towards the very end of his life when he was giving her information
for her book.
But he said that the Roswell crash was a drone piloted by Stalin containing a,
a humanoid, there was a guy, a Nazi guy that Stalin got,
that was like a, I always forget his name,
but he was like a surgery guy.
He was in charge of like doing all this crazy,
like surgical experiments, manipulating people.
And he did this surgical manipulation on like kids with Down syndrome and made
them look like aliens and crashed them in there to sow panic and chaos in the US.
What do I think about that? And then hold on. Yeah. And then, um,
he, she went back towards the end of her research years later and she goes,
she goes, um,
why wouldn't you say something about this? She's like,
this makes them look terrible.
If you guys found out the truth and could find evidence proving that Stalin was
behind this, why wouldn't you do that?
And the EG&G engineer said, because we started doing the same thing.
He literally said that they started doing the surgical stuff,
experimenting on kids.
It's all a total brain fart. Total. I mean,
you can get extraordinarily intricate stories by people who are total
psychopaths. Uh,
and they're completely convincing because they made some of them believe it
themselves. It's not true. I, I, I'm the guy, I'm the guy that helped, uh,
expand the, the telegram in the hand of general Ramey,
the famous picture of him kneeling down next to the weather balloon,
kneeling down there. And he's got a telegram, a cable in his hand.
You can see it. I always saw,
I said that guy's got a cable of some sort in his hand there. I, I,
I can't read it from the photograph. And so like 1995,
I'm doing a talk, giving everybody a briefing on the John Mack case, you know,
uh, that was still underway at that time.
I'm out at the international UFO Congress out in Laughlin, Nevada.
And a guy comes up to me after I do my, my briefing on the, on the Mack case.
And he says, Mr. Sheehan, he said, uh, I've got something really important.
I need to talk with you about, uh, could you come up, meet me up in my room?
And I went, uh, I think I better bring somebody with me.
So I get into the friend mind, we go up and he says,
I think I have found the photographer from the Roswell
newspaper who the editor called him at two o'clock in the morning
after the July 8th, you know, headline banner headline in the Roswell paper
that everybody's seen about flying saucer that they found a flying saucer.
It went out over the AP wires and everybody was going ballistic, right?
And he gets a call at two o'clock in the morning from the editor of the paper
and says that general Ramey has flown in from Texas and he's demanding that he
sent, we send a photographer out right now because they want to get the
photographs, uh, uh, and put them on the front page of the paper for the morning.
And he goes out and here's Ramey, you know, uh, with, uh, uh, with, uh, Marcel
and the rest of the guys and they're all still up and they've got a weather
balloon kind of spread out on the floor.
Uh, and he's kneeling down next to the weather balloon and he's got
this cable in his hands.
You can see the, the telegram.
Uh, and so this guy says, I think I may have found the photographer that took
the picture and I said, great.
I said, if you, if you can find out and it's the right guy, see if he's got the
negatives, if he's got the negatives, we might be able to digitize them and blow
these things up and we can read the telegram, right?
So he does, he goes and finds the guy.
Sure enough, as the guy, sure enough, he's got the, he's got the negatives.
Sure enough, we get them blown up and digitized, right?
And it says right in them, we had to do some computer stuff with, you know,
where the consonants and vowels were to be able to fill in where some of the
wrinkles were that were in the thing.
But it says, bring the disc to right field and bring the bodies.
Okay.
Now, and so that we, we know that it was real.
It wasn't any weather balloon, you know, the, and all the guys, the guys that are
there, I mean, they know what a weather balloon looks like.
Well, that story would fit in with the EG&G engineer story.
It's not, it's not even close to a weather balloon.
I mean, this was a huge crap.
He said it was a drone.
He said it was like a flying saucer that they literally piloted the bodies.
Anybody can make anything up.
And we've seen them.
I mean, look at Corey Good, the guy, what I told you about Corey Good went on and
on for dozens of appearances.
He went on and went into great detail about how we had interstellar craft.
Yeah, but this, this source, he was completely, he was a confidential source.
He was completely remained anonymous.
She never named the guy or anything.
And she said that he was, why would he admit the fact that he went and did it too?
Do you realize, do you realize how many people that have come to me to tell me that
they knew what the Watergate burglar was about and what the Kennedy, who killed
Kennedy, you know, and all that, and the people hiding in the drain and all that
shit. I mean, they go on and on and on, you know, and it's just, that's what I'm
saying, why you have to have the ability to, I mean, we could slap this guy on a,
on a psychological stress evaluator in, you know, it's just that they notice that
we've got, we've got like a dozen witnesses who have, who've participated in
that, who saw the crash debris, you know, and it's not a weather balloon at all.
You know, and they, they, they, and they've got, they've got multiple bodies.
They've got multiple bodies, you know, and they, they didn't, they didn't, you
know, find a bunch of people that were kind of human mutants and they kind of
operated on them and put them in a, in a weather balloon and flew, or a drone and
flew, they didn't even have drones then, you know.
Well, they had the Horton, was stuff the Horton brothers were working on the Horton.
Have you seen the, the, the flying saucer type object that the Horton brothers
developed?
Well, there, there were a number of them that were, were trying to be developed.
The, the Russians there, the Nazis were working on, which may well have, had been
a result of the, the craft in 1933 that was recovered in, in, in Italy.
So, but, but they weren't able, they weren't able to figure out the
technology of this thing, you know, that, yeah, see, that's it there.
So this, what are we looking at right here?
That's the telegram right there.
This is the telegram that was in the guy's hand in the photograph.
And Ramey's right there.
See it?
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
See it?
That's not a weather balloon.
That's not a conversation about a weather balloon.
They're talking about the disk.
Where does it say Wright-Patterson?
It says Wright Field.
Oh, Wright Field.
See, that's what it was.
It was Wright Field at that time.
It wasn't Wright-Patterson.
Oh, wow.
But it's taken to Wright Field.
And here's, here's all the stuff that, see.
Yep.
Wright Field.
They talk about, we're going to send out, send out a weather balloon
story for it to cover that.
Right.
Yeah.
No, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It was definitely a, it was definitely a cover up.
Yeah.
So, and it's, so, and it's, it's one of those, it's one of those kind of things
where, where, you know, not in a thousand years would they think that you can see
this, would you would ever be able to see the telegram that he had in his hand.
Right.
You know, so I say that nobody, nobody's going to be smart enough to, to do that,
to have a fake telegram in his hand and think that, you know, 30 years later,
somebody's going to find the technology to read it, you know, it's, you know, it's,
it's just like, you know, eventually we'll be able to get the Zapruder film and
we'll be able to have a technology that can track the heat signatures of the
bullets in, in the emulsion on, on the negatives that they're going, we're
going to be able to do that.
And we'll be able to find the actual heat, heat signatures of the bullets.
And so you'll know exactly where the bullets came from.
And by that time they'll all be dead.
And, and you know, that's, that's what did that say, Steve?
However, this book written, oh, this is, okay, this is talking about
the EG&G engineer, right?
In this book written by Andy Jacobson, a respected investigator reporter offers
such contrasting explanation of the, for the Roswell mystery that I suggest you
clutch something solid right now.
Yeah.
This is what I explained to you.
According to the Telegraph, Jacobson suggests that the flying object
crashed into a, was an earthly machine.
She also reported a suggestion it was sent by Stalin, blah, blah, blah.
Down here is where it gets interesting.
Maybe it's right here.
She's in children.
Stalin.
Yeah, yeah.
Stalin apparently believed that it could have been said they sent a plane full of
these children created with the already exiled Ming, Mingel, Mingel.
That was the guy's name.
The Nazi.
Mengele, Mengele, Mengele's help over to the U S in order to create mass hysteria.
However, the remote piloted plane, which wasn't a flying saucer crashed, but yeah.
So, so the Horton brothers and a bunch of these guys that were working with the
Nazis, they had all kinds of crazy sci-fi looking shit they were working on.
That looked like flying saucers.
No, I mean, what I'm saying is that we've got, we've got 40, you know, above
top secret witnesses testifying to the recovery of the UFOs, you know, and that
these are not, these are not.
So that's made by the Soviets or.
So it goes back to my, my, my original question is if we have 40 of these people,
do you really think we're going to get these people to let the cat out of the bag?
They've already given it.
They've already given sworn testimony to the Senate intelligence committee under oath.
I'm talking about the, the, um, the private contractors, but tell, I'm
talking about these, these companies.
Once, once we get subpoena power to go after them and you know, they, I can
tell you, you know, they, the people all the time don't want to talk.
They have every, in any case you're going to do are going to lie or going to
cheat and hide the stuff they're going to do all that you have to have
professionals that know how to get that stuff, you know, and as long as the
Congress has made the decision that they're going to get it, they'll get it.
You know, now they'll do everything in their power to try to stop it because
it's worth trillions of dollars.
If they, if they can get the patents on, on, you know, anti-gravity technology, if
they can get a patent on superluminal speeds of a vehicle, if they can get a
patent on the metals that can withstand that, that kind of G forces and stuff, if
they can do that, it'll be worth trillions of dollars for them, you know?
So they'll go to almost any lengths to, to refuse to do this.
So that's why we have to have the power of the institution of Congress to be
able to get behind this.
And that's why, you know, it's a slow process of being able to bring these
people on, but we've, we've now gotten the virtually unanimous support from the
Democratic and Republican senators and almost unanimous support from the members
of the house, you know, but for these few guys, you know, Mike Turner, Mike Turner,
who is the head of the Republican head of the, of the intelligence committee, who
comes from the 10th congressional district in Ohio, Wright-Patterson, and,
and that is the chief field office for radiant technology.
You know, that's where they are.
And the other guy that he brought on is Mike Rogers, who's the head of the, the,
uh, uh, the armed services committee in the house, who comes from the second
district in Alabama, right next door to the red stone rocket range.
Okay.
And that's the home office of, of, uh, of radiant technology.
And they've got the program, which is called prompt global strike.
They're the ones that are trying to use the technology of the craft to propel
nuclear American nuclear missiles that can be launched Stateside and hit into
the, in the center of China or Russia within two minutes, you know, I mean,
and sure they'll do that.
I mean, that's, that's perfectly logical that they, they will, they're, they're,
you know, the old Sufi saying is when, when a pickpocket meets a Saint,
all he sees are his pockets.
And so these, these guys live in the world of, as soon as they see, oh, a crash
UFO, man, we can make a weapon out of that, because that's their life.
That's their job.
That's the prison through which they see everything.
So you can't really hold it against them that they want to do that.
That's their mission.
What sort of terms do you think they'd be willing to negotiate with to let the cat
out of the bag or to let this, to disclose all this stuff?
Like would you have to sell it?
Look, you can still control it.
You can still control it.
You guys still own it.
If you, if you could, if you would give them the patents, if you'd give them the
patents on it and you'd let them own it for in perpetuity, so they could make
trillions of dollars, they could, they could be making billions of dollars on
every single craft that the United States built, you know, that use that technology.
And they could give the money to their shareholders so that they'd be all, could
have more yachts, you know, or more country houses or, or give their great,
great, great grandchildren and nephews, you know, in Mercedes for their 16th
birthday, I mean, these people are completely insatiable because, because
they've got a hole in their soul.
You know, I mean that they, they do not experience any kind of
unitive experience.
I mean, experientially that somehow that the, the universe is some kind
of harmonic unified hole that they don't have any sense of that at all.
Everything is dialectical.
Everything's confrontational that there's bad guys all around all the time.
You know, that they develop an entire worldview in that they, and what does
that do to your, to your mind and to your psyche when you have these secrets and
you know about these secrets and you know, nobody else does, only you and a very
few people on earth know that this exists.
I wonder like what that does to your worldview.
Well, it's, I mean, the people who are into power, you know, it's a, it's a
chakra, it's, you know, it's a, it's the third chakra, the third chakra in the
human body is, is, you know, rooted in power, the, the lust for power and
control and, and it, it satisfies that, you know, people, people feel privileged
and, you know, people all, I mean, if you, if you have a Superbowl ticket and get
Sid in the box, you know, the head of the NFL with them to watch the Superbowl
game, you know, why are people getting off on that?
Why, why, why is that, why is that exciting?
Some people so much, you know, and other people are ho hum.
They don't care about that at all, you know, but a worldview is
extraordinarily important thing.
That's how I ended up eventually at Harvard Dunany school is that, you know,
the, I'm in F.
Lee Bailey's office, you know, I'll tell you a story.
I'm sitting in F.
Lee Bailey's office, right?
And it turns out that what had happened is the, this little old man who had
owned a little mom, pa grocery store in Boston, in the North end of Boston, you
know, a Friday afternoon, two big no net guys come into his, into his store and
say, they want to sell him Angelo fire insurance company, you know, and he said,
I don't need fire insurance.
I've already got fire insurance.
And they said, well, you don't have kind of fire insurance that'll keep your
place from being burnt down next Friday night.
And, uh, and he, and he looked at them like that and he just, he just rolled
up his sleeve and he said, look at, you see these numbers right here, the tattooed
on my arm, I got those at Auschwitz.
He said, you people don't fucking scare me at all.
Cause I've been through the worst big mistake on his part.
Cause what they, what they did is they found out that he had a, a daughter,
single child who was like nine months, eight months pregnant with her first baby.
And they tracked her down on the mass pike and chased her down on the pike.
And she pulled off the road and went into a phone booth to try to call the
emergency call to get help.
And they got out of the car and shotgunned her right through the glass and
killed her and the baby and she was dead.
And the, the shit hit the fan and it was in all the newspapers, you know,
the Boston Globe all over the place.
Right.
Uh, and the ones that killed her that, uh, that, well, it was the Angelo brothers,
Mikey Angelo, you know, gave the order to killer, you know, and I'm sitting in
the office, I'm sitting in the office with, with, uh, with, uh, with Lee Bailey.
Right.
Uh, and, uh, I get a call from Lee and he says, Danny, he said, uh, have you
seen the stuff in the papers there about the killing out on the pike?
And I said, yeah, he says, come on in here, come on down.
So I go down the hall to his office.
I come down and here's Al Johnson, who's the managing partner at the
firm, uh, and bad Andy Tooney, who's, uh, Andy Tooney, who was the head of
the Strangler Bureau that caught the DeSalvo, the Boston Strangler, right.
Bailey got appointed by the court to defend him and Bailey stole, stole Andy.
He was the head of the Strangler Bureau for the Massachusetts state police.
So they're sitting in the office, right.
And, uh, and, uh, they're, they're saying, oh yeah, did you see this thing?
You know, I'm, I'm anticipating getting a call from Mikey Angelo to ask us
to defend him on this thing, because what's happened here is catch this.
It's like a three, three to four days after the killing.
And with all this roaring going on in all the news media, you know, somebody
drives past the place where she was killed, like a hundred miles an hour
and tosses this guy out of the car and bounces down the highway.
And he's laying there dying beside the highway.
Uh, and, uh, well, the Massachusetts state patrol, highway patrol, find him,
pull up and find him laying by the road.
And they recognize him as one of Tony, uh, of Mikey Angelo's people.
He says, he said, Joey, it's just, you know, you're dying.
He said, tell me, tell me who did this, who, what's this about?
He says, are you the guy that pulled the trigger on this lady?
And he said, yes, I am.
He said, well, who, who told you to do it?
Who gave you the order?
And he said, Mikey Angelo.
And then they, they bring the ambulance, they bring them to mass general
and he survives, he lives.
And so now they're getting set to prosecute him and they're going to turn
him on Mikey Angelo, right?
And so, so Lee calls me into his office and I'm sitting there with, with, with
Lee and, uh, Al Johnson and, and bad, Andy, and we're sitting there.
Uh, and he said, I'm anticipating, he's probably going to call us or try
to retain us to represent him.
He said, and Danny, you wrote your, uh, honor thesis at Harvard college, right?
On like the fifth amendment and the right against self-incrimination.
So I said, yeah, I did.
I was predicting the Miranda decision and my thesis at the college, you know?
And he says, uh, you know, so he says, you know, that, uh, I want you to stay here
because I, I'm expecting a call from him and the door opens and his secretary
says, uh, Lee, she said it's Mikey Angelo.
So I'm sitting here in the office and he goes, look, here, he goes over
and he picks up the telephone and you can hear him say, yeah, Mikey.
Yeah.
I saw that.
Oh shit.
Yeah.
That's really terrible.
No, I hear you.
I hear you.
No, no, we'll, we'll, yeah, we'll do that.
We'll, we'll represent you.
Uh, yeah, no, that'll be, uh, $1 million cash.
Uh, anyways, he says, and that's for us, but for the investigation thing, you
know, the, uh, uh, Moriarty and associates, that's another million dollars.
Whoa.
No, Mikey, uh, no way.
Hey, well, Mikey will fuck you too.
He said, you know, look at, if you want to call it, and he slams the
phone down on him like that.
And so he's sitting there and he's laughing.
And he's saying, oh, he says, look at, and he reaches, he reaches in his
fight, he takes out his wallet and he takes out a hundred dollar bill.
And he lays it on the table and he says, a hundred bucks.
He calls back within 15 minutes.
And Al Johnson reaches in his wallet, it takes out a couple of $50 bills.
And he says, okay, a 10, I'll take, I got a hundred on 10.
He'll call within 10 minutes.
And in bad Indy band, he says, I'll take a piece of that.
He says, look, uh, I'll, I'll take the, uh, I'll take the five minutes.
I'll take five minutes.
So, and so Bailey turns to me and he says, Danny, you want a piece of this?
That's literally, you want a piece of this?
Yeah.
I said to myself, what the fuck am I doing in this room with these people?
I said, you know, I do not want to be here.
I, you know, and we'd already found out that he was on index four.
Anyway, I already told you.
So I get up and leave the office.
Right.
And, uh, so a day later I'm sitting, I'm sitting in my office and, uh, it must
be five o'clock in the afternoon.
I mean, in walks Lee with Mikey and Julo.
He comes walking in, uh, in Mikey and he says, Danny, this is Mikey and Julo.
And Julo walks over and sticks his hand out at me like that.
And I sit there and I just look at him and I say, yeah, I know, I know who you are.
I know who you are.
And Julo says, Oh, you know, Lee says that you are, you don't want to help me.
You don't want to do anything on this case.
You know, he says, everybody's got a right to, everybody's got a right to have a
defense.
And I said, not from me.
And he says, well, look, I want to have you kind of help me on this.
I said, look, let me be really clear.
Mr.
Angelo, I wouldn't piss on you if you were on fire.
You understand?
And he just looked at me and it'd be, uh, Lee almost cracked his pants.
I said, cause look, I said, you know, I know who you are and I know what you do.
And I think that you kill people, you know, who you think betray you.
So I don't ever want to be in a position where you're ever going to think that I'm
going to betray you because I won't put a piece of, I won't put a pencil to paper
to help you.
So, and I'll never have to worry about betraying you.
And he just looked at me and he just burst out laughing like that.
And, you know, but, and I just would not have anything to do with these people,
you know?
Uh, and so I realized that that it's just a completely different worldview.
And so I would talk with Lee about why you, you, you, you got this whole practice,
you know, you're a great criminal defense attorney.
You got this entire private investigation firm, you know, of Moriarty.
And so it's just, just to do, figure out all the facts on everything.
Right.
You know, and, uh, I said, why don't you do something good?
You know, about this, that you've got a whole lot of, you got a lot of notoriety.
You can do really good things.
It was like talking to a wall, you know, it was like, uh, you know, uh, and he
said, no, everybody's got a right to a defense, you know, and I said, yeah, but
these are professional criminals.
I mean, you know, they're total gangsters, these people.
He said, well, everybody's entitled to a defense, you know?
And so I, I got into this kind of row with him.
So I leave that, that Friday afternoon, I'm, I'm standing in his place
over on Beacon Hill, right?
Uh, and he's living out in Walpole or something, because he's now
married to his third wife, uh, you know, in the, so I'm staying at the place.
So I go to church on Sunday morning over at, uh, uh, uh, with St.
Cecilia's, so I go over to St.
Cecilia's and I'm, I come out of church and I'm kind of wandering back over to
her Beacon Hill and I stop in at a bookstore and I'm kind of looking around
at the books like I do sometimes.
And I found John Rawls theory of justice.
John Rawls is the head of the department of philosophy at Harvard university.
And he's written this major treatise on, uh, on justice.
It was long story short, I read through the thing and he says that there's this
whole group of people, which he calls the intuitionists who are the ones who
make these kinds of statements, like all men are created equal endowed by their
career or certain enable rights and their life, liberty and pride, you know,
they've got all these rights and stuff.
And they are a counter force in our country to what they call the
majoritarian unitara, utilitarians who, if they're, if our people are faced
with a choice between one policy or another, they will pick the one
theoretically that generates the greatest good for the greatest number, right?
John Stuart milled, you know, utilitarianism, you know, but he
says it doesn't happen that way.
He says, if that were true, what Rawls says in his theory of justice that, you
know, then the 90% of us that are white was still owned the 10% of the people
that are black, he said, but we don't because there's this other group called
the intuitionists who keep making these kind of proclamations about natural law
and their natural rights and all that.
And, uh, and so I saw it.
So I bring it home, I buy a copy and I go home and I read it.
Uh, and I call up John Rawls, you know, and I talked to his secretary and I'm
saying, you know, I graduated from Harvard college and Harvard law school,
and I did this and did that, and I'm waving the school tie through the phone
at her as I'd like to get a chance to talk to professor Rawls, you know, about
this, about his new book.
Uh, and so she calls me back a little bit later and she says, okay, you
can get 30 minutes, you know, Wednesday afternoon.
So I go over and sit down with John Rawls, the head of the department of
philosophy at Harvard university.
And I started talking to him about what's caused me to come and talk with him
about this, cause you know, I've got this thing with Lee Bailey, I've been
to Cahill firm, Cahill firm was trying to get me to represent the Arkansas
Missouri power company that was trying to buy an all black company and raise
the rates and I wouldn't do it, you know?
And, uh, and so the bottom line is I was explaining this all to him and he ended
up talking me into coming back to Harvard, to coming back and doing a
master's and PhD in comparative social ethics, uh, comparing, contrasting
different worldviews.
And it was there that I began to really study and find out that people have
completely different worldviews, uh, about things.
Uh, and we got to understand what the underlying premise was of different
people's worldviews that are even unconscious.
They don't even know sometimes what they believe.
And so I ended up doing the work there.
And that's why I got recruited by Jesuit national headquarters because I've been
writing some papers and stuff from my master's work in father Roger Couture,
who teaches the course at Harvard loss, Harvard divinity school on the
theological underpinnings of human rights, you know, called me in and said,
uh, he said, look, uh, I'm a son of shared these papers you've been writing
and the, the, the work that you've been doing on this, you know, uh, are you
aware of the fact I can tell that you're Catholic from the way you're writing?
He said, but, uh, and I checked out, you know, you're not married or anything.
He said, you know, uh, are you aware of the fact that, uh, that the Jesuits,
that the father general of the Jesuits Pedro Arrupe has called all 100
provincials of the Jesuit order into Rome, uh, to do some major treatise on
social justice, and they're going to create a new national headquarters in
Washington, DC, and they're looking for a general council, uh, and I've recommended
you, uh, would you be willing to do an interview with them?
And so I said, sure.
You know, and so I did, and they asked me to become general counsel.
Uh, at the Jesuit headquarters.
So we had 10,000 Jesuits all around the world.
We got doing social justice documents in the, the turns out that the Jesuit
order has, has become a huge source of all the social justice documents that
are being published by the Catholic church and Francis, Pope Francis, who's
the first Jesuit in history to ever become Pope, you know, and so that I was
right there at the, at the international headquarters where we were dealing with,
you know, liberation theology, you know, all the stuff in South America.
Uh, and I knew all the people.
I knew Gutierrez.
I knew everybody who writes these things.
You know, I got to go to Rome and meet with the, the superior general
with Pedro Arrupe, you know, uh, and so that I was right in the catbird seat.
And what I brought in was I brought in the professional investigators from
Lee Bailey's office, the people that were in Moriarty and associates,
cause they all knew me and they knew that I had thrown this big shit fit
and that I wouldn't work for the organized crime people.
I wouldn't do any of that stuff.
And so these guys were all calling me up saying, Oh, you've got
anything I can do to help you.
Can I, can I help you with some stuff that, you know, you're doing the
kind of things that I always hoped that I could really do.
And so we became this source of them getting to do good things together.
Right.
And so here I was at Jesuit headquarters.
So I had access to all the Jesuit guys around the world.
I had the investigators from Bailey's office, you know, and I, so we
started putting together a group and I had access.
The secret that I had, you know, uh, is that, that, uh, William
Johnstone Taylor, who was appointed to me to be my chief investigator,
three tour Vietnam Marine Corps, CID, criminal investigation division,
you know, uh, liaison to the CIA and in Saigon, you know, was, was my
investigator, uh, and he had, he'd been there three tours in Vietnam.
So he knew all the guys coming through army CID office of special
investigations for the air force, the naval intelligence guys, he knew
everybody in these guys, after they would do like a two year tour in
Vietnam, they would leave, leave the military and they go into secret
service and the FBI and the CIA, US marshals offices, you know, uh, district
attorneys, investigators all over the country.
Wow.
And so I had all these guys who, that when Taylor would call them up and
say, look, I got a, I got a job for you.
I want you to help us.
And on board they were like that.
And we had guys, I had, I had the commander for United States army CID,
uh, you know, working with us, you know, telling us everything, you know, I had
to, you know, Gene Wheaton, the head of the U S military mission in Tehran, you
know, who, who had been the chief of security of United States Marine Corps
at Kaysan, you know, I mean, these are the guys, you know, and some of it had
to do with the fact that I was from Harvard law school and Lee Bailey's office.
And they all said, whoa, shit, you know, this would be cool.
And so I got all these people to come in to work with us.
And this was the best thing they'd ever done in their whole life.
Everything we did, they were just totally delighted that they finally
got to do something good, you know?
And so that's, that's what we are.
I mean, that's what the Christchurch Institute was until Bush ordered them to
yank our 501 C three saying that we were engaged in political activity because
nobody had been ultimately criminally convicted of the charges we made against
them because he pardoned them, you know?
And so that, so I don't mind, you know, people go, Oh, you know, he
yanked your 501 C three.
So what, you know, we'll get another 501 C three and we'll become the Romero
Institute, which we do, you know?
And so we just keep going.
And so that, that's why, that's why Lou Elizondo called me when the, he brought
the, the videos and stuff, he and Chris Mellon brought the videos to the New York
Times and showed them all to them.
And the Pentagon started shitting on him, you know, and say, we don't know
who Lou Elizondo is, he's never been any such thing, there's no such project at
the Pentagon, we were not investigating UFOs, he called me up and asked me to
represent him.
And so we put together the complaint with the inspector general's office of
the defense department, you know, it wasn't just a whistleblower defense, you
know, it was, it was challenging them for lying to the American people and lying
to Congress that this is unconstitutional for you guys to be lying to Congress and
concealing this information from them.
So we brought, we brought in this huge complaint into the United States
inspector general for the defense department and basically sat there
briefing the inspector general.
And as we started briefing him on what was really going on for the UFO issue, he
was just flabbergasted, you know, in, in, instead of being mad at, at, at Lou for
having blown the whistle on these people, he started bringing in officers in full
uniforms sitting around the desk and we would sit there briefing them on what was
going on, and their eyes were like big as saucers, you go, holy shit, you mean
this is really true?
I mean, the, the J2, the guy that was the head of intelligence for the joint
chiefs of staff was, was briefed out of this thing.
He, he wasn't allowed to ask any questions about it at all.
And he was the chief of intelligence for the joint chiefs of staff, and he
wasn't even allowed to ask any questions about it.
You know, and these guys were furious.
So, so we've got guys all through the military that are pissed off at these
guys, we've got all the people in Congress and the House and Senate that
are pissed off at these guys for lying to them and saying there's no such program
going on at all, and they're, and they're embezzling billions of dollars, billions
of dollars out of the defense budget, saying that they've appropriated the
money for some particular project and they really putting it over into trying
to back engineer the technology so they can build a weapon system, you know, to
be able to strike into the heart of Russia, you know, in two minutes, which
is going to totally destabilize the entire geopolitical structures that have
been put together to stop nuclear war.
You know, nobody's, nobody's, they've signed an agreement that they won't
have first strike weapons, you know, and this is an attempt to get around, you
know, the whole treaty because they consider the people in the state
department commies, you know, I mean, that's what they do.
They think that they're not really solely in, in, in defense of our
national interests, you know, that they're trying to make treaties with
people and negotiate, they hate the United Nations, you know, they, they,
they hate treaties with other countries, NATO, you know, that they're into, they're
fucking fascists is what they are, you know, and that's what they're into.
And they, they think that it's perfectly appropriate if they think it's
perfectly appropriate to, to engage in utilizing their military and their
intelligence resources to garner a privileged access to the strategic raw
materials of the planet.
What else is there?
I mean, that's, that's what they think is okay.
And that's their job.
And unfortunately, the way the institutions are set up is that is in
fact what they've been tasked to do.
And so they're totally loyal to that and they're totally devoted to doing it.
And they view the elected representatives as temporary employees,
you know, who come and go.
They're the BMOC types, you know, the big men on campus that used to be the
president of their fraternities and they're a bunch of phonies, you know, and
all they want to do is, is, you know, parade around and be celebrities, you
know, and they, they hold them basically in disdain, you know, including
the presidents, you know, and you say, no, what does that mean from a
constitutional point of view?
You know, I don't believe that I'm naive about it.
I don't believe that I'm, you know, fell off some melon wagon, like I'm
some country bumpkin or something, you know, I happen to believe this stuff.
And I believe that it, that we can make it true.
Um, thank you so much for coming all the way down here and doing this.
We just did almost four hours and that was incredible.
The amount, like I said before, the amount of knowledge and history that
you have in your mind and is, is absolutely astonishing and, uh, I'm
really grateful for you coming down here, man.
No, I'm delighted to come.
I want to talk to the people about these things, you know, that we haven't,
I haven't been talking about these things for people for years, but I
said, you know, this is the, this is the issue.
I'm just going to bring all of that to bear because the, the misdeeds of the
national security state, which I've talked about in a number of different
areas, all come to roost on this thing, you know, that they believe that they
actually are entitled to keep secret from the people, the fact that there's
an extraterrestrial civilization of people coming and going from our planet,
you know, and that our people are engaged in trying to back engineer their,
their craft to, to develop weapons systems.
You know, I'll do one story in closing on this is that, uh, help put off.
I don't know if you know how help put off told us that, uh, he was, uh, he
was meeting with Bill Clinton back during 1992 and the Clinton administration.
When they, when the Lawrence Rockefeller and the people were talking about trying
to consider putting this information out, right.
He's at a meeting in the science advisor for Bill Clinton is there.
And so Hal says to me, he says, what's, what's, what do you think is really
the source of all the pushback that we're getting on trying to get this information
out and the science advisor says, you know, let's go outside where I can talk
to you, which tells you something about what they're worried about, the kind
of surveillance and stuff that's going down against the political people.
He said, he said, so he goes outside and he said, here, let me, let me give you
an analysis.
He said of what I think the problem is here of why they're pushing back so hard.
He said, he said, there's a story about this old man, little old man who's on his
way back from somewhere, he's coming home at night early in the evening and he's
walking through this field and he looks down and he sees this light like in the
grass and he leans down and it's a frog and the frog has this little light like
on top of his head and he reaches down and picks, this is how put off telling me
the story.
He said, he said, this is the answer that the, this is what the science
advisor told him is the answer for why they're pushing back like this.
He said, and the little man reaches out and picks up the frog and he
recognizes that it's a crown.
The little light is a crown on the head of the frog and the frog looks up at
him and says, I'm not a frog.
I'm a princess.
I'm a beautiful princess and I've been turned into a frog by this evil
sorcerer and all you have to do is kiss me, you kiss me and I'll turn back into
this beautiful princess and you and I'll be married and we'll have many great
children and we'll be able to rule our, our place with priests and justice.
And the little man looks at her and he says, at my age, I think I'll
settle for having a talking frog.
That's good.
Okay.
That's what we've got happening here.
These people are willing to settle for talking frog.
You know, just, just like Woodward and Bernstein were willing to
settle for just that they caught creep money going to the people that
burglarized the water gate, you know, and let the whole other thing go.
You know, they're missing out on this astonishing opportunity for our
entire human family to enter into an entire new era, you know, of, of safe
energy and plenty for everybody and a positive relationship with an entire
extraterrestrial civilization and all they can think of do is how to make
weapons out of it so that we can shoot a missile into Russia in two minutes.
That's a serious problem.
And I don't think the American people are going to support that.
I think the American people want to know the information about this.
I think that they, they want to, and I want to have the people understand that
the national security state has to be disassembled because the United
States has become the Russians has become the bad guys that are applying their
trade all on behalf of establishing full spectrum military dominance over the
planet.
You know, we're living at the heart of Rome.
You know, people all like to believe that, Oh, if I were in Rome, I would
have opposed slavery, human slavery.
If I'd been in the South in the 1800s, I would have opposed slave.
No, you wouldn't.
They would be just as passive as a lot of the people are now because they
don't think they're involved.
They don't think they can have any effect upon anything.
That's what the, that's what the new paradigm Institute is going to be saying.
You have to be citizens.
You have to step forward.
You have to pay some attention to what's going on here.
You know, you got jobs, you got everything else.
We're not asking you for an awful lot of time.
What we're saying is all you have to do is go to new paradigm Institute.org and,
you know, get as much information as you want or as little as you want.
It's going to be very informative, very entertaining, you know, and, and you can
be actively participating in helping to get the Congress to do the right thing
about all this, you know, and you can, you can, you can tell your great, great,
great grandchildren that you were there.
I mean, we're, we're, we're at the time where the protocols are going to be
established, they're going to control our relationship with an extraterrestrial
civilization for 10,000 years in the future.
I'm ready.
I'm ready for it.
You know, this next year is going to be, uh, quite a whirlwind.
I have a feeling, especially with the presidential elections coming up and
everything that's going on in Congress with this grush guy and I can't wait.
And, uh, thanks again for enlightening me on all this amazing information.
You're more than welcome paradigminstitute.org.
I'll link all your stuff below and also I want to ask you a couple more quick
questions, but I'm going to do it after we wrap up this podcast because I don't
want to get my, I don't want to get this video nuked by YouTube for asking you
these questions, so it's going to be on our Patreon, so that's also linked below.
Goodnight everybody.