Hello world. Today my guest is Professor Avi Loeb. Avi is an astrophysicist at Harvard
and his new book, Extraterrestrial, The First Signs of Intelligent Life Beyond Earth, proposes
that an interstellar object that passed through our solar system in 2017 may have been the
creation of alien intelligence. This man is truly a genius who is pushing the envelope
in the world of astrophysics and cosmology. I hope you guys enjoy this one as much as
I did. Please welcome Avi Loeb.
Pleasure to meet you. Avi, is that how you pronounce it?
Yes.
So again, I just asked you before we started recording, have you done any of these Zoom
conversations in the past?
Well, thanks for having me. Yeah, over the past three weeks or so, things were very
hectic. I've had about 150 Zoom meetings of this type, interviews with either podcasters
or television or newspaper or radio stations, and there seemed to be an enormous interest
in the book. And I think part of the reason is that the scientific community starved the
public on this topic of the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, technological
signatures for many decades. And the public is thirsty for information. And I address
this interest. And it's intriguing to the public. And hopefully, the scientific community
will start discussing this topic within the mainstream in the future. That's my hope.
That's incredible. You know, it's funny that we reached out to you probably maybe three
weeks ago, we scheduled this interview. And then late last week, I saw you pop up on Joe
Rogan's podcast. Right. So did all of this sort of like spiral out of control after you
went and visited him?
Well, it started before that. There was a report in the New York Post that I did not
anticipate that started lit this fire of interest. And just to give you another example,
over the past couple of weeks, I had about 10 filmmakers and producers from Hollywood
contact me about the book with interest of perhaps using it for a documentary series
or perhaps a film. And it's just extraordinary, the response that I'm getting. And as you
know, the book that came out just a few days ago is already, I mean, it has been a best
seller on Amazon for a couple of weeks before it came out, even before reviews came out.
But now that there are a number of reviews of the book already in the New York Times,
in the Washington Post, in the New Yorker, also overseas in many outlets. And, you know,
I get a lot of requests more than I can accommodate. Basically, my day is full of interviews
from 8 a.m. until 7 p.m. every day. And that will continue for the next few weeks, based
on all the commitments that I've made. But I think, you know, for me, as far as I see
it, it's a platform to explain the importance of the issues that I'm trying to bring up
to the attention of the public and the science community, more than a privilege of, you know,
raising my status in any way. So I see it as an opportunity to communicate. And I'll
be glad to discuss with you the various issues that appear in my book. Maybe I'll just say
upfront that there are two major aspects of the book. One has to do with the object that
was discovered in 2017 that is very weird and doesn't look like anything we have seen
before from within the solar system. The object came from outside the solar system. And so
I suggested that maybe it's artificial in origin, not natural. And then the second part
of the book is discussing, you know, the implications that it could have to us as the
human species and why there is reluctance to consider that possibility that I just
mentioned. And are we ready to receive the news?
So the first time I heard about you is when I think Vice released an article about the
Amua the long cigar shaped shiny object that was traveling through our solar system. Could
you start out by explaining exactly what was this Amua that was traveling through our
solar system?
Well, first, also, I should say that I had many years in which I worked on other topics
of, for example, how did the first stars from the universe, the first light, which is
mentioned actually in the first chapter of the Old Testament, the Bible, how was the
first light generated in the early universe? And we can now address it with scientific
means. And I also worked on black holes for many years.
And the topic of the search for life or intelligent life in particular came to my attention
only over the past few years. And I'm actually in addition to the popular level book, we're
about to publish with a former postdoc of mine a textbook of a thousand pages long that
will be published in June 2021 that will include the foundation for future research on
this subject. And so I see it as the most exciting frontier that will that should
occupy center stage within the mainstream of astronomy in the future.
Unfortunately, right now, it's pushed to be at the periphery.
And and we can talk about that.
So let me come back to your question.
And that is Oumuamua.
This object was spotted in October 2017 by the Panstars Observatory in Hawaii, which
was tasked to look for objects that may come close to Earth because they could endanger
us. Congress gave this task to NASA to find 90 percent of all the objects that are larger
than 140 meters that get close to Earth so that we can protect ourselves by deflecting
them if they are too dangerous.
You know that the dinosaurs died as a result of a big rock.
I heard that. And they didn't have astronomers to warn them.
That's that's the point. So we have telescopes we can tell in advance if an object is
approaching us and devise methods to prevent that from happening.
So at any event, the Panstar started this process of identifying objects.
And in the process of surveying the sky, found Oumuamua, which is the very first object
that we spotted near the Earth that came from outside the solar system.
And you could tell that based on the fact that it moved too fast to be bound by the
sun. So it suddenly came from outside and it was given the name Oumuamua because it
means in the Hawaiian language, a scout or a messenger from far away.
The astronomers at first, of course, assumed that it's just like all the rocks that we
identified in the solar system.
So it probably is a comet because most of the objects are a rock covered with ice and
they reside in the outer parts of the solar system.
And the same kind of objects may exist near other stars and get ejected from those
environments and reach us.
But the problem was that there was no cometary tail.
We couldn't see any gas trailing the object.
Visually, we couldn't see it, but also the Spitzer Space Telescope looked for any traces
of carbon based molecules, couldn't see it.
So it was clearly not a comet.
But yet, at the same time, it exhibited an extra push away from the sun that is often
associated with evaporation of gas from a comet.
But since it wasn't a comet, the question was what gives it this extra push?
And I suggested that it may be the reflection of sunlight.
And for that purpose, the object had to be quite thin and not naturally produced.
It has to be something like a sail that you find on a boat, which in the case of a boat
reflects the wind.
But in the case of the sun, we're talking about the sail that reflects light and can
be pushed. This is called a light sail.
And it's a technology that we are currently developing for propulsion of
spacecrafts in space.
And the advantage is that the spacecraft doesn't need to carry its fuel.
It's just being pushed by light.
I should say there was another object identified in September 2020 just a few months
ago that exhibited also an extra push away from the sun.
And in addition to the sun's gravitational force and didn't show any cometary
tail. Turns out that this one was a rocket booster from 1966, a lunar lander
Surveyor 2 mission that was launched by NASA.
And it was simply hollow and thin.
And that's why it was pushed by reflecting sunlight.
So we know in that case that the object was artificial in origin because we produced
it. In the case of Oumuamua, we don't know who produced it.
And the other thing I should say is that from the reflected light that Oumuamua
showed, as it was tumbling, it was tumbling over eight hours, roughly the size of a
football field, from the amount of reflected sunlight, we could tell that it's
most likely flat, not cigar shaped.
And also that it's very extreme in terms of its geometry.
It's much longer than it is wide when projected on the sky.
And that fits the bill in terms of it potentially being a thin surface.
So have you seen on a lot of the articles online, have you seen some of the
renderings that they've created of it?
Oh, yeah. So the most popular rendering is that of a cigar shaped object.
And that is incorrect based on the evidence we have.
And the most likely shape is disc shape or pancake shape.
Interesting. And how far away is it from the Earth?
Oh, right now it's beyond the distance of Jupiter.
And so it's actually right now a million times fainter than when it was close to
the sun because it dims very rapidly such an object because the amount of
sunlight impinging on its surface drops inversely with distance squared.
And then the amount of light we see reflected from it drops by another factor
of one of a distance squared. So altogether, the object dims inversely
with distance to the fourth power, which is very quickly.
So by now, we can't really see it anymore.
And therefore, we cannot even design a mission that will chase it, but we can
search for other objects. You know, when I go to the kitchen and I find an ant by
looking at a small portion of the kitchen, I know that there should be many more ants
out there. And so the conclusion from finding this object is that there should be
many more. If we use the PANSTAS telescope within a few years, we should find another
one. But in fact, in three years, there would be a new survey telescope called the
Vera Rubin Observatory that could then that would be much more sensitive and
therefore could find such an object every month or so.
Right now, the telescope that found this Amuamua, what is the I guess the goal of
that telescope? Is it just like generally blanketing the sky or is it particularly
looking for doomsday asteroids?
Yeah. So the latter, it was intended to find those near Earth or objects called
NEOs. But then it just started the job of doing that.
And the Vera Rubin Observatory would then go two thirds of the way towards having a
full census. Congress tasked NASA to find 90 percent, but with the Vera Rubin
Observatory, we find maybe 60 percent of all near Earth objects above 140 meters
in size. How how much do astronomers, your colleagues or yourself, how much of your
time and focus goes towards worrying about giant Earth killer asteroids?
Very little. There is a relatively small community of astronomers that they focus
on on objects within the solar system. And then out of that community, a small
fraction worries about near Earth asteroids.
So it's mainly an observational effort to identify individual objects that may come
close to Earth because we can forecast their orbits using the law of gravity.
And so it's sort of a practical matter to monitor and figure out which objects
might come close, monitor the sky.
And we can see objects based on their reflected sunlight.
So the bigger the object is, the easier it is for us to identify it at a greater
distance. And it also depends, of course, on the telescope size and the amount of
light that you can collect within the telescope diameter.
Now, if there was an object that was similar to the one that took out the
dinosaurs that hit the Yucatan, how soon were we able to find it?
And is there anything we could possibly do to alter its course?
Yeah, so the dinosaurs went extinct.
And in fact, three quarters of the Earth's life forms were killed in that event.
I mean, there was this giant rock that collided with Earth.
It was roughly the length of Manhattan Island, tens of kilometers.
And then as it approached the Earth, probably it was a beautiful sight.
But the fun of the dinosaurs stopped when it collided with Earth and caused this huge
environmental damage, the Chicxulub crater and sort of a change in the climate of the
Earth because of all the dust that was raised.
But perhaps we owe our existence to that impact because it changed altogether the life
forms that appeared on the surface of the Earth.
And then such a big object can be identified far enough for us to plan years in advance
what to do. And there are various ideas about how to deflect it.
You can, for example, paint a side of it in a color such that it will reflect or will
evaporate more quickly and then there will be some push on it and that will deflect it
from colliding with the Earth.
You can detonate something on the surface of such an object and that would also push
it aside.
You can shine a laser beam on one side of the object and achieve the same goal.
There are all kinds of...
You can also shepherd it gravitationally with a spacecraft.
All kinds of suggestions for what to do.
It really depends on the size of the object and the composition as to what we want to do.
You don't want to, for example, destroy it into a lot of fragments because those fragments
could hit the Earth with a higher chance.
During the Gulf War, there was this Patriot missile that intercepted the missiles that
were sent, for example, towards Israel.
At the early version of these Patriot missiles, they just blasted the incoming missile into
pieces and that caused more damage than the original missile would have caused.
So you don't want to do that.
And we will have enough time to make appropriate plans depending on which object is
approaching us.
We will definitely not get extinct as the dinosaurs did.
The human brain, even though it's much smaller than the body of a dinosaur, it's much more
precious for long-term survival.
Now, why is it that you think that you're the first astronomer to come out with some
fascinating stuff like this, talking about the Amuamua and talking about interstellar
potential extraterrestrial objects coming through our solar system?
Well, first I should mention that this subject is at the periphery of astronomy.
It's not funded much.
And anyone that talks about the search for technological signatures is sort of marginalized,
sometimes to the point where the subject is ridiculed.
And that is unfortunate because it doesn't allow new talent to enter the field or to
get funded for doing research in this field.
And it's sort of like stepping on the grass and then saying, look, it doesn't grow.
So obviously, we don't get major discoveries or important results because of the
self-fulfilling prophecy that the fact that the community is not supporting it.
And I find this to be completely inappropriate because the public is extremely interested in
the question, are we alone?
I'm interested in the question beyond that, because I think that we are probably not alone.
Half of the sun-like stars have a planet the size of the Earth, roughly at the same separation.
So you have billions of Earth-Sun system just within the Milky Way galaxy, our own galaxy.
And then you have a trillion galaxies like the Milky Way within the observable volume
of the universe.
So altogether, there are more Earth-Sun systems than the numbers of grains of sand on all
beaches on Earth.
It's just huge.
And the chance that we are special or unique is really minute.
And out of modesty, we should consider the possibility that things like us exist everywhere
as the simplest assumption, the most conservative assumption.
If you replicate the same circumstances, you get the same outcome.
But for some reason, the mainstream community prefers not to think that way and say, maybe
we are unique, maybe we are special.
You need extraordinary evidence in order to argue otherwise.
I would argue that you need extraordinary evidence to assume that we are unique, because
whenever we thought that we are special, we were wrong in the past.
We thought that we are the center of the universe.
Aristotle suggested that in his philosophy.
And for a thousand years, people believed it until Copernicus and Galileo demonstrated
that the Earth moves around the sun.
And even then, the philosophers at the time didn't like the idea.
They didn't look through Galileo's telescope.
And they just maintained their ignorance.
That reality doesn't care about whether we ignore it or not.
And whenever we assume that we are unique and special, we were wrong.
It's sort of like my daughters when they were infants.
They thought that they are unique, they have qualities that nobody else has.
And they're at the center of the world.
But once they went to a kindergarten, they saw other kids and they got a better perspective.
So for us, as the human species, as civilization, to mature, we need to find others and get
a better perspective about our place in the universe.
But many people prefer, you know, it flatters their ego to maintain the view that we are
alone until proven differently.
And I find that to be completely opposite to where they should be.
But by preventing any research in this subject, by ridiculing suggestions that we might not
be alone, you know, you don't get anyone to work on that.
And that's why I'm sort of alone standing against this mainstream.
And I should say, you know, I'm not an outlier.
I've worked in the mainstream for many years.
I had a lot of leadership positions.
I was the longest serving chair of the astronomy department at Harvard between 2011 to 2020.
Nine years, a position that was renewed twice.
And I'm the chair of the Board on Physics and Astronomy of the National Academies.
And at the same time, I think that the current view is misguided.
And I think that this subject appeals to the public and the public funds science.
And therefore, we have an obligation to address it with the existing tools that we have,
telescopes and instruments.
And we can do it.
Just to give you an example, you know, the astronomers are developing the next generation
of instruments to search for and these would cost billions of dollars to search for oxygen,
for example, in the atmospheres of planets around other stars.
Because the idea is that oxygen will tell us if there is life on these planets around
other stars.
The problem with this idea is that oxygen was rare, did not exist in the Earth atmosphere
at noticeable levels for two billion years, for half of the lifetime of the Earth.
For the first two billion years, there wasn't much oxygen in the atmosphere.
But there was life on Earth.
There were microbes.
So not finding oxygen is not evidence that life doesn't exist.
Also finding oxygen is not evidence that life exists because you can make it by natural
processes.
And if you ask yourself what would be a conclusive signature of life is if we find industrial
pollution in those atmospheres.
Those molecules that are very complex and are produced by the industries that we have
or by refrigerating systems, they are called CFCs.
If we do find evidence for those, then we know that life must exist.
So in fact, the justification to the future, the next generation of instruments that astronomers
are developing is much stronger in the context of the search for technological signatures
than it is in the search for primitive life.
But nevertheless, you would never find an argument or a motivation for these instruments
in that context.
What sort of conversations have you had or debates have you had with your colleagues
or other astronomers when it comes to the pushback that you've received from being outspoken
about things like this and the Oumuamua and intelligent life?
Well, I can give you an example.
There was a seminar about the Oumuamua at Harvard.
When I left the room with a colleague of mine that worked on the solar system for decades,
he said, this object is so weird, I wish it never existed.
And that illustrates to you that the properties of this object take people away from their
comfort zone.
And most people prefer not to change their views and not to update what they thought
to be the worldview that describes the universe.
And it's sort of like a GPS system when it gets to a place that it doesn't recognize,
it says recalculating.
And unfortunately, most of my colleagues do not recalculate, they just want to maintain
their views.
So most of the mainstream would simply say, business as usual.
I don't care about the details.
It must be a rock.
To me, that sounds just like a caveman saying that when presented with a cell phone, you
know, the caveman is used to playing with rocks all of his life, saying, oh, the cell
phone is just a shiny rock.
And the point of the matter is since I don't find technological signatures as speculation,
I think it should be contemplated as a real possibility put on the table and then, you
know, one can gather more evidence to try and see if indeed it's consistent with that
and it should not be dismissed upfront.
And so I think there needs to be a revision in the culture right now within the academic
community.
There are also parts of, for example, physics, the physics community, theoretical physics,
that engage in concepts that cannot be tested experimentally, such as extra dimensions or
the multiverse or supersymmetry or string theory.
These are concepts that were not yet proven to be correct based on experimental evidence.
They are highly speculative and for decades people have been working on them and doing
mathematical gymnastics or about demonstrating how smart they are.
But you know, doing physics is not about showing off as being smart.
It's about understanding reality, understanding nature.
And if you're trying to do that, you should be guided by evidence.
Yeah, I mean, there's tons of money that goes into things like the LHC that they go to find
the Higgs boson and all those other things.
It's amazing that I would imagine, and correct me if I'm wrong, the number one thing on the
checklist of reasons to become an astronomer would be to find extraterrestrial life or
to find something out there.
Well, in fact, a lot of physicists would say that they were attracted to doing physics
because they read some science fiction stories.
And I think that this is the most exciting question for us to address because it will
change our perspective about our place in the universe, our aspirations for space.
And it could impact many things we do, including religious beliefs.
You know, and so I think it's just a missed opportunity for scientists if they have the
tools to address this question and search for technological signatures, not to do that.
And that's why I speak out loud and I use Oumuamua as an anchor to demonstrate
that here is an anomalous object that didn't look like anything we have seen before.
And all of the mainstream suggestions for why it looks so weird also invoked something
that we have never seen before, you know, a hydrogen iceberg or a cloud of dust.
And given that we are entertaining possibilities that were never seen before, why not also
a technological origin?
It's sort of like, you know, walking on the beach and most of the time you see rocks or
seashells, but every now and then you stumble across a plastic bottle that indicates that
the civilization might be around.
So how did you first come across this Oumuamua?
Well, I heard about it when it was discovered on October 19th, 2017.
After a week or so, it became quite intriguing in the sense that, you know, we realized it's
the first interstellar object, looks a little bit strange in terms of its shape.
And so I had a discussion with Yuri Milner, a Russian-Israeli science founder in Silicon Valley
about using radio telescopes to which he had access through a project called Breakthrough Listen
and trying to see if there is any radio signal coming from this object.
We checked it and put an upper limit of roughly the transmission of a cell phone.
So clearly, Oumuamua was not transmitting at the frequencies that we were looking at,
the radio frequencies.
It could have been transmitting at other frequencies, could have been transmitting in
a different direction, but we ruled out the possibility that anything in our direction was
more than the power of a cell phone.
And so at that point, you know, I thought, well, it must be probably natural.
But then six months later, there was the report about it showing, exhibiting an extra push away
from the sun.
And that could not be explained in terms of a cometary tale because we haven't seen any.
And at that point, you know, that was the straw that broke the camel's back in my vocabulary
in terms of me saying to myself, look, it's so unusual.
Maybe we should look for something out of the box to explain it.
And I wrote a couple of articles in Scientific American talking about it being a technological
artifact or relic, and then wrote a scientific paper about it in October 2018.
That got a lot of attention.
We didn't have any press release.
It just became viral in the media.
And after that, I wrote a number of papers on Oumuamua and its implications.
So you mentioned it was moving away from the sun.
Well, when we discovered it, it was already receding away from us.
Yes.
It's sort of like having a guest for dinner and realizing that the guest is interesting
when the guest goes out the front door into the dark street.
And that was unfortunate because we couldn't chase it at that point.
If we were to discover it in July instead of October.
And by the way, I was visiting that observatory,
the Pan-Stars Observatory on Mount Haleakala in Maui.
Just around that time, July 2017, with my family, we were on vacation in Maui.
And I gave a seminar there.
And at the time, nobody knew about Oumuamua.
If we were to know about it, then we could have contemplating sending out a spacecraft
equipped with a camera along its path and then getting a better view of what it looks like.
Unfortunately, we didn't know.
And so it was too late for us to chase it afterwards.
And the moral of this story is that if we find another weird object in the future
on its approach to us, we better send a camera that will take a photograph of it.
And, you know, a picture is worth a thousand words.
Right.
Now, is that something that you think we'll be able to do
next time one of these is coming close to us?
Yeah, I think it's quite possible.
And science is all about the evidence and it's about reproducibility,
the ability to study something again and again when it repeats.
And in this case, given the fact that Pan-Stars looked,
surveyed the sky for a few years before it discovered this object,
we should definitely find another one that looks like it within a few years from now.
Because otherwise, it's very unlikely that we found a rare object just within a few years.
Now, what were the main differences between this and other things that you see,
like asteroids or comets or something like that?
Obviously, the shape was different.
And yeah, the shape was more extreme.
It was projected on the sky 10 times longer than it is wide.
And imagine a piece of paper tumbling in the wind, even if it's razor thin,
the chance of it being exactly edge on is very small.
So most of the time, it would change the amount of area that you see.
But the change by a factor of 10 or more is quite extreme.
And the second is that we infer that it's most likely flat based on the
amount of light that it reflected as it was tumbling.
What do you think it was?
What do you think it legitimately was?
Well, I think it was probably a very thin object, artificially produced,
and probably dysfunctional, not something that is being used for spying on us or some other purpose.
Simply because it was tumbling, it was out of control in a way.
But also, if you think about it, we sent out Voyager 1, Voyager 2, New Horizons,
all kinds of space junk.
And a million years from now, all of this will be real junk
in the sense that it will not be functional anymore.
So if you wait for long times, these objects that are being sent into space
may not continue to be functional.
They don't have enough energy supply to keep them functional.
And there might be a lot of them floating in space,
just like plastic bottles in the ocean that are swept ashore.
And we find them every now and then.
So it's sort of like waste filling up interstellar space.
And every now and then, we will bump into one.
Now, could you define exactly what interstellar...
Does that mean not bound to the sun?
Well, yeah, interstellar...
Well, more generally, interstellar means between stars.
And in this...
So in this context, you can say Oumuamua came from the space between stars.
It came into the solar system from outside the solar system.
The question about its origin is not answered,
because we don't know where it came from.
It was actually...
Another weird fact about it is that it was situated in a special frame of reference.
It was in the local standard of rest,
which is the frame that you get to when you average
over the motions of all the stars in the vicinity of the sun.
And Oumuamua was at rest in that frame.
So it's sort of like finding a car that is parked at rest in a public parking lot.
You cannot really tell which house it came from,
because all the stars, in the case of the local standard of rest,
all the local stars are moving relative to that frame.
Only one in 500 stars is so much at rest,
relative to the local standard of rest, as Oumuamua was.
One way to think about it, it was like a beauty sitting on the surface of the ocean,
and the solar system bumped into it,
because the sun is moving relative to that frame.
And you may ask what purpose does it serve being in that special frame?
You know, one possibility is that there is a grid of such objects,
and they serve as road posts.
When you navigate through interstellar space,
you can find your coordinates where you are relative to those objects.
Another possibility is that it's a relay station for communication,
that you don't need to communicate across large distances,
you just communicate by the signal hopping from one relay station to the next.
We use this approach on Earth.
Now, what did you say the name of the telescope that was being,
the new telescope, the billion-dollar...
Vera Rubin.
Oh, the name of the telescope that we survey the sky, you mean?
You mentioned that there was like a billion-dollar telescope being built in Chile.
Well, there is the Vera Rubin Observatory that will be much more sensitive than
the Pan-Stars Telescope that discovered Oumuamua in Hawaii,
and it will be in Chile, yes.
Okay, and the primary focus of that will be to
discover these things before it's too late.
Yeah, discover near-Earth objects with much greater sensitivity than Pan-Stars,
and it will be able to find about two-thirds of those that the Congress tasked NASA to find,
you know, so 60% of the entire population.
What are your opinions on, in the recent year or two,
all of the different, you know, there's been Air Force pilots based in San Diego
that have come out and they've had their videos of these UFOs coming out of the water
and within one second being meters away.
Do you guys pay any attention to that stuff?
Well, I do. I mean, I cannot speak for others.
And my view on these reports, these eyewitness reports of unidentified flying objects,
UFOs that are unusual, my view is that these eyewitness testimonies come from
people that are not scientists, that were not planning to find these unusual things,
and we will be better served if we were to deploy scientific instruments
in those sites and monitor the environment.
You know, I have two concerns about these reports of UFOs over the past decades.
One of them is that now we have cameras and recording devices
that are far better than we had decades ago.
And back then, you know, the images were fuzzy
and it was difficult to be sure what it means and so forth.
But with present-day instruments, it should be crisp clear.
They are much better than we used to have
and they are still fuzzy and, you know, on the margin of believability.
The second reservation that they have is there are far many more cameras
available to monitor environments right now by orders of magnitude.
You know, people have cell phones, you have drones,
you have cameras on satellites, on airplanes, in the streets of cities.
And the number of video cameras looking at what's going on
is many orders of magnitude larger than it used to be a decade or two ago.
Nevertheless, the reports on UFOs have not increased.
So that concerns me that maybe, you know, all of these reports were sort of
artifacts of the instruments that were used or impressions of natural phenomena.
But I think that it would be appropriate to deploy
scientific instruments and check it out.
It's really, I mean, science is about reproducibility of results.
So one-time events are not believable in science.
You should be able to reproduce them by being in the same environment
under similar circumstances.
And I would trust instruments recording these events.
You know, there is this biblical story from the Old Testament about Abraham
that heard the voice of God and that voice told Abraham to sacrifice his only son, Isaac.
And imagine Abraham having a cell phone with a voice memo up.
If he could have pressed the button, he would have recorded the voice of God.
And then instead of an eyewitness testimony, we would have the recording
and that would have convinced all of humanity that God exists.
And so my point is that by recording things on instruments,
you get a much more objective evidence than all these reports that are now being
declassified from the Pentagon and so forth.
We should not obsess with these old reports that were based on either eyewitnesses
or instruments that are much more inferior to the instruments we have now.
We should simply use our best instruments, go to these sites,
and see whether we see anything unusual.
Well, the Pentagon actually said that they were in possession of some sort of
extraterrestrial craft in the New York Times article.
Well, what I'm saying is that it's better.
You know, Abraham said that he heard the voice of God, right?
So the question is, do you believe Abraham or not?
I'm saying if he had a cell phone, we could have looked at the evidence.
He didn't have that.
And then you have to decide whether you believe the biblical story or not.
And the same is true here.
People report things and I don't know whether to believe them.
So the only way for me to believe them, scientifically speaking,
is to deploy recording devices in the same sites and see if they find something.
What is your opinion on humans and how long we're going to be here on Earth?
Do you think we're ever going to have to leave Earth?
Oh, yeah, definitely.
Currently, all our eggs are in one basket and everything that is precious to us
could get eliminated, extinct if something catastrophic happens on Earth.
If an asteroid impacts us or if there is, for example,
a nuclear war or a climate change or something catastrophic.
And it would make much more sense to spread our eggs in different baskets
and go somewhere else as well and have duplicates of what we hold important and valuable here.
It's sort of like the Gutenberg printing press.
There were very few copies of the Bible before the printing press was invented.
Then they were all handwritten and each of them was extremely precious.
But once the printing press came to exist, there were many more copies.
And if something bad happened to one of them, it wasn't a catastrophe.
You could make new ones.
And then we can imagine saving life as we know it on Earth.
And the approach would be similar to what Noah did in the biblical story of Noah's Ark.
There is the story about the great flood that endangered life on Earth.
And so Noah decided to build an ark and put animals in it so that it will save them.
We can, in principle, design a similar approach and build
Noah's spaceship that will save life on Earth.
But we don't need to put elephants and whales on it.
We just need to put the computer and a 3D printer.
And if the computer has the information about the DNA of all life forms that we care about,
then this system can go to another planet.
And in principle, it could make the life as we know it out of the raw materials
that exist there on another planet.
You don't need to bring the life with you.
You can recreate them as long as we figure out how to make synthetic life.
And that's not speculative because people are, as we speak,
people are trying to produce synthetic life in the laboratory.
And so I wouldn't be surprised if within the next few decades we will be able to do that.
And so once we are able to do that, we can potentially produce life on other planets
without carrying it from Earth and just using what we know about the genetics and so forth
in making that life over there out of the raw materials there.
How long do you think it would be before we would have to do that?
Oh, that depends on us.
How quickly we inflict the wounds on ourselves.
If we are not smart enough, we might not survive for more than a few centuries from now.
We started developing our technologies about a century ago.
And our technologies are advancing exponentially with a characteristic timescale of a few years.
So it's quite possible that within the next century,
unless we are careful, we could develop technologies that will destroy us.
And we need to be really careful about what we do to the planet, what we do to ourselves.
We don't pay that much attention to it.
Because we are so close to when technology started developing.
But once we go a few decades into the future, we will be in a real risk of extinction, I think.
And because there would be technologies that could potentially destroy life on the planet.
And then we just need to be smart enough to avoid that.
And right now, I wouldn't say that we are very intelligent in the way we do our politics.
There are lots of conflicts.
And we invest most of our efforts in fighting each other among nations and so forth.
And that is not the smart approach.
We should collaborate, especially on issues that science can address.
And you could see that in the context of COVID, right?
So when it started in China, there wasn't much sharing of information.
And science is global.
Science is international.
It's supposed to be a mode of collaboration among nations.
And in promoting a better future for humanity.
And I very much hope that then ultimately science will prevail
and suppress all these tensions among people that really could bring us down.
If you look at the World Wars, there was a lot of effort dedicated to killing people.
And that makes no sense whatsoever.
Yeah, I think especially recently, I feel like the internet has really
made everything in this world so much more transparent.
And I think there's a big paradigm shift happening, especially with the recent news.
I'm sure you've heard the GameStop stocks, the people online that were buying the stocks
that the hedge funds bet against.
And 10 years ago, this is something no one understood hedge funds
or the stock market or what these bets on them failing even were.
And people were able to benefit off that and essentially create this massive gap,
this massive gap between the billionaires on Wall Street
and the average working person, blue collar worker.
And now it's becoming the internet has made this so much more transparent.
I feel like this is something that has to happen with science.
You can somehow correlate it to what's happening with what you're doing.
And now you released your book and you're talking to everybody about it.
Well, one thing I would like to highlight in this context is we tend to think that
technology and science is superior to the humanities.
So humanities are in decline, the study of philosophies,
the study of literature and so forth.
Young people are more attracted to science and technology.
The problem is that we develop tools using science and technology that could destroy us.
And the only way to prevent it is to have the humanists
telling us how to guide ourselves towards a better future.
For example, how to set the rules such that genetic engineering
will not end up making people the type that we want
and all kinds of other issues that come up, like artificial intelligence.
If we allow it to make life-death decisions on medical issues,
we have to worry about the morality of that.
And at what level do we allow the machine to decide the fate of a person
versus having people involved?
In the past, it was the doctor that made the decision.
You could trust the doctor better because the doctor would be a human
that has a bigger perspective, that is more balanced in a way.
If you have a machine deciding, you have to decide about a set of rules
of what's moral and what's ethical and how the machine decides who dies and who lives.
There are lots of such issues with modern technologies.
The humanities, the way I see it, play a central role.
As a young kid, I was mostly interested in philosophy.
I grew up on a farm, and then circumstances brought me into physics and astrophysics.
But I value these areas of humanities, like philosophy, very much.
I think they are essential for guiding us to a better future.
Without them, we could be nerds developing all kinds of tools that will kill us as a civilization.
How did you transition from studying things like black holes
to studying what you're studying now?
How did you make that transition?
It was by chance.
For example, I was studying the first generation of stars in the universe,
the first stars that formed, that lit up in the universe early on.
Those stars had an impact on their environment.
They basically broke the hydrogen atoms around them into their constituent electrons and protons.
If you want to see the scars left by the first stars on their environment,
you want to image the hydrogen around them.
Hydrogen emits faint radio waves.
Therefore, I worked on a frontier that tries to map the hydrogen in the early universe.
For that purpose, you need to develop radio observatories.
Observatories that are sensitive at radio frequencies of around 100 to 200 megahertz.
It so happens that these radio observatories operated exactly the same frequency band as
FM radio stations and TV stations.
One concern was that there would be interference from TV and radio stations on Earth.
Then it occurred to me that the same observatories could, in principle,
eavesdrop on another civilization, on a planet around another star,
that transmits those radio waves.
I wrote a paper about it.
That was my first encounter with a search for technological signatures.
I visited Abu Dhabi for the inauguration of a new campus for NYU.
That was around 2012 or so.
When we went around, the tour guide was bragging that the city lights
there are visible from the moon.
They're so bright.
That gave me the idea of checking how far can you see a city
with the Hubble Space Telescope, for example.
We found with Ed Turner, a collaborator of mine,
that in principle, the Hubble Space Telescope can see a city like Tokyo
on Pluto, the edge of the solar system of planets.
That was an interesting idea, that you can look for artificial lights
as a signature of another civilization.
You can identify these artificial lights, not as reflected sunlight,
by the way the source dims as it changes its distance from us.
That was my second paper.
Then the third one on this subject was when astronomers talked about
searching for biological signatures in the atmospheres of planets.
If you look for industrial pollution, that would imply
there is an industrial civilization there.
I wrote a paper about that.
Gradually, it drifted in this direction.
That was 2015.
Over the past few years, especially because of Oumuamua,
I published a lot on this subject.
In about half a year, I will have a textbook out of more than a thousand
pages with my former postdoc, Manas Vilinga,
that lays the foundation for future studies on this subject
of the search for both primitive and intelligent life.
You mentioned earlier when you were talking about 3D printing
and printing organisms or basically duplicating ourselves on other planets.
Now, I've heard reports of people who have worked at S1 and Area 51
have obtained crafts that are very small,
saying that only really tiny beings that have no reproductive organs.
Is it possible that other beings are printing these sort of cadavers
or basically like humanoids, but aliens,
that can travel long distances through different solar systems
that don't have to stay alive, they don't have to eat?
Everything is possible and there are lots of possibilities
outlined in science fiction stories.
The key as a scientist is to look for evidence
and that should guide you as to which possibilities are real
and which are illusions or our imagination of what might be out there.
It's sort of like a detective story.
You can have an infinite number of possibilities
and you just sort them out and figure out which one is realized
by collecting clues and evidence.
We could think that we are wealthier than Elon Musk,
we could have a lot of money
and the only way to figure out what we actually have
is to go to an ATM machine and check it out.
And so the ATM machine represents an experiment
where you actually check what you have
and that's what guides modern science, evidence and clues.
Many times scientists prefer to have ideas
that do not stand up to the scrutiny of experiments
and that's legitimate as long as the ideas can be tested in principle.
The frustration I have is that some parts of the physics community right now,
you know, there are hundreds of people working on ideas
that will never be tested in their lifetime
and that to me could be a waste of their time
because it's imagining things that may not exist.
If we were to go and put ourselves on another planet,
which planet do you think it would be?
Do you think it would be Mars or would it be a Proxima B?
So there are two planets that are closest to us
and in principle could have life on them
or we could imagine going there and changing conditions
such that we could live there.
They are Mars and Venus on the two sides of the Earth.
Mars used to have an atmosphere
and probably had conditions similar to Earth early on in its life
but then because it's 10 times less massive than the Earth,
it couldn't hold on to its atmosphere so the atmosphere evaporated
and then it lost the potential for liquid water on its surface
because you can't have liquid water unless there is an atmospheric pressure
and so even if there was life on Mars it couldn't continue.
There was no liquid water available
and the Perseverance mission will actually get there in February 2021
in less than a few weeks actually
and we'll figure out whether there was
or maybe there is some left over signatures of life in the Martian soil
and so that would be very exciting
and I'm very much looking forward to seeing the results from this mission
but then going there for us, for humans,
would require a lot of adaptation
because just standing on the surface of Mars
without an atmosphere, without a strong magnetic field that Mars doesn't have
we will be exposed to energetic particles, cosmic rays
that could damage within a year
you will have a substantial damage to the cells in your brain
and you need protection from that
and one way to protect our bodies is to go underground
to go into a cave or to build some infrastructure that will protect us
there is not enough attention given to that
so just sending humans to Mars without proper protection would be irresponsible
it's sort of like a death sentence
you don't want to do that
so we need to come up with solutions to protect people that go there
but potentially it's a place that we could
modify such that we could live there
and you can imagine not necessarily going to a planet
you can put some platform in space
we started in the jungles of Africa
and we ended up in apartment buildings in cities
that's a big leap over a period of a hundred thousand years
I don't see the leap from an apartment building
in a city in Manhattan to going to space
as big as the leap from Africa to an apartment building
we could do it
it will require some time
but a hundred thousand years is a huge period
over which we will have technologies that are far superior to what we have now
so I'm quite optimistic that we could adapt to living in space
but it will take some time
and then Venus right now on the surface
it went through a greenhouse effect
and the surface is extremely hot
it cannot sustain liquid water
you cannot live on the surface of Venus
there was some suggestion that maybe there is life in the clouds of Venus
so the only way for us to inhabit Venus would be to terraform it
to change the condition such that it's not as hot as it is
but then of course we can go to Proxima b
we can go to another star
the nearest star is Proxima Centauri
and it has a habitable planet next to it
and that planet is the star that it has a permanent day side
and a permanent night side
and my daughters say that the strip that separates those two sides
is the most would have the highest real estate value
because it will be a permanent sunset strip
and have a house there you can see the sunset forever
for dummies like myself who've never heard of Proxima b or Proxima the other one
can you explain where they are and what they are?
yeah Proxima Centauri is a member of a three star system
that is the closest to the sun right now
I mean it will continue to be the closest star system to us
for about a hundred thousand years
so every hundred thousand years or so there is a new star coming closest to us
and then it's passing
and right now Proxima Centauri is the nearest
and it's actually a dwarf star that is only 12 percent of the mass of the sun
so it's much fainter
most of the stars are much smaller and fainter than the sun
so we live next to an unusual star
most of the stars are like Proxima Centauri
and it has roughly half the surface temperature that the sun has
only 3000 degrees Kelvin compared to almost 6000 that the sun has
and therefore it emits mostly infrared light
the sun emits mostly visible light
that's why our eyes are tuned to visible light
but the creatures if there are any creatures on the habitable planet next to Proxima Centauri
they should have infrared eyes
which would be very strange for us to see actually
and if there is any grass growing there it will be dark red
so if you think about interstellar travel agencies designing trips
if most of the living creatures are living near dwarf stars that are the most common
they are used to red to dark red grass
and they will never come to a planet like ours that offers green grass
that will not be a desirable tourist destination
because they don't like this color
they enjoy having a vacation on a dark red grass
that may explain why we haven't seen any visitors
can you explain a little bit more what would the eyes of the beings on that planet look like
why would they be what would an infrared eye look like?
I don't know it would look shocking to us
it would look very different than our eyes
so our eyes were developed over time to take advantage of most of the light produced by the sun
which is visible light
but if you're next to a star that produces mostly infrared radiation
then evolution would lead you to be sensitive to that kind of light
this is the kind of light you get from warm objects
like soldiers have those goggles that are sensitive to infrared radiation at night
at night there is not much visible light
because you're on the other side of the earth where the sun is not around
but objects are warm enough to emit infrared radiation
and you can see them with these goggles
that's what the people that have infrared goggles can see
the heat emitted by bodies that are warm
and that's the kind of infrared radiation that the star Proxima Centauri is mostly emitting
so of course if we had goggles, infrared goggles, we would see that radiation very clearly
but those animals, creatures that may be born there, they have those sensors
infrared sensors that they are born with
because that gives them an evolutionary advantage
the reason we have visible light eyes is because it gives us an advantage
we can survive better if we see the light from the sun
because it's reflected off objects so we can protect ourselves
if there is something endangering us
we can avoid that danger by seeing that object
and that's why we have sensitivity to visible light
which is the most common type of light near the sun
but if we were next to Proxima Centauri, it would not offer us much advantage
and then probably we would not survive
and animals that have infrared eyes would survive because they can see the danger
if there is another animal coming to eat them
they would be able to escape because they're sensitive to infrared light
which is the most common form of light in their environment
real quick, I wanted to go back to the mission you just spoke about
that's about to arrive in Mars in a couple weeks now
what is the purpose of that mission?
they're looking specifically for life?
right, so this is the Perseverance mission
and yes, one of the highlights of this mission is to search for signatures of life
and there were previous missions going back almost 50 years
that had some tentative evidence that perhaps
there is something in the Martian soil
that is going through metabolism that is living
because they took a sample of that soil
and they noticed that there is some gas coming out of it
that may indicate life
and when they heat that soil to a high temperature
suddenly that goes away
and there was a suggestion that maybe it indicates that there is life in that soil
and so the Perseverance mission is equipped with all kinds of instruments
that could then search for life that may exist right now
but also search for life that may have existed before
if there were rivers or ponds in the location where Perseverance lands
then there might be some leftover signatures of life that may have existed there
we don't know exactly how it might look
it might be skeletons or something else
but the idea is to search for it
and it would be very exciting to see what they find
yeah, I mean it sounds like we're doing everything we can possibly do
within our means to do these types of studies
and to try to find extraterrestrial life
and to find out if we're the only ones here or not
well, primitive life I should say
because technological signatures we are not doing enough
that's what I started from
I've heard you compare stagnation of the scientific community to technology
or to corporate commercial technology
you know, companies like SpaceX for example
which obviously are funded and they generate a profit
compared to science and the communities that you're involved in
can you speak a little bit to that?
yeah, so one would expect the academic world to take more risks
than the commercial world
because companies are mainly focused on making a profit
whereas in academia there is this concept of tenure
where the professor has a secure job
and the purpose of that was that once you get to that phase
you can explore blue sky research and take risks
and allow yourself to be wrong if it doesn't end up the way you wanted
unfortunately, most of my colleagues in academia do not take risks
because they want to get honours and awards
and they want to maintain an image of someone that doesn't make mistakes
and they build echo chambers that repeat their voice
making it louder so that their reputation is improved
but at the same time they don't innovate much
because innovation implies taking risks and being wrong sometimes
and at the same time in the commercial sector
you find companies as you mentioned like SpaceX or Google or many others
that have groups of people that are thinking
that are taking risks and checking ideas out of the box
and the reason they do that is because they recognise
that the next major discovery that will make them a big profit
would come in unexpected directions
so they're taking risks because even though some of the directions fail
if one of them ends up being real
it would compensate for all the losses associated with the failed directions
if companies recognise the value of that
academia should have recognised it much more
and it's quite unfortunate that there is not as much innovation in academia
as there should be
and that's why I'm trying to promote an open mind
in the context that we discussed before
of searching for technological signatures
but more generally I think it's extremely important
for example for federal grants to be given
also to people that have risky propositions
people that consider ideas out of the box
NASA for example very often funds projects
that can declare ahead of time what they will discover
what they will find
and that's contradictory to the nature of discovery
very often you discover things that you haven't expected
you cannot tell in advance to the funder what you will find
or else what you're doing is very boring
so I think the funding agencies should also allocate
some fraction of their funding to risky propositions
to out of the box thinking and allow for that
it all comes together in a culture where innovation
and risk-taking is appreciated
yeah it almost doesn't make sense
it almost seems like somebody like Elon Musk
would have way more to lose by venturing outside the box
than a researcher or a scientist would
it seems like they wouldn't have as much to lose
I completely agree but it's human nature
that drives people in academia towards
being less innovative, less risk-taking
because this way they can maintain an image
that makes of someone reputable
so that they get honors and awards
and by the way one way to not make mistakes
is not to put skin in the game
so not to be engaged in predictions
that can be tested experimentally and proven wrong
and that's why you find this culture of people
that work on subjects that are sort of esoteric
have no connection to reality
and cannot be tested experimentally
because that's much more attractive
you can just demonstrate that you are smart
and never be proven wrong
isn't that the point of science to be proven wrong
yes I would argue that
and that's what I argue yes
and that's what I practice
I don't just preach
but it's not easy to change the culture
and I think it should change
and I hope it will change
and my book discusses that
as one of the most important messages of the book
so I very much encourage people to have a look in it
and you talk about Einstein as well
yeah I mean Einstein in the last decade of his career
when he was the most experienced
and obviously he was the leading scientist of his generation
made three mistakes
and these were major mistakes
that we now know are completely wrong based on experiments
you know we detected gravitational waves
and he claimed they don't exist
we detected black holes
he claimed they don't exist
we also detected spooky action at a distance
in quantum mechanics
and he claimed it doesn't exist
but that's part of being at the frontier
you never know in advance
what is the right direction
and even if you are the smartest person around
like Einstein was
you make mistakes
and that should be tolerated
because if you look at Einstein
you know he also made important breakthroughs
at the same time or before that time
and so the other thing is
his generation was putting skin in the game
you know he was making predictions
and they were tested
the current generation wants to always be valued as smart
without putting any skin in the game
so they you know a lot of physicists
theoretical physicists
are doing intellectual gymnastics
they're using sophisticated mathematics
and that serves the role of demonstrating they're smart
but it doesn't necessarily describe nature
do you think some of the reason
that you're getting a lot of backlash
is because people are threatened
by you coming out and talking about this
maybe they see Avi getting all this attention
and talking about this
but they've never gotten this amount of attention
from anyone about any of their ideas
well one aspect of that is jealousy of course
for that attention
but another one is because I address
my main message is that we should be modest
that science is a learning experience
and that making mistakes is okay
that's part of the scientific process
you know we should be just like kids
trying to understand the world
and willing to not be so attached to our egos
so I'm trying to remove that connection
between the ego of a scientist
and the profession
you know we are trying to understand nature
we should engage in a dialogue with experiments
we should not consider it as an evaluation of our abilities
it's not about us
it's about understanding nature
and it's a dialogue with experiments
and we just have to start from a point of modesty
you know and that modesty is communicated to us
by looking at the universe
you know we are so small
we are so short-lived
how can anyone be arrogant
okay that makes no sense to me
how can anyone be racist
you know that also makes no sense to me
because just based on the color of his skin
you decide what the person is
I mean that's completely ridiculous
so people have this tendency of wanting to feel superior to other people
either by demonstrating that they are smart
or by demonstrating that their DNA may be superior to others
all kinds of ways of demonstrating superiority
and it all drives it all stems from their ego
and what I say is just leave that aside
that causes the worst in human nature
you know all of the wars
all of the the worst things that happen in human history
were driven by ego
we should try to push it aside
be as modest as possible
which is what the universe is telling us
stay modest
you're not at the center of anything
and we might not be the smartest kid on the block
I'm trying to convey this message
and the pushback is in part
because people are too attached to their ego
it bothers them
takes them out of the comfort zone
they want to feel as if they are respected, smart
never make mistakes
never have to revise their view of the universe
just like the philosophers during the days of Galileo
they didn't want to look through the telescope
because they were happy believing that they're at the center of the universe
they were comfortable where they were
exactly it's sort of like my daughters saying
we don't want to go to a kindergarten
you know at home
if we have a small enough environment at home
we feel as if we are the smartest kid
there is nobody like us
we feel great
that's our comfort zone
we will never go out
and you know that's sort of the tendency
not to explore
because then you feel proud of yourself
you can be arrogant
if you limit your view to a small environment
but it goes against the fundamentals of science
because staying comfortable inhibits growth
exactly that's my point
exactly
and that's why I have this battle
and by the way I'm getting a huge response from the public
a lot of emails
also from people in academia that feel the same
mostly young people
because young people are not attached as much to their ego
and I'm hopeful for the future
you know I do not care how many likes I have on Twitter
I just am focused
you know just like basketball coaches
advise their team players
keep your eyes on the ball
not on the audience
and that's what I'm trying to do
now you don't even have any social media right?
no I don't
because my wife asked me not to have any
and I respected that
and I don't miss that
because it frees my time
and also allows me to be more creative
without being biased by the herd
or the you know view
so for my audience
you don't have any social media
so people that are listening or watching this
what can you suggest to them
to learn more about what you're doing
or to find more of your writings or your books?
yeah they can go to my website
by putting my name on Google Avi Loeb
and I have a main website where I list
my commentaries in Scientific American
I publish roughly once a week
or once every two weeks
I also have scientific papers
more than 800 of them listed there
and books
and they're welcome to say
anyone is welcome to send me an email
and I'll be glad to correspond
so in general I do have communication
with a broad audience
but not through social media
that's amazing man
well hey I'm super grateful for you
having this conversation with me
I really appreciate it
I've learned a lot from you
my pleasure
thank you for having me