It's an honor to have you here. I really appreciate you coming down and doing the show.
You have a phenomenal body of work behind you from Phenomenon, all the works before
that, your latest film. It's totally, absolutely mind-bending, some of the stuff that you do.
For people that aren't familiar, I doubt there's any, but for people that don't know or aren't
familiar with your work, just give me a brief background on how you got into this subject,
filmmaking.
How brief?
Yeah, we got plenty of time.
Okay, because I could actually give you a slightly less brief version because it's kind
of funny how I got into it all.
Were you into filmmaking? Were you originally just a filmmaker first and just got obsessed
with this topic of UFOs and UAVs?
Kind of, kind of.
Because I can tell just by your work, the way you produce your films, the style and
everything, I'm a big fan of that in a totally separate bubble of the topic. If you even
separate the UFO topic, which is fascinating, the style of your films and the way you cut
them and the way you shoot them, I'm a huge fan of that.
Thank you. I strive for credibility with the Phenomenon because I used to always tell people
they're like, oh, you got to add the green smoke and the, you know, the cheesy lights.
And I'm like, no, you don't. The story itself, any UFO story is so fascinating, so otherworldly,
excuse the pun there, but that I would always say if you could add credibility to a fascinating
story, like someone coming in contact allegedly with a UFO, then that will succeed, you know,
because that's the story's already so incredible and already so unbelievable that if you could
add that element of credibility to your production, then that's a winning recipe.
And so I developed that very, very early on. I remember having like shouting matches with
the two older guys that I was working with. They're like, you don't know anything about
filmmaking and we're going to put, you know, you need to add overproduce and put cheesy
effects in and just, just stuff that was just makes you want to puke in a bucket. You know
what I mean?
Yeah. We talked about this before. There's a lot of, there's a lot of shows out there
on the big networks that they go so far overboard with the graphics, the motion graphics and
all that stuff and the production of it. And it's just so for people like, I don't know
for normal people what it's like, but for people like you and me, it's just, you can
see right through it. It just makes it, I don't think it does the subject any favors.
I find it unwatchable when I look at it, because if this, if the story's not compelling enough
to carry itself and you have to add those so-called bells and whistles or whatever to
keep people's attention, then, then don't do that story. You know what I mean?
Let me back up. My father was a mainstream journalist. His name was Charles Fox. He wrote,
we lived on the East coast. He wrote for Car and Driver magazine in the sixties and he
was born in England and he got multiple sclerosis when, when I was born. And so I, as I grew
up, I became sort of his, his legs, his secretary, his chauffeur, his assistant, and I traveled
all around and got to do these really cool stories, watching my father perform as a journalist.
And it was a lot of hard work. I remember thinking like all the writing for the stories
and all the copy editing that goes into it. It was more work than you'd expect when it's
just words. And so I kind of was exposed to journalism at an early age, more so than it
would have been because of my father's condition. And people would be like, oh, you're so lucky
you got to travel around the world and do all these cool things. I'm like, you try traveling
with a quadriplegic sometime. Okay. And see how, how hard that is, you know, because it's
basically like, you know, having a, you know, a 200 pound baby trying to make a living.
And I'm not referring to my dad as a baby. He was an amazing guy, but I had to take care
of all of his needs because he couldn't move, but he would travel and he was incredibly
driven and he was hilarious and fun to be around. And so we had a kind of a different
relationship, father-son relationship very early on because of his dependence on me and
my dependence on him. It was a co-dependency thing, but we got along great and we had a
lot of fun. We traveled all around the world and I was driving on the Autobahn when I was
like 15, you know, basically doing stuff that I shouldn't have been doing until I was, I
remember driving to go see this guy, Dan Gurney was a race car driver. He, there was films
about him even on now, I think Mustang versus Ford or no Ford versus Ferrari. Anyway, my
dad goes, God, my legs are really bad today. I can't drive, you know, and I was like 12
or 13. We were in Southern California and he goes, you're going to have to take the
wheel. I said, dad, I've never driven on the freeway. He goes, just keep it. I'll never
forget this. He goes, just keep it between the lines. So I've got this big van and my
dad in his chair and I'm like, you know, because with multiple sclerosis, he couldn't, he got
to the point where he couldn't walk anymore, but he could still like move his legs a little
bit on a good day where he could, you know, activate the accelerator. Eventually he lost
all movement, but there was a period of, I don't know, five or 10 years where on a good
day things were going well. You know, he could drive if you could get him behind the wheel.
He could push the accelerator pedal and the brake pedal and all that stuff. But I just
remember like, and then we pulled up to interview this guy, Dan Gurney, and who won LeMans,
I think in the sixties. And he goes, uh, how old your son driving, you know? So my point
is, is that I got to, uh, share a, intimately share my father's career as a journalist very
early on because of his, his condition. And so I, um, I remember, uh, finding the video
camera, like just discovering the video camera and what a great tool that was for instant
playback and communication and documentation of stuff. And it seemed to me a really nice
alternative than all the hard work that my father used to have to do with writing stories.
I mean, I was shocked at how much work went into writing an article. Of course, later,
I realized, you know, once you document things, you've got to edit them in the edit room and
that process is very tedious. But any case, I picked up a video camera and, um, I thought,
wow, this is great. I could really get into this, you know, documenting stories. I, uh, I did,
I did some PSAs, public service announcements, just basic editing. And then a very good friend
of mine turned me on and I'll give you guys, I don't want to give you the super long version
of it because I'm, you know, you guys would, your eyes would glaze over, but, uh, uh, it turned me
on to UFOs. And he was like, this is back in the nineties when it wasn't really out that much,
like the early nineties, you know? And, and, and I went to high school with this guy and I
remember thinking, boy, too bad this friendship's over because he's lost his mind. And he was talking
about Roswell. He goes, Oh, you haven't heard about Roswell, the UFO that crashed and the recovery.
And I just dismissed him as quickly as you could. I mean, I literally was like,
what a pity. My very dear friend, Renee, I'm gonna have to write our friendship off because
he's lost his mind. And then I was, um, I was apprenticing at a video production company in
Northern California. And I started talking to this guy, Richard Van Sickle, who's running the
company. And I had a lot of respect for, I looked up to him a lot and I said, yeah, my buddy, Renee,
started leaving UFOs and Roswell. He goes, Oh, you don't know about that? I was like, no, I don't
know Roswell. I mean, an alien spaceship crashed. He goes, yeah, you didn't know about that?
I was like, no, how am I supposed to know about that? You know? And so I started to look into it
and I realized, you know, wow, the military really did put out an official statement
that this happened. And then I went to a couple of conferences and I met some ex-military guys
that were talking about, you know, gun cam footage of UFOs in the fifties. And I thought, wow,
these guys are really credible. Maybe there's something to this. And I was just kind of,
kind of interested. And so I was like, I got my video camera. I'm going to make a documentary
on UFOs. And, and, um, my father was horrified. I mean, he was like, son, please come back. Like,
what happened? What did I do wrong? You know? And he was begging me. He said, literally, I'll never
forget it. He goes, it's a dead end street, son. There's nothing to it. It's going nowhere.
Don't waste your life. And I thought, my father's been so supportive of so many things for so long.
He used to say to me when I was a kid, I don't care if you want to be a garbage man or if you
want to be a teacher or whatever it is that makes you happy. That's what I will support always.
That's the only thing that matters in life. And yet this, he was so opposed to it. And he had
members cause I was born in England. He had members of my family writing letters to say,
please, your father's begging you to reconsider it. Don't waste your life, you know, kind of thing.
And I'm like a Taurus. I'm kind of stubborn. And I thought, well, I'll, I'll show him. And so I
probably worked like 10 times harder than I've ever worked in my life just to kind of show him,
you know? And it was hard, boy, it was really hard. And, um, it took me about four and a half years
and I got some incredible interviews. And the, the final coup for me was I got to,
I got the opportunity to do a phone interview with Apollo 14 astronaut Edgar Mitchell.
And that really kind of solidified, um, the credibility of the film. It kind of
stepped it up a few notches. And I went to Roswell for the 50th anniversary towards the tail end of
production. And I got some, some never before seen testimony from, uh, alleged army officials
that were involved in Roswell. Cause like in 1997, that was the tail end of when the people
were dying off. You know what I mean? Was Roswell, right? Like it was, it had been 50 years. So the
people that were, you know, they were like in their, excuse me, they were in their like, uh,
twenties, they would have been in their seventies. So 50 years was kind of the last, the 50th
anniversary of Roswell. You could actually go there and meet a handful of people that were directly
involved with the incident. They're all dead now pretty much. I don't think there's anybody left
alive. So anyway, I went there and I, and I, and I made this film and I ended up selling it to
Discovery Channel. And I was so burnt out by the process. I had no idea what it took to make a
documentary and how long it took and how much work it took and all the B-roll and the editing
and the writing and the researching. My God, you know, it just really kind of caught me off guard.
But it was about four and a half years and I sold it to Discovery Channel and everyone was kind of
shocked, my dad included. And I thought, well, never again am I doing any UFOs. I've, you know,
that's, this is, this was it. And then, um, and if I'm going on too long, just, just tell me,
because just trying to tell you how I got involved with this whole thing. And I never intended to be
where I'm at today, nearly 30 years later of still producing documentaries on UFOs because
never in my wildest dreams did I ever think I'd be that guy. And I never wanted to be that guy. But
when the film sold to Discovery, everyone was shocked, myself included, and doors started to
open like, oh, here's an independent guy who treated the subject matter seriously, who didn't
ridicule and add green smoke to production. Hey, if you want to meet with anyone, meet with this guy.
And so suddenly doors started opening. I was invited to Russia and I thought, gosh, um,
I can't not go to Russia and meet with like Pavel Popovich, cosmonaut. I went to Star City.
I got to meet with generals. This is the nineties and you know, uh, okay, well, I guess I'm going
to do another film on UFOs. How could I not? Like, I mean, these doors are opening. And so
I worked another and, and raising the money was always incredibly challenging. Oh my God. I learned
how to operate cameras and how to edit and how to do the sound, all those things completely on my
own. Cause I couldn't possibly afford to pay somebody else to do any of it. And so even though
I sold my film to Discovery, I didn't make, I would have made more flipping burgers at the end
of the day. You know what I mean? So anyway, so then I, I made another film called out of the blue
and it was, it was really funny. When do you know a film is done? You know, and, and it's, it's a
tough moment to when do you actually realize, Hey, this film is done. Cause I never really feel
satisfied with any work I ever do. It always feels like I can make it better. So I'm looking
at out of the blue. We're about five years into production and my buddy, this guy,
Boris Zuboff was kind of my mentor. He was in a fetal position crying and his wife and his wife
is not really that funny, but his wife's like, you're killing my husband. Stop it with this movie.
Stop it. You're killing him. You know, and he's like, Oh, cause I'm pushing so hard everybody.
Right. And there was not enough money. And so I was like, all right, well, I guess I'll put out,
you know, out of the blue. And then I sold out of the blue to NBC universal and aired on sci-fi. It
was again, just a total coup, you know, like I just completely locked out right place, right time.
I don't know. This guy, Larry Lansman at sci-fi, I saw it and he was like, you know, came in at me.
I didn't even have a lawyer. I didn't have an agent. And I have these like people at acquisitions
at NBC universal asked me, so kid, like, what do you want for your movie? I'm like, I have no idea.
Like what I, I didn't know how to negotiate with any people. I know what I was doing, you know?
And so I sold it, I sold it, but I sold it reluctantly because I felt like it wasn't the film that I,
that I envisioned when I set out, when you embark on a certain project, you have a vision of how
you want something to be, you know, whether you're building a house or designing a bar or doing a
podcast, whatever it is, excuse me. And, um, it didn't, it never materialized. You know what I mean?
Like I, I just, I was, I was unsatisfied when it came out. So I sold the film. I did. Okay.
Probably again, flipping burgers at the end of the day, you tally it up all the hours and, uh, and
about about three years after the film came out, I got a letter from NBC, NBC universal. And they
said, they're not going to renew the broadcast option. So guess what? I owned the movie again.
So I was like, well, I'll, I'm going to make a checklist of all the things that I was unhappy
about. I'm going to redo this film. And I remember at the time my partner was like, you know,
what are you doing? What are you talking about? Redo the movie. We did that movie. We sold it.
It's done. I was like, yeah, but there's never the movie I wanted it to be. So they were like,
you're out of your mind. Okay. Go sell crazy somewhere else. We're done. And so I ended up
having to bring in new investors and new partners and to redesign out of the blue and raise more
money. So I made a checklist of things that I wanted to accomplish for, um, the film out of the
blue to revise it, make a director's cut. And that was about 10 people long. And the ninth one,
one was like, I wanted to get more direct eyewitness accounts of the Rendlesham forest
case back in December of 1980 that happened in England at a joint U S British air base
that housed nuclear weapons that had a UFO land. It's a fascinating case. You can look it up bent
waters, Rendlesham forest. And then, um, there was a very, very compelling close encounter,
like a mass sighting that happened in 1997 in March in Arizona. And it's commonly referred
to as the Phoenix lights. If you talk to witnesses, they say, don't call it the Phoenix lights,
call it the massive, you know, UFO flyover because the object was not lights. It was a massive
boomerang shaped object that was one to two miles across. And that's something that you wanted to
include in that film. Well, I investigated the case and I did include it in the film, but in,
in, uh, I think it was like June, the sighting happened in March 13th, 1997. And then in,
I think it was June, there was mounting pressure from the people, from witnesses. It got like a
national story and the governor of Arizona, the then governor of Arizona, five Simonton was like,
you know, we're going to get to the bottom of it. We're going to find out what it was.
I'm contacting the local Luke air force base and the, you know, Pentagon above them all.
Isn't that the guy, is that the guy who like walked out of the press conference dressed like
an alien or something? So a couple of hours later, he has one of his aides and I was investigating
this case when this was all going down, you know, I was into production on it's either 50 years or
out of the blue, probably out of the blue. But in any case, I was in, in deep investigating this
case and that little, so, so five Simonton, the governor, then governor was like, we're going to
get to the bottom of it. And he was serious. Like he really was. You could look at the press
conference it's in out of the blue or, and, and, um, a couple hours later, he has this unscheduled
press conference and he has one of his aides dressed up in an alien suit and makes a joke out
of the whole thing. And I'll tell you, man, the witnesses that all the witnesses that I were
talking to, they were pissed. They were like, I put you in office, you know, we're your constituents.
How dare you like make fun of us like that? What's wrong? You know, and it was, it was, this object
was witnessed by a lot of people because everybody was out under the night sky, trying to get a
glimpse of the hell bob comment at the time. So, and this object flew from the north all the way
across to the south of the entire state of Arizona. It's a fascinating case. Anyway,
my goal was to get Fife Symington on camera and find out, you know, why the hell he did what he
did. Right. So this all takes many years to do all this stuff. And so to my complete astonishment
or shock, um, I got nine out of the 10 objectives done for that film, including an interview with
governor Fife Symington. He was no longer governor at the time, but I got an interview with the
governor Fife. Nobody ever got an interview with Fife. Right. So I'm driving down. I'll never
forget it. I had my, one of my partners and he goes, he's, he's like, uh, well, what's Fife going
to say? I said, who cares what he's going to say? You know, we got the former governor of Arizona
willing to meet with us, like, you know, so on the way down to meet, to meet with him and send
in Santa Barbara, he was like, well, I, I have a house in Arizona, but I also live in, in Santa
Barbara. If you want to come down and, and, and, uh, meet me in Santa Barbara, say that, that'll be
a little easier for me. So I'm sure I'll, I'll meet with you. So on the way down to meet with the
former governor of Arizona, Fife Symington, I, uh, pulled the car over the side of the road,
got out my pocket tape recorder, and I contacted one of the witnesses, this woman, Stacy Rhodes,
who literally was driving on interstate 10 with her daughter, Emily, and they got out of their car
and they said there were all the cars stopped on both sides and it was like maybe seven o'clock
in the evening, 6 37, something like this. And she said that every car on interstate 10 between
Phoenix and Tucson were stopped and they got out of the car and this massive boomerang shaped thing
like this, like a big Chevron floating like a city, super slowly. We were just sat there
just looking at it as it floated right over huge, like a mile. She goes, if I, excuse me, if she
goes, if I held up and opened up newspaper like this directly over my head, I could not have blocked
out this craft. That's how big it was. Okay. And a lot of people saw it. I mean, I interviewed
people all across the state of Arizona that saw this thing. So in any case I pull over, I was like,
you're not going to believe, and she was furious at the stunt that the governor had pulled.
So I was like, you're not going to believe who I'm going to go meet with right now. And she's like,
who? Take a guess. She couldn't. I said, governor 5 Simonton, is there anything you'd like to say to
him? She's like, you're damn right I would. Like I said, well, hold on, let me get my tape recorder
out. And so I pressed record and I recorded her statement and it was directed directly at the
governor. And who better to ask a question than a former constituent of his and witness to the event.
So I get into the interview and I thought, well, I'm not going to like spring this on him
right away because I'm worried this guy's going to just, you know, get up and walk out. So let me
get what I can get out of him. And then when the time is right, I'll put the squeeze on him and
I'll do a little bit of an ambush with this, you know. So the interview was going great. He was
like, you know, I was, he talked about the reason why he pulled the stunt, that he was just trying
to find some like, trying to calm the people down. A little bit of levity is the word he used.
Didn't mean to like make fun of anybody, you know, this kind of thing. So then I said, hey,
governor, I've got a little something I'd like to share with you. It's one of your former
constituents and a witness to the event. And she'd like to ask you a question if you don't mind.
He's kind of squirmed in his seat a little bit. And, you know, he's like, it's been a while since
I've been kind of, you know, ambushed or whatever. So I press play and she kind of lays into him
pretty heavily. Like, how dare you like, you know, make fun of all the witnesses. There were
thousands of us, you know, it was a serious event. And we voted you in office and you just like,
you know, left us out to dry. And the one representative, Frances Barwood of Sydney
Councilwoman, you made fun of her when she was to try to make serious inquiries into the whole
thing. And he sat there for a moment. I thought, well, I probably blew it. He's probably going to
get up and leave. To my amazement, he admits right there that for the first time ever that he too,
as a former Air Force pilot, that he too saw this thing. And he knew immediately it was not of this
Earth. And he said that because of the sheer size of it, because it was so big, this big V-shaped
thing. He said, there's just nothing terrestrial that could be that big and fly that quietly. And
you know, all this stuff. And so I knew the story was going to be big, but I didn't realize how big.
And that story came out as I wasn't even done yet with the revision of Out of the Blue. And we were
just catapulted all over the headlines. I was on Larry King seven, eight, nine times. I was on
every talk show, nightline, dateline, you name it. Right. Which is great. I mean, you get, you know,
you get in the spotlight a little bit and you can make some moves. You got a little influence,
you know, people are watching you suddenly. And so I'm probably definitely boring you guys to death.
No, no, not at all. So anyway, because I'm just on this ride, right? I don't really know where I'm
going. You know, I don't know where this is leading. I'm, you know, I'm just a curious Joe. I'm just a
guy that really wanted to know what the hell was going on. Yeah. You know? And so I was just asking
a lot of questions. And every now and again, I got some traction. Now I'm in the limelight
and I'm on Larry King with the former governor of Arizona. We were on together, you know what I mean?
And I'm on all of these shows. I mean, I had like, my phone memory was full. I mean, they were
calling, everybody was calling me, Jay Leno, like you name it. So anyway, I figured, well, hey, let
me capitalize on this. Well, then I decided, God, you know, I might not ever have the spotlight
like this again. I should do something big. I should capitalize on this moment. So I woke up
in the middle of the night and I saw this press conference in, I know it sounds crazy, but I saw
this press conference and I don't think I had like two dimes to rub together at the time. I think it
maybe had like 500 bucks in my bank account max. And I had a little room on my credit card. I was
living with my sister at the time. And I woke up in the middle of the night and I had this dream.
I had this kind of like, I just saw this event at the National Press Club where I got military and
government officials from all these different countries to come and testify and do this thing
right at the National Press Club in Washington, D.C. Well, I had the attention of a lot of the
media at that point. I had their numbers in my pockets and I think I called my contact at
Larry King and I said, hey, I'm thinking about doing this event. I didn't get many details and
I had no money. I was like, I'm thinking about doing this event at the National Press Club.
And if I did it, would you guys cover it? And they said, yeah, we'll give you a full hour.
I said, fantastic. So then I contacted this woman, Leslie Kane, who helped break the story
of the New York Times article in 2017. It catapulted this whole phenomenon on the front
page of the New York Times. And that was like the secret Pentagon program. So I contacted Leslie.
This is way years ago. I said, Leslie, I'm thinking about doing this thing. And she'd
seen me in the news all over the place. She knew that I had a little traction and
and she was like, well, hold on. Well, we got to think about this. We got to hold on.
We got to strategize. I don't know. I need to think about it. I might need to think for a
month or two. I said, look, I'm doing this and I'm doing it starting now. Are you in or you out?
And she's like, oh, fuck it, I'm in.
And so so now all I needed was the money to put the fan on. So then I was like, OK,
so now I got the media coverage and now I got this. Now I need some money.
So I contacted the National Press Club and I booked the ballroom, which is the biggest,
most fancy room they had. And I had to put five hundred dollars down to hold it. But it was like,
I don't know, thousands of dollars to book it. So I called the National Press Club that morning
and I said, well, we take a five hundred dollar deposit. Well, I had five hundred dollars on my
credit card. So I booked it and I heard my sister in the other room. She goes, did you just book
the National Press Club? I was like, yeah. She goes, how are you going to afford to ever do that?
I was like, I don't know. I'll figure it out. You know, and
and because I was getting a lot of media coverage, that really helped. I was able to buy out my two
other partners and bring in new investment. And for the money that I bought them out and that I
sold the their share of the of the production, the new production, I was able to fund the National
Press Club. In fact, I was a little short. Somebody ended up sending me some. And my point is,
is that, you know, you have an idea, you might not have the resources, but an idea could lead
to something big because a lot of people are too scared to go for it because failure is kind of a
scary thing. Right. Especially if you're like at the poker table and you push it all in your chips
in on one bet. You know, but, you know, I remember at one point having a bit of a meltdown. And by
the way, my father had slowly started to come around during this. And I took him to a when I
got back from Russia, I went and met with Mercury astronaut Gordon Cooper, who was an iconic figure
of my dad's generation. He was the last American astronaut to go up in space alone. And, you know,
everybody knew of my dad's generation knew Mercury astronaut Gordon Cooper, he was in the right stuff.
And I brought my father along to that interview. And Gordon Cooper had talked about a landed flying
saucer that was filmed at Edwards Air Force Base circuit 1965, and how he chased these discs and
fighter jets over Germany in the, I think it was late, late, late 50s, like 57, something like that.
But in any case, my dad was like, God, here's a man whose credibility is on the line. He's
got nothing. He's not getting paid. He's got everything to lose, nothing to gain. Why on
earth would he make this stories up? That was a bit of a turning point for him. And he also saw,
you know, some of the success and I was, you know, things were really taken off. And my dad
definitely started to recon more than reconsider. He became a very big supporter of mine and was
very, very excited about what was happening. It was all just kind of unfolding, you know,
as it was happening, but getting back to the National Press Club event. So we did that.
And I didn't have, I'll share another story since we have the time, I guess it's kind of kind of
funny. We didn't have an alternative, a plan B to promote the National Press Club event. Okay.
It was a big deal. We were flying in 15 people from seven countries from all around the world,
military government, FAA officials, people from Tehran. I've got a photograph of a fighter pilot
in Tehran that had one of the most dramatic encounters with the UFO in 1976 over Tehran,
Iran, where he literally tried to fire at the thing. It blocked up and seized his plane. He
started falling out of the sky. I got to, I'll show you a picture of that a little bit. Incredible
encounter. And nobody had ever gotten Parviz Jafari to come to the United States ever. And it was
right after the Bush administration had called Tehran, I ran the Axis of Evil. So I was like,
dude. I was like, don't say that. I'm trying to get visas to get this guy over to the state.
Anyway, the time was very sketchy. So we do the National Press Club event. And I was like,
I'm going to make a movie out of this National Press Club event. I'm going to film it all in
HD. And everyone's like, how are you going to make a movie about a bunch of old retired guys
standing at a podium testifying under the UFO phenomenon? I said, well, who's the guy Al Gore
made a PowerPoint presentation on a film and that, you know, if he can do it, heck, I can do it.
Right. So I ended up making a whole movie and I was still in production. I still hadn't finished
production with Out of the Blue, the revised version of Out of the Blue. But suddenly this whole
new thing came along. And so I made a film on the National Press Club event that I did with Leslie
Kane. And it's called I Know What I Saw. And I continued production with that. But the crazy
part was, as I was saying earlier, sorry, I keep going off these tangents, is I never really had
the money. I never ever had any money up front to do anything I've ever done. I always kind of found
the money because I really believe and I've lived it. People will see and be inspired by
you're going for it. Right. And it's a scary thing to go for it. It really is because, you know,
you're soldering this project. You don't know the ultimate outcome. You don't know
witnesses you're going to get to come forward or not come forward. You don't know where your next
like checks going to come from. Right. You know, but people will be inspired, particularly when I
had some traction in the media. That really helped. And they'll be inclined to want to help you
and support you. And so there was this upswell of support coming from this. I had one guy,
I never even met him. Bless his heart. I just went to thank him the other day. I found out he
passed. His name is Joe Bellotti. Never met the guy. He goes, I love what you're doing. He sent
me a check for 20 grand. That was like a million dollars to me. I mean, I did so much with that
money. Yeah. And I contacted him recently. I was like, yeah, I'd lost contact with him. And I
reached out and I, his daughter goes like, yeah, Joe Bellotti, unfortunately, you know, he passed
a couple of years. I was like, oh my God, I never really got to anyway. My point is, so that phrase.
Yeah. So then I did. And I could go on till I'm blue in the face. How many times, you know,
people come out of the woodwork to help out and support what you're doing. Some anonymously, some
not. But then I did, I know what I saw and I sold, I know what I saw to A&E. It was all rather
precarious. And you know, you've got a gritty, do-it-yourself production. Things have changed
in the last decade and a half, a lot. But I remember finishing the movie and it was a pretty
good movie. I narrated it. The first time I went out, broke out from Peter Coyote and it was a good
film. And Tom DeLong was helping a little bit with the sound. I recorded some sound in his studio in
San Diego. And you know, at the end of a production, you're pretty broke. And then you got deliverables
and deliverables at that time were a nightmare. You had to like, you had to produce standard
deaf, high deaf version, short version, long version, audio stems, this side, that side,
independent, textless version, texted version. Oh my God. And I had to do it on Digi Beta tapes.
Digi Beta tapes. I was like, what the hell am I doing these on Digi Beta tapes? You guys are
going to digitize this stuff anyway. It's already digitized. Like, what are you doing? And it was
like the last year or two that they did that stupid process. It was a nightmare and it cost so much
money every time. And I kept failing the delivery process. Black levels have to be a certain this
and they're very, the A&E had very high standards of like deliverables. And it was like, you know,
super expensive process to do these Digi Beta tapes and everything. So I failed the first two
attempts. And then my financial backer said, we're not putting another penny into this movie. I was
like, we have a sale right now for half a million dollars on the line. Right now? You mean to tell
me you're not going to put another dime into this thing? My really good friend had just died, left
me with this fancy BMW. So I pawned that car to pay for the last round. And I literally contacted
the guys at acquisitions department at A&E. And I was at the end of my rope. I had nothing to lose.
And I was pretty much arguing with them, right? I was like, look, man, this is not a high def,
you know, production on the beauty of the Grand Canyon. What the hell is wrong with you guys?
Like, it's never going to be. It's a gritty do it yourself documentary, but look at the content.
And it was shot over like a long period of time. And I got archival footage and there's
different frame rates and who cares? Like, and then I was like, oh, God, maybe I went a little
far with this guy. I was like, oh God, I was like kind of silent on the phone. I was like a half
million dollars and I was so broke. And he goes, yeah, yeah, yeah, you got a point. You got a point.
Okay. I'll tell you what, I'll let these three things go, which I could have never fixed.
I need you to do this, this, and this. And if you do that, we got a deal. So I went back to the
drawing board and I went into the production facility that was making the tapes and I sat
there with them. And they were like, you know, our clients don't usually sit and look over our
shoulders and look at the black levels and know this and then that. And I said, look, buddy,
I can't afford to do this one more time. This is it. So I need to get this right. And so there
made an exception. And I looked over, you know, send the tapes off. I mean, it was like 15 grand
or something. Send the tapes off back east. And I barely made the FedEx. I was so precarious. Oh
my God. People had no idea. So precarious. What was the biggest difference between?
So the last one I'll finish. Yeah. So the next morning or two mornings later,
I get a phone call. I was driving my car. I looked down, it's 212. I was like, oh God,
that's Amy. I pulled my car over. Mr. Fox, how are you doing? This is so and so. We're at
acquisitions. I was like, well, I don't really know how I'm doing. Why don't you tell me?
He goes, you passed. And so, you know, so I know what I saw, you know, I sold that and then that
went out. And it just kind of, but I was never satisfied with a production of mine since the
early concept in the 90s when I was like, I'm going to do the feature length documentary
on the topic of UFOs. It's going to like transcend into the mainstream. And I wasn't satisfied until
I did the phenomenon. That when I finished that, I cried and I was like, I did it. It took me like,
you know, years and years, but I did it. Excuse me. So you released the phenomenon in 2020, right?
At the end of 2020. Yes. What's the biggest difference in your experience from creating
these films in the 90s compared to now, right now? Because obviously there's a ton of resistance,
right? There's a ton of friction with the whole topic, especially when it comes to
different secret levels of government, people not being one of wanting to be associated with
the stigmas. Yeah. Yeah. How is the whole world around this topic changed? So I used to get laughed
at all the time to the point where if I go to a cocktail party, I tell people I was with, don't
tell them what I do. I don't want to spend the night defending myself. I'm not interested. And
I'm not here to like prophesize and get people to join my cult of believers. I really don't care.
And so that is what I was used to. You know, I was used to being laughed at and ridiculed and made
fun of. So there was like, you know, a few people that might quietly kind of behind the scenes like,
Oh, is there really something to that? You know what I mean? Or I have a friend that claimed they
saw something that all changed December 2017 when the new and I had no idea. I was like three or
four years into production with, with the phenomenon. Of course, I didn't have a title
for it at that point, but I was three or four years into production and I was kind of struggling
for financing. You know, a lot of times on with making a doc, I'll get, you know, funding and
it takes me so long. It'll dry. That funding will dry up. Then I got to go find more funding.
Well, right around the time when the New York Times revealed the secret Pentagon UFO program,
that changed everything because it wasn't just the fact that they revealed
this secret Pentagon UFO program, but they also revealed or released evidence.
That was the cockpit recordings of those UFOs, you know, and then you had slowly the pilots
coming out. Right. And that really, and then you have the former Senate majority leader,
Harry Reid, talking about how he initiated this with a couple of other senators. And like,
they gave the contract a big low. And anyway, this whole thing had come out and I had people
from all around the world apologizing to me. I'm not kidding you, man. Like, we're so sorry. We
made fun of you for so long. Wow. I guess there really is something to this. It really changed.
It really changed everything that front page of the New York Times. So I got to wipe my nose.
Yeah. So the difference in terms of perception,
I think the phenomenon, the film, and I'm not trying to pat myself on the back, but I guess
I can pat myself on the back. I was terrified. So there are three categories of UFO sightings
according to Dr. J. Allen Hynek, who investigated UFOs in an official capacity. He was a scientific
advisor to Project Blue Book. Project Blue Book ran from 47 to 69, someplace to 70, but they
announced its closing in 69. They investigated 12,000. This is the United States Air Force.
They investigated 12,618 cases, out of which 701 remained unidentified. And remind me about
that number. I'll explain the relevancy with that number to the report that came out yesterday
on the Hill. Okay. So that's a very stubborn small percent. So Dr. Hynek
broke them down into three categories, close encounters of the first kind. It's when someone
claims to see a UFO, close encounter of the second kind. They see a UFO and somehow this UFO
interacts with the environment, whether it leaves a burnt mark on the ground or the radiation affects
someone's face within certain proximity, burns, soil samples, leaves, trees, bushes, whatever.
That's close encounter of the second kind. Okay. Close encounter of the third kind is when the
witness reports allegedly beings, entities associated with the UFO. That's close
encounter of the third kind. So the phenomenon for the first time in all the films that I'd ever made
dealt with close encounters of the third kind.
Alleged beings. And it's very different between objects in the sky and beings on the ground.
Yeah. It was a big, big difference, right? Because you talk about Russia or China, all you want.
But when you talk about beings on the ground, that's just a game changer. I'm going to get to
the relevance of what the close encounters of the first, second, and third kind. So all the history
I'd done, I did 50 years of denial, which I sold to Discovery. I did out of the blue version one,
out of the blue version two, I did I know what I saw. I'd never ever dealt with close encounters
of the third kind where the witness report, they report seeing beings associated with the craft.
Okay. I felt like a slippery slope and boy, that's kind of a difficult one to kind of swallow.
Yeah. With the phenomenon, I went for it. And honestly, I was terrified because I had
high level government and intelligence officers in the film. Several of which, including the
former Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid, refused to sign a release form until they got to see the
movie. Wow. I don't blame them. Right. So I got a movie that starts in Alabama in the 50s and it
ends in Africa of an alleged landing of a UFO, multiple UFOs, and the occupants getting out
in broad daylight with 100 witnesses and interacting telepathically with these witnesses.
That's just nuts, right? I mean, come on. Like, I thought the Harry Reeds and the Podestas and all
the other intelligence people that are in my movie, the New York Times, like, take us out of
the movie. I was terrified. Nobody had ever done with a mainstream reporting with all that
and dealt with alleged close encounters of the third kind. That's just such a game changer
because you can no longer, like, talk about whether it's Russia or whether it's a drone or
whether we're talking beans. Right. And these beans look very different than a human. Right.
In fact, if you want, I've got some illustrations I could tell you. Yeah, no, we'll definitely get
into that. But anyway, my point is, is that that was the first film, the phenomenon, where I
broke through to a much broader mainstream audience. And not only that, but we dealt with,
we reported on very compelling close encounters of the third kind.
Yeah, the stigma, when you talk about the stigma associated with just UFO sightings or encounters
of the first and the second kind. Right. It's definitely been largely erased by the New York
Times article. For sure. There's obviously still a lot of it when it comes to actual creatures
or beings being reported. To you, actually, before we get into that, let's talk about the
Hill. Yeah, the latest news that just came out yesterday regarding the Hill. And I also want
to ask about what you know about the new bill that was passed to protect whistleblowers. It's to
maybe you can find it. We'll talk about that after, but it's a new bill that was passed to
protect whistleblowers of private organizations that are working on some of these secret programs,
for example, in Lockheed Martin or Raytheon, whatever it might be.
They've been talking about basically giving people immunity that can come forward and share
government secrets without fear of prosecution. Because the violation of National Security Act,
I think it is. But backing up for a moment. So I read the article that came out, I think it was
yesterday, in the Hill, Vice. And I thought I interpreted it fairly well. But then I reached
out to Lou Elizondo, who ran the ATIP program at the Pentagon, just to be sure, because we go back,
we text things back and forth and I share stuff with him and vice versa. So he was, for people
who don't know who he is, he was the head of the ATIP program. So it was Advanced Aerospace Threat
Identification Program. It was the program at the Pentagon, the secret UFO program that ended
up on the front page of the New York Times. And you see all the little UFOs that came out with it.
So let me read you the text that he sent me. Yeah. Because, and I'll explain this.
Okay. For the first time in recent history, our Congress is focusing on UFOs in a non-prosaic
manner. Meaning, if it turns out that a particular incident, a product of man-made process or
technology, then the UAP JPO, I have to look up what the JPO is, will not continue to study it.
Only those phenomena that fall outside the category and are truly anomalous will be focused.
So basically what he's saying is, you've got a select committee, right? And they're saying,
I talked earlier about the 701 cases that ended up in the unidentified category that were
investigated from the Air Force out of 12,618. So that's that very stubborn, small percentage of
cases. So what the select committee is saying, we're only going to look at stuff that's non-human.
All the other stuff we have no interest in investigating. So by them saying that,
they're admitting that a small percentage of UFO, we're not trying to find out if all UFOs are of
extraterrestrial origin, right? It's are any, are any of them, because it only takes one or two,
right? So they're saying, we're only interested in that core 10 or 15% of truly unidentifiable
cases like the non-human cases. So it's basically them saying without directly saying that a small
percentage of UFOs are not of earthly origin or not of human, you know, or not manmade.
And they changed it to where they, they talk, they're now talking about being transmedium
to where they're like, they're, they're aerospace and submersible.
Yeah, they can go, they can operate in outer space. They can operate in the atmosphere
and they can operate underwater and they can do all three simultaneously.
Yeah. And this is new. This is something that the commander David Fravor was talking about.
The thing was hovering about, there's videos of the crafts that are hovering above the water
and then disappearing into the ocean. And that's something that hasn't really, that I don't think
the New York Times article talked much about the underwater aspect of it, but the underwater
aspect of it to me is fascinating. Unbelievable. I mean, look, I went and I got to interview
Fravor. I got to meet a lot of people, you know, for the phenomenon and
the videos that have been released are pretty impressive, but the videos that I'm told
that people have seen that I've spoken to that have not been released are just like, you know,
more in focus. They exhibit, they'll exhibit like a flight characteristic. Like for instance,
there's one out right now called the GoFast. According to people that I've talked to,
you see the GoFast and the guy likes trying to, he's trying to get his, his radar on it.
He goes, I got him, I got him. And he finally gets it as it's screaming across the top.
The GoFast, you can look up GoFast, but apparently that video is much longer and then it does a 90
degree angle turn and then shoots off the screen. So there's, there's that, the, the, the famous
tic-tac that David Fravor had talked about where it's like stationary and the jet's flying towards
it. And then it shoots off to one side. That was in 2004, the Nimitz UFO encounter that apparently,
according to David Fravor and others, there's a much higher resolution version of that one.
Somehow that has not been released. There's stuff that underwater, I mean, I've, I just heard some
incredible stories. In fact, I've been hearing incredible stories for decades about video and
photographic evidence that has yet to see the light of day. And, and when I got to meet with
the guy who spearheaded the ATIP program, he was former Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid,
which I had to pinch myself that I was in the same room with the guy. He confirmed on camera,
which was a very, very big gotcha moment in, in, in the phenomenon where he says,
I said, wait a minute, are you suggesting that the, there's a lot of evidence, there's evidence
that hasn't been released to the public. And he says, I, I'm telling you that most of the evidence
has yet to see the light of day. So some intelligence or agency,
I don't know who's in charge, is sitting on the most compelling, I know this because I've talked
to the witnesses that have either handed the evidence over or that they've seen the evidence.
They've seen the video and photographic evidence. So one of my objectives moving forward is,
is locating that footage and locating who has the authority to release it. Because that would be,
it's one thing to talk about the reality of the phenomenon. It's another to start, you know,
they've got all the sensors for them to start, you know, releasing it into the general public.
Right. Another thing is, Al Putoff, who was the head of, I think, what was he? He was the senior
advisor of ATIP, which was at Bigelow airspace. And the guy, Al Putoff, older guy, he talks about
the same thing, except that the, what happens is a lot of this technology, a lot of this information
that's being held is in the hands of private agencies. That way it's protected by FOIA,
by the freedom and information act. So people can't go to the government and request these
records because they're held by these, these private entities, like whatever that might be,
like he Martin or. So that's, that's a very, very good point. And I sort of organically came to that
conclusion because, well, I'll give you an example. This book right here. Okay. This is a briefing
document that was sponsored. If you could see it. It's a briefing document that was,
that was paid for and sponsored by Lawrence Spellman Rockefeller. It was done during the
Clinton administration. And he was, this is a briefing document for world leaders to bring
them up to speed on the most compelling aspects that, you know, that five or 10% of truly
inexplicable UFO cases. This, this book features a lot of the really best ones. And in it,
he, during, during making the, during putting this whole thing together, he was putting
significant pressure on the Clinton administration. In fact, he even said to Clinton, you either
going to go after the UFO phenomenon or I'm going to expose the fact that you're not willing to do
this. I know this, I have inside information. This is definitely happened or I'll, I'll, I'll
publish on the front page of everything. And UFOs were kind of getting a little bit of traction
because you had the 50th anniversary coming up for the Roswell. You know, there had been some
reports coming out. There was the Bob Lazar thing. You know, people were talking UFOs in the early
nineties, early mid nineties. So ultimately what concluded was he said, okay, president Clinton
said, okay, give me a case. What case should we go after? And Rockefeller said Roswell. So
they went after Roswell, the, the, the administration. They've got, I cover some
of this in the phenomenon, but they went after Roswell. And at the end of the day,
they concluded that the hard evidence had gone out to these subcontractors. So these, these,
these outside companies that were free from oversight. So when the government says we don't
have it, they really, they don't, they really don't have it. You know, it could be like,
let's just say Boeing or Lockheed Martin or one of these companies. They are outside of oversight
from members of Congress and presidential reach. So, cause people go, well, the president has
access to everything. Well, naturally he doesn't because if it's outside, I guess, or if you don't
know about it, he said, president Clinton said he was not happy with the answers he was getting.
So, and you know, you hear the same thing. I mean, president Jimmy Carter had said that
Gerald Ford had gone, you know, I talked to Gerald Ford. I interviewed Jimmy Carter very briefly at
a book signing where he was basically like, we went after it, but we weren't like, we weren't
getting the answers. Who else was, well, I'm sure Bush knew probably quite a bit because he was
head of the CIA. I don't know about Bush Jr. But yeah, I definitely, I have definitely concluded
from all the people that I've talked to is that presidents do not have access. And I don't know
who does, to be honest with you. I'm not sure what agency does. I wish I did know, you know,
I'd like to know. Yeah, it almost seems, it almost seems like it's obvious that some of these private
aerospace companies are holding evidence or material, physical material that's, that's not
available to academia or the public, obviously. Which I think it makes it, which shows, you know,
one of the reasons for stuff like this, the Congress having the bill to the whistleblower act
to protect the people who work in those companies to shine light on it or make it public. But at the
same time, it seems like those people, it would be hard for them to do it because they would just be
sacrificing their career. Also think of it this way. How do they benefit by sharing what they have
with the general public? How do they benefit? Right? Like, you have to reveal your vulnerabilities
and the things that you don't know in order to reveal what you do know. Because as soon as you
start talking about these, I mean, just think about it. If the president of the United States
tomorrow said, you know, my fellow Americans, it's been brought to my attention that we have
structured craft of unknown origin, whizzing around with impunity in our airspace.
We don't know, they fly rings around our fastest jets. They exhibit a technology that's light years
advanced from what we have. We don't know who they are, where they come from, or what they want.
Thank you and good night. I mean, that's honestly what I believe. I believe that they know
that the phenomenon is real. I believe they have hardware and bodies. But does that mean they have
but does that mean they have all the answers? Does that mean that they understand whatever
the agenda could be of whoever these people are? Do we know where they come from? Are they
interdimensional? Do they live under the ocean? Are they interplanetary? Are they time travelers?
Are they all the above? I have no idea. Do they know? I mean, they got more answers than we do,
but they might not have a whole lot more. They might be opening up a can of worms.
There are people right now fearful of what the level of transparency is. And don't get me wrong,
what's been happening since 2017 is unprecedented. It really is. But remember,
somebody forced the government's hand. The former intelligence guy Christopher Mellon,
who's friends with Lou Elizondo, who ran the ATIP program, they walked those tapes out of the
Pentagon. Granted, they found a loophole that they didn't necessarily like violate the law.
They took advantage of that loophole. But they kind of like bend the rules a little bit, right?
Those tapes came out of the Pentagon, and they went on to the front page of the New York Times.
That was kind of forcing the government's hand. They can't put the genie back in the bottle.
So there are people that want this out, and there are other people that do not want this out.
And they don't want it out for fear of like, A, they've been lying to us all these years. But B,
it exposes their vulnerabilities. It exposes our vulnerabilities. Just imagine for a moment,
like I said earlier, if there really were these unknown objects that could just fly rings around
our fastest jets, they turn off our nuclear weapons, turn them on, turn them off, mostly turn
them off, right? They whiz off at an unbelievable rate of speed. And we don't know who they are,
where they come from, why they're here. Like, that's a little unnerving to release to the
general public, wouldn't you think? I'm not saying that your audience to believe what I'm telling you
or not. Just imagine if that's the case. You can kind of see a justification for secrecy,
right? Not that you agree with it. I don't agree with it. I don't care how scary it is. I want to
know the truth. Right. Let us all know the truth. We're all entitled to it. Let's let's know this.
Do you think it's possible that one of these private aerospace companies has some sort of
have has figured out in any capacity, anti gravity, or anything like that, some of these projects
that Bob Lazar was talking about? Do you think it's possible that they have some of this technology
and aren't letting other scientists and academia know about it? I think that they have the
technology and I didn't just believe that overnight. I mean, it didn't just like it was a very slow
process for me because I am, believe it or not, I'm actually quite skeptical. A lot of the cases
that I cover, like my new film Moment of Contact, we'll talk about that a little later, you know,
which is the UFO crash case that happened in 1996 in Brazil. I didn't believe that for over 10 years
when I heard about it. I didn't believe in the Rua case, the landing in Africa. Absolutely didn't
believe it. Wouldn't even look into it. I was like, there's no way that that happened. So
the fact that I believe that crashes have happened and bodies and debris have been recovered,
it was a very slow process for me. It was witnesses after witness, after witness,
after document, after intelligence person I've talked to. Like I finally was like,
there's more evidence to suggest that it happened than it didn't happen.
And that clearly went somewhere, right? I've even asked, you know, I jokingly ask, I always
kind of do it with a smile on my face, but I'll say, all right, hey, you know, to some intelligence
guy that I'm talking with. All right, so here we go. All right, here we go. I want to know where
the bodies are. We'll get that. Let's talk about that first and then we can get over the debris.
Where are they hiding the bodies? And I think they kind of know that they are being hidden somewhere,
but it sounds like crazy talk. I know. We were talking about it last night. The bodies from
Roswell are apparently in the Air Force base in Florida. Yes, and I've also heard California too.
Maybe they go back and forth. I don't know, but that was in the seventies.
Right. Yes, yes. The seventies is the story when Jackie Gleason and Nixon went to go see the Air
Force base. Yes. How did that story go? Well, so, because I've heard it before, but nobody seems
to know the whole story. Okay, so a really good friend of mine, a guy who's very high up in the
entertainment industry, who's been very instrumental in getting my foot in the door with some executives
over the years to help me out. His name is Jeff Zaganski. And one day, quite a while ago, actually,
I was doing, I know what I saw. I said, Jeff, you're so nice to me. Like, why are you helping
me? You're this top executive. You're a gazillionaire. Why are you helping me? I'm just
this little guy, like this little independent guy. And he goes, you know, James, I was friends with
Jackie Gleason. And Jackie Gleason told me one time, Jeff, don't ever believe anyone that tells
you that UFOs are not real. I had 100% definitive proof, excuse me, whether he saw it or shown it,
but he was somewhat nebulous as to exactly what happened. But he said, don't ever believe anything
this event's happened. UFOs are real. They're here. It's a fact. So he said he'd always remembered that
encounter with Gleason when he told me that. And when he saw this independent guy, myself,
just striving to get the word out and find out what's going on, he always like offered a helping
hand. He was always really helpful. Then I think it was like, maybe about two years after Jackie
Gleason died, his wife came forward and said that one night he came home in the early 70s
from a meeting with Nixon at a Florida military base. You know the one. Homestead. Right, the tip
of Florida. And that his eyes were wide and his face was white. And he said, I was just shown
entities from a crash in New Mexico. And they were floating in some fluid or something at
the Air Force base. That's what his wife came out. Now, you know, that's probably what Gleason was
referring to, I would imagine, when he met with Jeff Zaganski and told him that. I would imagine,
right, if he had that level of confirmation, that's what he said to Jeff. He didn't say to Jeff,
you know, Nixon showed me the bodies. He just said, I had definitive proof. Like there's no,
don't ever believe anyone tell you otherwise. They're absolutely here. It's a fact. That's
what he said to Jeff Zaganski. And so when his wife came out with that, that's probably what
happened. Do you get the feeling that a lot of when you talk to a lot of these people that you
interview that obviously there's people who worked in the government and worked on some of these top
secret programs. Do you get the feeling that they're holding things back? A lot of things
back sometimes where they're talking to you, because obviously there's times where you're
talking to people like witnesses who aren't tied to anything and they're just talking to you freely.
There's having a conversation with you, but then there's people you talk to
who are influenced by organizations and it's a different kind of conversation.
Yeah. I'll give you an example. This is kind of funny. I'm not going to, I'm not going to,
is an intelligence person. We're putting together this, he was helping me put together
some language for something I was doing. And he said, no, no, no, change that, change that wording.
And I said, okay, why? It was like, I don't know if I said like extraterrestrial or if I said alien
or otherworldly, I can't remember exactly how I phrased it. And he said, no, no, no, no, delete
that, change it, make it to this. And I said, okay, sure. Why? He goes, well, they might be living in
our, under our oceans. And I was like, uh, okay, can you elaborate a little bit? He's like, no.
What? Yeah. That's what he said. Hey, where did this guy work? He was an intelligence guy.
I'll leave it at that. Okay. He definitely would be in a position to know certainly, you know,
but that's all he said was like, they might be living under the ocean. They might be living
in our oceans. Yeah. They might be. They didn't say they did or they did or didn't. They said
they might, but he was sort of on Shallan about it. He was just like, I'll tell you, I'll tell you
Robert Bigelow. Yes. We talked about him last night. Yeah. So I did, I know what I saw. Now
your audience knows a little bit about my history, so you'll have a reference when I tell you this.
When I finished it, I know what I saw. And it was based on that event I did at the National
Press Club, which was pretty credible civilian effort at the time. It was like, you know,
you have all these retired military and government officials and pilots and FAA officials from seven
countries. We had Chile, we had Iran, France, Belgium, England. Anyway, Peru. It was incredible.
It was incredible listening to these like officials from all these, you know, I was,
it was, it was credible. It was a pretty credible civilian effort to get this stuff out. I,
the film comes out and I get an email from, which I showed you last night. I get an email from
Robert Bigelow. He's in aerospace. He's designing these. He's a billionaire. He lives in Nevada
and he has contracts with the United States Air Force dating back God knows how long decades
where any reports, any pilot reports, things of that nature of UFOs all goes to Robert Bigelow's,
you know, he had like a think tank, NIDS and his organization was like, how could this civilian
like be getting a contract with the government on UFO? What? You know, and he's also, he was
working at one point with, with Tesla, Elon Musk with, I guess he was trying to use Elon Musk's
rockets to put his habitable inflatable zones up into space because they're lightweight.
Oh, really?
Anyway, I'm not sure what that whatever happened with that effort, but in any case,
he's a high profile guy. He was on 60 minutes. So he sends me an email or his secretary.
Mr. Bigelow has a message he wants to pass along. He watched your film. I know what I saw and he
wants to congratulate you on a job well done. And I was like, damn, Bigelow reached out to me,
like, wow, for Bigelow. So I, you know, I emailed back, thank you so much. Would he be willing to
get together for, you know, dinner or lunch or something? And yes. So I was like, well,
I'm going to go meet Bigelow. Why not? Right? I mean, the guy is like, he's gotten all the
contracts. Now, what was really funny was that I didn't realize this until later.
Robert Bigelow at the time was actually, and I'm convinced of this, he was fishing to see what my
next move was going to be. He wanted to know what I was, what I was up to, because he was asking me
like, oh, what's your next thing? You know, maybe I'd finance it. You know, he just wanted to know
he wasn't he wasn't going to finance anything I wanted to do. He just wanted to know. And I'm
pretty sure of that. But I said to him at one point, I was like, well, you know, what side,
who side are you on? Because every case that I'm looking into, particularly the case of the United
States and international cases too, I get people saying, oh, well, Bigelow, Bigelow's organization
came and took all that evidence. And I kept hearing that it's like, so what are you doing
with all this evidence and stuff? Anyway, he says, James, do you,
before I say this, I was going to say that this guy, I guess, legitimately is in a position to
know a lot more than I know. Okay. Particularly at that time. He had the government contracts,
he had the contacts, he had the intellectual heavyweights in the scientific community all
working for him. This guy definitely knows a lot. No question. And so he says, James,
do you understand the implications of disclosure? And I said, I'm not really giving it too much
thought. Why? He goes, meaning the implications of disclosure. This story really came out. Okay.
So he's like, and to be honest with you, yeah, sure. I guess I thought about it. I mean,
doing this even though it's that big of a deal to me, we're not alone. Great. You know what I mean?
I don't think anybody thinks that we're alone in the universe anymore anyway, but
they're coming here. He said, I just need to really emphasize this to everybody out there.
So you understand what I'm telling you. I'm not saying I believe what I'm about to tell you. Okay.
I need to see more evidence. I'm not saying I don't believe it, but I don't just believe something
because someone told me that. I need to see supporting evidence. I need to hear testimony.
I need a lot more. What's taken me as long as it has with all the other cases that I investigate.
I don't just believe a case. Okay. So Robert Bigelow said to me, they're walking among us.
I said, what do you mean they're walking among us? He said, they're walking among us. They live
right here kind of thing. So again, I'm looking at him going,
I need to see, I'd like to see some proof of that. But then he said,
we've done studies. We've done extensive studies on the impacts of this story we have on the general
population globally. And I said, okay. Well, like what kind of studies? He goes, well,
you take Iran-Contra and you take all these other like super big scandals and you multiply those,
every one of them that's ever happened in the history of mankind in modern history.
And then you multiply that by a million. And that's the impact according to our studies
that this reality would have on the general public. He said the economy would collapse,
organized religion would collapse. And he just rattled off all that. Like again, I'm not saying
that I believe this. I'm just telling you what he said to me. How could you possibly conduct
a study on that? I could see how you could, you could gather, you could collect data on
individuals, but how could you possibly do a study on an entire civilization or large
group of people? Like, how would you do that? That's what he told me. That's what he told me.
I mean, look, it would have an impact. There's no question that it would have an impact and it
probably would affect religion, right? Why am I going to work? Why the fuck am I paying taxes?
You know, and it's like, I remember having this conversation with the sixth man to walk
the moon, Edgar Mitchell. And he goes, you know, this story is just part of the bigger picture.
Let it out. People should know about it. People should be okay. He goes, you know,
you still have to take out the garbage. You still got to pay your mortgage or your rent. You know,
I thought it was kind of funny. Every time I take the garbage out, you know, I believe we're not
alone in the universe and it's being covered up from us, but I still got to take my garbage out.
Imagine also, imagine the kind of power you must feel holding onto that information that would,
you're holding something that could potentially alter humankind, alter the mindset of every one
of our species on earth. And that could probably change the trajectory of where we go, how we
evolve, et cetera. Like if you hold onto that information, how does that affect your ego?
I literally just interviewed a guy, I get, I've got goosebumps on my arms talking about this
because it's just crazy. Cause I believe it. Who drove a bean called a creature or bean or
they called it kind of ET on that UFO crash case in Virginia, Brazil in 1996. And I said to him,
you have a level of confirmation that only a handful of people on this planet have.
What does that feel like? Cause I wanted to know, you know, this guy was serious as a heart attack
and he was not out there trying to get an interview with anybody. We were chased him down for years.
And it was like all the money in the world and never coming forward. And the stars lined up and
the stars lined up and we had like a 36 hour window where we managed to get this guy on camera.
But I asked him that question. You have a level of confirmation, you know, definitively you drove
this thing around. What does that feel like? And he, he responded like it was more of a burden
than anything else. And it's actually kind of ruined his life. The level of secrecy. He gets
phone calls from the base that ask him like, Hey, how you doing? How's your family doing?
You guys having a good time? Did you, did you move yet or are you still in the same spot?
Right. Great. Great. Well, I'm glad your family's doing good. I'm glad you're,
you're doing good. You know, any change of plans, you know, let us know that those kinds of calls
he gets all the time. Yeah. I mean, the main difference between people like the people you
interviewed in Brazil who were a part of the Virginia, Virginia case and people like Bigelow
is Bigelow is a powerful, rich and powerful guy who probably has a lot of leverage in government.
Like I'm sure if he chose one day on his, whether it be just because he was in the right mood or
because he was on his deathbed, whatever, if he chose to release that information, I'm sure
he could do it and wouldn't have to suffer any kind of crazy repercussions. Maybe I'm wrong,
but the guys that are in Brazil, like literally the, like they're dealing with the threats of
military and government threatening their families. I feel like it's a little bit different. I feel
like Bigelow is in a position of, I hold onto this mad, like it's, it's like this piece of magic that
he's holding this, this power, the power to change the world. Yeah. For me, I feel like Bigelow is
selfish. Yeah. Because when I met with, I think I might've called him later as well a couple of
times. I can't remember, but I, I said to him, whose side are you on? You know, and I was serious
because like everything that I do, I do to share everything that I uncover with the rest of the
world. That's why I do what I do. I honestly and firmly believe that every man, woman and child on
this planet is entitled to this information. I believe that with all my heart, you know,
and it pisses me off quite frankly, that someone feels that we are not worthy of knowing this,
that we can't handle it or that we don't deserve it or something. You know what I mean? So it's like,
when I see someone of his, like stature, you know, he's got resources, man. That guy's a billionaire,
you know, I'm like a squirrel trying to get a nut out in this, you know, compared to a guy like that.
And then the fact that he's hoarding it all and it's under armed guard in a vault at his house,
like, or his whatever his office kind of pisses me off a little bit. I'm like, what, what, wait a
minute, what, what, how are you, does he have an agreement with the government? So he has to do
that? Or is he just being like selfish and doesn't want to share the results of, of his, you know,
work and investigation with the general public? Cause he's like, feels like he's better. I don't
know what the hell he's thinking, but I share everything. The only thing I don't generally
share is stuff that I know for sure beyond a shadow of doubt that I'm going to be looked at
like a crazy guy because I've looked at myself as a crazy guy. You know, I, I can't tell you enough,
like I'm putting my credibility on the line for this Virginia case. Okay. Because you got this and
I'll say right up front, I honestly, sincerely, and unequivocally do not expect any of your
audience to believe any of this without looking at the testimony. In other words, don't believe a
word coming out of my mouth because I heard about this case decades ago. I heard about it within a
year or two of it happening. And you wrote it off. I dismissed it like, like that. I was like,
no way a UFO crashed and the bean survived and we're walking through the town. No way. No way.
In fact, I dismissed it for 10 years. Let's see. No, no, I dismissed it in 97.
I wouldn't look, I wouldn't look into it for one second. Not one second. In 97, 98, 99,
one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 13 years. Okay. So 2011, I was going to
Brazil on a completely, I was going to give a presentation on one of the films I'd done.
Probably I know what I saw or something. And my buddy, Jeff Sagancki, the guy I was talking
about earlier who met with Jackie Gleason, he goes, oh, you're going to, you're going to Brazil.
You got to look into the Margini case. And I was like, you mean the one where the UFO crashed and
the alien survived and they're walking through the town? I go, sure, Jeff, I'll look into that.
Click. And I had no intent in looking into it. I told him I might've said I would. I'm not
looking at it. I'm not wasting my time on that case. So I get to Brazil, and this is 2011,
and totally accidentally, completely like inadvertently, I met some witnesses
from, they were happy to be at the conference that I was at and talked to them a little bit
about it, a little bit. I was like, huh, okay, interesting. Kind of believed them a little bit.
So I went back in 2012 and I thought maybe there's something here. And I was knocking on doors and
really chasing it. I mean, I went down to downtown Virginia, Brazil. Virginia is in the state of
Minas Gerais, which is about four or five hours north of Sao Paulo. In Sao Paulo, everyone,
myself used to think I included the capital of Brazil, but it's actually Brasilia, which is way
to the north. But Sao Paulo is like the big city, right? And second time around, I was like, wow,
hmm, maybe there really is something to this. And then I went a third time and then I went a fourth
time. And then ultimately I made the film. And now I'm absolutely beyond a shadow of a doubt,
fully, completely convinced that a UFO crashed in January of 1996 and that the beans, some of the
beans, survived and were captured by the authorities and witnessed by civilians in the
town of Virginia, Brazil. And the film is complete now? Totally done. And you started working on it
how many years ago? Well, I started actually making the film. I know you've been researching
it for a long time. Researching it for a long time. So if you look at it from when I started
researching to the completion, it's probably 10 or 11 years. 10 or 11. Yeah. But in terms of
like production, like go there, boots on ground, we're going to do this. But all that prep work
went into it. That was just less than a year. Absolutely mind bending film. For full disclosure,
I watched it Monday night and it had me completely, it had me in a choke hold the whole time I was
watching it. Like I did not look up once. Maybe we should show the trailer before we go deeper
into it. Can you pull the trailer for it? For a moment of contact? This trailer took I think
three months to make. Maybe a bit more. In 1996, the people of Virginia, Brazil, witnessed a UFO
event that would change their lives forever.
Call it another Roswell, if you will. It is a crashed vehicle that had beings on board.
Finally, the facts will be revealed.
The Virginia case is considered the most well-kept secret in the military circles of Brazil.
My objective here is to put some clarity on what took place in Virginia, Brazil, January 1996.
The witnesses are some of the most compelling testimony I've ever heard.
Action! A lot of people in this town have a little piece of the puzzle.
This year, he had captured this creature with his bare hands.
After he captured the creature, he developed this infection that wouldn't go away.
This can no longer be covered up. They might shoot us because we're on the property.
This can't be denied.
This was proof. Pull this off. It'll be the most compelling testimony revealed. Of contact.
This is a level of confirmation that only a handful of people on this planet have.
His first mistake turned out to be his last.
I'm pushing the envelope a little on the comfort level of those around me because you're dealing
with like this. I know how I looked at the case and I looked at the case when I first heard about
it, the Virginia case. I dismissed it so quickly. I told you earlier, like I know how other people
are going to react when they hear, sure, a UFO crash. Sure, the being survived. Yeah.
I'm literally putting my 30-year reputational line for this one. 29-year reputational line.
Do you know what I mean? I stand behind it. I stand behind it and I really believe and I
think you do as well. Sure, it's got a lot of pizzazz. The trailer is designed to get people
to watch the film, but the film delivers. It does. It delivers. It delivers. It's not just
a bunch of hot air. Not at all. The amount of evidence that you have and the amount of people,
civilians, and ex-military that you talk to is astounding. Correct me if I'm wrong, I know the
Zimbabwe case is close to this when it comes to the amount of witnesses,
but when you have civilian witnesses mixed with military and police witnesses, on top of that,
people handling this creature and seeing it come into their place of work, into the hospital,
I don't think there's ever been a case where there's been a being like this
with all these witnesses running around a neighborhood or a city. Has there? No,
I've never, I've never, I've never. It seems so sci-fi. I get the goosebumps talking about it
because I challenge anyone out there in the UFO community, anyone to show me, let's say crazier
story. It's the most sensational story I've ever heard and the crazy part about it is that you
will believe it. I have one of my most skeptical friends who's watched my career from day one,
one of my best friends. He lives in San Diego and he's been moderately supportive and he watched
the phenomenon. He loved it. He watched this one about a month ago and he's my barometer
and he called me up and he goes, I'm floored. He goes, it's the craziest story I've ever heard
in my life and I actually believe it happened. I think this is the most powerful thing you've
ever done and it's not my story, right? I'm just reporting on it, but we went out of our way to
really, I mean, we worked on some of those witnesses for nearly a decade. We identified
some of the doctors early on and they were like, I will never talk with you. Like this is never
gonna happen. You might as well just not even, and then one of them, allegedly the guy that did the
x-rays, which for some reason, I don't know, there's something about that testimony that really just
for me personally, listening to him, and he goes, at the end of it, he goes, thank you for giving
me this opportunity. This has been the heaviest weight on my shoulders for so long. The fact that
I had the opportunity, even though I'm doing it anonymously, the fact that I've got, and everybody
that we feature that you're filming from behind, we have their credentials. We have them in uniform.
We have all the history of them, all of it, right? So we verify all of that before they even,
and then the fact that we get them to come forward was just a miracle, quite honestly,
just a miracle, yeah. To you, what was the most compelling piece of evidence or interviews that
you did from all the people you talked to in Brazil? In Brazil? Yeah, to you, what was the
thing that stood out to you the most? I met with an Air Force brigadier by the name of Jos
Carlos Pereira. I have a photograph of him in uniform somewhere, and he said, I'll talk to you
about the UFO phenomenon in Brazil gladly. I could talk about this case in 86, UFOs in Brazil,
and I could talk about the Calaris case, but I don't want to talk about Virginia. I was like,
okay, why are you going to talk about Virginia? Don't even bring it up. I was like, Jesus. So
Marco, my partner in Brazil, we did the interview. I honored the fact that he didn't want to, I don't
know how I brought it up, but I basically didn't bring it up on camera. At the end of the interview,
and I have video and photographic proof that I was with this guy, at the end of the interview,
we walked him to his car where he had his driver waiting. I looked him in the eye and I said,
I swear on my life and on my family's life, there are no recording devices anywhere on my body,
no cameras rolling. Please, General, please tell me, did Virginia happen or not? Marco and I were
just basically just, I mean, we were like, I mean, I'd never begged. I wanted to know so bad.
And he looked at Marco and he looked at me, and as he was getting into his car,
he opened up the back door and he goes, it happened. And he got in his car, closed the door,
off he drove. So I had, at that early stage, very definitive, for me, it's obviously this is a story
for you or anybody else listening to what I'm saying, why on earth would he not want to talk
about it? Why on earth would I have to beg and plead with him on my hands and knees to get him
very discreetly at the last possible second when he was driving off to look at us and say it happened,
why on earth would he lie to us? And so I had a pretty concrete level of confirmation early on
on the case. So now it's like, okay, we got to keep digging, we got to keep digging.
But what we were finding was, is that the better the witness, the less likely they wanted to come
forward and that the more likely that they had been intimidated and threatened. And they would
do it in a way where it wasn't like, hey, we're going to kill you. It was just like the punishment
for violating your security oath or your security is going to be so severe, they would say, so
severe. How's your family kind of thing? Not we're going to kill your family, but these are the
kinds of things. It was spooky to the witnesses, like really spooked them. And then to get phone
calls every couple of years, hey, how you doing? That kind of thing. So we worked incredibly hard
and we were so lucky. And I've got to tip my hat 100 times to Marco Leal, my producing partner,
who's Brazilian, who's been investigating this case longer than I have, and he's been just a
force to be reckoned with, could never have done it without Marco. It's incredible. For people
that are listening and watching, can you lay out kind of a linear timeline of what went down?
What was seen first? Was it crafts, the crash from the girls to the cop that actually captured
the being? So in January, probably 12th or 13th of 1996, there was a ultralight pilot
by the name of Carlos de Sosa. And Carlos was driving from Sao Paulo up to a state called
Minas Gerais. It's a state to the north. And in Minas Gerais is Vargenha and a number of surrounding
cities. And he was driving on the freeway, I think it was five o'clock in the morning, five,
530 maybe. And he saw something in the sky that was cigar shaped, that didn't look right,
and it looked like it was in trouble. And he witnessed it crash. Prior to that, there were two,
it was like 2.30 in the morning, there were two farmers, which I interviewed both of them as well,
that saw the object that looked like it was going to crash, but they didn't see it crash.
There was two of them and it was about 2.30 o'clock in the morning for them.
And it was a cigar shaped object and it had a gash on the side of it and it had vapor coming
out like a white vapor coming out according to the witnesses. But they kept kind of expecting it to
impact the ground, but they didn't see it impact the ground because it looked like it was in serious
trouble and it was flying slowly. So then Carlos de Sosa, like I said, was up early one morning
driving to go meet some ultralight pilot friends of his to go flying. And he saw this object and
then he saw it kind of go down like it was going down. And he jumped off the freeway and he drove
up this farm called Maolini Farm. And he came upon maybe a football size field of debris and
one very large piece of the cigar shaped UFO that was kind of a metallic light that was still intact,
but a lot of bits that were not intact. And he jumped out of his car. He ran up and he said
there were like these like tin foil type pieces. He wasn't thinking extraterrestrial. He thought
it was a government thing. He didn't know what it was. He thought there were some people that
were in trouble. Yeah, he thought there was people in trouble. He wanted to help them.
He never ever, ever did he think alien. Not one time. Not to laugh at what I'm about to tell you.
So then, I don't want to give too much away, but he held one of the pieces and he said it was light
as a feather, very similar to what the description of the people at Roswell where he could take it
and crumple it up and then it would rebound and reshape itself. But he said it was light,
like just so light you could barely feel it in your hands. He was looking at her going,
the hell is this? And then all of a sudden these military trucks start rolling in.
They take guns out and they threaten him and he gets in his, you know, gets in his car and they
force him to leave and it was all rather terrifying for him and he, off he goes and he was collecting
himself, I don't know, half an hour down the road at a gas station, went in to get a coffee
and that's when he had a visit from these men that basically like knew his name and knew everything
about him and warned him of keeping his mouth shut. This was right after? It's pretty much right
after, yeah. I think within an hour, half an hour, something like this. And a couple months
after the incident, he met with a famous UFO researcher by the name of Clodio Covo and he
gave him one brief on-camera statement and then he vanished for 26 years. Well, Marco and his
associates were, because I kept saying 10 years ago, I was like, we've got to find the crash,
we've got to find Carlos. Like we've got to find the guy, but he was just vanished.
I think it took us like eight years and we found him. Marco found him. Anyway, we got him. Then,
so then roughly, let's see, it would have been the morning of January 13th, so the afternoon of
January 20th, you've got all sorts of reports of unusual activity in the town of Virginia.
You get in reports of weird, strange creatures. Nobody said ET. It was like, what the hell are
these creatures? The fire department was called. It was five days, about five days, yeah. And the
distance, I think the distance between the crash and the sighting in the town of Virginia is
somewhere in the realm of 12 to 15 miles. Whoa. Something like that. And so you're getting these
reports. The most compelling reports came from civilian reports, came from three girls. It was
Katya, Liliani and Valkyria. And Valkyria and Liliani are two sisters. And then Katya was a
little older. She's 21 and it was like 14 and 16. And they were going through a little field
on the outskirts of town, but in the town. And they saw this creature in broad daylight,
I think it was like three o'clock in the afternoon, crouched against a cinder block wall.
And we're like, you know, looking at this thing, like, what the heck are we looking at here? And
it had, it was weak. It had spindly arms and legs. It had like a brown oily skin, almost like a
kidney or something. Do you know what I mean? Like it was like an exposed organ. And they shrieked
when they looked at it and then it turned and made eye contact. Two of the girls, I think it was
Liliani and Valkyria took off and Katya got completely mesmerized by making eye contact
with it. There was some level of communication that was happening and Katya was kind of frozen
in her tracks. She was about eight feet, maybe 10 feet away from it. And it was, it was feeble. It
was scared, according to Katya. It wanted help, like get me out of here kind of thing, help,
according to Katya. The other two girls got, I don't know, 50 or 70 feet away and were like,
where's Katya? We got to go back and get Katya. And they ran back and it was Liliani,
ran back and grabbed Katya and broke her stare and yanked her out of there. And then they
they reported, they went running home to their mother and they were like telling her what, you
know, and they thought it was something of the devil, like it was a devil or something.
Did she say, did she say anything about any kind of communication between the being and her?
Yeah, well, I asked her about that. Yeah. Cause I said, this is where the title came from. I said,
and I didn't even realize this at the time. I said, cause I wanted to know, I know it was very
brief. It was probably just a couple of seconds, but a lot can happen in that moment. In a couple
of seconds, time slows down and you kind of get, you know what I mean? Like, so I said during that
moment of contact, was there any level of communication? If so, what was said, what did
you feel? And she says it was obviously no words or anything, but it was like, I'm scared, I'm weak,
I'm scared and I need help. That was what she got. And Katya was, was staying behind and Lilliani and
Valkyria ran back and grabbed her. Katya was the oldest, she was 21. And so they run back to their,
the mother's house, the two sisters with Katya and the mother says, we're going to, let's go back.
And then the two sisters weren't, didn't want to go. So she went back with Katya was the oldest one.
So the mother went back and they found a footprint where it was. And it just,
the strongest smell of like ammonia, just, they said the smell was just like paralyzing, like
a hundred thousand times worse than a skunk. Just the smell. I had somebody say to me,
that seemed to be in a position to know, but I don't know, it could be complete speculation,
because everybody had talked about the smell of this thing. That when certain creatures get scared,
they have this, they excrete something that, that can protect them or paralyze those around them to
protect, do you know what I mean? Like a skunk does. And that, that a lot of people thought that
that's what these creatures did. So it was like a sulfur mixed with ammonia. Sulfur ammonia,
they said it was the worst, like it was just paralyzingly bad. Okay. And it was in your,
it was in your nose for like a week. Yeah. Everybody talked about that. So in any case,
so the mother, I don't know if I'm going into too detailed, the mother went back and smelled the
smell and saw the footprint of, you know, this weird creature, which I actually have a drawing
of the footprint if you want to see it. Yeah. Yeah. They drew the pictures or they had an artist do
a rendition from, from their description. No, the mother actually drew the footprint for me right
there on the spot. Let's see if I have it here. Watch me not have it. I saw it last night when I
was going through these. Yeah, I think it's in there. Okay. Here we go. This could be it,
but it's basically like two digits, like two digits like this with one appendage that looks
like it maybe comes out when it's trying to beep by when it's standing up and when it's not standing
up, it looks like this kind of like, so we can walk. Right. I'll, I'll keep discreetly looking
here. You guys right there. Oh, there it is. Boom. Wow. Okay. Yep. Good. Good. So kind of around,
around paw with three long fingers. This is exactly where you can see that.
Pull it back, back behind the mic right there. Yeah. Okay. So this is exactly where the encounter,
this is exactly where the encounter took place. And these are the three witnesses.
That's Katya, Valkyria and Liliani and his exact location. And this photograph was taken in 1996.
Right after that, right after it happened. And then you've got, here, hold this up by the microphone
real quick. You've got the footprint. That was the, that was the footprint of the creature. Then the
mother who saw the footprint drew this for me. A little bit higher. There you go. Perfect.
Perfect. Yeah. Crazy. She drew that for me. And a lot of witnesses I talked to had seen the foot
in the hospital. So later that day, only a few blocks away, there were two military officers
on patrol. Nobody was talking ET. Okay. Nobody had mentioned ET. The girls thought it was the devil.
They were very religious. Right. The mother didn't know what, you know, the girls saw.
Later on that day, two military officers, Eric Lopes and this guy named Marco Cherizzi.
And when you're in the police, it's like the fire department's part of the military. The police is
part of the military, military police. So these two officers were on patrol looking for something
unusual. They didn't say UFO crash and there was ET walking around. Right. So they're driving around
and they're just a couple blocks away and it's around 5.30 PM. They're a couple blocks away from
where the girls encountered. And by the way, I talked to a lot of people that had that area
of Varginha completely cordoned off by the military, like military blockades all around
there. And I talked to a lot of, I have them on camera, but they were armed and like, you're not
walking one step further, including the local news outlets. I interviewed them as well. So they
cordoned off the area that I'm talking about right now. And that's where the girls had the encounter
and two blocks away at 5.30, where military officers Marco Cherizzi and Eric Lopes saw this
creature run across the road in front of them. Slammed on his brakes, Marco jumps out the passenger
door and grabs this thing with his bare hands. And he takes it and he puts it in the back seat
on his lap. Believe it was the back seat. On his lap? On his lap. Yes. And they take it initially
to a clinic in the town of Varginha and the guy comes out and says, I don't know what the heck that
thing is. Get it out of here. I've no, what are you guys doing? Kind of thing. And so they go to
another hospital called hospital regional. And at which point the creature remains in hospital,
regional hospital. Sorry. The creature remains in regional hospital for,
I'm not sure exactly how long, but it ultimately ended up in Humanitas hospital.
And we have testimony from doctors that performed certain things, as well as
military guys that drove the creature. We have the whole, the entire area where the
creature was. So they, they captured two creatures. One was alive and I think the other one was not
alive. The one that Eric Lopes caught that you said was in his lap in the car, was that one alive or
dead? It was alive. That one was still alive. Yeah. But very little resistance. So he got a cut on his
arm, kind of on his shoulder, like right here during the capture of it, whether it scratched
him with a nail or I don't know what exactly happened, but he got infection. And within days,
week or whatever it was, he went into the hospital. The doctor administered antibiotics and he said
he'd never in all of his years prior or since seen anything like it. Marco trees, a perfectly
healthy 23 year old young man got this like complete immune system failure and he died.
And we interviewed the family, his sister, we interviewed the doctor who worked on him
and they wanted to put him in the ground as soon as possible.
Uh, I couldn't believe that you actually got the doctor on camera, the doctor that treated him.
I know it's crazy, right? What, what did he say? What was he looking for? What did he see
when he was treating Eric? He just said that he'd never in all of his career and he's been
in there for like 40 plus years. He's never seen, uh, someone with an infection from a simple cut
like that, uh, have a complete immune system failure and not respond to any of the antibiotics
that he's, he pumped him full of everything and nothing worked at all. And he just,
his health just went down and he died. There was some sort of mention of a granular toxin.
Yeah, I know. I didn't quite, yes, we have the autopsy reports, which the family had to fight
to get. We interviewed, uh, we w I didn't interview his wife. His wife was interviewed one time very
briefly, never seen the light of day by Roger Lear. Roger Lear, Dr. Roger Lear is a UFO
researcher. He used to take allegedly implants out of people. And when Roger Lear found out
that I was making this movie years ago, 2014, he was adamant that he wanted to talk with me.
He wanted to get together. And I, I sincerely wanted to talk to him too, but I was investigating
Rua at the time and I, I was kind of backburning, backburning, uh, Virginia case.
Long story short, he sent me, he said, well, if I can't, if you can't get me on camera,
you got to have my tapes. I went to Virginia in 2002 and I documented a bunch of witnesses,
some of whom have gone off the radar completely forever. Those tapes had never seen the light
of day. I transferred the tapes, had them digitized and then Dr. Roger Lear sent them back to rear
Dr. Roger Lear and then he died. And so I never got a chance to talk to Dr. Roger Lear,
but I got his tapes and one of those tapes, he interviewed the wife of Marco Triese.
Nobody's ever done that. Nobody's even going to get a hold of her, but nobody had ever managed
to get the driver, Eric Lopes. He'd been in hiding for like 26 years. Marco, what's the name of the
guy who died again? That was Marco. Marco Triese died. Yes. He was the guy that leapt out of the
passenger seat and grabbed this creature apparently. And the guy who was driving the car has never been,
no, he won't even talk to the family of the guy who deceased. The guy who was driving the car,
that's the guy who basically was trying, was about to shoot you guys. Yes. Yeah.
Yeah. It's a crazy story. You know, and we interviewed the town mayor. He was like,
yeah, this is unbelievable as it sounds. I believe this actually happened. I interviewed the local
news station, you know, saying the same thing. They completely threatened to lock us up if we
asked one more question at the military base as a, to lock up the local media in prison for asking
questions. They came down so hard. And then, you know, I don't want to give away too much of the
film, the storyline, because I don't want to ruin it for anybody, but they shut it down. They shut
the story down. And then we came to the realization, not for about 10 years, on my last trip to
Virginia, which was just last year, we came to the realization that the U.S. government was 100%
involved and that they arrived and they took, we talked to the radar operator, we saw the plane
coming in. Saw U.S. Air Force plane. United States Air Force airplane come in and it came into the
exact area where we knew the body was because we drove, we interviewed the guy who drove the body
to that location. And then the United States Air Force plane came in. Yeah. And then flew out,
in and out. Yeah. Wow. So it's heavy. Highly likely, extremely likely that they, one of the
reasons for the level of secrecy is that the Brazilian government would be exposing the U.S.
government by revealing what they know. So I'm just guessing here, but
there are some pretty crazy aspects that we uncovered during meeting the witnesses
and stuff that you just go, Jesus, like really? Guys in suits from some unknown government agency
coming in and trying to like intimidate and influence testimony and offering large sums of
money. Bribes, yeah. Bribes. And then you've got like the lead UFO researcher on the case,
Uberajada Rodriguez, who's a lawyer in the town of Virginia, who suddenly, after writing a book,
does a complete 180 and he won't even talk to anybody anymore. Pacaccini, the same thing.
Claudio Coville's unfortunately passed. But so they managed to like get the lead UFO researchers
to either recant what they said previously or made to print in a book or just go silent altogether
and never comment on the case ever again. And then threatening the witnesses. I never heard a witness
say to me, they said they're going to kill me. They just say the consequences of revealing what
you know would be extremely severe. The punishment would be extremely severe. And then ask, you know,
that kind of thing. Right, right. So yeah. So now, as crazy as it all sounds, and I think I told
your audience earlier, don't believe a single word I'm telling you because I wouldn't if I were you.
But this story happened. One of the parts that freaked me the fuck out the most was the interview
with the x-ray technician. Crazy. What did he say specifically? Like how was his description of it?
Just working in the hospital one night, one late afternoon or evening, and military trucks pulled
up. And they're like, you're going to be doing some work for us. He's like, OK, like what exactly am
I doing here? And they had an object in a black body bag. He said it stank to no end. And it was
kind of smaller. But he said that they were armed guards in there watching his every move.
Look at him in the eyes. You just perform this. You can't look at the x-rays. For the first time
in history, he couldn't look at the x-rays because he always verifies to make sure they come out.
Couldn't look at the x-rays. They just looked at him very carefully. And then he performed his
duties. And then they said, don't you ever talk about any of this stuff. And he said he x-rayed
the skull, the torso. Yeah, all of it. The whole thing. He actually thanked us when,
at the end of it, I mean, I think Marco Leal, my partner, co-producer, who's amazing, Brazilian,
he said that, I think he spent like eight years, because he found him in the hospital through a
student that he revealed the story to once. But he was still working in the hospital. He was like,
they'll never, ever reveal. And then he retired. And then we worked on him. And Marco worked on
him for a couple more years after he was retired. And then he finally agreed, provided we shoot the
back of him. But we got a photograph of him at the hospital. We shoot the back of his head and
disguise his voice that he'll come forward. And at the end of it, he said, I feel so much better.
Thank you so much for giving me the opportunity to share this story, because I've been holding this
on my shoulders for 26 years. And they all were very, quite honest. Could you imagine
if something like that happened and you couldn't talk about it? That's a big deal. Yeah. Yeah.
Really big deal. Yeah, man. It's compelling how a lot of those interviews are. Those people had to,
they demanded to be interviewed from the rear and have their voices changed and completely be
censored. 100%. It was that or nothing.
So it seems like the thing that would blow this out of the water is if it's just crazy that there's
this whole story happened and there's all this evidence from everybody. All these people are
willing to talk, but still we can't get a photo or a video clip. All we get is, can we show the
drawing? Wasn't there a rendition of the creature hiding? There's an artist at a rendition of the
creature, kind of like huddled, like crouched in the corner. Well, hang on a second. Is it online?
Well, I do have the actual creature that the girls gave me. They said it was the most
accurate depiction of what the creature looked like, but it's a little model. Oh, okay. Yeah,
yeah. I mean, because I don't have that really high level drawing. I don't have that with me,
but I have the, let me grab it. Okay. Hold on one second. Yep. It's like super glue would probably
do it. The head fell off. There's super glue here. We'll, we'll fix it after.
Oh man. So it's this shiny brown creature. Well, they, you know, I, I generally try to,
you know, avoid little trinkets like that because there's somewhat cheesy paraphernalia for UFOs,
but the girls who came into contact with that creature allegedly said that this was the most
accurate depiction of what the creature looked like. And that's why I brought it.
I don't know if you want me to see if I can hold it. The reason why I have this is because
the girls gave this to me and said that this is the only, facing me. There you go. This is the
only depiction of the creature that is totally accurate is exactly what they saw. And it was
given to me by, and how big was it? It was like about four and a half feet, maybe four and a half
feet tall. Wow. Brown, oily skin, big eyes, scared, cowering, non-threatening. It was
non-threatening. It was, it was scared. That image, that drawing isn't anywhere on Google.
It was, it's, it's strange because it kind of, it matches all of the traditional depictions of
the alien beings. Except for the eyes. Except for the eyes and its brown skin.
Yes. And it had like ridges. There you go. There's a bunch of them.
All right. So that's, that's pretty accurate. That one upper right. Yeah, it's pretty accurate.
That's pretty accurate. So it had this brown skin and red eyes. Yeah. It wasn't evil looking.
Yeah. Some of these renditions try to make it look evil. I know it was not. Oh, look at that one. Go
up. Left. Yeah. Yeah, that doesn't. Yeah, that's too big. And, you know, it wasn't reaching out.
It's the wrong position. It was crouched. I mean, if you could see like all it did. Okay.
The entire time it was crouched, it had, it had its arms kind of between the legs
like, like this, right. And when the girl screamed, it went like this.
And that was it. It didn't get up. It didn't come after them. It just turned to look them right in
the eyes. And they say it made any noise? No, they didn't. But others did. Like a, like a,
there were witnesses and we actually have them in the movie where they say kind of
sounded like a cricket, like a, like a cricket.
Um, yeah, I can't replicate. There were people in the hospital, uh, once they took the alien that
had died, it was partly covered up, but there was people in there who said they saw the feet of it
kind of hanging out and they were all just looking at each other in bewilderment, not knowing what to
do or what to say. Yes. Yes. I said, I said to that witness, I said, put me in that hospital room.
Right. What was the feeling like? What was the atmosphere like? What were the doctors doing?
What were the other military officers doing? And he said they were all scared. Like they were all
feeling in over their heads. Like, what are we looking at? What is going on here?
Do you know what I mean? Like everybody was freaked out. He said he's looking at these
feet and it was like, you know, I think it had another appendage that when it stood up and did
that because, but, um, yeah, it's, it's a truly crazy story, but you know, there are other
crazy stories like that. I was talking about the Rua incident, which is different because they
were in control. Right here. These creatures were clearly not in control. They were scared,
which is so crazy, man. It's so crazy. You always think of in these stories of the creatures being
the ones in control. Yeah. They're the ones who have the upper hand. In this case, this thing was
all alone and in distress. That is what makes it so insane to me. Oh my gosh. I was going to tell
you. So I flew my, my drone. Yeah. I learned, I fly remote control airplanes and I remember years
ago, I was like learning to fly remote control airplanes. So I could put cameras on them and then
of course the drones and, and, uh, so I think my drone, I took it everywhere I go just to get
aerial photography of cases. Right. And I took it way up and I pointed the camera straight down
because I wanted to document the area where the girls came in contact with this being allegedly.
And you could see the block, the military blockade where that was from a different witness. Then you
could see where the girls saw the creature in this one little area. And then you could see where the
capture occurred. And I was, we were all like coming to the realization, wow, this, the vast
majority of this occurred in a rather small area. Like, I don't know, within eight, 10 blocks. Right.
Right. And then the family that we rented, we, we Airbnb'd a big house on the outskirts of town.
It was fairly secure. And the owners of the house were doctors and, uh, they were like,
what are you guys doing here? And we told them, you know, we're making this stuff. Oh, okay.
We'll have really good friends have a story. So, uh, we end up
going to their house. It took like a couple of days cause they really didn't want to talk on
camera. And then they want to just, they were like, no, no, we weren't going to go on camera.
We just wanted to tell you where their doctors and they were worried about the impact it would
have on their careers and their credibility. And they didn't want to, they were like, no,
we're just going to tell you it and not on camera. We just wanted you to know what happened.
We were like, well, okay. Well, why don't I film me from the, you know,
you think all this camera equipment's here? Yeah, I know. Yeah. So long story short, what we,
what, what we realized is that, uh, we had done an overhead shot of the cap of the
encounter site, the military blockade site, the capture site, according to witnesses,
all with one shot and the home of the witnesses that we were just about to interview the whole
family, the mother, the husband, and the daughter. And they all watched this thing for about 12 to
15 minutes. And we realized in the middle of the interview, wait a minute, the proximity to
these witnesses, to the girls' witnesses, to the capture, to the military blockade, it's all
right here. So we have testimony from an entire family that watched that night in January,
right around midnight, a UFO, according to the entire family of doctors,
looking for something. And it was doing a grid search over the area where the girls seen it,
where the capture happened, where it all happened. That to me was so compelling because I'm going,
wait a minute, now you've got witnesses describing a recovery effort.
You've got very compelling testimony of people witnessing. And I actually interviewed four
people that all claimed of this disc shaped craft that was looking for something.
Doing sort of a grid. Well, I mean, if we left our people behind,
I'm sure we would be looking for something too. Right. I know it sounds so crazy. I really do.
But you didn't put this together. They didn't put two and two together when you talked to them.
No. Well, they said they were looking for something. I said, how do you know? They were
doing this grid search. Everybody said it was looking for something. Then I was like, wait a
minute. I think we just accidentally captured their home from my drone. And I'm looking at the drone
shot and I've got their home, which is like, say, you know, like here, let's just show you.
So we got overhead shot. This is representative of about 10 city blocks, maybe a little bit more.
Right. This is the road where the capture happened. This is the little area where the
girls came direct contact with the creature. This is where the military blockade was.
And this is the home of the family we interviewed. It's all right here. It all took place.
Yeah, man, it was incredible. I had goosebumps. So I was, we were all just going, oh my God,
they were looking for their people. Clearly. What the hell else are they looking for?
If you are to believe the accounts of the people that you met, and I believed all of them,
no question about it. Can I have some of this liquid death? Oh, absolutely. Hell yeah, man.
It's for you. Awesome. This is water in a bottle. Water in a can. I really like that because I hate
plastic. I always feel so bad about all the plastic. So this is recyclable aluminum.
Murder your thirst. Murder your thirst. I'm going to do that right now.
Did you get any sense from any of them, whether this being was a biological entity
compared to possibly being some sort of robot or humanoid sort of drone or clones?
Because you think when these creatures visit us, if they're coming from some place far away,
similar to the way we look at Mars, we send robots. Why would they come here themselves?
So there's so many unanswered questions. But according to the witnesses that I interviewed
personally, that being was a sentient being. It had emotion. It had intelligence. It had fear.
It was cowering. It was scared. It was non-threatening. It was scared. And it was
feeble and having a hard time. So I mean, it's kind of sad when you think about it.
I started thinking like, gosh, how did they treat this thing? Were they kind to it? Did they try
to make any kind of communication? What did the authorities do? How long did it live? Did it live
for weeks or days? I just wish I knew. I need to find the counter. Once it left the Brazilian soil,
and we have very compelling testimony that it did, what happened to it? Was it alive?
How long did it live?
How long did it live? Was there any level of communication with it? All these questions I
have unanswered, I'm just dying to know. And I'm going to continue researching this case in the
United States because I'm going to start finding out. I know of a bunch of evidence, photographic
evidence, videotaped evidence, filmed evidence, and now physical debris evidence with bodies.
I'm very confident that some unknown government agency or outside government agency, whether it's
an independent contractor for the United States government has got this stuff. Now, my objective
moving forward is where is it and who has the authority to release it? And I want to know if
there are any Americans out there that were involved in this case. In fact, if there's any of them
listening to this podcast right now, please reach out. They can get in touch with you
or they can email me at jamescfox.gmail.com. And I'd love to hear from you.
What are the obstacles for you in order to get your hands on footage of something like this or
photos or something like this? What are the biggest obstacles? What do the people that have
them have to lose? The people, unfortunately, are terrified. The higher the stakes, like the
this has been across the board with pretty much every case I've ever investigated,
you have people that are just legitimately scared. And the more better evidence they have,
the better the encounter, like the girls encountered this thing, the mother had
men in suits come and intimidate her. And I absolutely believed her. No question. The guy
that watched it crash had men in suits come up to him and intimidate him, scared him, spooked him.
People with photographic or videotaped evidence are terrified. I can't emphasize that enough.
Let's just speak hypothetically for a moment, okay? Obviously, I'm covering this case.
Clearly, I want to uncover photographic videotaped evidence. I mean, come on, man,
it's obvious. If you don't think I'm going after that, then you need to readjust your
thinking. There's nothing. It's the holy grail, right? How do you execute? Let's just say
hypothetically that you did identify someone with evidence like that, and you offer them
a significant compensation for it. Either they don't want it, they're too scared, there's no
amount of money. Well, let's just say they do agree to take money. How do you get 100 grand
or 200 grand cash into Brazil? You can't even take more than 10 grand with them asking you
questions. They're watching you. I know the military base is watching me. They've already
called all around to half the witnesses I've talked to. Instead of Bitcoin.
Yeah. I had some people say, yeah, some of the alternative currency, but how do you do the hand
off? How do you get it out of the country? Do you upload it to a server? This is all logistical
things that... And then you have people that are just terrified. I mean, look at Eric Lopes,
the driver of the car. He's been in hiding for 26 years. He threatened to shoot everybody when
we got to his property. He's not messing around. What did they tell him? Is it not just threatening
him, but his family? What would get a guy to literally say he was going to shoot everybody?
He wouldn't even give a statement to the family of his buddy who was in the passenger seat.
Like, think about that for a minute. He wouldn't give a statement to the family of his buddy who
died after handling that creature. What on earth? He grew up. Those two grew up together. They were
good friends. Like the fact that he... You know? I mean, isn't that... So you just kind of have to
have to fill in the blanks a little bit. It's not easy. It's not easy going after
videotaped photographs. That stuff has a weird way of disappearing.
It's horrible. I know. It's like, I mean, there's nobody on the planet probably trying harder than
I am. I mean, no civilian that I could think of. I'm giving it 110%, 24-7. And look,
I'll be incredibly satisfied if our film comes out and it triggers other evidence and testimony
to come forward. And maybe that's a part of another project that somebody else does or I do. I don't
really care. I want it out. But of course, of course, we know there's that kind of evidence
out there. We know that. Now, John Mack, the Harvard psychiatrist, did he interview the girls
in... Or all the girls and the boys in Zimbabwe after that thing happened. But he also interviewed...
Did he also talk to the people in Virginia? Yes. That's fascinating. How did he get in touch with
them? How is it that almost no Americans and even the UFO community, researchers, know very little
about this case? You had two people that I know of, Americans, that investigated. Excuse me, Roger
Lear and Dr. John Mack. They're both deceased. Dr. John Mack is really funny because I was
investigating the Rua Zimbabwe case. That's that landing at Ariel School in 1994. I think it was
September. And where roughly 100 school children were out in broad daylight and they all witnessed
a couple of disc-shaped craft come down and land in the field next to their playground.
And they all ran out with great curiosity and came face to face with beans, very similar to what the
girl... The big eyes, spindly arms and legs, about four feet tall. There was telepathic communication
that occurred. Sounds totally unbelievable, but I'm pretty sure that case happened as well. In fact,
I'm convinced it did. But Dr. John Mack was investigating that case and he was doing so
at the behest of Lawrence Spellman Rockefeller, who was funding a lot of his efforts at the time.
Rockefeller was putting pressure on the Clinton administration. He was funding
researchers, Harvard psychiatrist, Dr. John Mack. Harvard tried to fire John Mack because of his
association with UFOs and alleged abductees and the work that he was doing. And apparently Lawrence
Spellman Rockefeller picked up the phone and called and said, you know those grants you guys like
getting from the Rockefeller Foundation? Well, if this guy gets fired, those are all gone. So anyway,
so he was funding him. So you had John Mack investigating with the camera crew in Africa.
Two years later, you got this another amazing case in Virginia, Brazil. He's interviewing the
witnesses there. Those were only two years apart. Two years apart. Wow, man. The 90s were amazing.
Like think of the two, some of the best cases ever. That massive broad daylight mass sighting over
Arizona. That's such a good case, man. Even the governor saw it. That massive, you had-
You're talking about the Phoenix lights? Phoenix lights. You had the 50th anniversary of Roswell.
You had the people coming forward from Roswell because in 1997, a lot of them weren't dead yet.
A lot of them had died, but a lot of them had not died. So you had the Roswell thing.
You had the Belgian UFO wave, which was the late 80s, but early 90s as well. You had
94, you had the landing at the school in Africa. In 96, you had the crash in Virginia. In 97,
you had the massive flyover of the state of Arizona, the Phoenix lights. I mean, my God,
that was hot. What an exciting- Why was the 90s so hot? I mean, you cover in phenomenon
the 80s during the Cold War. Yeah, I cover a lot of-
They targeted these nuclear facilities. There were many sightings. I love the way you showed the
graphic of the world and you showed the timeline of every nuclear bomb ever detonated. Yeah.
Crazy. That was Lance Mongia's idea. It was a brilliant idea. That was like, yes, Lance,
let's do that. I had no idea we detonated so many nukes. I know. Isn't it crazy, those stories of
the UFOs or these top secret facilities of shutting these things off? Fascinating.
That was an afterthought because I was pretty much wrapping up the phenomenon. Of course,
you got the front page of the New York Times revealing that Pentagon UFO program. Then I
was interviewing the former Senate Majority Leader, Harry Reid, who had initiated ATIP,
Bigelow and everybody else. I don't know why. For some reason, during the sit-down interview,
I didn't ask this question and that was bad on me. But when after the fact, I was walking,
I said to Senator Reid, hey, do you mind really quickly if I get a quick B-roll shot of the two
of us walking? He's like, okay. He had just a couple of minutes. He had these security guys,
detail, kind of looking at me. I couldn't even get near him without them looking at me all funny.
It was kind of weird. Big, brute guys. Is it okay if I stand next to him and we'll walk down the
hall? Yeah, okay. They were walking and I said, what was one of the more astonishing aspects of
the phenomenon that you uncovered during this Pentagon UFO program? He immediately said the
fact they're shutting off our nukes. I thought, oh my God, I just got that on camera with
Senator Harry Reid. That's an aspect of the phenomenon we're going to have to cover in
the movie. I went back to some researchers and that was the last thing we did. That was the last
aspect of the phenomenon that we put in the film. But in any case, getting back to John Mack,
I was following his work in Africa, kind of picking up where he left off with that case.
Randall Nickerson also did a film on Chus Rua, which is, I think it's out now,
called Aerial Phenomenon. He was very helpful and helped me put me in touch with some of the
witnesses. But in any case, I was following Dr. John Mack and then to my astonishment,
when I got to Brazil, I uncovered archival tapes of John Mack in Brazil. So John Mack was doing a
lot of like cutting edge investigations in the 90s that he never really saw through to fruition
because he was struck down I think in the early 2000s by, he looked the wrong way. People think
it's a big conspiracy that he was killed. I really don't believe that. He looked the wrong way in
London. I've done it. It's easy to do. You go across the street and you're, you know,
especially if you don't spend a lot of time there, you don't know the way traffic flows.
Got a couple beers in your belly and you just looked the wrong way.
Yeah.
You know, you just go jump across the street. You're so used to looking this way or what, you know.
So unfortunately, he was run down and died. But it was amazing to see him. He was like at the
forefront of a lot of these incredibly compelling cases. And I'm so glad they're coming out now,
you know. Like Varginha happened how many years ago? What's it?
1996? 28 years ago?
Is that 28?
Close to 28. My wife was born in 96. I think she's 28.
Okay. Wow. Wow. So it's almost three decades it's taken for the story to really come out
in the United States. Varginha is known pretty well. And it's funny actually,
they put their spin on it the same way like with Roswell in the United States.
And I think that's changed a little bit recently. But
like when I hired a local talent from Rio de Janeiro, this audio guy twice, two different
audio guys, and they were laughing, oh, we're going to go investigate Varginha, you know,
kind of thing. And then at the end of it, after they met the witnesses, they were like,
whoa, this happened. Like, you know.
Yeah.
But they kind of had that level of disinformation that had kind of swirled around
the Brazil. But that too now is changing. And I think there's going to be
a lot of questions once this film comes out. Yes.
It really exposes this case unlike it's ever been exposed.
Well, the most fascinating thing to me about the Rua incident is the telepathic communication
that they all explained to John Mack. The videos with John Mack are fascinating,
how he's talking to them and they're explaining this. Like, I don't know how long after the
incident it was. For people that don't know, maybe for people that don't know, you can give
kind of like the bullet points of that encounter. Sure. So there was a sighting of a UFO over
probably a three or four or five day period in South Africa, as well as, which is just to the
north, Zimbabwe. Harare is the capital of Zimbabwe. And then there's a school in a town
called Rua, which is maybe an hour or 45 minutes away from Harare. And the school's called Ariel
School. And it was like, I want to say September 1994. And there were roughly,
they'll say 66, but no, no, there were roughly, I went there and I talked to the teachers,
there were roughly a hundred school children playing outside during recess. It was like 10,
30 in the morning. And they suddenly saw these objects that looked like a disc and they were
coming down and landed. And the next thing they knew, and a lot of the, you know, either the kids
all saw the UFO. Some of them came, saw the creatures from further away. Others saw the
creatures face to face. Like I would ask, you know, some of the witnesses, well, how close did you
get to these, this being or whatever you call it. And they were like, oh, arms reach. Like I could
touch them. Yeah. And there was this apparent, oh, so within I think a week or two,
Dr. John Mack, this Harvard psychiatrist, again, I was telling you he was being funded for research,
general research on the phenomenon by Lawrence Rockefeller, gets a camera crew and flies to
Africa and goes to Ariel School within a week or two. And so he interviews, I think it was 66 kids
on camera right after it happened, all talking about what they saw. Some of them had a download.
They would look at the creature in the eyes and that's when they would, there was a communication
with imagery and they were talking about- Imagery.
Imagery. Yeah. Like, well, so I'll talk about the communication. I can also talk about another thing,
which is kind of crazy, but they had this telepathic communication they described as like
images of environmental destruction, fires, like the earth is, like we're having an impact,
a deleterious impact on the earth, on the environment, our presence, technology,
this kind of thing. And the kids were young. They never thought about climate change. This was 1994.
I mean, nobody's written anything about climate change that was in the mainstream.
So they reported that. But also, and this didn't make it in the film, and this is something that
I've only shared a couple of times, but it's something really delightful about this.
So I heard this directly from the witnesses, the children, now adults. They said, so they had these
very defined areas of the playground because it was Africa. They had these big telephone pole-like
things that would define the absolute outer perimeter of where the kids were allowed to play.
And because there were like dangerous snakes and tall grass and spiders and this sort of thing,
so everything was like groomed within that area and then the children weren't allowed to go beyond
those poles or telephone poles. But what they would do is they would go, children being children,
they'd skip and dance on top of the poles at that furthest perimeter. Like if they went two more
inches over to the right, they were out of bounds, right? And they would skip along there. And
apparently, according to some of the children, these beings were mimicking their behavior and
skipping with them, dancing with, yes, I know, kind of a benign encounter. But they were mimicking
their behavior and kind of just, yeah, isn't that weird? Wow. That's super weird. I never heard that
part of that. Yeah, I know. I didn't put that in the movie, but I thought there was something
delightful about that. That it was a very benign- How would they be doing that?
Well, they said to me like this, because when I meet a witness, I always want to know,
sometimes I even close my eyes and I say, put me there. I want to be there. The reason why I close
my eyes is because your words need to recreate the scene, right? And if my eyes are closed,
what am I looking at here, okay? How far away were they? What was the sky? Where were you?
What were you standing? I wanted to know every aspect of it. And this witness said to me,
have you ever been out in the wilderness, like in the middle of nowhere, and had an encounter with
a wild animal? There's this standoff, this moment where almost time freezes, where you have
a level of curiosity from both, whatever it is you're looking at, the wild animal and you,
it's like you're both frozen and you're observing each other with a level of curiosity,
a piqued curiosity. What are you? What are you going to learn about each other? And like,
are you trustworthy? Is this a threat? What is this? Curious, very curious. They said,
that's what it was like with the beam. It was just as curious about them as they were of it.
And I was always kind of stuck in my head about that. How many of them were there, did they say?
Well, according to the witnesses, there were multiple UFOs. One was bigger than the rest.
And I want to say between, and they would appear here and then come over here. Several. Several of
them. Yeah. Several. Yeah. Can you pull up the pictures that they drew? Oh, absolutely. Jordan?
Yeah. Can you see that? Yeah. Yep. So that's just three of them, one in front, two behind. And
this is corroborated by a bunch of the children that were there. Oh my God. Are you kidding? Like,
so many children. And this was drawn, I think this is, I'll think of her name in just a second.
Does she put her name on the back? Gosh, why don't you put your name on here?
Well, it'll come to me anyway. So. Okay, that's interesting. That shows like eight of them.
But again, I don't know if there were eight, like some of them said we saw one,
others said we saw more than one. You know, some of them, yeah, most of the kids saw more than one
UFO. Most of the kids saw more than one UFO. And multiple beings, more than four or five beings.
But not all the kids came within arm's reach. Only a handful came that close. They were
gathered around. So I wanted to share something really crazy because I was in Africa
and right after, right after I left Africa,
I went and I investigated another. That's wild. I know. I went and investigated another
UFO landing case at a school. And this case was Westall and it occurred in April of 1966.
Okay. But there were like all over 300 witnesses to this case.
300. Over 300, including a science professor in. School in Australia. Okay. Outside Melbourne.
Okay. Westall, I think it was Westall Primary or something, but it's called the Westall Incident,
1966. So I'm, I was just in Africa. Okay. And I had some of these drawings with me.
I was just kind of sharing them a little bit, you know, and I had very much like the classic alien
spindly net, long neck, big head and big eyes. So anyway, so I'm kind of sharing this and I had
someone say, bloody hell. I mean, like that looks just like the one Gina. I said, the one Gina.
He said, yeah, the one Gina from the, their 4,000 year old cave paintings here in Australia.
Yeah. So I looked up one Gina and I don't know if you, yeah. And look at that on their upper right
hand. 4,000 year old rock art. Yeah. So click on that one on the upper right, if you can, the big
one. Yeah. And I just have to remind your audience, this is 4,000 years old. I mean, hello. Do you see
some resemblance? I mean. Yeah. It's kind of crazy, right? It looks, it looks exactly the same.
That's what I'm saying. I, it was just, it was spooky to see that. The resemblance, I mean, these
are children in 1994. It looks like a snake slithering in between all these heads of these
creatures for people that are not watching and only listening. They've, it's, there are these 4,000
year old cave rock paintings from Australia. And these heads look like the traditional UFO heads
with the big eyes, the big head, the spindly bodies. And there looks like a snake slithering
through it, two tall, skinny looking beings off in the background and a bird, like a.
Anyway, it's just, I mean, could that possibly be a coincidence? I mean, I don't know, man,
but that was just, and there's obviously. And this is, so these are apparently in some caves
and how do they date? How do they date it to 4,000 years ago? That you're going to have to talk to,
you know, specialists because I don't know, but that's according to everyone I talked to,
these are thousands of years old on cave paintings in Australia. In fact, I almost went to one of
them. And next time I go to Australia, I'm going to go and look at some of this stuff because
it's just like, I'll look, I don't know which one that is. That's interesting.
I mean, it's just the big eyes, that shaped head. It's just fascinating stuff. And I think I,
you know, this is like the historical, for your audience listening or even watching,
you can check out probably, there's a book that's put out by Jacques Vallee and it's called
Wonders in the Sky. And he documents ancient sightings, whether it's cave art or paintings,
or coins. Historical paintings, Renaissance paintings. It's fascinating. It's called
Depicting UFOs. Depicting UFOs, which cannot be interpreted as anything other than UFOs.
Anyway, there's one drawing that I brought in this briefing document that I was talking about
earlier. Yeah, pull it. You can pull that one up, Jordan. I think you have that one we were
looking at earlier. It's painting the Madonna. It's in a, right there. Yeah, there you go.
The Madonna with Saint Giovanni. Yeah, there's tons, there's lots of these old Renaissance paintings
from like the times of antiquity with religious depictions of Madonna and Jesus and the Virgin
Mary with strange objects in the background. I think this one shows a guy looking up at it in
the sky. Yeah, if you, yeah, if you can click on that and if you zoomed in, you could see there's
a guy standing there with a dog and they're looking up at it. So let me, can I share, can I share,
can we go back to Australia? Yes, yes. This is Westall UFO case. So I went to Australia
right after Africa and I was fascinated because I, it's so hard for me as a researcher to imagine
how a mass sighting like a school could happen in broad daylight and that the whole world
wouldn't know about it. I just have a really hard time wondering how is that possible?
Do you know what I mean? So I started investigating, well, with the help of a number of Australian
researchers and there was a guy who was 12 miles or less, eight miles away from the school.
It was two days prior. Usually when there's a UFO sighting, there's always a couple of days lead up
to a, whether it's a big event like a landing or something, it's almost like they're kind of
casing the joint. I don't know. You'll always, you know, there's a UFO activity on a big mass sighting
usually for a few days before it does something. There was a guy that was about, like I said,
eight, 10 miles away. His name was James Kibble. He'd never come forward ever.
His, he was out in his garden with a Polaroid. It was, I want to say April 4th, I'd have to look
at the exact, but it was April 4th, 1966. And he wanted to share the progress of the flowering
garden at his mother's place. So he had his Polaroid camera out there and then he saw some,
something glinting in the sky that caught his eye. And he looked up and he saw this disc
that was, according to the witness, James Kibble, he deceased now. He sent this to me.
This is a direct scan of his. He mailed that to you? He mailed this to me. Yeah.
So it's descending like this. Yeah, please. It's descending like this. And then
all the witnesses at the school that saw this object take off, they said it was a disc and it
went like this. It goes up like this on its side and then it shoots up straight up in the air.
Well that, according to James Kibble, is the disc that flipped up horizontally like this
before it shot off. A moment later, he said it was like a bullet leaving a gun shot out of there.
Now I'll share some interesting aspect with your audience. And that is, if you ever see
a UFO photograph with crystal clear defined edges, it's probably a fake. They don't know why,
but there's something to do with the propulsion they're guessing that causes the edges to blur
ever so slightly. Like if you look at a legitimate bonafide good photograph that has been like
scrutinized to death, like 1950 McMinnville, Oregon, or 1964, 65, the UFO worker that snapped
off three or four Polaroids. I'm looking at his face right now. It'll come to me in a second,
but you'll see that the edges are slightly blurred. And according to witnesses or specialists that
I've talked to, that's a pretty good indicator that coupled with the testimony of the person
that shot it, Santa Ana Rex Heflin, 1965, he shot, I think, three or four Polaroids. And the edges,
the great pictures, points of reference, broad daylight, light reflecting off the object,
fantastic. If you zoomed in on it, on the originals, the edges are slightly blurred,
just like this one. But this is like a metallic structured object that went from this position to
this position and then shot off at high red speed. Well, it's interesting. That's exactly how Bob
Lazar described those things flying when he was on S4 testing those scraps. I learned about that later
on. And I, you talk to the witnesses, I'd never talked to, prior to Australia, I'd never talked
to someone who described, I mean, this thing was sitting on the ground when the kids ran up to it,
okay? Sitting on the ground right there, broad daylight. It lifted off, got like 20 feet up,
and then it flipped on its side and then that's when it rocketed off. That's what the kids
described? That's what the kids described, yes. So, that's what this guy who snapped a picture of it,
in that position right before he said a moment later it shot off, he said,
described the acceleration to me. He said like it was being shot out of a gun.
Bang, gone. Yep. The pilots described it, the pilots that saw it off the coast of San Diego
explained it like if you put a ping pong ball into a cup and you shook the cup, that's how the motion
was. And then Bob described him flying belly first, like when they did the test flights.
Which brings me to the picture you showed me last night of that red glowing object.
Okay, well. Can you show that? I can. I have that on my phone. I can text it to you and you can forward
it over to him. Okay, okay. But that's kind of a bigger story behind that whole thing. I don't
know if that's something that you, you know, want to go into detail on. Well, as much as you're
comfortable with sharing. I'm happy to do it. Absolutely. I'm happy to do it. Because that is,
if that's real, that is one of the most compelling photos I've ever seen. Yeah. Of a UFO.
I'm happy to share that story. Yes. I just shared a single frame clip of an object.
That's what I basically what I saw. But I saw video videotaped. I don't know if you got it yet.
I just got it. I'm forwarding it to you now, Jordan. Okay, cool. So then I'll tell you the story
about it. Because I get it. It's footage that I've seen with my own eyes. That's truly. So is the
first time you told the story about this to Logan Paul's first time you told the story? Well,
I was always kind of hush hush about it for a long time. I mean, I would tell my friends. Yeah.
Because I was worried about it. I was worried about jeopardizing my efforts to get it. Why is
that so small? Yeah, blow it up. Make it bigger. Oh, yeah, there we go. Okay, so.
But I've told the story a couple of times publicly. And the most detailed was probably when I was on
Logan Paul's show. Because he's like, evidence, where's the evidence? And of course, I feel them.
I feel I feel the same way. I mean, I've got some evidence, you know, uncovered some nice
photographic evidence and video. So let me tell you the story behind this, because it's pretty crazy.
Okay. I was doing my first UFO documentary way, way, way back. Believe it or not, they had cameras
back. I'm old, but not that old. But and I was interviewing a guy who lived on the outskirts
of Area 51 in the area where you could live. It's not like restricted, you know, space. His name
was Chuck Clark. He lived in a double wide and he was a former military guy, an amateur astronomer.
And he had a sighting of something out at Area 51. And remember, this was kind of around the time
that Bob Lazar story was coming out, really big. It was, this is early 90s. I couldn't tell you
exactly what year, but early 90s. And so Chuck and I, he was he was participating in my film.
It's called 50 years of denial. And we were going back and forth for several months. And I was
fascinated by what was going on in Area 51. I was a very curious person by nature. So I stayed in
touch with Chuck and we communicated often. Well, one day he calls me and he goes, I got something
to show you. And I said, okay, well, can you tell me what it is? He goes, no, but I'll tell you this
much. When you see it, your jaws can hit the ground. I said, really? And he's not one fraud
verbally. I mean, Chuck is a pretty mellow guy. I said, really? He goes, yeah, really? I said,
I'm getting in my car and I'm driving straight there. It was like 16 hour drive, 14 hour drive.
But I was like, if Chuck says, you know, so I get to, I get to the little alien Chuck lived just a
block away in Rachel, Nevada. Going to do his double wide, super clean trailer, very nice,
like beautifully air conditioned, nice, very clean, nice situation. And he's got a TV and he's got a
VHS tape and he pops his VHS tape and he said, sit down, I'll show you. And I see two guys on,
all I can describe is like the typical road trip. They're listening to tunes,
they're filming out the window, they're goofing off next to the, they go into like the little alien
and they're posing next to the little alien, you know, just goofing off, just a road trip.
Going to chat Area 51 after all the publicity that Bob Lazar gave Area 51 was a ton.
The first time, right?
Mm hmm. Bob Lazar story came kind of public in 89, it was like 93, but still it was like making,
you know, people were doing tours Area 51 and there were areas that you could go to
and look down onto the base that had yet to be closed off. If you knew what you're doing,
you know what I mean? You could still see the base. That doesn't happen anymore
because they bought that section too. But anyway, they're goofing off, they're posing next to the
ET sign, blah, blah, blah. And then all of a sudden the car's parked, they're in the car,
the car's parked. The camera is on probably the armrest and it's crooked. It's not like level
because it's just caulked a little bit. The camera's filming the dashboard, a little bit
of the windscreen and the heater and the vents and all that stuff. And they're arguing,
and what it sounds to me like, you can't see them yet, you can't see them. It sounds like
they're trying to crawl under the seats is what it sounds like. And they're arguing.
Excuse me. And all of a sudden one of them is like, it's over the top of us. Get down,
get down. It's over the top of us. And I'm like, what the hell is going on? I'm looking at this
video going, what am I looking at here? What's going on? And that point, this light, like
this is the car. There's a light source above it, shooting directly down.
And it's lighting up the inside of the car. But not normally like if you just had a spotlight
with a helicopter. No, this light was like a yellowy orange and the shadows inside the car.
You couldn't see the light. You can only see the effects of the light. You couldn't see the source
of the light. The shadows on the inside of the car were eerily moving around like the source of
the light was on a pendulum because it was kind of like this. So all the shadows, I'd never seen
anything like it on the inside of the car were moving around very fluid, super smooth and fluid,
right? There was no abrupt stop or back and it was all fluid. And one of the guys goes,
you know, they were like, it's over the top of us. It's over the top of us. I don't know
what the hell they're talking about. I don't know what the hell was over the top of us. I have no
idea what they're talking about. I don't know what I'm looking at. And at this point, the camera's
still filming just the dashboard. Just the dashboard. Nobody has it in their hand.
And I hear this, I'm getting out. And the guy's like, no, stay in the car. Stay in the car. I'm
getting out. And he grabs the camera, opens the door. And I don't remember like pretty sure the
camera pans up. You could see like the desert floor. You could see like tumbleweed. I remember
seeing like a tumble. I think I saw a tumbleweed. It was dark, but it wasn't like it was dusk.
You could still see outlines of the desert, right? Okay. They're outside
100 feet is that. Okay. Now here's the crazy part. What I remember is that I'm looking at this thing,
probably 30, 40 feet in diameter. You could have easily hit it with a rock.
It's sitting in the sky and it's magic. It's like floating silently. It's kind of rocking,
like floating. Like it's like a ship on the water. It's doing this. And the skin of the craft
looks like it's alive. Like the molecules are alive. Like it's glowing. Like phosphorus on a
beach or something. Right. And I'm looking at it and all I'm thinking of is all the witnesses that
I've talked to that have seen these things at a loss for words to describe what the hell they're
looking at. Right. Do you know what I'm saying? Yeah. Like, cause it looks alive. It looks like
it looks, and it looks like magic. Like you're, you're just, you're, you can't even speak. Like
I was just like, like, just, you know, like Chuck Clark was right. My jaw was on the floor. Like,
I just couldn't believe what I was seeing. And then the guy operating the camera goes,
Oh my God, like this. And then bam, oh, the camera shuts off.
Did he shut it off or was it just, you know, like shut down? I have a vague memory of something
like him saying something about a battery, the battery or something, but the camera shut off
pretty quickly. Camera shut off. And that was that. And I looked over at Chuck Clark and I went,
Holy shit. Like, who gave that to you? Like, I need to have that. I was still in production
of my first piece. Right. I was like, I gotta have that. And I just said, and he's like, oh,
they're really scared that they, they shot something that, that's like a secret, super secret,
you know, stealth government, whatever. And they're, they're terrified. I said, okay,
well fine. Give them my telephone number. Tell them I'll work with them. They could be anonymous.
Right. I'll get, raise whatever kind of money. Are you kidding me? Like,
just give them my number, Chuck. And I kept harassing them and calling them and calling them
and calling them. And he had a copy of this video. He had a VHS copy of it. Yes. And you know, I hate
to say this, you know, you know, it was probably one of my biggest regrets is I didn't run out of
that thing. Had I known that it would never see the light of day, I probably would have,
because that's not right. Like they could be anonymous, you know, make copy of it, at least
for how did you get, can you tell me how you got the screenshot? So, so well, somebody will, there's
a photograph that was taken in France. Somebody, it's so, okay, I'm sorry. I'm just trying to
reveal what I can reveal comfortably here. Okay, that's fine. I do have screenshots that
was given to me about a year and a half ago. I got contacted. I talked about the story on a podcast.
I just one day said that the hell with it. I don't care anymore. Like, you know, what good,
everybody needs to know, I saw this footage with my own eyes. I swear on my life. Okay. And I knew
there wasn't, and I look at a lot of photographs and video, there's nothing on this one. Okay.
And not only that, but usually when I look at a photograph or some video footage, I immediately,
I'm highly dubious. It's fake. It's been, not one, not even zero, zero, 1% of me said that.
This felt the most authentic stuff. It was just old enough to be before all the special. No,
this was, this was phenomenal, man. Okay. Trust me when I tell you this, this was like the,
this was the most, this is the gold standard by which we're all going after the definitive
piece of videotaped evidence. This was it. Okay. Right. It was like, this is the Holy grail
of evidence. And I saw it with my own damn eyes and the fact that I didn't get my hands on it.
Anyway, about a year and a half ago, maybe it was two years ago. I don't remember.
I sat out the heck with it. And I publicly told the story on a podcast
and I get contacted by a guy who was a PI. He's like, he does private investigating. He finds
people. He's like, I heard your story, man. It's unbelievable. I'm going after this guy,
Chuck Clark. I said, go for it. Don't mention my name. Chuck won't talk to me anymore.
And so I said, good luck. Let me know how it goes. And he finds Chuck Clark and he goes,
I got his number. I said, well, give him a call. So he did. And so he, about maybe a year ago,
he went out and met Chuck Clark and Chuck still had that same VHS tape and it was
pretty degraded. But Chuck actually let him keep a couple of frames of it. I don't know,
let him shoot a frame off the TV screen. That's not one of them, but that's exactly like that.
Somebody sent that. So I don't know where that that particular object. I don't know exactly
where that came from. Somebody texted it to me and said, is this what it looked like? I said, yeah.
Now, the difference that I remember is that the one that I saw had like,
like if you took a pie and you took a knife and you symmetrically cut pieces of that pie,
very symmetrical, but you didn't remove the pieces. You just made the seams.
Those were darker. There were like lines that were darker, like it was like it was a pie,
but it wasn't taken apart. But they were perfectly symmetrical. And I remember that.
I remember that and I don't see it there. But in terms of like the color, orangey yellow
and glowing like that, that's what it looked like. Like it was alive, like it's phosphorus.
That's so weird. Yeah, I know. And it had been being that close to Area 51. It must have been
right there. It must have been a test flight by one of the people there. Could very well have been
that. Could very well. I have no idea. But that's what I saw. And it was flipping. It was, it was
magic. It was like, like you look at it and you have nothing to relate it to because you've never
seen anything like it, not even remotely like it. It's so foreign to your eyeballs. Like seeing
those shadows on the dash, the way they were moving. I'm like, the only way you could recreate
that is to have a light on a pendulum above a car at night that's bright enough. Like and it's
moving so slowly. Like the shadows were moving around in this fluid motion on the inside of the
car with this light source coming above the windshield. It was just like you've never seen
that before. How would you see that before? And then when you see the object and it's like,
it's like, it's not stable. It's, it's, it's kind of wobbling, like maybe slower, but it's kind of
wobbling. Do you know what I mean? Like if you thought of a boat on the, on the ocean, the way
it's kind of move around the ocean like that, that's what it looked like. It wasn't stable. It
wasn't like, you know what I mean? The camera shut off, but did the kids describe to Chuck or
anything what happened after that? He, Chuck wouldn't tell me. I mean, where is Chuck at?
We got to find Chuck. Chuck's in Arizona. Yeah, he's in Arizona. Chuck, god damn it,
released the footage. Yeah. And when this private eye went out and checked it out,
he said, yeah, Chuck said that he would never talk to you. He goes, Chuck said that,
Chuck said that he told, cause he said to me, he said, if you ask me again,
I'm never going to speak to you again. If you ask me again, of course I'm going to ask you again.
Like I, I was, I was selling, I think it was out of the blue. I just sold out of the blue,
the NBC universal. Sorry, my mic away from the mic there. And there was this guy, Larry Landsman,
who was at NBC universal. I told him the story, you know, he was buying my movie,
sci-fi, whatever. And he goes 30 grand. We'll get 30 grand. No problem for that.
So I was like, okay, I'll reach out to him, but I don't know how well it's going to go down.
It was like 2009 or 2010. And I reached out to him and he goes, I'm never talking to you again.
I said, well, I just have 30 grand. Could you just offer to the kids $30,000? Like, come on.
Right. Just talk to them. He wouldn't even entertain it. No.
You think he's in a similar situation to some of those people in Brazil? Maybe
no. Or those kids are in a similar situation. No, I don't know. Why would he show it to everybody?
I mean, you think you keep it in a vault. He never got it transferred. He never got it digitized.
That footage should have been transferred to beta SP from that bloody VHS tape from when I saw it,
because I can assure you VHS tapes deteriorate. They degrade, go over and you play them over and
over that half inch tape. You know, so that tape is like,
who knows how bad it is now, but it's not great. It's not like, you know,
what I saw was pretty phenomenal. I mean, it was VHS, but it was, wow.
It was, I mean, it was like a couple of weeks old when I saw it.
I didn't dilly dally, man. I went straight out to that stuff. I'm not kidding you. I was like,
I was like, okay, I'm going. Like, I don't know how much more time we have, but there was a couple
of things that I could share with you or however you feel.
Yeah, let's share it. Let's talk about everything.
Well, this is kind of interesting because we'll start with this one first.
This was just something that we stumbled upon when we were making the phenomenon.
We, it was a tel, I think they call it a telex. What was it when you send a telegram or a telex?
I have no idea.
It's in lieu of, it's in 1952. We didn't have fax.
So if you're communicating directly, you'd send a, I'm sorry.
A telex, maybe. I don't know. That was way before my time.
I know, before my time too, but I still, but in any case, this is interesting because we came
across this, this is from the White House, from the Truman Library. In two consecutive weekends
of July, 1952, the White House Capitol was buzzed by UFOs.
Right.
I actually found through an archivist, excuse me, through an archivist, testimony from a guy
named Al Chop, who was in the radar room the night that the pilot, one of the pilots in 1952,
streaking across the night sky over 500 miles an hour in the pitch black and suddenly was surrounded
by these UFOs. They were like, kind of could be described as tic tacs. They were small,
circular, self-luminous objects that surrounded his plane. The testimony is phenomenal.
They were given the authority, and we have the newspaper clippings to validate what I'm telling
you. They were given the authority to shoot, and apparently they did shoot, and they attempted to
shoot at these objects. We take a very hostile position, according to the witnesses that I've
talked to, on unknowns. I mean, it is oversensitive airspace. I mean, the White House, the Capitol
building, and it was two consecutive weekends. So there was this guy, president of the Rocket Society,
his name is Robert Farnsworth, and he wrote a direct plea to, I guess it would have been
then President Truman, and he said, it's really cool, I respectfully suggest that no offensive
action be taken against the objects reported as unidentified, which have been sighted over our
nation. Should they be extraterrestrial in origin, such action might result in the gravest consequences,
as well as possibly alienating us from beings of far superior powers. Friendly contact
should be made, should be sought, as long as possible. Anyway, it's just kind of a cool little,
came right out of the Harry, yeah, Harry Truman Library. Wow. Yeah, I got it directly from the
Harry Truman Library, and I thought that was neat. And what I wanted to share with you is
this photograph, this photograph here, this is- Up a little bit.
You got it? Perfect.
This is Parviz Jafari. He was a general. And in 1976, he had an incredibly dramatic
dog and cat, dog, you know, what was it called, a dog fight, but he had an encounter with a UFO,
him and several other pilots, and he tried to shoot it down. He got it in his sights,
and he pulled the trigger to fire at this thing, and his entire cockpit froze, and he started
falling out of the sky, and he said he was ready to, he was a second or two away from bailing,
thought he was done. And I interviewed him, we flew him out from Tehran
to Washington DC to testify at the National Press Club event that I did,
that I made that film about, called I Know What I Saw. And on camera, all these years later,
he's since deceased, he said, gosh, my biggest regret is why did I try to shoot it? I should
have tried to make friendly contact. You know, that really kind of left an indelible impression
on me hearing him say that. Like, why did we have to have an aggressive posture? Why didn't we try
to make friendly contact? You know, we're such an aggressive species. It's like, then you have to
ask yourself, and it's all speculation, man, nobody really knows, in my opinion, what's going on.
But these objects chose a school to land in Africa. They chose a school to land
in Australia. They chose a school to land in England. Is it a coincidence? Are the children,
they see as a benign presence, that they'd rather try to make contact with,
I'm just putting this out there, I don't know. But you know, the military takes an aggressive
posture. We shoot at these things. We have very credible reports of landings and contact
at schools. I mean, with hundreds of witnesses on some occasions. So I don't know, it's just part
of my personal journey. Sometimes I think like, maybe, maybe if we weren't so aggressive and
warlike, maybe, maybe they would make contact. I don't know. It's all, like I said, man, it's all
speculation on my part. But you look at what the phenomenon does, and that tells you some things.
But you also look at what the phenomenon doesn't do. All they have to do is hover over the Macy's
Day parade and it's game over. They don't do that. You know, you look at some of these abduction
cases like Travis Walton firing this guy. I think it was 75 at Snowflake, Arizona. And they
got him, I'm convinced that he got in the way of the propulsion when he jumped out of the truck
and was affected by it. The propulsion of the craft as it was spooling up and getting ready to
take off. And they came back and got him. And when they five days later dropped him off,
if they would have dropped him off in a location where he was captured or
obtained, he would have died. It was the middle of nowhere. I've been there twice.
Really?
Yeah. They dropped him off. I actually have a photograph of the location if you want to see it.
They dropped him off at, let's see this one. They dropped him off on the outskirts of town
that was just far enough away in a valley where they could swoop down quickly.
This is a little prize possession I have. This was a drawing that, oh no, 10 or 12 years ago,
Travis Walton, the key witness to the fire in the sky case, drew for me.
Oh, wow. There's something about that. That's what the disc looked like.
And he signed it. That's amazing. Oh my God.
Yeah, look at that. 10 years ago. So it's a ton of glowing. And then this, oh, that's at the site.
Yeah, you got it. Cool. That's at the site. And the weird thing was, proximity to where the object
was was seen hovering, they cut some of the immediate trees as samples to look at the
growth rings. And there was a pattern of accelerated growth within a certain proximity of where that
object was over like a 20 year period, whatever it was since, or maybe it's 30 years since that
sighting. But what I wanted to mention that I thought was rather interesting was so much of what
these alleged beings did with Travis. It's a very credible case because there were so many eyewitnesses,
seven of them, they all passed polygraph. But when they dropped off Travis, they did it so
right on the outskirts of town in a little valley so they could dip down quickly, deposit him right
on the outskirts and then shoot off, minimizing the likelihood of them being spotted. Why? But
they also cared about his wellbeing because if they would have dropped him off where they picked
him up, he wouldn't have made it. And so that tells you something too, right?
Excuse me. It's a fascinating. So, you know, you have to look at like
what UFOs do and you also have to look at what UFOs don't do. I mean, they do some pretty
provocative things, but they don't make overt contact on a mass scale. Why?
Which is interesting, very interesting. And the children aspect of it is even more fascinating.
Children, think about it. I mean, children, they're the most open-minded. They're not
set in their ways. They're closer to the source than we are.
Yeah, they really are. They really are. Well, James, thank you so much for doing this, man.
It has been fascinating. I'm grateful for you coming and sharing all this information.
Thank you so much for having me on the show. It was a real pleasure. I hope I didn't talk too much.
No, you didn't. I wish you could talk more. Where can people find, when is the movie coming out,
Moment of Contact, and where can people find it? So Moment of Contact is coming out in mid-October.
There are a lot of streaming platforms that are currently looking at it. It's right now scheduled
to be released on TVOD, which is iTunes, Amazon, Fandango, Vimeo, Hulu, all those platforms of
transactional download. But it'd be great if anyone out there could just look up the trailer,
Moment of Contact, and just spread it out because the more views the trailer gets,
the higher profile the film and the more leverage that we have. Also, if anyone's interested in
seeing the phenomenon, you can watch it for free on Tubi. If you don't want to get commercials,
you can rent it for $2.99 or something like that on iTunes and Amazon. If you buy it,
some people go, why didn't you tell me this? Because I don't know. I never think about that.
But if you do decide to buy it, if you want to buy it, you can get it on, I think it's iTunes,
with three hours of bonus material. Oh, wow. And a lot of people, for the same price,
you'd buy it anywhere else. But I think it's Vimeo and iTunes. But check it out. I'm pretty
sure it's iTunes. They have bonus material that you get when you purchase it for nine, whatever,
bucks. I don't know. But people that are really into it want to know that. If you're going to
watch it for free, watch it on Tubi. If you want to spend money, go to the cheapest place to rent it,
which is like $2.99. Don't be cheap. You've cheap bucks. Spend the money.
If you watch it free, too, I don't care. I don't do this for the money. I have to make a living.
Yeah. But thank you for having me on, man. Absolutely, man. Thank you so much. And thank
you for bringing all these amazing photographs and everything. It really made the experience
so much more incredible. Oh, cool. Well, thanks, man. That was a lot of fun.