Is it true, you were one of the first, or were you the first active duty fighter pilot
to come out and talk publicly about UAPs?
Yeah, specifically active duty.
I was actually active duty when I did first speak about this.
David Fravor, Commander David Fravor, he was kind of the first one to, I think, come out
and speak about this, but at the time he was no longer in the military.
Why is it that you were the first one to come out and talk about this?
Because people have been witnessing this and observing these things for long before you
came out, right?
Yeah, that's my understanding of it.
So I mean, why was I, you know, the first, that's a great question, I think.
Perhaps I wasn't just, maybe I'm the one we're hearing about, but you know, from my position
it was a little different because we weren't just seeing a one-off object on the radar
or on a camera and then never see it again and question whether, you know, we really
saw it or not.
We were seeing this on such a regular basis that it was something that we were briefing
to every time.
We were not only briefing to it, but we were also informing others that did not have the
proper technology to see them.
And we were notifying the general public essentially with our notice to airmen, essentially broadcasting
out that there were objects that we didn't understand what they were, but they were essentially
a safety of flight hazard.
So for me to speak about it, it was just trying to solve that particular problem.
And that's why I spoke out about it.
And there was just, the day we're recording today, which is, what is today, the 13th of
January, and I think it was two or three days ago, the report came out that there was now
over 500 reported incidents of UAP sightings or UFO sightings by like service members or
military members.
Yeah.
My understanding is that reporting comes strictly from the reporting mechanisms that have been
created within the Navy and the Air Force.
And so, yes, they are seeing more, and we would expect to see that, you know, assuming
what I've been saying is true.
An increase in reporting will lead to an increase in reports.
And so that's what we're seeing.
Now it doesn't necessarily mean the quality of the reports will increase and it'll likely
have more false negatives when we do have that.
But generally speaking, you know, they're out there and now we have the agency to actually
report them.
And so we're seeing the data come in.
I believe the New York Times, there was a bunch of articles about it, but the New York
Times article, I'm sure you saw, was speculating that a bunch of it was basically junk in the
sky or weather balloons.
And they even mentioned, I think they quoted about the gimbal and the go fast video saying
that the go fast video, the object was only going 30 miles per hour.
Did you see that?
I don't remember if they specifically called out the go fast video in those articles.
But generally speaking, you know, there are aviators out there that are talking about
this constantly.
They talk to me about it and they tell me how this is something that they're talking
about in their cockpits all the time now.
What they did express disappointment in was the fact that there were no reliable mainstream
media organizations that they could talk to about this.
Not that they're necessarily looking to go out and make news, but they are looking for
an opportunity to tell their story.
And what we're seeing from the mainstream media is just kind of the same old, you know,
little giggling, little, okay, well, maybe it's real, maybe it's not.
And these people are putting their careers at risk to come forward to talk about this.
So to have it blown off like that didn't really go over well to the aviators I spoke with.
They're saying that the big mainstream media corporations weren't taking them seriously?
Essentially, they didn't feel like they could go and have a respectable conversation about this.
And we see that with some of the reporting we've had where they've essentially dismissed
these sightings.
And what that does is the exact opposite of what I've been pushing for, which is to increase
reporting.
If you're going to mock the aviators when they actually do report something, well guess
what's going to happen?
Naturally, you know, some people are going to second-guess whether they should report
if you have a news organization like New York Times, you know, putting things out that are
detrimental to the safe operation of aircraft, right?
We have to report safety incidents and if we are minimizing those that report it, then
guess what?
We're not going to have as many reports.
Yeah.
A Navy aviator seems like it would be the last person you would want to mock.
Well, it's that topic, right?
We kind of did it to ourselves.
It's a conversation where it might not be pure mocking, but it's almost a defensive
mechanism, at least from what I've seen.
People immediately want to laugh when they hear this topic.
And I don't think they're laughing because they truly think it's funny.
I just think they don't know how to react, right?
And so they just burst out laughing and then they listen for a real response and sometimes
they're shocked when they hear one.
But I think that we're going to see people continue to kind of hold that flag of ridicule
until they convince themselves of it.
I don't think that one thing will be able to show them that data and they'll say, okay,
that's clearly something interesting.
I'm going to now stop mocking this and really pay attention.
I see some of these people kind of holding on for quite a while until they have real
evidence to stand behind.
Yeah, I don't see that.
I don't see many people that have that stance, really.
Maybe it's just the people I surround myself with, the people I talk to.
But it's interesting hearing you say that because I'm sure you deal with a lot of people
that are still active military or still in the Navy.
So a lot of people that you talk to that are still active service, are they the ones that
you're referring to that still kind of are holding on to that stigma?
Well, certainly I'll say in the military, but I think it's more complicated than that
because now that there is a classified reporting mechanism for this, I wouldn't expect them,
nor would I ask them to communicate about it.
However, I do still think the stigma is there.
The stigma that I was referring to primarily is on the commercial side.
Since they do actually have the agency to have a conversation about this, they really
want to.
Some of the aviators I've talked to have got some pushback from their employees about speaking
on this, including cease and desist orders.
I don't think they're necessarily asking them to cease talking about UAP or UFO, but just
generally talking about operations of the aircraft.
I can see why they might have an issue with pilots communicating a safety issue publicly
throughout without their filter.
Where are the cease and desist coming from?
Just corporate airlines or commercial airlines.
When there are pilots that are interested in speaking out, occasionally they have received
cease and desist orders.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, so I'm interested.
What was your take on that new report coming out with over 500 new sightings?
Was it 500 total or 500 new?
I think it was 500 total.
Yeah, well, it's a good thing because we're going to continue to see those numbers growing,
I think, as more people report.
And again, that's only military.
What also came out at the same time as the report was also an interesting PowerPoint
presentation that was given to the National Transportation Board by Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick,
which kind of fell out, actually, I think, the same day, which has some interesting information
regarding how serious they're taking this aviation safety threat.
Additionally, we also have seen the release of even more of what they're calling the
Range Fowler Reports.
Those are the actual reports from aviators who are...
Those are the data sets that they're generating these reports from.
And so those data sets, I'll suggest, are much more interesting than the reports themselves.
You actually hear from the pilots themselves about the objects that they're seeing and
why they're so confusing.
Interesting.
Okay, so for people out there who may not be familiar, can you summarize your career
as a Navy pilot?
I'll try.
Yeah, I mean, it's really not that complicated.
I, you know, I went with a four-year degree.
You got your degree in...
Mechanical aerospace engineering from Worcester Polytechnical Institute.
My junior year, decided that the degree I was going for wasn't really that exciting
enough, essentially.
I had an internship that really sucked.
So I essentially changed my major to the aerospace and decided I wanted to go fly jets, applied
to officer candidate school, got in as a pilot, and essentially, you know, the rest is kind
of history.
I just kind of kept passing tests and moving forward and, you know, luckily the needs of
the Navy were such that I was able to get the aircraft that I wanted, which isn't always
the case.
But yeah, I joined, excuse me, I got in the F-18 Super Hornet for the first time, I believe
in 2011 in VFA 106 on the East Coast.
I was there for a year and then immediately assigned to VFA 11, the Red Rippers, where
I flew the F-18 for three and a half years and two combat deployments.
Once I was finished up with that, I went to Mirdy, Mississippi, where I was an advanced
strike fighter instructor and the T-45 Goshawk, teaching people how to land aircraft carriers
and dogfight, drop bombs and fly formation, all that good stuff.
And that was when I first actually spoke out about this, kind of near the end of my time
in that instructor tour.
And that was the last tour before I got out as well.
So I was in for about 11 years.
Wow.
What's it like being a fighter pilot?
I don't know, I'm still figuring it out.
It's one of the most fascinating things.
They make movies about it and there's the mechanics of it and it's just hard to wrap
your mind around flying a machine like that and then landing it on this boat in the middle
of the ocean.
And I mean, it's just, it's hard to grasp, you know?
A lot of people in the military do kind of like mundane things that aren't necessarily
as thrilling as flying in a jet, you know?
Even people that are, you know, boots on the ground in the Middle East and stuff like that,
it's kind of, it's just not as, I mean, it's definitely terrifying, but doing what you
were doing is just like on a whole nother level, it feels like.
Well, I mean, I was very fortunate to be able to be in a position like that.
Truly, for most of it, it's, you know, a matter of your own skill and how you can perform.
So in a way, it's unique in that there's just so much concentrated effort and focus on applying
the skill sets to the maximum capability of the aircraft and the weapons, right?
We don't go out there and fight at 60%, we're always pushing the envelope, we're always
max performing the jet.
Guys and gals on the ground as well are doing that, but we're up there, we're very protected
in a sense, even going into combat, at least in the environments we've been in, we're not
doing air-to-air combat.
And so my job may have been more thrilling, but I have that much respect for the folks
that are on the ground doing the hard work there.
It was my great honor to be able to fly around in Afghanistan and Iraq to provide support
for the people on the ground.
That's essentially what I was there to do.
What can you talk about as far as what you were doing in the Middle East, flying and
like what sort of missions or objectives did you have?
How similar was it to the Top Gun movie?
Well, I was trained to do flights like you see in the Top Gun movie, that's typically
called like a high threat, we would call it close air support.
That was a pre-planned strike, which is relatively rare, but we do train to do low ingresses
like that.
The reality is a little more complicated, however, because typically what we're doing
is kind of playing chess when we're down there, we're not necessarily just trying to go as
fast as we can toward the target.
We're usually identifying things and executing tactics while we're performing down there.
And to answer your question earlier, that's really what's so difficult about being a fighter
pilot.
It's not the flying itself, it's learning how to employ that weapon, because that's
what it is to us, is we don't learn to fly the F-18 for very long, maybe a couple months.
I think it's our third flight is when we fly by ourselves in it.
We're trained aviators at that point, what we're doing is learning how to employ a weapon
system.
It's very complicated to learn the tactics and the timings and the distances and all
the things that are required to survive up there if we are to go into combat.
So what sort of targets are you going after and what sort of objectives do you have?
What is day-to-day life like on the aircraft carrier in the Middle East?
Are you spending your days and nights on an aircraft carrier, I'm assuming?
Yeah, so once we leave, we're pretty much out there for 9, 10, 11 months or so, depending
on how long it is.
But on a daily basis, essentially, you're looking at anywhere between 8 and 9-hour missions.
You're going to launch sometime between 5 in the morning and, well, I don't want to
use times, but pretty much all day we're launching and going out on those missions.
And once we fly out there, it's very complex to kind of get into the battle space.
We fuel several times with tankers to get out there.
So it's quite the trip.
And then once we're out there, really what we do is we get tasked to various ticks, as
they're often called, troops in contact scenarios where we have to buster over as fast as we
can to provide support to those troops that are in combat.
And that either looks like us identifying targets on our own with our sensor systems
and either questioning or having authorization due to the role of engagement to employ on
that or talking with someone that's on the ground or in some base somewhere that is identifying
targets for us.
Then we come in and prosecute them.
So that's the majority of what we do on a regular basis in Afghanistan or Iraq, at least
what we were doing.
However, a few years ago, we were also operating near Syria and there were aircraft that were
launched and we actually had one of our first combat shoot downs since the early 90s, not
too long ago.
First one since the early 90s.
I believe it was a Syrian MiG that was essentially getting too close to one of the fueling operations,
fueling tankers, loaded jet.
I don't know the specifics, but either way, so we were seeing a little bit of air to air
combat over there as well, which is somewhat unique.
Air to air combat is unique.
Like dogfighting?
It is.
It's not something we do on a regular basis or train to at least over the past decade
or so.
You guys more have like strategic strikes from air to ground, right?
Well, let me be clear.
We do train all of it, like 100%.
We don't even prioritize one over the other.
But when we are in those operations in the Middle East, we already have air superiority,
so we're not focused on air to air combat.
We're simply employing on the ground.
Right, right.
Not to say we don't carry, we do have the weapons as we've seen with that shoot down,
but primarily it's air to surface.
When you're training to become a pilot, how important is vision, like human vision?
Do you do any tests on vision?
And what is that like?
Can you walk me through that?
Well, I don't think it's overly complicated.
Is your vision correctable to 2020 and below some limit?
My vision was not.
I had to have PRK, laser eye surgery, before I joined.
Wow.
I did one eye at a time since I was still in college at the time, so I could still see
the blackboard.
So I did that to correct my vision so I could fly.
And it's pretty, pretty common.
I mean, you can fly with glasses, yeah, it just has to be correctable.
Interesting.
Yeah, because you're moving so fast and you have to make, I heard you describe it before,
like when you're flying, you're kind of, you're moving so fast, you kind of just don't even
have, you don't even have time to think about anything.
You're just sort of reacting to your environment and just using your senses and your intuition
to make decisions.
A lot of times, yeah.
I mean, I think, you know, the trait of a good fighter pilot would be to overcome that
to some degree and push that.
There are best practices and there are tactics and there's standard operating procedure.
How do we push past that bubble to adapt to a real life scenario in order to engage the
targets?
Now in air to surface arena, everything's pretty static and fixed, but when you start
talking about large air to air battles, that's when it gets a little more art, a little
less science.
What are the biggest dangers of your job or your job when you're a fighter pilot?
Probably crashing into the back of the boat.
Oh, really?
Yeah, that's probably the most riskiest thing we do.
What is that like?
How do you, how can you describe the difficulties and landing and taking off from an aircraft
carrier?
Yeah, so I guess the best way to describe it, and so I was, I was actually a landing
which means I was specially trained as kind of an authority to land on the boat within
my squadron air wing.
I was eventually trained up to head landing signal officer for my squadron, which generally
means that means I would go to the back of the boat with my team with an actual like
telephone looking thing and talk to the pilots as they're coming into land.
And what we do is we train them to our voices so that if we give a verbal command, they
immediately apply that command, whether they agree with it or not, because there are misconceptions,
visual misconceptions and cues that they can receive under certain scenarios.
And that's why it's so important that they listen to our voice.
Once we start talking over what we call the ball with the lens landing system.
And so, you know, what is it like?
It's difficult and it's never something you don't just get it one day.
You know, I've seen commanders and admirals, you know, having the worst passes just like
the new guys.
And so it's very much, it's very much kind of like one on one in a sense, you know, it's
just you in the boat.
And a lot of times you'll, at least for me, it was very meditative and almost serene,
especially at night on these long straight ends when you can barely see anything.
I can send you a video of a night landing that I have.
Really?
It's pretty cool.
I just see a speck of light in the distance for a while and then it's just an aircraft
carrier all of a sudden as we're landing on it.
But you know, how do you do it?
You have to, it's so difficult because imagine if you were driving a car at about 170 miles
an hour and, you know, three dimensionally, a car is kind of easy because you can only
go two ways really, but you need to drive this car within a one foot, one foot box or
fly your head through a one foot by one foot box while you're in the cockpit going over
the aircraft carrier at a particular plane.
Your head needs to go through that one foot by one foot box in order to catch a three
wire on a perfect pass essentially.
So 170 miles an hour, you're constantly making corrections to the right because the aircraft
carrier is an angled deck and so it's slightly moving to the right.
So as you come down, you're making these little corrections, looking to fly your head kind
of on that curve, you know, you're kind of curving down a little bit to fly your head
through that, that box.
And that's, that's essentially a perfect pass.
Wow, man.
It can be tough.
And there's a lot of risk there.
Flying a perfect pass is not what we teach.
We don't want people to fly a perfect pass.
We want them to fly a slightly high pass because that's, that's safer.
Because if you're flying a perfect pass, any, any descent is going to put you below glide
slope and that's, that's where it's dangerous.
Have you ever failed in doing that or have you, was every, every single landing kind
of flawless?
Oh, no, definitely not flawless, but fail now I'm still here.
So right.
But I'm sure not every, every failed attempt would be fatal, would it?
No.
So when we come in, well, I want to call it a failure, not the trap.
So sometimes you do everything right and you just don't trap.
So what we do when we come down is we immediately put our speed brakes in, which kind of slows
us down and we bring the throttles all the way up as soon as we touch down, we rotate.
So it's almost as if, if we didn't catch the wire, we're just bouncing off the deck, which
is exactly what we do.
If we do catch the wire, then it stops us there.
And so if we miss it, we just outs up and go and do it again.
I don't know if I call that a failure per se, but that's kind of the, you know, the
negative, the negative example of a pass that doesn't involve a crash.
Right.
That would be the best case scenario other than catching the hook on the wire.
Pretty much.
Yeah.
The worst thing you'd want to do is clip the edge of the ship and take off your landing
gear.
What's the worst thing you ever saw on the aircraft carrier like that, like with a landing
gone wrong?
I've seen a tail hook hit the back of the boat.
It's called a ramp strike, but it wasn't too bad.
It didn't explode, which was nice.
I mean, because sometimes the hook, it hits the back of the carrier and the metal shrapnel
goes everywhere.
But that didn't happen.
My buddy ejected off the front of the cat, it wasn't a landing, but he ingested foreign
object debris or FOD during the cat shot, which took out one of his engines.
And there was a subsequent issue with the other engine as well.
They ended up ejecting shortly off the front of the boat.
Really?
They were pretty low too.
His WIZO weapon system officer in the back seat got pretty messed up, broke his back
in several spots and you know, X, Y, and Z. He's actually flying again.
I think he either was or is the commanding officer at XO of the Blue Angels now, actually.
Wow.
How rare is it for someone to eject, especially during training?
I don't know the numbers, but I'm sure there's a number calculated in hours of flight time.
I've witnessed, I think, five ejections?
You've witnessed five ejections?
I've flown over two of them.
The fireball is in the jet.
What?
Is this during combat missions?
No, these are all training.
These are all training?
Training is much more dangerous in combat typically.
But you yourself, you've never had to eject?
No.
Nope.
I don't think I would have survived my back.
It would have got messed up.
What are these guys?
Did you ever talk to these guys after they ejected?
I was responsible for investigating some of these mishaps, so I had to interview these
guys.
Really?
What do they say?
What is that experience like?
It's a lot, you know?
For some guys, I think it kind of depends.
In movies, they kind of gloss over it.
It seems like something that, when they do it in movies, it seems like the guys are always
good to go.
Especially the recent Top Gun.
What is he going, like, 10 Mach and then he just walks into a diner?
We should all be so lucky.
But no, I've seen varying degrees of response.
Some younger guys are easy and happy to just brush it off and go back up.
Other guys that have families and stuff, it can really shake them.
These guys are getting almost as close to death as you can get and still surviving some
of these times.
One of the cases I'm thinking about, they basically ejected at the ejection window.
Basically 135 degrees down, about 400 feet up from the ground.
They were really ejecting into the ground.
And luckily they came out and they were able to swing at least once before they hit.
And they were fine.
But they had varying responses to how that kind of made them feel in their comfort level.
And they even trained me to be an aviation safety officer.
They sent me down to their Naval Aviation Safety School for about five weeks.
And that was my job.
That was one of my collateral jobs as a pilot.
For when someone goes down, I go out there and I figure it out.
I clean the pieces up and figure out what happened and publish a report and then go
into the manuals and try to make it so it doesn't happen again.
We had to do that a number of times.
Every time there's a mishap, that's what happens.
And that's why we say our pocket checklists are typically written in blood because we
usually fix the problems afterwards.
And I've seen that lesson over and over again and I can't say for certain, but perhaps
that was part of my motivation to kind of speak up about the UAP topic because it was
just a matter of time before someone just slammed into one of these objects and we lost
aircrew.
Yeah.
So when was the first time you experienced one of these objects, the first time that
you noticed one of these things?
Can you explain what was happening before you saw them and then what was happening after
you saw them?
From what I understand, you had some new equipment.
So we got back from our deployment on the USS Enterprise in 2012.
We entered what's called a maintenance phase where essentially we kind of give our good
jets to the forward deployed squadrons and we cannibalize some jets and we fix some stuff.
And our jets just so happened to be ready to be upgraded to a better radar.
Had the cooling systems already installed in X, Y, and Z.
And so eventually we upgraded.
And as soon as we upgraded, we started noticing objects on our radar that we hadn't seen without
that upgrade.
And so we went from flying around with our APG-73 radar and we see our little sweep,
right?
Just like a radar you see in a movie.
APG-73 you call it?
Yeah, APG-73.
Okay.
And it's kind of like a...
And is this the thing like the clock that goes around in a circle?
Kind of, but we see it kind of just like as a box with a line.
Box with a line.
And so what do we see?
We basically just see like a little icon, a little blip and it tells us the speed and
various kinematics about it.
And that's what we would expect to see.
We weren't seeing anything on the APG-73.
We upgraded our radars to the APG-79, big jump, kind of like mechanical to digital in
a sense.
Much better, stronger, more powerful, see farther, all that stuff.
And we'd go out there and we'd see objects.
We'd see things on the radar.
And it's like, okay, well, does my wingman see this?
No, he has a different radar.
So we kind of just thought it was some kind of error at first.
We were seeing objects on our radar that weren't there with the other one.
It was just a natural assumption.
They were vulnerable, not vulnerable, but they were prone.
There was all those errors that are involved in things like this.
And so we thought maybe some of those had carried over.
But long story short, we eventually got close enough to see these not only with the radar,
but also with the camera system that's on the jet, the FLIR.
And so that kind of tucks in on our cheek pad here.
Whenever we look at stuff on the radar, all our sensors go to that spot.
And so as people were kind of noticing these and taking locks on them and our sensors would
go over, eventually people were close enough to see that there was IR energy coming from
those spots as well.
What kind of energy?
Infrared energy.
Okay.
So our camera system, the FLIR, shows us either just like a camera view or IR energy, heat
energy.
And so that's what you see on, say, the gimbal video, that black and white.
He's able to switch it from black to white, right?
You can switch it from black hot to white hot, which means the white is the hot that
you see on the screen or black, just changing the contrast.
Or you can go to like a full color mode, which is TV, you know, it doesn't show you heat,
but it shows you what you'd look through on a camera.
We typically fly with IR because you can see better, you can see further, it's more prominent.
And yeah, we were seeing IR energy come from these spots where radar was dropping us off
essentially.
And so at this point, we had to conclude that there was physically something there and we
had to at least respect it as aviators and not, you know, get too close to these objects
or just ignore them and fly around them because we thought they were clutter.
Yeah, at this point, you know, we were confident they were physical, though we didn't know
the origins or even that it was overly remarkable.
What do you mean confident they were physical?
What does that mean?
That if we were to fly through the spot that we, our radar was showing us, there was something
that we could damage our aircraft.
Okay.
Generally speaking, right?
What are the possibilities of if it wasn't something physical, what would show up on
the radar that wasn't physical?
Well, there could be energy in that spot.
There are, I believe plasmas can be captured on a radar and other things you can have extremely
thick clouds can return radar signals in the AVG-73.
And so even like temperature inversions where the air is extra thick with the older systems
could potentially show you radar track files.
So that was our initial assumption that there were some strange things like that.
But now to have energy coming from that spot in the sky as well in a very precise manner,
as if someone was shining an IR flashlight at us, we had to make the assumption that
they were physical at that point just for safety of flight.
This episode of the podcast is brought to you by Hostage Tape.
Nobody wants to be a mouth breather, but the truth is 25 to 50% of the population habitually
breathes through their mouths.
I like many people learned about the importance of nasal breathing when I first read James
Nestor's book.
And I have actually been sleeping with my mouth hole taped shut for the past two years.
And the problem isn't just snoring and sleep apnea.
There is tons of science behind how mouth breathing actually is responsible for an array
of neurological, respiratory, and even metabolic problems in humans.
The nose not only filters bacteria in the air, it humidifies it, it removes particulates
in the air and gives you a huge release of nitric oxide, which is extremely effective
in fighting off pathogens and viruses.
Now I've tried probably close to a dozen different brands of mouth tapes from Amazon and they
all suck.
Hostage Tape is the king of mouth tapes.
It's perfect.
It sticks perfectly.
Even if you have a beard and it's easy to get off, you just put it here.
I'll show you.
Just like this comes off easily, doesn't chap your lips when it comes off, head on over
to hostagetape.com forward slash concrete to get your year supply of hostage tape for
a $150 discount, which equals like 55 cents a day to sleep better and be healthier.
That's hostagetape.com forward slash K-O-N-C-R-E-T-E.
It's linked below back to the show.
When you saw these things, you mentioned you were flying with a wingman.
What does that mean when you're flying with a wing?
That's not the whizzo.
That's not the person in the cockpit with you, right?
Nope.
We'll have one person in the back seat called a weapon system officer, and then if we have
a wingman with us, if we're a section, that's two aircraft, lead, kind of trail like this,
flying formation like that, and we'll go do our mission.
Once we get out there, maybe we'll break up, maybe we'll be fighting against each other.
Maybe we'll fly around as pairs and drop bombs.
There's a million things we could do, but we'll fly out there in close formation.
Once we get into the areas, we'll do our stuff and then we'll join back up and fly back as
a pair.
Is that typically how all missions are carried out with multiple jets flying in formations
and planned attacks like that?
Is there ever a solo jet flying?
There is.
There is all the time, but I would say it's just as common to go out in two.
We pretty much ... It's just one of those things you might just go out by yourself,
but there's plenty of two sections or singles or even four aircraft in what we call a division.
Just all of the above, frankly.
What is it like to ... Sorry, I'm going off on a bunch of different things, but flying
in formation, how hard is that to learn?
That's like flying at the boat.
That's what I would tell the students because I had to teach them that as well.
It's the same power motions when you do that as when you land at the boat because when
you're on the boat, you have to ride a glide slope.
If I add power, I'm going to start going above that glide slope.
If I just keep the power there, I'm going to keep going.
That's to make what's called three-point power corrections.
I have to add power, get myself going in the right direction, pull it back to de-accelerate,
then re-add power a little bit less to stabilize on that new higher glide slope.
Every time I have to make an adjustment, it requires three power corrections every time.
When you're flying the ball, boat, you're doing this the whole way down, just very,
very small.
Actually, we'll leave our pinky up like this on the rail too so we can have a reference
point where we are.
Wow.
When you get close, you'll be just doing it fingered.
Now, I'm moving the two throttles just with your fingers and using that as a reference
point, essentially.
When you're flying formation, same thing.
Pinky up there.
Now, instead of your reference being the glide slope, your reference is the other aircraft.
If I am falling behind, I have to add power to stop that de-acceleration so I can catch
back up.
Then, I have to take power off to de-accelerate and then add a little bit back to stabilize
where I am in that relative position, so three-point power corrections all day long.
If you're in perfectly clear skies, you might go out to a mile and do that in a transit
position where it's much easier and the small mistakes, it's not dangerous to look away
for a second.
If you're in bad weather, man, you're going to be a few feet away, potentially for hours.
Hours?
Oh, gosh, yeah.
It's painful.
It's going to be very painful.
Holy shit, man.
My first flight into Iraq, I was on day one missions when our squadron got there.
I was one of the senior lieutenants in the air rank at the time and only one in our squadron
lieutenant anyways that had been on a prior combat deployment.
I got to go in on day one and we had to go through a damn thunderstorm and not only that,
but we had to tank in it.
We were all running out of gas, we were in a thunderstorm, the tanker is there.
You're free-fueling in the air?
Oh, yeah.
In a thunderstorm?
Yeah.
The very first guy, he could not get in the basket.
He couldn't get in.
He was getting frustrated, he ended up going below his bingo number, which means he should
have already diverted, which is not good, day one, we don't necessarily have bases set
up, things of that nature.
But anyway, long story short, he ended up getting in and just how it is, it's just something
to deal with all the time when you're flying, you never know what you're going to get.
Back to where we were, first time you saw one of these objects, you guys were flying
in formation doing a training day.
What was the weather like that day?
Well, let me correct you a little bit.
It's hard for me to say what the first time was, because we were seeing his radar, it
never was like, okay, we're seeing them, we didn't quite realize they were real, and then
they're on the FLIR.
But then we did see them with our eyeballs.
So this wasn't just like the first time it happened, it wasn't just like this unbelievable
experience?
No, it was just kind of like, ugh, you know, something's messed up, right?
The radar's messed up.
And then when we're seeing energy, it's like, okay, our curiosity is peaking a little bit,
but you know, your drive to survive and do what you're doing out there takes precedence
over a lot of things.
This is 2014?
Yep.
But we were getting more curious as we were seeing them more.
And then eventually, one of my squadron mates, well, four of them, but one saw it, they were
flying out in a section.
So two aircraft, four people, again, in this kind of formation, flying out to the working
areas.
And there's a single spot in the sky where all the traffic going in to those working
areas goes through.
Cap point?
Not a cap point, just an entry point.
An entry point.
Okay.
What is the...
Difference?
Yeah.
Well, what, yeah, definitely.
What is the difference?
But what is the reason for that?
So a cap point is a, is kind of a tactical term that we use as a combat air patrol holding
position when we're looking for a line of defense against enemies.
We might be holding at that cap point such that we give a command to push and now we're
attacking enemies.
An entry point is just the administrative point in the sky that we all agree upon that
is the safest way to enter an area.
For entering only?
Yes.
And there's a separate spot for exiting?
Same spot, thousand feet below.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
All right.
And so it's one of the busiest places, you know, on East Coast probably for air traffic.
And so they...
How far offshore?
Ten miles.
Okay.
Yep.
Like maybe 12...
I forget.
Maybe it's like 18 or 19,000 feet, I can't remember.
Maybe 12 actually.
It's been a while.
But either way, you know, it's not like at 2,000 feet.
You're not going to be seeing Cessna's up there very often either way.
They were flying in that formation and right at the entry point, one of these objects went
right between their aircraft, closer towards the lead side.
The lead aircrew saw it, the aircrew and the other aircraft did not, which is not surprising
because you're so focused in on flying formation, you're not, you don't have much of a scan
going on.
You're not taking in the scenery.
No.
But lead does.
And lead did see the object.
And...
Who?
The lead aircraft.
Okay.
Yeah.
And they...
He just described it as a dark gray cube or black cube inside a clear sphere.
That's the description.
And it went in between their aircraft, but I'd be careful when I say that because we
don't know whether it was moving or not necessarily, right?
I don't believe he had it on the radar.
If he did, I don't think he would have flown through it because we knew they were physical
at this point.
Right.
I also just can't remember whether he had a radar or not, but my assumption is he did
not.
They ended up turning around and coming home after that.
They didn't trust their radar anymore, right?
And they're going to do a combat mission, or not combat mission, but you know, like
a dog fighting training set, something that requires a radar.
So if you're not even seeing objects and it was hitting them, it's time to come home.
Right.
But he came back and, you know, he had all the gear on the ready room and he was describing
what he saw, just as I just described it.
And you know, he's just like, I don't see one of those fucking things, you know, because
we were all very familiar.
We didn't have a name for them or anything, but we all were aware of them that they were
a potential safety issue and, you know, but no one had seen one with a naked eye.
Not yet.
Not until this point.
So now, of course, now we're all like, well, this is getting weird, right?
Maybe there's some kind of weird drone thing or X, Y or Z.
I mean, he didn't describe any propulsion.
There's no obvious lifting services, but hey, that's what he saw.
So we're kind of thinking it was a drone at this point or something.
So we submitted a safety report, a hazard report, which is something you submit when
there's a chance of a mishap in the future.
Like maybe you got lucky this time, but next time you might not be so lucky.
And this is a good example of that.
And so we submitted out and, you know, we were thinking, hey, maybe this is someone's
classified drone program.
Maybe this is, who knows what, but maybe by submitting this report, they'll get the message
that, you know, they're stepping out of their lane here and creating a safety hazard.
They, right, we assumed it was some classified program at this point.
Of course, nothing actually happened.
I forget the total number of reports that are related to UAP off the East Coast in that
period, somewhere around eight or 10, I think.
So it wasn't just our squadron, it was other squadrons that had this type of radar.
And you know, over the course of time, we weren't necessarily going out and, you know,
interviewing people or taking any type of data sets.
But generally speaking, whenever we talked to, whenever I talked to anyone on the East
Coast that was a pilot that had a sufficiently powerful enough radar and they had seen the
objects, they described it the same way, cube and the sphere.
Really?
Which is very unique compared to what Commander Fravor talked about.
He talked about like a tic-tac object that was not even close to what you guys saw on
the East Coast.
Yeah.
I don't think there's gonna be just one answer for this whole thing.
But so there's no, so if I can recall, Commander Fravor talks about sort of trying to chase
this thing, right?
He was trying to chase it and the thing was mimicking him or mirroring his movements.
And then he talks about the thing showing up at his cap point before he even knew where
his cap point was.
He knew where his cap point was, I believe.
He probably had it written down, but he hadn't been there.
Right.
From what I can deduce from what he said, he wasn't sure where, like he didn't even
know where he was gonna be prior to where, like there was no way maybe the object knew
where he was gonna be before he got there.
Yeah, it's kind of like one of those things where you have like a bunch of waypoints and
you're like, I know I need to be at waypoint nine, but I have no idea where it is.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Right, right.
He clicked over like, hey, is that your cap point?
You know, it's like, oh shit.
The guy who saw it with his naked eye and you guys were in the ready room and he was
describing that, who else was there and what was like, could you read the room?
What did you take in from the other people that were there and what was their reaction
to it?
Kind of had a similar reaction to the look that everyone had on their faces when we watched
the Goodwill video.
It wasn't the same people, but kind of had that like looking around with a dumb look
on everyone's face, like what the fuck?
I mean, the commanding officer of our squadron was there, four or five lieutenants like myself,
the duty officer who is always there, is always someone at the desk and he's the one on the
radio with the planes, welcome back and troubleshooting and stuff, dealing with issues of the day,
which this was.
And yeah, everyone's kind of like, I was hit with one of those things and it's like, well,
what are we gonna do now?
And the answer was to talk to the safety officer and submit a hazard report.
Eventually, the hazard report, of course, didn't change anything, it's more of a data
collection mechanism than a proactive prevention mechanism, aviation and safety.
Like I said, a lot of our procedures are written in blood, but yeah, sorry, I forgot where
I was going with that.
Did you ever see one of these things with your own eyes?
No, I didn't.
I looked, what would happen is crazy and I talked, again, when I didn't talk to people
that had seen it, almost all the others had seen it, but not physically seen it, but seen
on the radar or had tried to see it but couldn't, much like myself.
And so what that looks like is, okay, we have something on a radar, maybe it's 20 miles
away or some distance, not within visual range.
As you get closer, you start to pick it up on your FLIR, you dial in your course and
you're trying to have a 500-foot pass with it.
All your sensors are slewed, your radar is looking at it, your camera is looking at it,
your weapon system cameras and sensors that are on your weapon, individual weapons are
now all looking at it.
All that information is getting pumped into my helmet and so when I look out, I can see
a box around where I should be looking and I look back at my radar and yes, I still have
the object locked and it's right in front of me and I look over at the FLIR and yes,
I can still see the energy coming out of that piece of the sky, very precisely.
And then my sensors are telling me where to look and we fly right by it within a few
feet or a few hundred feet and I just can't see anything.
And you don't see anything.
But then it's still on the FLIR, it's still on the radar.
What is going through your mind when you see it on every single one of your instruments
but you can't see it with your bare eyes, your naked eye?
You know, I don't know.
We didn't make anything of it in a sense.
You think it was like something's fishy with the radar, something's wonky with the mechanical
instruments?
At this point, it's inconceivable to us that our radar and FLIR and visuals would potentially
be  now, not for everyone, right?
Not everyone, but for the cases that we did see objects, to be able to fool all three
of those is interesting.
Now, what you can do is you can say, okay, well, perhaps some were physical and some
were not, right?
That's one way you could go down this and bottom line is we just don't have the data
for that, right?
To say whether every object represented a physical object or there were only some physical
objects and the others were not physical.
We just don't have enough data to kind of make that assumption, but when you're flying
around out there, you have to make the assumption that they're all physical.
Right.
And how long did it take before people on the boat, when you guys got back and did debriefs
or went over  how many of these reports were there before things started to change?
Or did things ever change?
I don't know how many reports there were.
There were about, I think, eight or so hazard reports that were submitted to the Aviation
Safety Center that were specifically referencing objects that were, I don't want to say unexplainable,
but not identified as drones or anything else.
There's a lot of others that indicate it's a drone, but what else are you going to call
it, right?
But I don't know how many because we weren't really tracking it, right?
And so then what did change, essentially, to answer your question, eventually the Navy
implemented a reporting process through the UAP Task Force where they were mandating,
I believe, naval aviators submit reports upon landing of any objects that they witnessed.
And it didn't go through the Naval Aviation Safety Reporting Method.
It went to the UAP Task Force.
And so that is what changed.
I don't know how many incidents there were before that, but the UAP Task Force report
and now the ODNI report that came out shows that it's happening quite often.
You spoke about, I forget which podcast it was, but you spoke about a moment when you
were in the room and there was a senior officer, like a top guy who was reviewing it, and then
he looked at it and he's like, mm-hmm, and he turned around and walked away.
What was that?
So everything we've talked up to this point has been off the east coast of Virginia Beach
with no aircraft carrier involved.
In 2015, we started to prepare for our workups, or actually it was 2014, but it was right
at the change of the year.
But we left essentially on aircraft carrier to essentially get ready for war.
It's called a workup cycle.
We spent months on the boat and we basically do all that training from the boat just to
practice like we play.
And while we were off the coast of Jacksonville, Florida, that's when we filmed the gimbal
video that people are familiar with.
And so yeah, it's pretty intense.
And there's actually bases on the coast where they have called Red Air, contract Red Air
essentially where they come out and test us, right?
So they'll, day and night, they'll come out and fly out and try to like penetration test
the carrier, right?
While we're doing missions.
We might be on like a training mission and then we might need to break off of that because
we're going to intercept some other Red Air fighters that have been launched off the coast
to test whether we can intercept them before they get within weapons range of the boat
or things of that nature, right?
So it's kind of, I mean, in one sense, it's awesome fun, right?
I mean, you're out there sipping around, intercepting aircraft as they try to break their way into
the carrier.
So it's kind of like...
Where are these guys coming from?
Various bases off the East coast near Jacksonville.
I forget where they are, but they just buzz right out there and they're essentially targets
for us.
And we do that for our air to air training as well.
But anyways, we were doing an air to air mission out there.
This is actually, well, interesting little tidbit.
I'll get to that after.
No, please.
Right after I tell the gimbal story, I'll tell you this little piece that doesn't get
talked about much, but yeah, we'd gone out doing an air to air mission, the air crew
that filmed the gimbal essentially started coming back to the boat after they had run
out of gas or waiting to land.
You don't like just come back and land, you have to wait for the deck to open up.
So what that means is you essentially have to just slow down and do what's called like
a max endurance profile, fly at a certain airspeed that maximizes your time airborne
versus being an afterburner in a dogfight.
That burns the least amount of fuel.
Yeah.
So if you're in like some dogfight training mission in the boat, you're eventually going
to hit a fuel number and you bring your throttle back and you essentially just hang out.
You're done being tactical at that point.
And so that's the position they were in.
They were coming back and they ended up seeing these radar contacts on their radar and they
initially thought it was a penetration test as I had talked about.
So they went over to intercept the aircraft and they were looking on the radar and all
that, but the kind of mechanics of it didn't really jive with what they would expect to
see.
It's too slow and performing turns that they wouldn't expect to see.
Long story short, they essentially went to stern convert the object, which what that
means is you essentially want to, if the object's just flying around, you're in any position,
you want it to kind of arrive in a position like this, stern convert.
And so what that really looks like in real life, usually you're like 10 miles apart.
You make this big arcing turn, kind of come in like that.
So generally that's what they were doing as they were trying to get closer to the objects.
What they saw on the radar was one object and then nearby were about five other objects
that were flying in like a wedge formation.
And so the wedge essentially proceeded along more or less a straight line and then kind
of got jumbled up and did a very tight turn essentially and started proceeding in the
opposite direction.
These objects that are in formation is my assumption that they were the object we were
seeing off the East coast on a regular basis.
And I say that because they appeared on the radar similarly as what we were seeing on
the East coast.
There are ways that we could identify it, such as the way the objects kind of like skipped
around a bit with what we were seeing on the radar.
It wasn't like a perfectly clear radar representation.
It would kind of skip around as if it couldn't really tell exactly which direction it was
going, even though it was showing it moving in a consistent manner, which is confusing.
But that's how we were able to identify them on the radar.
And these look similar.
So it's an assumption that they were the same.
However, the gimbal object we had not seen before, that was kind of located below the
objects, I'll say, or maybe to the south, if we assume up is north, but they're kind
of like below the wedge and falling in the same direction, just slightly behind.
And when the wedge made that turn and then rolled out in the opposite direction back
in formation, the gimbal object just kind of went, it just kind of was going one direction
and appeared from a God's eye view, and it just started going in the other direction
with no radius of turn.
That gimbal video was from a God's eye view?
No.
Okay.
But what I saw on the situational awareness page, you hear the pilots referencing, that's
a God's eye view.
And so that screen, typically between our legs, we have one screen here, screen here,
screen here.
So typically we keep the SA page down here, and then we'll have our radar here, or our
FLIR, and a different type of radar over here.
And so the SA page takes all of our sensors and has a fused image.
It's a God's eye view, 360 degrees around our aircraft, the aircraft in the middle,
with color maps and all this stuff.
So that's kind of like the conglomerator of all the data.
Right.
Okay.
That makes sense.
And that's a God's eye view.
The thing's here, and then the other thing you can pull down here, these turn, and then
this just kind of, with no radius of turn, just start going in the other direction from
a God's eye view.
What that turned out to be, it seems, upon further analysis, was that the object did
with a vertical turn, essentially like a vertical J-hook, whereas if you're looking from a God's
eye view-
So like that?
Yeah.
in like a few hundred feet, the reverse direction.
Which is not something you see a fighter jet do.
No, certainly not.
It takes almost a mile for a fighter jet to turn.
But I don't think this was fighter jet size, per se, it was smaller.
And I say that because our velocity vector, which is in the HUD, but also gets transcribed
onto the FLIR, that's set to a size.
And we can set that in our jet so that if we're in a dogfight and the wings of the aircraft
in front of us in our HUD are equal to the size of that velocity vector, it gives us
a rough estimate of the distance of the aircraft.
And so if I look at that velocity vector and we're 10 miles away and that object is half
the size of that velocity vector, it gives me a rough estimate of the size.
And I don't know what they necessarily have it set to, so I can't necessarily make a judgment
on the size.
However, if it was set to standard, I don't have a number, but looking at it, it would
be smaller than an F-18 based on its relative size to the velocity vector.
Smaller than an F-18.
How long is an F-18?
Oh, shit.
Put me on that.
That's something you should know, right?
Yeah, 30 feet, 35 feet, something like that.
35 feet long, and the wingspan, roughly-
28.
We're going to have to cut this part because I'm probably wrong.
Maybe you can find that.
We've pride ourselves in not doing stuff that doesn't affect us in combat.
56 feet?
Ah, man.
Wow.
That's big.
No, that's the Hornet.
So the Super Hornet is twice the size.
Not necessarily length, but it's a big aircraft.
60 feet.
Yep.
That was way wrong.
Whoa.
So that's what you were flying?
Yep.
The Super Hornet.
Find some better images of this thing.
It's 33% larger overall, carry different engines, electronics, and all that.
Carry lots of weapons.
Wow.
That's incredible, man.
So yeah, anyways-
Look at that one.
Look at all the bombs on the bottom of that one.
The one in the middle?
Yeah, right there.
Jeez, that thing is loaded.
What?
It's an Argum ER, advanced anti-radiation guided missile, extra range, Argum ER.
So that is something that you would shoot, and that's actually not an F-18 right there.
Oh, it's not?
No.
That is actually a growler.
A growler.
Yeah.
And actually, well, I'll tell you what, that's actually probably a test one.
What is the sickest jet that exists?
Oh, man.
I hate this question.
I'm partial to the F-35 because it's just the right aircraft for the digital environment
that they need to operate in.
We talked about flying and operating a weapon.
That's a 36.
Yeah, I don't think a 36 exists.
Okay, this is a 35.
Yeah.
I mean, the F-22 is a great jet as well.
I mean, the F-22-
Wow.
That thing looks pretty cool.
It's like very stealth looking.
It is a stealth aircraft.
That's a gen five stealth aircraft that's designed for penetration.
Okay.
Like basically every fifth generation fighter is nowadays.
That has pluses and minuses.
For example, the F-22, fantastic aircraft, lots of thrust, ability to operate high and
fast, all the good stuff, and it's stealthy, and all its weapons are carried internally.
But that also means the sensors on those weapons can't look out either.
What does that mean?
The sensors on the weapons can't look out?
You build weapons, say there's one called the AIM-9X, which is an IR seeking missile,
which we use to employ it in close range.
It could also be used for, let's consider high off-boresight shots.
That sensor needs to be able to kind of almost look behind you in a sense to find that guy.
If your weapons are loaded internally to your bay, it doesn't have the ability to do that.
Right?
So there's some interesting problems.
I know they've worked through them at this point to some degree so that those aren't
as much of an issue, but no fighter is perfect is the point, and they're built for different
things.
The F-22 is no different, and the F-35 is no different.
Very different aircraft, but both applicable in the modern warfare.
Yeah.
You know, it's funny, isn't it true that when the first, I forget the name of it, but the
first, that big triangular black stealth bomber came out.
There was, I think the government was going along with stories that it was UFO.
They were trying to push the fact that it was a conspiracy because they hadn't officially
announced it yet.
So this is the gimbal video, right?
So this is the object we were seeing next to the five other objects.
Okay.
Yeah.
Let's go ahead and roll it.
These are friends of yours.
It was so weird when I was, I'll tell you a sec.
Yeah, one of them was at my wedding party.
Really?
I won't say which one, but one of them I spent most of my career with.
We went through training together in the fleet replacement squadron when we first met.
So we were like in a five person class together.
We trained together and he ended up going on the boat with me.
He was like my whizzo, not my whizzo, but he was the whiz on the back seat.
We went to do our night landing for the very first time.
Oh really?
And it was his first time landing on a boat because the whizzos don't do that until later.
But the pilots get day traps when they're in the advanced strike fighter training.
So with the whizzo, they don't do the landing though, right?
They don't.
Right.
But it's still like, this is like now they're like with another student, right?
And this might the student's first time landing on a boat and now he's in the back seat.
You know what I mean?
So it's kind of like this big trust thing in a way.
It's like, all right, saddle up.
You know, here's a guy who's never been in a boat before doing it by himself and you're
sitting in the back.
Oh God.
Right?
So I imagine it's a little nerve wracking.
They don't have a stick.
I mean, they're not pilots.
Right.
They're just holding their breath.
Yeah.
So we did this.
We did this together and it was an interesting story.
Hey, I know that guy.
We live two guys.
Yeah.
So we were going to do our first night trap together and the way we do that is we hold
way back behind the boat up high and we actually, when it's our time plus or minus three seconds
of our push time, we have to be at a particular point in the sky.
As soon as we hit that, a certain airspeed would go down eight degrees nose down, 250
knots, which is pretty aggressive.
That's like, I'm pretty sure that's aerobatic flight in a Cessna theoretically, but in effect
it's no big deal.
We're coming down and then at about 5,000 feet, we arrest our descent from eight degrees
nose down to four degrees nose down.
Because there's something called the minute deliverable.
If we're descending at that eight degrees nose down, our rate of descent is greater
than how much altitude we have left in one minute if we were to continue doing that.
So you're going to die in one minute if you don't change something here.
So that's why we bring it up a little bit.
So what happened was as we were kind of approaching that altitude where we start to roll out,
we're down eight degrees, everything's steady.
That's all good.
But as soon as we start pulling essentially, our mission computer is inside the jet, failed.
And they started resetting.
So what that led to was all of our displays going blank and resetting.
So not only, now this is night landing, so there are no external lights, I have no navigation,
the jet's still flyable, I just can't see where I am.
And this is just as I start to pull up, which means I've lost my equilibrium.
So I'm pulling at one G, which means it feels like I'm sitting in a chair, but I could be
upside down, I could be sideways, I could be inverted about to hit the water, it just
feels like I'm sitting in my chair, it's no different.
And that's what's so terrifying.
The mission computers reset, we're pulling up, they come back and we find ourselves somewhere
like this, and then they go out again.
So now I'm like, fuck me, and I'm not waiting for the reset, now I'm looking for my flashlight.
So I can at least turn it on and shine it at my backup instruments, because there's
no real lights on those either.
And so I'm trying to do that while I'm fiddling with that, essentially trying to somehow keep
the plane upright, because there's a layer, overcast layer at 8,000 feet, which means
there is zero light.
If there's just no moon and just sunlight, that's cool.
You can see the waves, you can see the ground, but when there's an overcast, like 8,000,
you might as well have your eyes closed, you just can't tell.
What is this?
What is it?
Night landing?
Oh, this is a night landing.
Yeah, I have a video just like this.
What are we even looking at right now?
This is a tiny, looks like, oh, it's the aircraft carrier.
There it is.
Wow.
So that's, I mean, see how it's like black up there?
That's what it looks like if you have that overcast layer, you literally can't see anything.
So you're basically surrounded in blackness, and you lost all your, all your...
It's like I just went blind.
Everything went gone, and you pull out your flashlight in the cockpit and you're shining
it on your back of the instruments.
I'm trying to at this point, yeah.
I'm like trying to get it out because it's strapped right here, and I'm like, I'll just
tilt it down, turn it on, and then it'll be like, I don't want to hold it.
Meanwhile, you don't know if you're about to hit the water, hit the, are you above the
water?
You're above the...
Yeah, it's all ocean below us.
We can't see it, like I said, because of that overcast layer.
So yeah, it was just like, man, we ended up, you know, the mission computers were rebooting
again.
The rebooting is staying up that time.
We were somewhere like this, you know, kind of just floating there around like 3,500 feet
or so as we were kind of coming down like this, just slicing down like this more or
less, you know?
Oh my God.
And so again, we had a minute.
It takes about 10 or 15 seconds to reboot.
What is the protocol?
What if your instruments don't come back online?
What is the, what are you supposed to do?
Go to my standby instruments, yeah, and then fly that back, essentially.
So at this point, we declared an emergency.
We were probably about four miles, five miles from, like two miles from actually like being
on the path.
You know what I mean?
Like being in that image where you like see the runway and there's a lens over there.
So we declared an emergency and that was the easiest landing.
I thought it was going to be very difficult and stressful to land at the boat for the
first time.
But as soon as I saw the landing lens in the runway, essentially the boat, I was like,
wow, you know, at least I won't hit the ground because I know where it is now.
And so everything else was just easy because I was just happy to be able to see, you know,
see the ground essentially if it went out again.
Wow, that's terrifying, man.
So anyways, we did that together and then we ended up going to the boat and I was taught
my class on the boat.
They sent me priority alpha, which means I was deployable to, or I was, I could be sent
to a forward deploy squadron just because my grades were high and then I did well enough.
And so about two weeks after I finished that training, I was sent out to the USS Enterprise
and I flew my first combat mission about a week after that.
And the gentleman I was just talking about, he actually got assigned to the same squadron.
So then we hung out for the next three years, we did specialized training together.
And then when I left, he left too, and he actually transitioned to be a pilot.
And so he actually ended up in Meridian, Mississippi when I was an instructor there as well.
No way.
So we pretty much spent our whole career together.
That's incredible.
Pretty cool.
So this, that gimbal video that we just watched, it was only 35 seconds long.
It was much longer than that though, right?
I don't know if I want to say much longer, but it was definitely more there.
Yeah.
Why, why are they only, why do we only get 30 seconds?
I don't know.
Do you have any speculation why?
I mean, there, you mentioned that there was like the wedge shape formation.
Is that a part of this video?
I never saw those on the FLIR, but what I did see them on was the, the essay page.
Okay.
And that was primarily what I was looking on.
And when I did look at the FLIR, basically saw the same image that you saw, plus maybe
a little bit more near the end as the flight mechanics seem to get rockier.
So it kind of, it kept kind of doing that, that motion that you see that kind of seemed
unstable in a sense.
I don't want to put words onto it until it comes out because it has been like six years
for me now since I've seen that video and it hasn't, you know.
Which one is this?
Just the more of the gimbal, essentially.
The full version.
Oh yeah.
So correct me if I'm wrong, but I believe Christopher Mellon was the one who sort of
leaked these videos and is the reason they even came out in the first place back in,
what was the year that first came out in the New York Times?
I think it was 2017.
2017.
That's what it was.
Yeah.
We talked about in James Fox's documentary, The Phenomenon, how there's much more, these
videos are much longer and they're yet to release the full videos for whatever reason.
Do you have any speculation of why they wouldn't release the full videos?
Well I think it depends on your definition.
So full video, the full video has radar data, right?
So the FLIR and the radar and the situational awareness page are recorded at the same time.
Not necessarily those two pages, but the screens that they're displayed on.
So if you have one, you have the other.
So what that means is the situational awareness page with all the radar data, it did exist.
I don't know if it still does exist, but that's what you'd want to see because it has all
the radar, the kinematics, and it's going to show it over the entire course of when
they were detectable, whether they were directly looking at it or not.
So there is much more data to be had even outside of just the video.
What is your buddy, the guy who actually filmed this, the guy who was in your wedding party,
did you guys talk about this often?
Not really, he's still in, he's deployed a lot, he's very busy, so he just heads down.
But no, not really.
I'm eager to engage with him when the time is right.
I know this isn't the time to be distracting him with stuff like this and I'm sure he already
has enough of it from the people inside.
It's no secret who he is within the military just based off the uniqueness of his response
to the video.
Is that the reason that he hasn't gone public about it is because he's still in there and
he just doesn't want to, he doesn't want the attention?
Not even attention.
Legally, he's not allowed to speak about it.
Legally, he's not allowed to.
Do you see any other military people just kind of talking about it?
You?
Yeah, I was almost arrested for that.
Really?
Yeah, that's what I've been told.
So when I did that, I communicated to the best extent I could that I was just communicating
as a private citizen about experiences I had.
The night before I left to go to D.C., I got a call at like 10 p.m. saying that I now had
orders to be there and I needed to be there in my uniform, my whites, essentially, and
I needed to go to the Pentagon before I went to Congress and the Senate, which was not
a great revelation.
So I was scrambling, right?
I was months away from getting out, my uniforms packed up and shipped across the country
at this point.
I wasn't expecting to wear in case someone died or something, really.
So I'm going around to my buddy's houses at midnight, borrowing their uniforms and their
stuff so I could show up because my flight was out like six in the morning the next day.
Oh my gosh.
So it was a bit of a scramble.
I ended up going to the Pentagon into the bowels with some naval intelligence folks,
some who we might be more familiar with nowadays since the public hearings.
Who?
I'm so bad with names.
But we had a conversation about our experiences.
It was nothing nefarious, necessarily.
It was more, I think, wanting to hear from the horse's mouth before him.
I got quite the entourage from there over to the Senate.
There were representatives from the numerous admirals from the Navy and the Pentagon that
accompanied me to that meeting, which included representatives from the executive branch,
Pentagon, Senate, elsewhere.
And essentially, me at a table like this with Pentagon folks on one side and senators and
whatnot and their staffers over here and me at the head of the table.
How old are you at this point?
That's a good question.
How old am I now?
That's a great question.
I was probably 27, 28.
Wow.
Yeah, maybe a little bit older.
What was that like?
What was the conversation like?
What did they seem interested in?
What did you sense the priority was there with them?
They seemed to just want to understand what they were seeing.
So from the Pentagon side, it seemed like they had some understanding that there was
a problem in this regard, but it was classified.
We weren't really able to have too much of an open conversation about it in that environment.
I would say things.
Senators would ask me questions and they'd ask the DOD folks, do you have any comment
on that?
And the answer would be yes, no, or we'll talk about it under a higher classification,
essentially.
They didn't have a lot to add to that conversation on the Pentagon side, but it was clear that
the folks on the Senate side were intrigued and were interested and they seemed to be
asking the right questions.
Of course, at the time, I didn't know where it was going to go.
I said my piece and then just headed back, essentially.
It was maybe an hour maybe conversation, I think.
What were you afraid was going to happen?
Were you afraid that something was going to happen and they were going to get fired or
something?
Yeah, that or Leavenworth, I suppose, but you can't really get fired from the military
per se.
I mean, you can a little bit, but I don't think that was the fear.
What do they say?
I was ignorant of all this kind of drama going on in the background.
That night, I got a call from someone who was in the meeting that we had on the Hill
inquiring whether the Pentagon had intimidated me or whether they had tried to influence
my story or anything of that nature.
There seemed to be somewhat of a distrust between those two.
Wow.
That's very interesting.
What I communicated was that that was not the case.
I did not perceive that.
Well, maybe a little bit.
Well, I imagine that's got to be an intimidating situation for a 27-year-old to be called up
there the next day and sitting down in front of all these people, especially discussing
things.
I mean, it was classified stuff, right?
It was not.
It was not classified.
It was not classified because it wasn't happening, right?
Like this wasn't a thing.
What made you think that you were almost going to be arrested?
What indication did you have of that?
Did they make that clear?
The person that ended up being responsible for giving me the orders came up to me and
told me they did that so I would not be arrested.
That's how I know that.
Wow, man.
Well, that explains why no one else is speaking out about it then.
Again, I wouldn't expect military members to publicly speak to the press about this.
That is, I would suggest, out of bounds, especially now that there is action going on.
There is a proper way to alleviate this through the system.
I didn't have that luxury at the time.
Not only did I not have that luxury, people didn't even think this was a real thing.
So I made a decision I made so that we could prevent someone from getting into a misapprentive
instead of it happening and then us writing our PCL in blood again.
When was the first time you ever spoke to Commander Fravor about this stuff?
I spoke to Commander Fravor the first time I interviewed with the History Channel for
the show Unidentified.
Not the first time, the only time I did.
They introduced me to Dave Pryor and then he was there as well.
I think they were kind of using it as a kind of a comfort thing for me to show that there
was someone else.
I actually had recognized Dave because I hadn't known him personally at all but he was in
a show called Carrier, which is kind of like a documentary of Squadron and he was the commanding
officer of the Squadron at the time Dave was.
So I had seen him actually before I was even a pilot on that show.
Oh really?
It was funny to, you know, and we're friends now.
We talk a lot now.
But yeah, that was the first time I met him.
I know the objects were very different and the stories are very different, but what was
the biggest thing that stuck out to you talking to him?
I don't know if it's the biggest thing, but the thing that kind of seemed similar was
just kind of what the reaction was, right?
How it was just completely laughed off and ignored and trivialized, which always pissed
me off.
Not because, I mean, you know, we all joke and it's fun, that's all good, but you know,
this is directly something that we train for and have a lot of respect for, which is not
only aviation safety hazards in the sky, but tactical threats as well.
We're very well aware that other nations are spying on us, you know, at various times we're
flying out there and this could very easily be an extension in some cases, or it could
be leveraged to be a vulnerability for us if a foreign nation wanted to do so.
And so from my perspective, I just wasn't, I don't approve of the mocking from that angle
because this is exactly what we're trained to do.
A friend of mine, James Fox, he produced the movie, The Phenomenon, I'm sure you're familiar
with it, I don't know if you are or not, but he was very close with Jacques Vallee, who
is one of the, I don't know how close you pay attention, I don't know how close you
pay attention to like the history of UFO sightings and the different documentaries that have
come out about it.
I know Commander Fabric doesn't, I know he's not very interested in UFOs in general, but
James is a big name in like the UFO community as far as investigating the different events
that have happened throughout history of the United States and around the world.
But when he was making that movie, The Phenomenon, he told me before he went to interview Commander
Fravor for the first time, he was working close with Dr. Jacques Vallee and he asked
him if he had any sort of, you know, can you give me any sort of guidance to how I can
approach this guy?
And Jacques Vallee, his question was, I'm very interested in the possibility of them
seeing it, if they ever saw it with the naked eye or not, or if it was only on radar, because
his main concern was holograms in the sky.
So and when he brought this up to Commander Fravor, he was actually kind of like, he almost
stopped the interview because of, he's like, how, you think I'm an idiot?
You think, you think I don't know what DARPA is, you think I know what holograms are, you
don't think I knew what I saw?
He said, he was very like, not happy about that question.
But a lot of people speculate, especially on, depending on where you look online or
wherever, that a lot of these things could potentially be some sort of secret military
technology that is used to confuse enemy radar, like with different holograms or whatever
it may be.
I don't know which part of the military would be responsible for this.
I don't know if it'd be the Navy or the Air Force or whatever.
But are you familiar with this idea?
Yeah.
What are your thoughts on it?
In particular, I even had a guy on here that was a Harvard professor that was contracted
by DARPA.
He was the one who brought this up to me in the first place.
And he claimed, he said to me that these sort of holograms that are designed to distract
enemy radar are a real thing.
Something I've never heard of before.
Yeah, let me just kind of provide some background on what DARPA actually does.
I've worked with DARPA, it'd probably be mad at me, but Dave's worked with DARPA.
He works generally, well, I don't want to say anything more, but DARPA is a very low
technology readiness level organization.
What that means is they work on things that are very low TRL, call that TRL 0, where the
other end of the spectrum would be TRL or technology readiness level 9.
And 9 means that it's a capability that is deployable for testing, essentially, with
operators.
Right?
9.
And so DARPA usually works around the 0 to maybe like doing a little bit more of like
3 or 4 TRL.
So what that means is the technology is not really proven.
If it's a 0, it might be math equations.
And so when people talk about DARPA doing things, DARPA's MO isn't to build an operational
technology and then test it for years.
That's not what they do.
That would be post TRL 9.
That would be another organization, it would be the Navy.
Because they would be the ones, or perhaps another organization, and I don't think there's
a relevant like NSA or CIA, like they could potentially leverage that technology and take
it in.
If we're talking about Nemesis, which is what I understand to be kind of generally speaking,
kind of the holographic EW confusion type technology, it would be the Navy testing it
in our most active training ranges off the East Coast.
That's what that would mean.
It would mean that they were doing it for the better part of a decade and still doing
it.
It would also mean that they're doing it over international waters, which means any country
can go out there and study it.
And it would also mean that we're not testing these things at our billion dollar ranges
that we have out in the Western US that are designed specifically for this type of activity,
such as Navy China Lake or any of these other testing facilities that we have.
Navy China Lake?
Yeah.
It's a weapons testing place that a lot of test pilots go to in the Navy or other places.
It's where we develop weapons, essentially, and test them out.
We get a new bomb sent to China Lake strapped on F-18 of the test pilot and see what happens
when you drop it.
It's an operational test area.
So we have places to test this type of stuff.
So when people talk about these programs like that, that's all well and good.
There's a lot of interesting technology that could be pieced together to provide examples
of how something could be feasible.
If you step away from that and look at the application and the implementation of that
technology, it starts to not make as much sense.
Why would we be testing this for seven, eight, nine years after it's been public in international
waters off the coast, especially when there's safety reports now?
Why would we be testing it for eight to 10 years in international waters?
Like you're saying that we wouldn't typically do it for that long?
No.
That's a whole cycle of development.
Ten years is a long time to be testing a particular piece of technology in a public yet hidden
manner.
So this doesn't directly refute what you're saying, I understand that, but I'm just kind
of providing some context around these systems and why it becomes a little probability.
I think what you said about DARPA is very interesting and a lot of people could gain
some context from that.
So you said you worked with DARPA.
Why would a Navy pilot work with DARPA and what exactly is DARPA for people who don't
know?
Navy pilot, yeah.
So Navy pilot in it, but when I was working at BAA Systems as a technology development
manager, that was my job was essentially to source or create or ideate on technology that
would be relevant to the war fighter in 10 to 15 years that I could essentially pitch
to DARPA and we build it.
And so primarily what I was doing when I was at BAA System was automating my job as a fighter
pilot.
I was working on multi-agent intelligences, right, so autonomous wingman, forward edge
tactical systems such as tactics on weapons or aircraft related to autonomous systems,
the reality of what hypersonic weapons and tactics look like.
So this is all areas I was working in.
Wow.
So and what specifically does DARPA do, what does it stand for?
DARPA is the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency.
Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, okay.
So their charge is to work on technologies that are highly risky, that could fail.
They expect a lot of their projects to fail.
In fact, they call it DARPA hard projects.
Like if you bring a project that's not hard enough, they'll just tell you no, right?
They would prefer to see something that has a lower probability of success, but a greater
reward if it's successful, right?
So that's kind of the regime that they work in.
And they work close with these quote unquote think tanks, correct?
Is that?
I don't know if that's the case or not.
I mean, what is a think tank?
I don't know.
I mean, I'm sure a think tank.
Sounds cool.
Yeah.
I mean, I think tank could potentially just be a group of smart people that bid on a contract
for that DARPA was put out and they have the specialty to win that contract.
But DARPA typically works with big defense corporations, but also with the startup community
in some sense.
The intelligence community essentially has its own version of DARPA that is specific
for intelligence type operations.
DARPA is more military.
But yeah, that's what they do.
So are you aware of anything?
Is there any sort of technology that's utilized with the military to confuse enemy radar like
this though?
Like is there even if there's tons of it, not like this per se, but there's a ton of
that, right?
That falls under general category of electronic warfare or even cyber warfare.
You could consider it that.
I mean, another branch essentially that's being stood up at this point, cyber command,
having an understanding.
The F-35 that I told you about is very much an electronic warfare aircraft.
It soaks everything up.
It can jam.
It can do all sorts of stuff.
When we start talking about, and it's not just us, you know, everyone wants to see how
we can fool the next, the first wave essentially, right?
If we have a World War III with anyone or whatever, there's going to be a lot of jamming
and missiles are going to be falling out of the sky and things of that nature.
And one way to do that is with fooling radars to make them think that there's something
there when there's not.
I don't know why you would then take that and apply that to IR.
I guess there are some reasons.
IR sensors are getting better for combat, I'll say.
There's something called the IRST, and that is essentially an IR targeting pod.
The Russians have been using them for a while, but we didn't quite use them that much because
our radars were better.
They were essentially compensating for a lack of radar technology by having them.
But we're getting IRST now as well.
And so really what that is is a different way of being able to target into these things
at range.
Because if you think of the way Fravor talked about the tic-tac moving, it seemed like he
was basically describing a laser pointer, right?
That's the way those things moved.
If you point it at a wall...
It was moving as if it didn't have mass, I think was the way of describing it.
Light does not really have mass, so a shadow or something that was nonmassive could move
as if it didn't have mass if it wasn't physically real.
So it was nuts and bolts, but it was also psychic, if you will, like knew where he was
going to be, right?
Yeah, I mean, the objects showed up at the cap point.
Is that...
That wouldn't be psychic.
I know sort of the way these things are moving doesn't necessarily jive with general relativity,
right?
These things could be using some sort of propulsion that is gravity, like anti-gravity, or it's
not necessarily like a jet, it's not shooting something out the back to move.
It's somehow manipulating gravity to move like that.
I'll agree that we don't see them spitting stuff out the back, but the mechanism that
they are using, although gravity and space-time metric engineering is a potential option for
that, there I think are others as well.
Really?
Yeah.
So there's...
Well, let me just say this.
Transportation really at the end of the day comes down to energy, right?
If you can put enough energy into one piece, we have the math to build a warp drive or
what have you, engineer space-time metric, warp space-time, which therefore would be
warping gravity and allow you to potentially move super-liminally.
That's one fun theory.
Mass reduction is a technology that has been proposed.
If you are able to reduce the mass of an object, then moving it through the air would be much
more seamless.
Is it warping space-time around it to avoid the friction or is it somehow moving air particles
around it, right?
We just don't know the answer to these questions.
So one of the things I'm doing is trying to get the answers to those.
And the way I'm doing it is through the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics,
where I chair the UAP Integration and Outreach Committing.
It's about a 50-person large engineering organization under the AIAA, or AIAA as I call it, which
is a professional engineering organization with 30,000-plus members.
And we've built a team of fantastic industry engineers that are coming out of the woodwork
to study this from an industry-first viewpoint.
And one of the projects that we have underway is to help define what some of the detection
mechanisms could be for these objects.
And just like you said, is it affecting gravity and how can we detect that?
Is it using some type of ionization and magnetohydrodynamics to move air around the vehicle?
And if that's the case, how can we detect that?
And so we're going to be promulgating a document to the engineering industry on a yearly basis
that updates the best-sensing phenomenologies and lessons learned and everything we know
so that the rest of the industry can start putting technology together to expand our
data sets.
So there's a lot of private aerospace companies that are working on this, correct?
That are basically sharing information and trying to work together to put more data together
to try to understand this?
I don't have information on that.
I thought I read that.
That was part of, what is it, AAIA?
Our group is made up of engineers and scientists from all across the industry, from NASA to
various DOD, to industry, to startups.
So I wouldn't say necessarily any of those companies they represent.
Actually, I would say they don't represent the companies at all when they're there.
But there are members across the industry that are very interested in this.
Do you think it's possible that there is private aerospace companies, contractors, that have
technology that they're not sharing with the mainstream academia?
Technology?
Yeah, absolutely.
100%.
Science?
I don't know.
Like, anti-gravity.
Do you think it's possible that there's some sort of private aerospace weapons contractor,
like whatever, for example, Boeing or Lockheed, that has figured out anti-gravity and it's
not being shared with the public?
I think it's possible.
Because it would effectively, it would be immune to FOIA requests, right?
Because it's a private company.
That's a theory I've heard, or maybe it's not even a theory, maybe it's a fact.
Generally speaking, yeah, I think that is possible that private defense industries and
contractors have technology that isn't promulgated and is classified.
But it would be for them to be testing it off the coast of...
That's not a defense contractor.
That would be a government program.
It would have to be, right?
Yeah.
Lockheed wouldn't just be out in those areas.
That would have to be, again, approved military tests, which means...
I mean, forgive me if this is like an ignorant question.
I don't know anything about this stuff.
So Lockheed wouldn't be able to get permission or work with the military to do this kind
of testing?
I'm not saying it's impossible.
I'm just saying that's not the way things work on a regular basis.
They go to ranges all the time.
I've been to ranges in the defense industry to work on various technologies.
But operational flight training areas and flight operation areas are a totally different
beast.
I mean, that's a difference between...
I don't even know the best way to phrase it.
But like I said, that entry area to our working area is one of the busiest places in the sky
on the eastern seaboard.
So we're now testing objects by putting them directly at the entry point of that area at
altitude after hazard reports have been submitted for eight years.
I don't see the logic.
I don't see how we could be testing against ourselves.
Especially when we kind of zoom out and say, okay, where are we now in the world about
this topic?
Do we really think that John Ratcliffe and former President Obama are going out on a
limb because we're testing some EW on the East Coast?
The conversation's got too large to support the thesis that we're testing EW.
In my opinion, we've gone beyond that just based off of how much conversation has been
around this because we're just drawing more attention to this, you know what I mean?
Right.
And that's another kind of element you have to throw into this whole thing is if it was
something we had, why would we be throwing all this attention?
Why would the U.S. government intentionally kind of like acknowledge this like this?
Why would the Pentagon acknowledge it so much?
You always have to question their intentions just based on history, right?
Speaking of history, one thing I often think of, this isn't necessarily a leading question,
but what lessons did we learn from the proliferation of nuclear weapons?
We create a nuclear weapon and others are trying to create it and now we live in a world
that has nuclear weapons everywhere and it's a fear.
If we developed a technology that had the power of a nuclear weapon, perhaps even greater,
what lessons would we have learned from that proliferation and taken that and applied to
this new technology?
Where would we have blackened out the conversation, the engineering side, at the fundamental science
side?
I don't know the answer to these questions, but I imagine we learned some lessons from
that.
Yeah, I don't know, man.
I feel like we're a species that has amnesia when it comes to this kind of stuff.
You know what really kind of like tipped me off to or made me start leaning in the direction
of it could be human technology is that when the Pentagon started really acknowledging
it and putting out the New York Times dropping these articles and the Pentagon putting out
more and more information about it and declassifying these reports, but not showing the whole thing.
That's when I started to switch to maybe this isn't some sort of extraterrestrial thing.
Maybe this could very plausibly be something a foreign nation has or that we have that
we're just not getting the whole truth about it.
I bet it's probably somewhere in the middle.
I would think somewhere in the middle as in like we took the technology that we found
from somewhere off earth and then we sort of like back engineered it or something.
I think that'd be the safer bet to make that assumption that it's very probable if this
has been going on for a while that some of what we're seeing is our own, but originates
from something else and not to say alien or whatever the flavor of other you like,
but I think that's a very feasible consideration to think that we've been trying to work in
engineering this and some sightings could be contributed to that.
That's a reasonable statement.
What do you think about Bob Lazar's story?
How much credit do you give that?
Have you ever talked to him?
No, personally, no.
I mean it's interesting and like I told Joe, I want to believe it, it's interesting, but
I just don't have any evidence other than, you know, the media that's been created to
tell his story and that's just not sufficient for me to draw a conclusion on my own.
What do you think about the way he describes the anti-gravity propulsion and being able
to manipulate time?
That's something that you study, right?
That's grounded in good science.
Any time that you would create some type of field that warps space-time around you, you
would be by necessity warping time as well.
Any increase in gravity or concentration of it in some sense is going to cause time to
slow down the more dense and the stronger the gravity is.
I don't know if that supports his story necessarily.
That's something we've known for a long time, 20s or so.
It is consistent with I think special relativity or excuse me, general relativity.
Being a pilot and experiencing everything you've experienced and just being like immersed
in this technology, this war technology, which is incredible, what do you see as the future
of war and technology developing together and what does that look like?
Does it look like some of these objects, you think eventually in the future this is just
like there's no more pilots in fighter jets?
What do you think it looks like?
Yeah.
I think that's where we're going.
I think the direction we're going is, you could call it objective-based autonomy in
a sense.
A mission commander who might be in F-35 or eventually maybe back on the boat or elsewhere
will likely assign mission objectives that need to be accomplished to a swarm of assets
that the pilot doesn't necessarily know what they are.
He doesn't know where they are.
He doesn't know what weapons they carry.
He doesn't even know what they look like potentially.
I'm moving around.
But he verifies the target and validates it and issues the commands and then the target
is prosecuted with those assets.
The autonomy is suggested, we're going to use this and this and this to create those
effects first.
Taking one jet with a bunch of different weapons and saying, okay, try to make those effects
work with what you have.
And there's more of almost like a cloud concept of warfare and the mission commander is making
those decisions.
And so I see autonomy playing a massive role in that.
And what that's going to lead to is more congested battle space, which is kind of what all this
kind of talk about EW is all about.
It's about congesting the battle space and making it more difficult to target and making
it so the pilots don't know if the radar contact they just shot at is a real aircraft or not
or if they just wasted a missile.
Wasting missiles is great.
You only have so many of them.
So you can have the enemy shoot at drones or at false tracks on the radar.
Then you're going to win that fight eventually.
What this could lead to is a reemergence of dogfighting as a valuable skill.
So our fights actually take place over such long distances.
If it is a true war type scenario where missions need to be accomplished, eventually you're
going to have to go in and increase your risk if all your long-range weapons are gone
or if they've been trashed through EW.
So what that means is getting closer and using your guns and IR missiles in a dogfight.
And so there is a potential, should things get bad, to actually kind of reinvigorate
the dogfighting regime if there'll likely be a transitioning period where there are
still pilots where if that has passed, then it'll just be all autonomous stuff fighting
each other.
But before that, you could have a chance where the EW is so good that everyone's trying to
employ their weapons, they get trashed, so you have to go in close.
So if that's the case, well, I'm going to go into that.
So what does it look like?
It looks like congestion, right?
It looks like a fog of war.
It's more confusing.
There's more uncertainty.
There's more wasted assets.
There's more ability to be clever and tricky perhaps.
There's a weird thing that happens.
I had a guy on here who was a drone pilot.
He was working at a base in Las Vegas, and he was operating drones and pulling the trigger
and killing people on the ground.
I forget in what country.
But there's a thing that happens, there's a disconnect between people who are doing
that across the world, operating some drone like a video game, and then someone who's
actually flying a plane and being there in person.
And I just wonder the psychology of if that's what war comes to, people being across the
world just hitting buttons on a controller versus being there in real life, what are
the long-term implications of that, and how does that affect the world?
I think the long-term implications is that it could probably get to a new deterrent system
similar to nuclear weapons in a sense.
If you have confidence in your ability to be successful without risking lives or making
it politically tricky, then it might be more likely in order to engage in those type of
skirmishes.
That would be the fear in a sense.
It's like life becomes more disposable almost.
In a sense though, the technology, and I've argued for this, in fact, when I was at BIA
we had some interns come in, and one of them actually took the opportunity to ask, how
do you justify this type of work, creating weapons and things of that nature at this
point?
And as someone who has been out there employing these weapons, it was easy for me to answer
because accuracy enables safer warfare if you have a moral government in a sense.
If your government doesn't want to kill civilians, being more precise is better.
And that's what I said.
As long as we assume we have moral leadership, then we would want our weapons to be as essentially
powerful and as accurate as possible as a mitigating force.
And so I think that's where we go.
Things will continue to get more accurate and more precise, which may have negative
consequences because people may feel more justified using them.
So I think you're the perfect person to ask this question.
What is hypersonic?
I hear about it all the time.
I hear about missiles being hypersonic, especially when it comes to this war in Ukraine and Russia
and Russia having these hypersonic missiles.
What is that?
What does that mean?
Is it the same thing as like mock levels, like Mach 1 through 10?
Everything below Mach 5 is just supersonic, they call it.
Above Mach 5 is hypersonic.
So hypersonic, I forget what the barrier is, but there's also a thermal barrier that you
need to get through to go certain speeds.
You can't just continuously go faster.
You have a more powerful engine because you're going to start to melt stuff.
So there's kind of a thermal barrier that's related to our material science and engineering
level.
But generally, it is what it sounds like.
Things are just going a lot faster.
Just faster.
And what does that mean?
War is not that complicated at the end of the day.
You just need to do the simple thing better than the other person in a way.
And when we have these ICBMs and cruise missiles and all these things like that, the most important
consideration is how long can I intercept that missile for?
When is it visible to me?
It's visible when it's on my radar.
So if there's curvature of the earth, depending on where the missile is launched, we put radar
sites in various places so we can see the missile sooner.
We put them in space so we can see them as soon as they launch, perhaps.
Hypersonic missiles reduce the time that you can see the missiles because they're traveling
so fast that they can go at altitudes that prevent radars from seeing them due to the
curvature of the earth in some cases.
And then it also decreases the time to intercept that missile.
And so, for example, if Russia had a hypersonic missile that could just travel over to the
U.S., that could pose a significant issue because our systems might not be calibrated
to be able to hit hypersonic missiles, maybe only supersonic missiles.
So it's just a stair step, just like everything in war, it seems.
Something's fast, you find a way to take it out, let's speed it up so those other systems
don't work anymore.
Are there any sort of missiles that can just change direction on a dime?
Well, no.
There's some interesting stuff you could do if you had like a throttled missile, but that's
not what you're describing, instantaneous movement or anything like that.
Even if we had a missile, the way these missiles work is that you lock up your chute and they'll
go near the object.
And once they get within a certain range, they'll save some energy so they can perform
what they call like a Max-G maneuver at the very end in order to trade all their energy
to get close enough to impact the aircraft with shrapnel.
And so when they do that, they might pull like 70 or 80 Gs, which is a lot, but compared
to an ejection where the first few milliseconds is like 300 Gs for like a millisecond.
And then it backs off to like 12 Gs, but it just kicks off very fast.
The only reason that's survivable is just due to the inertia of your body and the blood.
Yeah, so 300, boom, and then it slows down.
Yeah, sorry, I forgot where we're going with that, though.
Yeah, we were just talking about like the way the missiles travel and how fast they
travel and then you got into ejecting at 300 Gs.
Yeah, but when you start talking about something like what David Fravor and moving position
very fast and the Gs in there could be in the thousands.
That's the first thing I just thought about is if there were actual like beings inside
of those things, they would just be liquefied.
Potentially, if they had mass and if they were operating with our normal space time
frame, right?
So if you're bending space time, then you're going to be in your own isolated bucket and
you're not going to be feeling those inertia changes, right?
Because gravity is a field, right?
Gravity is affecting the atoms of your body all at the same time.
It doesn't pull on your head and then pull on here.
It's a field that's pulling all in the same direction.
So if you're moving gravity, you're not going to be feeling that inertia changes.
That's one way you could do that.
Another way is to reduce somehow the mass of the object so that it doesn't have as much
effect from inertia.
Right, right.
And I don't have all the answers here.
I'm just kind of just explaining a couple potential options where you could see that
movement and still survive.
If we don't assume any of that and assume they're operating in a normal environment
without reducing mass or affecting space time, then yeah, the G-forces would be probably
well, not probably.
They would be too much even for hardware.
Has anybody ever seen one of these things manipulate the environment, like, for example,
punch through clouds or affect the water at all or anything like that?
Well, Dave Fravor talked about kind of the water being spun up underneath the tic-tac.
But I'm not aware really, no, I'm not really aware of any cases like you described.
Well, yeah, what did he say about how the thing was like hovering right above the water
and there was just sort of like white water below him or?
Yeah, I think they kind of described it as like foaming or bubbly in a sense.
Because that's another huge element of this is being underwater.
How much attention do you guys pay to being a Navy pilot?
How much attention do you guys pay to like things happening on the surface of the water
or ever?
Do you ever?
Yeah, no, we do.
We have particular radar modes for ships.
Are submarines a threat?
Not to me.
Not to aircrafts?
Okay.
Not that I'm aware of.
But they're certainly, well, if we're on an aircraft carrier, they are.
If the submarine comes to the surface, though, could they be a threat?
I honestly don't know enough about submarine weapon systems to tell you.
I hope not.
But no, typically we're not worried about submarines.
But we don't really have the capability to track objects in a transmedia manner.
So if we see something get close to the ocean, we may have trouble tracking it depending
on how close it gets.
Just do the movement of water and all that stuff.
And then if it goes below, it's just going to disappear off our radar.
There's no continuation.
So we can't necessarily make that assessment of it going in the water.
We just see it and then we'll see it.
Our radar, it can see very far away.
So almost 99.9% of the time, what we're seeing on the radar is well beyond our visual range.
What is sort of happening currently within the government, publicly or not, that you're
aware of to sort of move this whole conversation forward and push it more into, get it away
from the stigmatization that people are used to?
Yeah.
And we were seeing a lot of good work on that.
Within the AIAA, that's one of our primary missions is to mitigate the stigma around
this topic so that we can do real science on the topic.
And we're seeing that form up now.
We're seeing the engineering skill sets and prowess come in that want to approach this
scientifically and agnostically.
Within the government itself, we have the All Domain Anomaly Resolution Office, or as
I call it, AERO.
It's a mouthful.
Yeah.
Yeah, AIAA.
But there seems to be a very concerted effort to actually get to the bottom of this in my
view.
Dr. Shankar Patrick of AERO, I've heard him express that he believes he has all the access
that he needs in order to continue investigating this.
I know that he's made trips to national archives and he's really putting the legwork in to
understand this.
So I believe that he is truly working to uncover this to the best of his ability.
And from my perspective, he's getting the support he needs from the Senate and Congress
in order to do that.
With the National Defense Authorization Act that was signed by President Biden recently.
What is that one?
What is that act?
National Defense Authorization Act.
That's somewhere around 30 pages of UAP-related legislation in there that essentially forces
a reckoning of any classified programs or manipulation attempts on the public related
to this topic going back all the way to 1945.
Additionally, it removes whistleblower limitations for potential whistleblowers from $300,000
for liability to unlimited.
I heard about that.
And that applies both for defense contractors as well as military folks as well.
And so really what we see is this is a mechanism for kind of opening it up and allowing Congress
and Senate to really run this to ground.
Yeah.
Oh, and by the way, the NDA also has AERO reporting, I believe to the SEC-DEF or deputy
SEC-DEF now versus ODI and I.
And so the last report that came out was an ODI-based report.
I would think going forward, there might be a little more ease in communication now that
there's been a transfer.
Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick, what is his background and what is his?
He's a former chief scientist at the, I think the Missile Defense Agency, US.
So he's been, he's a well-established and published scientist that has been working
for the DOD in various capacities for quite some time.
Okay.
How much attention do you pay to some of the other stories that are coming out?
I mean, obviously you, your background is very objective, is very science-based, very
tactical.
But when it comes to like some of these other stories and some of these other things that
are coming out, like, for example, like James Fox's latest documentaries, how much attention
do you pay to that kind of stuff?
Or even like abduction stories, is that just too out there for you or do you pay attention
to it?
I'm doing my homework to some degree.
It's just, oh, there's a lot out there.
I, you talk about the, how do you pronounce it, Varginha?
Varginha.
Is that the one?
Yeah.
Did you hear about that?
Yeah, I watched that.
It was fascinating.
I mean, it's interesting, but generally speaking, it's not the way I kind of, so there's two
ways I kind of approach this topic.
One is, in a sense, it's almost due diligence where I am engaging in those types of stories
to some small degree.
I mean, not small degree, but, you know, just through the literature.
I'm not actively investigating or like talking to...
The problem is it's so entertaining, right?
Yeah.
It's, well, there's been a trend, I think, in the past where due to lack of data, probably
for one reason, that there has been an entertainment industry of sorts that has kind of folded
on around this.
I don't see myself as necessarily participating in that.
And so, yeah, go back a second, you know, I try to do my homework to get a broad understanding
of this, but I'm very focused on the future as well.
I think that there are real solutions that we can bring forward in order to better understand
this outside of the military leash, right?
I don't think the way to expand this conversation is to just wait for the government to essentially
provide us with the answers.
We know we can see these things, right?
We can see them on certain radars.
These radars aren't...
They're classified, but the technology necessarily isn't.
You can find phasor-age radars out there.
And the democratization and access to these technologies, I think, are going to allow
us to expand this conversation with or without the government.
And I think that maybe is why this time is so unique.
The tools that you have access to can provide answers that the government can't necessarily
keep a leash on.
Yeah, man.
But the Virginia case is so interesting too, because a lot of the people that were there
that day, James says that they were just intimidated to the point where they would not talk about
it.
The one guy, he literally chased him off, threatened to shoot him and kill him if he
didn't leave his property.
Because the government intimidation, they say these people, these quote unquote men
in black would come and basically tell them, if you love your family, don't say a word
about this to anyone.
And then additionally to that, this so-and-so, this so-called being that was found, the
Air Force, the United States Air Force, all these United States planes landed the next
day and basically hushed everyone up and took all the evidence and went back to the United
States.
So it's almost like the biggest barrier is at the same time the government, even though
the government is claiming to put all these things out in the New York Times, the Pentagon
wants to openly talk about it.
It's like, this is what we're doing on the public side, but on the other side, we're
also doing all this stuff with intimidation and all this stuff to keep people to shut
up.
Yeah, I don't disagree.
But I think one of the misconceptions is that the government is extremely well run.
Yeah.
One, I think there are different factions.
I think there's different people within the government that are involved in this.
And I don't necessarily think that they all work together.
The government is so big and there's so many people and personalities and interests.
It's not as monolithic as people make it out to seem.
And this story you just described, it's interesting because what official channel of communication
exists between Brazil and the United States in order to facilitate something like that?
That must be an ongoing relationship of some degree or form then.
Brazil, from what I understand, really relies on the United States and they rely on having
a good, strong relationship with the United States.
I could be wrong, but...
On UAP?
On anything, if they had something and...
So if you're Brazil, why would you want to keep that from the U.S.?
Was the U.S. even studying?
Right?
Like officially the government wasn't really studying this.
So was there some communication between them?
If there were some high level commander or like the head of the military in Brazil, do
you think they have an open line of communication to somebody here?
No.
No?
So I don't have any answer here, but these are the things that interest me.
The case is very interesting, but what does that relationship tell us?
When did it start?
Did it start then or did it start elsewhere and if it started elsewhere, why did it start
there?
What else do we know?
And so the case is fascinating, I want to know more, I want it to be true.
These are the clues I try to look for to help better understand really what's going on.
And it's so much different than what you're seeing too, because if that case was true,
there was a biological being inside of a craft that accidentally crashed.
If these things are so advanced, how the hell would it accidentally crash?
Why would they travel so far and put a biological being that is of importance to whatever civilization
it came from?
Why would they leave it?
Why would it be strange?
It seems like they're so advanced that that sort of thing wouldn't happen.
I think there's some assumptions in there that I'll push back on.
Even if you take that to the extreme scale, is there a 100% success rate?
I don't know, that's just one poor argument against the crashing, right?
If you were to take one back to 3000 BC and drop someone in a car, you'd probably think
it worked all the time too.
But let's just put that aside.
Let's put it aside for the most part and then talk about the assumption around a biological
entity having importance.
I would imagine that technology would move into an area where you'd be able to replicate
biology artificially and that would be probably a much more efficient means of reproduction
of the asset or modification of it and the maintenance of it versus, say, a heavy mechanical
object.
I'm not saying that's true or anything, but I'm just saying...
We would be able to print, like 3D print, our bodies, right?
Just because something's biological doesn't mean that it's evolved over billions of years
to be a self-intelligent, its own agent, right?
Intelligent agent.
It's biological, but does that mean it's not a robot in some sense?
Right.
I know that's an assumption, I think.
So just because it's biological, maybe that's just the best means for doing the thing.
Right.
Yeah.
No, no, no.
That doesn't make sense.
And then that goes to the idea that once we do advance to a certain level that we...
Our bottleneck right now is our biological bodies decay and we age and we die.
But if in a thousand years, it seems plausible that we would be able to...
We're already doing it.
We're already cloning ourselves, we're cloning cells and basically 3D printing skin, like
burn victims can get brand new skin.
So why wouldn't we be able to eventually just create new meat vehicles that we're in right
now and just basically take our consciousness and put it into a new one?
So essentially, if this was in a civilization that was that advanced, they would be able
to do something similar to that.
Maybe there is no consciousness, too.
Another assumption.
You potentially have a biological being that isn't necessarily a conscious agent, perhaps.
We can at least get rid of the consciousness transfer that you mentioned.
We can throw away that assumption.
But these are the fun conversations.
We're never going to get to a conclusion on any of this, but it's interesting because
I try hard to not anthropomorphize this conversation too much and it's so easy, right?
We assume it's a biological entity on there and so that has value to the society in some
sense.
Maybe that's not the case, right?
Right.
Exactly.
That makes this conversation so difficult.
Right.
The thing, though, is it is a very different situation what happened there with the thing
crashing with something in it than what it seems like compared to what you guys were
seeing.
I agree with that.
And then if you were to attribute something like a technology that we have, like some
advanced military technology, then how do you explain all the things that were happening
in the 40s?
All the different sightings and there's documented cases of all these things hovering above nuclear
bases in the early days, I don't know what decade that was, 50s, 60s, 70s.
How plausible is it that we had that technology back then?
What the hell was going on back then?
Yeah.
I don't have an answer to that question.
That is kind of the weird thing about this subject is it's so entertaining, it's so fun
to talk about, but at the same time, that's at the same time what makes it kind of like
what makes people be able to dismiss it so easily, you know, because you have the history
channel, but the history channel just makes stuff entertainment.
It's really entertainment.
I don't know if you've ever watched a show on the history channel, like some of these
shows like Skinwalker Ranch, like a person like me who's familiar with like production
and how it works and watching this thing happen, it's just they're making a fucking
movie and they're trying to entertain people.
Like for somebody who understands some of the stuff that has actually happened in these
situations and the research that's been done behind it scientifically and then you watch
it dramatized on television, to me, kind of like doesn't do it any favors.
It makes it less credible to me, but I understand like it's fucking entertaining and people
want to see it and you can make money.
Things like the history channel and the discovery channel, they make tons of money because it
is entertaining.
And now with the conversations that are happening with, you know, with the New York Times and
the Pentagon, now it's actually getting more and more truth.
So this stuff is becoming more and more of a financial opportunity for entertainment.
Nich, what's that word?
Nich.
Yeah.
I mean, generally speaking, I think more attention that goes on this, the more people for good
reasons and bad reasons will try to financially gain from it.
I do have one pushback, which is, you know, one thing I've seen a lot is that there seems
to be this almost gatekeeping around the topic where if you're not doing it for the pure
enjoyment of the topic, then you're doing it for the wrong reasons.
And I don't agree with that.
This has been relegated to a hobby for way too long and a hobby is not a sustainable
way of creating a new industry around something that we were seeing out there that requires
technology and investment and research and people to commit to that research and write
papers.
Right.
And guess how that gets done?
Money.
Yes.
So, hey, eventually we've got to grow up and start putting our money where our mouth is.
That doesn't mean necessarily entertainment, but hey, the government, you know, they're
not going to buy censors for the general public to figure this out.
Well, NASA, I doubt it.
I've had conversations, you know, with members from NASA and people from Aero and, you know,
they both are pretty aligned around the fact that the normal funding channels for this
type of work doesn't really exist within DOD and they don't really exist within NASA.
And we're seeing a little bit of a change.
We're seeing, you know, NASA put a little bit of money, $100,000, as they, you know,
essentially build a program to study this.
They put $100,000.
Yeah.
So, you know, but the point is that they're not doing work with that.
They're building a recommendation for a program, right, and that's the output.
They're going to be looking at the data and various things and providing a recommendation
on how NASA can actually gather data to bring answers forward on this.
And so that's when I think more money will come in and stuff.
And you know, to go back to your point on entertainment and stuff, I think that's why
a lot of pilots haven't been willing to talk about this because it has been more in that
UFO attainment type of mindset.
UFO attainment, good word.
Yeah.
And they don't want to, pilots don't want to risk their careers by going on something
like that and getting labeled as, you know, a believer or something like that, right?
It's I think a little derogatory to kind of label these pilots out of witness things believers
in a sense, because a lot of these people have seen some very inexplicable things with
their own eyeballs with multiple aircraft and multiple aircrew, like their first officer
and multiple other professional aviators.
And they're seeing things that have changed their lives, you know, that have they've gone
out and talked to artists to do drawings of what they've seen and they've kept in touch
with the pilots they've seen this with.
And so to take those emotional experiences in some cases and take it on to a UFO type
attainment thing, it's just no, they're not going to go anywhere near it.
They will, they will potentially lose their job.
And the way it works in airlines, you can be at a company for 40 years.
And if you leave that company and you go to another airline, you go right to the bottom
of the pile with 20 year olds, you know, that will be more senior to you.
It's all seniority based.
So if you've been in and you have a long career and you want to start talking about something
like this, that's quite the risk to take.
And so, you know, that's why I've created the podcast merge, because I want to provide
a scientifically focused, neutral place for aviators, scientists and innovators to actually
have a serious conversation about this outside of entertainment.
And it'd be more than just a podcast because we're going to be able to take that information
and we're going to be able to apply that within the AIAA and have conversations about the
technology and perhaps pursue that.
If someone has a good idea and we have a conversation about it, we can go get things done.
We don't just have to talk about it.
We have potentially the resources and the equipment and eventually the equipment and
the people and the minds to actually start to solve this.
And so we want to try to bring those together and have those conversations, both with pilots
and the people that are going to be able to figure it out.
That's powerful.
I think somebody like you being able to sit down on a podcast and talk to some of your
peers and some of the people that you respect or some of the people that respect you in
this industry and not have it be wrapped around entertainment.
But I do understand what you're saying.
Like it is important to have an industry, there should be a big market on this niche
because I mean, that's how you fund things, that's true.
The market should be, no matter how it happens from the ground up, if it is with some of
this outlandish entertainment, I mean, that's the way naturally it has to evolve.
That's the way that we're going to attract money to the situation.
That's the way people like you, you know.
It got me.
Yeah.
Exactly.
I knew there was something there to talk about.
But the document I talked about being able to release within the AIAA, that's really
what that's going to be centered around is being able to provide a broader understanding
throughout industry of the science and the sensing phenomenologies and things so that
technology can be built.
So to kind of answer your question, how do we get from there to where we want to be,
we're getting there, right?
We've created scientific organizations, they have been created to actually study this.
What's going to happen from that is we're going to be putting out information and data
and conclusions and results and that is going to go directly into developing new and better
technology that's going to help us understand this problem better.
So we're there, we're getting there, we're establishing that.
And when we look out in the wider scope of things, we see that Aero and others are taking
a whole-of-government approach on this.
This isn't one department, one agency, one organization, one senator or congressman with
a hobby.
The whole government is kind of wrapping itself into this so that we can take that whole approach
and make sure that we're using all the resources we have as a nation to understand that.
And that's what's happening now, whether people see it or not.
We're building the stage, we're setting the stage, and I think this year we're going to
see a lot of activity on that stage.
How many episodes have you recorded of your podcast so far?
Four.
Four episodes.
What kind of people have you had on there?
We had Professor Gary Nolan.
We're going to be airing that episode tomorrow actually.
Oh wow.
And the other three were commercial and F-18 pilots.
Wow, that's amazing.
And is it on YouTube or is it on Apple?
Yeah, you can MergePoint podcast on YouTube.
You can also find us on MergePodcast.com and you'll be able to find all the episodes starting
tomorrow on there.
And of course it'll be on...
Starting tomorrow.
Wow, that's amazing.
Good timing.
This thing won't be released yet.
I'll release this next Tuesday, whatever date that is.
Cool.
Yeah, so I think we're going to be airing about every two weeks now and then hopefully
every week with just constantly interviewing pilots because there's nothing out there and
they have their stories and they've been seeing this for a long time.
So we'll have that conversation and at the same time we'll be bringing in scientists
and not just, you know, I have a lot of respect for Gary Nolan, but he's pretty wrapped into
this conversation.
But I want to bring in some people that people aren't aware of that have been in the industry
for 40 plus years that have now volunteered to help at the AIAA that are really tackling
this.
Known entities, you know, known, you know, I'll say senior engineers and scientists from
across the aerospace industry are really getting around to put their might behind this in a
public manner.
And so we're going to see a lot of progress I think this year and in the future.
Have you thought about what happens once if and when this becomes just accepted public
knowledge that there's, if there is another civilization that is trying to communicate
or traveling here and monitoring us and that is here with us and we're not alone, like
if that does become common knowledge and accepted knowledge within the world and all the main
governments in the world.
Have you thought about like what the implications of that are?
What are the public implications and how does that affect wars and military and?
Yeah, I don't have the answer for that entirely, but I will say that I know there are efforts
underway to form certain organizations that will study this from a more broad perspective
like that.
Of course, within the AIAA, I'm focusing on science and engineering around this topic,
but I think we'll hear soon about some other efforts that consider the sociological implications
of this, that include the economic implications of this, the xenopolitical nature of this.
But to kind of get to external politics, we have to now consider something other than
ourselves in our relationship with how we interact in the world, perhaps.
How do we retain our agency if we do exist among highly technologically capable societies?
I think that's really what it boils down to if we do come to terms with this is that
how do we maintain our dignity and our sovereignty in such an environment?
And I think truly we have, well, I think that's what it boils down to really.
How do we interface on perhaps a stage like that as the weaker candidate, but with the
self-respect that we should have in order to operate at that level?
These are the conversations and the questions I think that we'll be able to explore in a
more organized manner.
Once we kind of get past this uncertainty phase, you know, there's so many more questions
than there are answers.
That's going to be the fun part.
Can't wait.
I mean, it's scary.
It's scary to think about what could happen because obviously, you know, the human mind
goes to all the fear first, like what could the worst, what would the worst case scenario
be if the public knew that, okay, that we're not everything, there's other beings here.
The economy collapse, what would happen to religion?
Like it's unfathomable, it's unfathomable.
I think we will do okay.
I really do.
I think that one of the reasons that perhaps this is an okay time for this is that our
society is measured in some sense right now by how fast we change, how fast our technology
advances.
And we see it all the time, our society and our social standards don't necessarily keep
up with the technology.
Our technology is created and then we try to find a way to live with it in a sense.
I don't think this is going to be much different in a sense.
I think as long as we can retain our agency and our self-respect in a manner like we were
just talking about, that we're going to be able to integrate that information because
really that's just, you know, that's how the modern person lives right now.
Every year there's new technology and something different.
Not to mention the state of the world in some sense with COVID and everything else that's
been going on.
I think people's comfort in reality has been shook a little bit by the events of the past
five to eight years.
If you did want to introduce some drastically different knowledge, I would suggest that
this would probably be a good time as a shock would be lessened.
Yeah, I am optimistic about it to an extent just, you know, hearing some of the stories.
It doesn't seem like these things, if they are from a different civilization, are a threat
to us.
It doesn't seem like they are here for that.
They don't have any any mal intentions, especially when you hear, you know, some of the most
fascinating things to me is how there's been a large number of sightings near schools and,
you know, with young children seeing these things and reporting these things.
And I don't know if you're familiar with the Zimbabwe, the Rua school in Zimbabwe.
Back in the early 90s, there was something that landed and there was like 30 or 40 school
children that all witnessed the same exact thing.
And there was that famous Harvard psychiatrist who interviewed them all.
And yeah, yeah, John Mack.
And, you know, there was communications.
They said that when they stared into the eyes of these things, that they felt this feeling
of be careful with technology.
Technology can lead you down a dark path or it could be bad for your civilization.
You know, probably not the thoughts that these children were having, probably not a natural
thought that these children will be having, you know, especially during that time in the
early 90s.
I mean, looking at where the world was then and then, you know, there were so many school
sightings like this, which is very interesting to me how, you know, because when you think
of children and how much more open minded they are than adults who are just hardwired
into thinking the world is a certain way, that that alone just makes me whether how
real that is or not.
That makes me optimistic about this whole thing.
And I'll say, too, that I don't think what we're experiencing is probably a new phenomenon.
I think that would be a statistical unlikeliness or be unlikely statistically to think that
this just started in the very recent past.
I work from the assumption that this is probably been going on much longer than that, you
know, what that means in my daily thinking, I don't know, but I don't think this is new.
And if we if we if we assume that, then I don't think we can we have to have that much
to fear as we better understand this because we're already living in that world.
We just don't know it. Right.
So the fear is all just our own internal chains that we need to come to terms with.
Yeah. The stories like this, there's only two things you can really do with it in a
sense. You can accept it or you can not.
And I think a lot of people choose the latter, like maybe perhaps a school teacher,
because it's almost like a cognitive dissidence in a sense where you just you cannot
process that information and continue about in your normal life immediately.
And so your brain just kind of dismisses it as either confusion or temporary stupidity
or what have you. Yeah.
And go about their lives. And I've noticed that in this conversation that I've been
having more broadly about this topic.
Sometimes there's just people that and one of the best ways you can identify them is
as soon as you mention something, quote, unquote, aliens or just different or UAP
media laughter. Right.
The first reaction is a ha, you know, like and then they like realize you're not
laughing. And and then they kind of like, oh, OK, but they don't know how to move
forward from that point because they're not ready to integrate that into their
reality yet. I truly think people really do live in their own realities.
Right. You create your you create your perception of the world in your brain.
Right. And you do that based on your experiences, whether they're true or not.
Right. And a lot of times I think people use that kind of mentality to protect
themselves from this type of information almost as a protection mechanism where
it's just too outside, you know, their scope of every day for them to really,
like, just stop and integrate it because it's just too much.
Right. It's too much.
And we're busy. Yeah, we're busy.
We got shit to do. Yeah. Right.
Like it's almost the same thing that you dealt with in the Navy in a way.
Oh, 100 percent is exactly the same way.
We got missions to do. We got this.
We got that. I want to promote.
I want to do this.
You know, I want to eventually get home and see my wife.
Right. People are just so focused on their day to day lives and what they have to do
in the next hour and staring at their phones on social media.
I mean, like we were I mean, that was even true for us as fighter pilots when we were
literally in the sky looking at these objects.
Right. Which bad on us.
But, you know, we only have so much fuel and X, Y and Z.
And there's a lot of reasons why that is the best.
You know, that was the right answer.
Of course. Yeah.
But it doesn't prevent me from looking back
with a little bit of regret, wondering what we could have learned
if we paid more attention at the time.
Well, cool, man. I really appreciate you coming and doing this.
This was fascinating.
Yeah, it was my pleasure. This is great.
Thanks for having me.
Tell people again where they can find your new podcast and and whatever else
that you have online, people can follow to learn more about you.
Yeah, absolutely. Oh, look, there it is.
There it is. The Merge podcast.
MergePoint podcast on YouTube or MergePodcast.com.
We're going to start airing our first episode tomorrow.
It'll already be out by the time you hear this.
You can also follow me on Twitter at Uncertain Vector.
And now I can't wait for you guys to see it.
That's incredible. How did you come up with the name Merged?
Well, that's how we saw these things, right?
We have a merge with them.
A merge is a fighter pilot term when you get close enough to an object
to visually ID it because you're uncertain of its origin or its makeup.
And so we go to merges and dogfights all the time.
And that's when we go nose on, we get as close as we can.
We merge plot, which means the radar operators can no longer
distinguish our radar contacts on their scope anymore.
So we've merged into one radar contact.
Oh, that's fascinating. Yeah.
And so that's how we visually ID things.
Appreciate it again, man. Thank you.
And good night, world. Good night.