Thank you so much for coming down here and doing this.
It's an honor and I'm very grateful for you guys spending the time and we timed it perfectly
with your birthday and we had quite an amazing experience last night on the beach.
So what was it we were seeing last night on the beach?
That's the first time I've ever seen anything like that.
It's also the first time I've ever stared at the sky for that long I think.
There was a lot of air traffic, we could see a lot of planes flying around, we could tell
what they were.
There was obviously a very dense highway of airplanes landing in Tampa that were coming
off the beach but there were some things that we saw that were definitely not airplanes
were moving in weird directions with the lights getting very bright and then going very dim
to where we couldn't see them anymore.
What were those orbs?
Well they were the orbs and the question of what are they is an ongoing study that's research
that we're all trying to figure out.
It would have been much closer but I think all the traffic and the population from the
beach kind of makes it more shy.
So to sort of give you an introduction Chris, out of all the people that I've talked to
involved in this phenomenon, I have a lot of people on the podcast before who have spoken
about it and studied it for years and it seems to be the consensus that you are one of the
most if not the most credible person that has ever experienced this phenomenon.
As I told you earlier, my friend Andy Bustamante who was here a couple weeks ago was telling
me that through all of his experience filming that show that he was doing for History Channel,
the Beyond Skinwalker show, the night that he spent with you witnessing those orbs in
the sky, out of everything else he said that was the one thing that stuck out to him the
most and it was the one thing that was truly unexplainable and real at the same time.
Hey guys, I want to ask you a quick favor.
Over the last few months, almost 70% of the viewers of this podcast are not subscribed
to the channel.
The most important common denominator that allows me to keep creating these podcasts
every single week is you hitting that subscribe button below the videos.
I want to thank every single one of you who watches and supports these podcasts.
I would not be able to do it without you.
Please hit that subscribe button if you enjoy it.
Now back to the show.
There's more people in the government and aerospace scientists that seem to be really
interested in you.
The CIA, DIA, FBI, NRO, and even the Vatican seem to be very interested in you and they
also seem to have their hands in this.
So can you go ahead and explain how this whole thing started for you?
I mean, I know you've told a bunch of the stories before on other podcasts and your
book goes through it very well, UFO of God.
Incredible book.
Thank you.
Nearly 17 years ago, we were, let's say over 17 years ago, in 2006 we had sold a company
that was going down the tubes because of the desert, not the desert storm, but the 9-1-1
attack when they blew up the World Trade Center.
I got caught with too many houses for sale.
I was a builder, contractor, and had been successful for nearly 20 years and building
anywhere from 80 to 120 homes a year, my wife and I had a Remax Realty Company.
She sold them.
I built them.
But when they destroyed the tower, it locked the Fort Bragg, which is where we live, now
called Fort Liberty I think, but it will always be Bragg to me.
The soldiers quit buying homes.
Most everybody did.
It just threw the housing market and two, it was the start of the housing collapse.
It further collapsed in 2008 completely.
I was in a bad way.
I was dealing with Crohn's disease and had been since I was a young guy in my 20s.
At that point, it started getting worse and worse and worse because stress makes it worse.
I had to wear stress trying to hide the fact that I'm shelling out everything I ever owned,
many apartments, was going out the window to try to keep this company, at least to pay
the interest on the notes.
So we sold the company in 2005 and I'd had a near-death experience in 2004 from being
over-medicated.
It's in the book.
It's a very tragic thing that happened.
my daughter died from an overdose that he was on drugs himself, some kind of medication
he was taking and he put 113 people in the hospital and I was one of them.
So that was a severe setback going through that along with what I was already dealing
with and that was one reason the company had to be sold.
So let's fast forward to 2006.
Along about October, I accepted a job my dad arranged to go oversee a big house on the
ocean at Holden Beach, North Carolina.
Four month long job.
It was over by Christmas and we had to finish it up to get paid the last 10% after Christmas
on the New Year.
So I sent the guys back down to the coast to do their job and bring a check back for
the retainer and they did and this was January the 8th of 2007.
They called me and said, we have finished the job and we got you a check and we want
to celebrate.
Can you take us fishing today?
I said, well sure, I guess.
My wife was out of town with her or with the rest of the kids.
It was just Chris Jr. and I.
And so they came in, got their checks, broke mine, or my dad's actually, and they went
to the bank and came back about 2 o'clock and said, let's go.
And so I followed them to their house, picked them up at 2.30 and away we went to the river
fishing and this is how it all started.
The reason I went through this is because it's important, it's one of the most important
things in the world for anybody to know about this phenomena of 17 years nearly of research
that I've been doing.
It came because I was in the worst suffering way.
I was at the bottom, ready to give up on life and I was crying out to whoever's up there,
help me.
Why?
I'm 45, 46 years old and I have to get free lunches at school now for my children.
And just moving out of a million dollar home with a pool in the back.
My kids have lived within that standard for most of their lives.
So it was a big thing and I was suffering bad from it, crying out to the skies.
I left these guys fishing, I left them fishing about 3 o'clock.
I walked away and I just never did pull out a pole, it was my son and three other guys
were sitting on the bank of the Cape Verde River, a little small river about 70 yards
wide and I said I'll see you later.
And I walked away up about a quarter mile to the field to where we came across this
corn field, it turned off the paved road, drove right through the middle of this field
on a little two road dirt road to the backside and to the tree line and when you get to the
trees you go downhill a hundred feet to the river and before you run into the river you
make a right and parallel to the river another eighth of a mile to a cul-de-sac.
So it's a quarter mile walk out of that cul-de-sac up to the hill.
When I got near the top of that hill I noticed what I thought was the sun setting, it's about
5, 10 after 5, 5.15 in the evening in January so it gets dark, you know about 5.30 the sun
sets and I'm probably 50 feet from the top of that hill so I'm looking up at the gate,
the gate is up at the top of the hill but you can't see the field because it's elevated
right and the higher I got up the wider my field of vision became so I'm looking down
a road that has trees straight up on either side of me really close so I had a narrow
field of vision.
So the closer I got to the top I saw what I thought was the setting sun and so I looked
down to take a few more steps because I'm walking through mud and bushes and it's dark,
almost dark where I'm at now and four or five more steps up that hill and that's when the
shock came, I began to see a second one instead of what I thought was the sun, the top edge
of it, when I made a few more steps up I could see the top edge of two suns and I knew right
then that this wasn't anything that we had and the reason I knew that instantly is because
I'm commercial rated pilot and I have studied it all my life and love it and I can name
every airplane from World War II to today pretty much and so shock came real quick.
I am, I'm afraid what I'm looking at so I dropped to my knees using the hill to hide
me from these objects, thought I was hiding and so I sat there and I kind of crawled out
of the road to the ditch because the weeds were real tall in the ditch and so I'm buried
myself in these weeds and I start crawling inching up the hill to where I could see and
I peek my head up and they're still there and I don't know how long I was there standing
or kneeling in these weeds on my knees you know using this waist high of grass and what
we call reeds or cane which is down near water wet areas right and I begin to ponder
everything I'm looking at and my son he's in these guys behind me fishing I thought
maybe I should get back down to where they are so I turned my body to point downhill
and I'm still hiding I thought you know I've got this hill up above me I could raise up
and I could see them I'd lower down and I couldn't see them so the minute I decided
to run when I made that decision I was thinking about it but when I turned my body to actually
run I looked back one more time when I stood up to see if they were there and when I did
that a third one same thing same size 40 foot 50 foot round blood red to orange balls of fire
just what we saw on the water last night that one of those looked like it come up out of the water
that she found yeah right and so the next thing I remember is walking up to the fire trotting
they couldn't see me because they're standing around the fire and it's burnt down to a little
campfire now and we had a big blazing fire there when I left and they were just standing there and
and I could see them from the fire glowing on I might have a flashlight so they didn't know I
was coming until I got right up on them and I said hey you won't believe what I just saw at the top
of the hill and they looked at me and said where have you been I said what do you mean where have
I been I was just up at the top of the hill just 20 minutes ago and they said no you've been going
all night and so I couldn't ponder I couldn't imagine what they were saying it just did not
connect with me I argued the fact no I've been going 20 minutes this no we've been looking you
all night and I realized Chris Jr. was missing and so I kind of freaked out worried about him
because I knew the direction they pointed he went in the back of the cul-de-sac along the bank of
the Cape River which is real rugged and valleys and big trees and it's just a place you can get
lost real easy and he was in there looking for me so I took off immediately and ran to the back
of that cul-de-sac shouting for him still not understanding that I've been gone but 20 minutes
right I'm to me that's what had just passed and when I found him he was he was in shock he was
laying on his stomach and had backed up under the undergrowth in the back of that cul-de-sac
wouldn't answer me until I almost stepped on him I'm trying to get in the woods to to look for him
no flashlight and what had happened with Chris Jr. was when about an hour after I was gone he realized
that I should have been back by now it's dark so he started bugging the guys we need to find my dad
where's he at so they got in the truck and drove looking for me left one guy at the fire and two
guys in my truck drove up and down across the field out on the highway they went everywhere
looking for me Chris Jr. went on foot into the cul-de-sac because I had actually walked in there
for a little while before I went up to the field and he had what he saw what he said he saw
was um he could see all the way down the road the path from the back of that cul-de-sac to
where it turned and went up the hill so he had a good probably a quarter mile view
of that road and the trees grow over the road so it's like a tunnel you know you come through
real thick stuff and while he was looking at me he saw a red ball of light like an orb he described
two red balls of light across the road way up about a you know a little less than a quarter mile
and they went in on the river side so he ran back to the fire which is toward the orbs right
had to run back towards them and they were sitting on the bank so the road parallels the river
and they're part of the way ahead of him on the right right on the bank so he runs up there and
he tells them what he saw and they were like don't kid around you know you know don't what are you
doing junior they took it as a joke right he's grown man saying you're messing with us junior
don't mess with it so he runs back to the back of the cul-de-sac again looking for me and he sees
these same two balls of light come out of the river side now back out in the road and here they come
too and towards him so he began to back hide he tried to hide so he backs himself up under this
rub so around the field if you're familiar with in our area and even here the edges of any field
is really thick undergrowth you got all this thick stuff once you get in the forest it opens up right
so he's trying to hide under this thick stuff and what he described when i was walking him back to
the fire was that these two balls of light came all the way to one closer he got the more he got
afraid then he started hiding and they got about 15 20 feet from him and there were two little
beans about three feet tall they had red glowing eyes so they looked like individual orbs when you
saw them but when they were closer to two little eyes about this big and um he couldn't shout he
couldn't scream he was paralyzed the whole time he was laying there just afraid and so i took him
back to the fire and funny thing was these guys were freaked out now they were really
freaked because what i was talking about i'd seen up at the top of the hill what chris jr is talking
about now it got him even more distressed suddenly one of the guys shouts look and we all look up to
the heavens and it looked like eight or nine stars or orbs like you saw last night these big
they were white that they were growing huge and white and they just went around in circles and
like they were chasing one another and they'd go out and they'd come back together and then
three of them landed in front of us about 75 yards away across the river and that's when
pandemonium sat in and we ran left the poles in the water coolers everything they had we just left
it jumped in my truck and took off out of there and when we got back to the top of the hill where
i was looking you know i was hiding well those same three orbs are sitting there two of them
are in the same spot but the third one that appeared and came down is now on the road in
front of us just about 150 yards away between us and the highway and we couldn't drive forward
we didn't want to go back because we just left three on the riverbank and so you can imagine the
fear that was in in my truck my son he was in bad shape these three guys were freaked out bad but
the weird thing danny was i wasn't afraid anymore i'd lost all my fear somehow i was curious i
wanted to get out and walk up to it but they won't have any part of that and that was one weird thing
i couldn't figure out is is it took my fear away i was afraid when i first went up and saw it and
to run down the hill but as it appeared again i was mesmerized i wasn't afraid but they were
terrified there were there was everything happening from crying to this is the last
time i see my family please get me home they started fighting who was going to go home first
it's all in the book but that's how it all started in 2007 so after this experience and you guys
started driving the truck home there was there anything else that happened after you got home
how far away did you live from the river how long of a drive was it okay um that was only the
beginning when we got to the field now we're setting up in my truck five of us with this object
sitting in the road halfway to the road and two up over the road and suddenly we heard three gun
shots we don't know who was shooting move on and everybody investigated that they went around the
neighborhoods looking for witnesses and they found eight different witnesses halp obama from nassau
found and interviewed eight different people that saw it that night they were sitting on the porch
when they flew over or whatever so after the gunshots these this object in the road it just
it's not sitting on the road is hovering five feet off the road it's about 40 to 50 foot long
it looks like an egg or it looks like if you took a round ball or let's say a raindrop and you
set it on the ground and it just kind of flattens out kind of egg shake it's the
orbs around in the sky but when it's sitting on the ground it looked like a football
and it just pivots it don't turn it don't lean it just pivot straight at us and here it comes
down the road to us so it goes right over our truck about 50 feet above the truck i could have
shot it with a slingshot through the sunroof of my truck when it went over
and it pivots again to the north and it blasts off like a gunshot at poop
i took i took off couldn't go fast enough for these guys they were screaming yelling halfway
down that road to the to the first house we had to stop two and a half miles away
halfway in there is this curve this really sharp curve dead man's curve
i grew up that curve everybody in our community knew about that curve and it was so sharp if you
try to go around it more than 35 the car just bound up you could feel it on the edge of losing
control and the crazy thing is is
in 2000 shoot 1982 81 i was married to a different lady that died she died in that curve
and i found her of all the weird things i was i wasn't home i was at the coast and i came home
and drove up on her after she'd turned the car over and killed her right there
so this uh orb huge thing was hovering right over where she got killed and we had to drive up under
it and i tried to get out i wanted to get out and look at it and they won't have any part of it so
we had to move on but what it did the reason i brought this up is what it did it spoke to me
in a way that i understood and in these images it went right in my head and i relived the whole
thing that happened that night in 82 and it said don't worry anymore this is not your fault because
i had thought it was my fault and i should have been there but i was and i was out of town hunting
that day with my father and so i'd carried that for all those years this feeling of guilt
and it was removed that night right away and so i had to put that in there because it's really
important to understand the phenomenon you know i don't like to talk about this but if people are
going to understand it how it reacts it reacts based on emotion suffering thousands of people
reach out to me about this and they'll all say the same thing when they started seeing it they
lost a family member they lost their husband their wife a child pretty severe suffering brings them
and this is something everybody that studies this is aware of so um we left there never stopped
never stopped we were down to about 10 miles an hour i was trying to hit the brake they were
pounding on my seat go and so i hit the gas ended up having to go four miles further and take the
feathers got home first because they were fighting who got to go home first dropped him off came back
and dropped the other two guys off and then on our way home we went the long way because we didn't
want to go back under that same curve where that orb was setting my son didn't want any part of it
so anyhow we get to the house chris jr is running through the house locking every door
turning every light on inside outside and he would he would go in the bathroom even with
no windows he'd turn the light on and lock the door he was that afraid i was at my study trying
to find anything on tv we just knew we were being invaded the whole world you know that's what we
thought and i couldn't find anything it was just a normal night you know and it was the weirdest
thing we couldn't compute what had just happened and nothing's going on on television
and so when chris gets all his lights locked and doors locked and lights on the whole house
he runs back to where i'm at and suddenly the dogs start going crazy my dad lived next door
he had 15 hound dogs in a kennel he'd raised them all his life he'd up upwards of 100 dogs at one
time 104 so he's always raised dogs right so i know their sounds i know the different barks
and suddenly this whole pen full of dogs is barking in a in a fearful way they were scared
and i knew it the way they were sounding anybody would have detected they didn't know what they
were seeing but they were they were all going you know loud mouths hound dogs really are very loud
so imagine 15 of them all at one time just this terrible fearful sound about a year ago i started
working with this company called merrick health and i wanted to get a comprehensive breakdown of
what was going on inside my body from my vitamin levels to my lipid levels to my hormone levels
etc using the most elaborate and cutting edge testing on the market they were able to advise
me on a new diet sleep training and supplement protocol designed to maximize performance and
support longevity i tell all my friends about merrick health because you simply cannot get
this level of knowledge or attention to detail from a general practitioner who sees up to 50
patients per day plus insurance companies regularly deny progressive treatment options
primary care physicians refuse to order comprehensive lab work and standards of care
lag years behind the leading research merrick health represents a paradigm shift in how we
approach medicine empowering those who want the most out of their health care and wish to
maximize their potential every client who orders merrick's optimization package receives extensive
lab work over 84 carefully selected biomarkers to help provide detailed insights into your hormone
profile cardiovascular health organ function and metabolic status expedited onboarding for
those interested in working with a merrick health medical provider for personalized treatment
options ranging from hormone optimization and cognitive enhancement to hair loss prevention
and body recomposition and all from the comfort of home the merrick optimization package includes
the same elaborate panel i get myself and with those test results that's how the merrick health
clinical team optimizes my personal protocol if you want the same panel and medical oversight
that i receive go to merrickhealth.com forward slash danny and use the code danny for 10
off at checkout it's linked below now back to the show and so we had this chesapeake bay retriever
110 pound dog standing on the back doorsteps she's just sitting there and she was growling
and she was barking at the same time so i walked up to the back door and could see her through the
through the door and chris juniors got me by the shirt please dad don't go out there don't go
i'm like son somebody's breaking into dad's shop because his garage is next to the kennels plain
view of the kennel so all the dogs could see the garage and i had a lot of stuff in that garage i
still do my mom's house and all our tools and welders and boats and fishing gear we just i
just knew somebody was stealing something right and the dogs could see it and so i talked junior
into walking quietly with me with no flashlight using our chesapeake to stay in front of us and
keep us safe i just wanted to walk over and see if i could see who's getting in that shop try to
scare them away and when i opened that door rosie took off straight toward the kennel where the dogs
were and she ran out about 40 yards and looked back and then took on all so chris and i snuck
our way up to the dog kennel and when we got there the weird thing was all the dogs were looking
behind the pen in the woods not toward the garage and they were all barking every one of them it's
a pretty long kennel we put a whole lot of dogs in there and it was you know just imagine a 50
foot long kennel with dogs in each pen and they're all facing the back and rosie the chesapeake is
pointing she's she's froze and she's looking into the woods same direction as the other dogs
and chris and i stand in there and i said this is really weird maybe it's a bear or something
has snuck in here and dogs are usually afraid of a bear they'll make they'll sound different
and um so i said junior i'm going to send rosie in to whoever's in there she'll run them out
whatever it is deer or whatever i don't know but we made a plan we're going to send her in
then we were going to run back around to our property so it was two lots they were on my
dad's property or on his lot right so we were going to go back to ours and see if she pushes
something out across in front of us just to see what it was so i sent her in the woods she took
off wide open park and so junior and i ran hard as we could down this path back to the backyard
and i had to make a left and go to the back of the property another 60 yards i guess run so i
had to run fast to stay in front of whatever's coming out of there and what i didn't know was
this chris had me by the back of the shirt the whole time he didn't want to turn me loose
when i made that left turn to go to the back he pulled away from me i thought he just turned
to lose i actually slipped a little bit it was frost on the ground and i didn't know it but he
had all he could stand he ran back to the house opened the back door and went in and locked the
door i didn't know that i thought he was still behind me running so i ran all the way to the
back and i knew where there was a big oak tree back there i could run up to and stop myself
because you had to do this quick because dogs usually something in front of a dog will be way
ahead of them so i knew i had minutes to to see what was in there so i run up to this stop in a
to this tree in a full run stop myself and i'm trying to catch my breath i'm panting i'm panting
but i'm trying to be quiet right because i didn't want to scare whatever's coming toward me i could
hear the dog coming it wasn't far it's probably 20 yards in the woods come in my direction
so the minute i hit that tree i turned around to see if junior is coming behind me and junior
wasn't there but what was there from me to you away probably four foot i could have leaned over
and touched it with my hand a good thing i didn't somebody from nasa told me it would have killed
it did could have the energy from it so
there was a being standing there just like junia described it was that he saw on the river it was
three three and a half feet tall it looked like a child not like a gray alien you would think about
people talk about it was a little glowing the color of the moon soft glow
three and a half foot four-year-old looked like a four-year-old child head and face was a little
different definitely want human eyes were glowing red they look mechanical when you look at them
they look like the little markers on a transfer truck the side marker you see these little round
lights along the side they were about that size inch and a half it had this triangle on its chest
glowing this thing was glowing but it had a dark section that won't glow it was in shape of a
triangle and i knew i was in trouble the minute i saw it now this all happened so quick i ran
against that tree and i stopped myself and i looked back and i'm like oh my god what do i do
so i got closer to the tree i didn't want to get closer that way to turn around so i backed my back
against a tree and i'm facing this thing and i said i surrender i mean you no harm i'm sorry
you know i'm not here i was just i surrendered to it i just knew i was dead and i heard this voice say
you don't understand we're not here to hurt you we're here to help you
about that time rosie comes out of the woods she's still coming she's still tracking whatever
it is and it just vanished right in front of me just disappeared instead of telling
chris jr what had just happened i walked back up at the house and he's standing in the back door
looking for me and i was scared to tell him anymore because he was in shock right and um
i went in the end i was a smoker back then i had to have a cigarette i just had to have one i was
just basically hyperventilating i had smoke so i walked into my study i have a couch was a sunroom
had windows all the way around and my couch was backed up to these windows so i put my knees on
the couch and i reach over the back i raise i start to raise the blind and jr is freaking out
don't open the blind don't don't please don't and when i raised it up about halfway i was
going to open the window and smoke and blow it out the window right but he had all the lights on
around the house and there was this thing this being a tall one i don't um i drew it i painted
but it's not my wife thinks it's too scary so she hid my painting away
all right did she really yeah yeah so it's a four foot tall painting and she saw the same thing
is it scary emily it's a conversation piece in our house back in the day for sure she turned it
around and hid it somewhere i don't know where it is now it's in her in the pod somewhere in storage
she won't let me bring it out but anyhow that's what i saw coming about 20 yards outside
and remember all the all the flood lights were on so i could see it perfectly and how tall would
you say it was seven foot it freaked me out so bad that i shut the shutter down without telling
chris jr anything i'm trying to protect him as a dad right so i pulled the blind down grabbed him
by the hand ran out the front door jumped in my truck and we drove about five miles away to a big
hayfield set in the very middle of the hayfield until daylight the next morning
fray that's that was the beginning and the end of january the eighth of 07
and believe it or not he didn't leave out details it's a big story but they're all in the book yeah
so that seven foot being what would you like how did that thing look was there any details you could
see was it what did it look like it was a real biological thing you could touch it was a tall
two-legged two-armed humanoid figure that looked more tan looking than gray but it's similar to
these gray aliens that you hear people talk about you always said it had human eyes yeah it's huge
it had human eyes sort of yeah bigger but it looked more human looking
but it was was alien though with the pupil and like an iris or was it just all one it wasn't
all all one color okay but the way it looked at me and yeah it was it was a scary thing
so i haven't seen those since but it was there it was on my property and usually i've heard stories
that they kind of run together these taller guys and these small ones but i don't know i have no
clue so out of all the people that were there with you lot that night other than your son
has anyone else corroborated any of that yeah they do they told their story with the guys that were
there with you yeah they went on the discovery channel and told the story just like we did and
they reported to move on i have all their interviews from move on and they all corroborated
every bit of it and what happened with them was the same thing with me they had children my
children's age or older and or younger all three of them married with children and they were just
good old country boys that worked for my dad as subcontractors with families and they all went to
school with my kids the most of them either elementary or middle school or high school
and so when the discovery channel made their show in 2008 they made a circus out of us
they made me look like a like i was crazy and a liar and they tried to discredit all of us when
they told us different they were going to they were going to vindicate us that's why we all
agreed because we were catching so much slack from the community it became worse because of
that documentary my children were at school and they would get made fun of and she'd come home
crying from teachers and their kids in school making fun of their what was going on right
so that was uh that shut them up to never want to talk about it ever again
that's why you don't hear much from them so after after this happened did you tell anybody else
did you tell your family immediately or did you keep it to yourself yeah i told everybody i thought
it was the most wonderful thing on planet earth you know this we're not alone you know we've
always been told that there nothing exists even people say god doesn't exist so it's all faith
you know you there's only us and we were created by evolution this time you know enough time
anything can create itself that's what they say so i just experienced something that uh
what i didn't say was the next day when we left the hayfield and came home i came home and was
worried about my medication because i'd take medicine every day and if i missed it i would
get worse couldn't miss one day it just had to stay regular and i didn't feel sick the next morning
and i didn't take any medication just for the crones for the crones and i haven't had a symptom
since then period went away that night and i was so sick that she can tell you i was uh i was in
the bathroom 20 times a day 25 at the worst when it was at the worst point that's what crones does
to you very painful you know it's an intestinal disease right right right so so i told the world
you know this is what happened suddenly i became um a laughing stock and i was playing with demons
you're playing with the devil himself and for long the churches were coming uh sprinkling
holy water on my kids on my house on my property on me really yeah like when you would go to church
well i wasn't going to church then because i was told if you you can't come if you ever talk about
this again so i'm like i'm gonna talk about it and so i never went back and how did word get
spread like throughout like emily you said you saw the people at school were like cracking jokes how
did how did everyone find out about it was well it's a small community and you know dad was born
and raised our generations of our family are from that area and so the people that are from there
know each other very well and dad and my mom also were prominent business people in town so
everyone knew who we were anyway and so when one person found out about this oh chris bloodsoe is
crazy the whole community finds out and then you go to the grocery store and people you know
recognize you and know things and people at school and then the documentary came out a year later
and it was impossible to keep it hidden from everybody it it it sent um the first five years
i called five years of darkness and that was uh that was the first year it happened
uh the second year after the discovery channel did their thing from the second year on it just
got worse i mean it got so bad that i didn't want to ever talk about it again and i actually
went outside and shouted to the heavens i'm done with you you know why do you do this to me
why is my children affected now you came in and you healed me and now i've got this problem
right and it's important to note that through these five years of you know we call darkness
not because of the phenomenon because in those five years we were having continued experiences
together and separately like i was 10 years old when this happened in 2007 and throughout all of
those years we were seeing things and then going and being ridiculed publicly and you know in
different circles while we were still having the experiences so there was a lot of like
cognitive dissonance there with like oh we're actually seeing it but nobody believes us and
it's still happening so this first experience sort of unlocked a whole
bag of other experiences on everybody absolutely on all of us yeah even you last night
so what other types of experiences are we talking about well go ahead you can talk i mean anything
you can think of really i've seen things we've seen things like jump off of the table without
being touched like moving things moving on their own seeing shadow figures being touched
anything like you would think it was a haunted house growing up but that's you know part of how
we explain that this is all spiritual in nature is because it can really manifest in any way that
it wants to and so the phenomenon is not limited to what people think of as aliens or ufos where
we were obviously seeing orbs every night as well we were seeing things in the home
that you would think of as like ghostly maybe yeah but it was all the same stuff when did the
orbs the orb sighting start immediately after never quit from 2007 that night it just continued
to the so from then on you just started noticing things in the sky it was in my face it was uh
yeah i mean i write about it in the book so many stories that we didn't write about
the i wrote 140 000 words for this book and we published 85 or 90 000 that's including
introduction so there's a lot that we didn't include but um daddy would wake us kids up
because mom didn't really like you know the the conflict with the phenomenon so she didn't
really encourage the experiences but dad would secretly wake me and my two other brothers
uh ryan and jeremy up at like whatever time of night and we would go out on school nights at
2 a.m 3 a.m and just look at orbs in the yard right in our face and then we would go to bed
and go to school the next morning like nothing happened some of these orbs would be 50 feet
around and a hundred yards away yeah huge bigger and biggest trees and flying some of them through
the trees and sitting out there for hours we had one blue orb that just stayed there for
everybody walked by the door and we looked through the wind and see it going through the trees and
stuff this now do these orbs make any sounds sometimes they do sometimes they do not all of
them but if they're close enough you can hear them what what how would you describe the sound
like a ringing like a buzzing kind of energetic electrical electrical sizzling if you heard it
you ever took a taking a light switch and when you go to turn it on an old switch especially you
hear a crackle sometimes when you go from yeah on to off that's a lot of what it sounds like a
crackling sizzling sound any there is there any other is there a smell no smell no smell
and what about the colors the color what is the color spectrum of them what is the range of colors
that you see nearly all of them all of them can change colors there i don't think there's a you
hear people say oh there's a red one and it's mean and there's a yellow one and there's an orange one
and there's these green ones will kill you i've heard so many people talk about that but it's
from my experience they're all the same they're just how they decide to appear in color but they
usually will start out white and shift from white to red so everything in between yellow orange
blood red back to white yellow orange and that spectrum but occasionally they're blue
they'll they'll they'll go from red to white to blue this bluish white light
not like an american flag thing but you know they're pulsed they're shifting red you'll see
you'll see the red end with the blue several videos of blue ones what is this photo right
here we're looking at that far if you look at christopher that's chris jr if you look
at his left shoulder behind him where the woods are that's where i had the encounter with the
three-foot being oh really yep and that's where they landed the orbs landed in my yard you can see
this circle here is two years old the grass still not growing it killed the grass except for a little
donut in the middle and those streaks you see behind him or where two other orbs came from
different directions and scooted along the ground burning the grass until they sat down
and created their circles so there were three of those circles in the yard and move on tested
that as well what can you explain what move on is move on is the mutual ufo network
that's who you call if you have a sighting and you want to report it you call those guys and
or go on their website and you can put your sighting in and that's what what so it's basically
it's just people scattered around the country that are interested in the topic and they just
donate their time to right research it and collaborate it's a pretty big outfit and they
have you know they have board members full-time people there but it's basically a
volunteer the investigators are mostly volunteers there so but yeah they they they tested that soil
and the funny thing is the tree back in that back corner there's a big oak tree
in the woods where i run up to it and stood there with this being from me
and it the tree just died limbs fell big huge tree it's just crumbled down just like the top
of that burning tree remember that orb that orbs where that orb landed there is 12 feet from the
tree i'll show you right here this is the well here's a better photo so when it come over the
tree one of those orbs the one that had the full circle the other two had tracks leading up to
where they landed right but the other one chris jr was standing at actually we believe came over
the top of that tree and he radiated it because you can see 40 feet of the tree is missing
broke right off it looks like it's burnt off at the top it wasn't burnt it just broke and
fell it died really tree died and then um caught fire so the so the first time you noticed this
you just saw the tree in your yard burning yeah we have a video of it it was uh oh there's a video
yeah do we have that yeah we can find it okay yeah but mom tried to put the fire out three times and
it came back there you go top one here we go it lit itself on fire three times that night at nine
o'clock uh it caught fire spontaneous oh here we go combusted in our backyard oh wow hit the
full screen button on the on the bottom right yeah right there this is so weird there's emily coming
home it hasn't been thunder or lightning no i don't even think it rained today
here we go you see the grass is wet where the headlights
ran as fast as we could in the backyard the tree just spontaneously
yeah burning from the inside out how is it burning from the inside out
i don't know but here's the weird thing dan we don't know
this is when i quit smoking remember in 07 i had to smoke to blow out the window right
this is 2013 and um i was i walked i paused my television von and i her mother and i were
sitting watching tv in our study i said i paused the tv i said i'm gonna go smoke
and so she got up to go to the kitchen i went out the back door full glass door and i'm standing on
the patio lit up a cigarette and i could see this tree is 75 yards from the house back in the back
of the property in the middle of nowhere and um i saw sparks come from the ground and go up it
looked like the little bottle rocket she'd shoot off the little tiny ones that red sparkles that's
what it looked like they came out and they went weird looking so my wife is coming back down the
hall and she could see through the back door see me um on the patio but she could see all the way
to that tree she opened the door and said what's going on with that tree i said i don't know i see
it too and suddenly it just erupted like somebody just poured gas on it poof it just erupted in the
flames and it was dead now look this is after the fire it came back how long after the fire is this
that's the very next summer the fire was in like october this was the next like spring summer
spring yeah wow it had been completely dead that year before 2012
um april of 2012 and we'll talk about the lady here it's in my book prominently about the lady
and um easter saturday night easter the night before easter of 2012
i was so distraught because of the way my kids were being traded i'm a big guy you know i got
to the point where i didn't care you can laugh at me you can call me crazy you can do what you want
i don't care you just won't be my friend anymore i don't need need you in my life that's kind of
what i thought about everybody that i grew up with cousins just family and friends so i'd wash my
hands with them but now it's affecting my children extremely bad it made fun of and and all so
i was desperate to prove to the world that i had actually experienced something that i won't crazy
because they'd labeled me that the whole community or you're playing with the devil one of the two
and i knew different i knew i was praying to god and these balls of fire came i knew they took my
crowns away i knew it wasn't the devil if it was what a big trick why does the devil answer prayer
if it does i don't want to be praying right so um i had uh given up that night and i walked outside
and i said look i've been trying to film you you're in my house you're around my family
everybody here sees your presence these orbs this is an intelligent they're intelligent beings
these orbs are beans they're individual beings sometimes more than one and so i shouted to the
heavens i'm done you won't let me film you you won't let me share you with my mom and dad lives
next door the minute they come out it never shows when they walk back in the door boom it's right
back in our family's face so it was like it was it was so real to us as a group of six people
but it wasn't i wasn't able to share it this episode of the podcast is brought to you by seed
have you ever been in a situation where you had a gut feeling and it paid off there's a reason you
trust your gut and that's why our enteric nervous system which regulates the gut is often called the
second brain seeds ds01 daily synbiotic is a new standard in probiotic which supports digestive
skin heart and gut health its non-fermenting formula is supported by clinical trials and
scientific studies and delivers what you need where you need it i personally use seed because
it helps support my body's ability to break down fats and lipids and it maintains my blood
cholesterol levels already in the healthy range and with seeds ds01 symbiotic it's two capsules
in one the outer layer dissolves in your stomach with fiber that feeds your gut bacteria and the
inner capsule is designed to travel all the way to the colon for the precision delivered payload
additionally seed is rigorously tested for 14 classes of allergens defined by the european
food safety authority listen to your gut with seeds ds01 daily synbiotic go to seed.com forward
slash danny and use the code danny for 25 off your first month that's 25 off seeds ds01 daily
synbiotic at seed.com slash danny code danny back to the show you so you couldn't witness it with
anybody outside the family not not before the first five years it was um but i did with other
people you know some scientists got to see or very selective yeah very selective but it was almost
impossible to introduce anybody to it and so i went outside that night and i shouted to the sky
i'm done with you you have ruined my life thank you for healing me i'm not sick anymore but my
life is in worse shape now than it ever has been i'm a big guy but my kids i can't take them coming
home crying and and three boys 15 16 eight 17 years old trying to date girls and now they're
withdrawn because of all this and so i'm talking to the heavens to the sky just like this i'm done
with you i'll never speak of you again don't come around me don't come in my house i'm done with you
and that's what i did and i walked in i went to bed my kids were there because of easter they
always had friends come over so the house was full of children and they were in the front part of the
house playing video games and i'm in the back alone my wife's sleeping with her because the
boys had all these boys over and mom's standing guard right so so she's she i'm totally by myself
so i'm i'm asleep three o'clock in the morning three o'clock on the dot i heard this voice say
arise in a manly voice i mean it sounded like thunder it was so loud and it woke me up from a
dead sleep till i jumped up out of bed and to a sitting position and i looked around the room
panicked i said i heard that who's in here if it had been my wife it wouldn't have startled me but
because it was a deep thunderous manly voice it scared me to death
and i looked straight at my clock had old desktop clock back then everybody had alarm clock right
i don't use one so now we use the cell phones yeah i looked and it said 3 a.m and i could see
movement in my room it looked like these shadowy figures that we've been used to seeing they were
at the bed foot of my bed these shadowy figures and what they did i don't know they put me in
some sort of trance like thing to where i stood i got out of bed i was in just my underwear
i put on full jeans pants shirt shoes and i walked right out the back door following them
and we went back out to the dog kennel to where everything had happened before right just right
up to the dog kennel and just before we got to the kennel one of these beings stopped and turned
and handed me this object with two hands just like this handed it to me and i reached out and
i took it said this is yours you must keep so when i grabbed it it felt like a hedgehog
it's prickly it wasn't hurting but it was prickly and it felt like it was a living
like a dog but it had no head or no legs i could see it but it scared me really bad the way it
hit my hands i dropped it on the ground this boy said no you must keep that this is yours you must
keep so i reached down to pick it up and when i did when i stood up they were gone there was no more
beans in front of me and i thought what am i going to do with this thing and i'm juggling it and i
thinking quick and so i opened the dog kennel and i set it in the kennel and closed the door
thinking you'll be safe there i don't know what it is this has all happened so quick
and the minute i closed that door i stood up and this blast of wind
it was so strong this wind it was a mighty wind but it was localized it wasn't the trees around
me it wasn't the forest it was a blast of air in a circle in front of me that the tree this
oak tree in front of me just disappeared into a black hole and out of that hole came this wind
which pushed me backwards really quick it was like so fast it caught me off balance and i fell all
the way to my back flattened the leaves and as i'm falling i could see what looked like a
a 1500 pound bull a cowl come out of that hole ran right over top of me
and i could see through it i could see the stars right up through it but i could see this bull
and so i land on my back and i roll to my stomach and when i roll and i'm trying to get up right
i'm going to run it happens within seconds i hit my back i roll to my stomach i'm facing the other
way so i'm trying to get to my knees and to my feet to run to know where this thing went
and immediately the cowl wasn't there it was a woman beautiful beyond measure she was glowing
this bluish white color and she had this um white dress on that sparkled when it was flowing dress
just moved and it looked like an old roman dress it went all the way to her feet and and sleeves out
to her hands here and a collar there's a painting of her right there that was done you painted this
no the man standing to me is a famous artist from new york doug ald and doug painted that
just out of you know what i described to him you can see the bull to the right there
and there's actually a triangle on her chest he put it on there and
and pretty crazy that painting's big but her face is different but that's similar to what was in
front of me so three foot floating in front of you yeah three foot off the ground but six foot away
from six foot away and the size of her was it like the normal size of a human she was smaller
smaller see-through could you not see no she was solid as you are yeah but her mouth wasn't moving
but i could hear her planet's day talking to me but she was hovering barefooted just like that
three feet off the ground and she looks at me i'm just in this biggest shock words can't describe
how the power i felt from this wind and this bull run me over and the fear that set in flight
i had to run you know i had this instant fear hit me but now i'm looking at this woman so the whole
fear thing turned into oh my god what is this is an angel what am i looking at
she leans over and she looks at me and she says this is your burden she said first she said you
know why i'm here and i knew why she was there because i had struggled internally for five
years these orbs come and it talks telepathically i hear them and we proved this on the history
channel live with andy right they knew that my brain was communicating with the orbs even though
i wasn't moving we did this on camera and neuroscientists measuring my brainwaves they could
tell so i'd had for all these years this overwhelming desire to tell the world
the more i told it the worse it got the worst ridicule and it spilled over to my children
so that's why i was ready to quit but she said this is your burden you got to bear and she said
um several things and this is
i've been telling this for a long time about the times we're in now
you know we're in some pretty weird times right but she told me about that and i put it out there
2012 this happened easter of 2012 she said um there's going to be trouble coming
in and we're going to wake the people up and we're going to let you do it we're going to use you
we want to help you introduce us to the world that's what she said and um
she told me about an alignment she said there's going to be uh she said when the red
she said when the star of regulus when the star of regulus arises on the horizon
in the gaze of the sphinx at that time there will be a shift in the knowledge of humanity
that's what she said i didn't know what it meant i had no clue if this star would align on
star of a regulus regulus a star called regulus when it aligns on the gaze of the sphinx
before daylight when that star comes up and it's right just above the horizon like the orbs last
night right on the ground in view of the sphinx there'll be a shift in in the knowledge there'll
be a new knowledge for humanity so i told that also saw visions of trouble that would happen
beforehand which is we've been having weird troubles right so i'm not a prophet and i don't
want to claim to be but i did say this in 2012 and i've said it for the last what 11 years
and it's all happening so the amazing thing is danny is um i went from totally
quitting and announcing it to the heavens i'm never going to do this again to a new renewed
energy of now what am i going to do if i tell this about the lady they're going to come lock
me up they're going to think i'm crazy for sure so i didn't say anything for a while
and two weeks later a week later i had vowed not to ever speak about it again one week later
i get a call from the move line saying we want you to talk in ashville ashville north carolina
which is six hours away and i readily accepted yeah i want to talk so i was a different attitude
towards it and that's where i met diana posolka two weeks after the lady came and i started
talking about the lady in that conference and the audience began to heckle me they made fun
they didn't want to hear about the lady they wanted to hear about the the river event so it
was a very traumatic thing and none of that bonded diana and i for all these years to where
that's how we became to know one another but the crazy thing is is immediately when she left
that's when i began to document everything i could get pictures i could take you out and share it with
you only after she came only after the lady came yep what do you think the bull symbolized
i don't know but i know this it got the attention of diana and the vatican
and cia nasa and everybody dod even the ministry of defense in britain australia
all these people they wanted to know about the lady immediately let me tell you in fact i put it
in writing to two generals at the pentagon what she told me i was asked to do that i have there
i mean i there's i have a whole bunch of questions in my head right now but i want
to try to figure out how to pick this apart a little bit first of all steve do you remember
when we were talking to randall the other day we were going through the different ages in the great
year yeah um what what age are we in now as far as like the constellations that's the first thing
i thought about is like the age of the bull and the lion it wasn't an aquarius we're an
aquarius right now like that song age of aquarius right right oh yeah we were singing the age of
aquarius and what's the next one is there a way you can pull up like a diagram uh that circular
diagram he was showing us well let me tell you what she told me she said that there was a shift
in the powers of the heavens and that she had been away the feminine energy was about to come
back and they won't know stopping it and that there would be a shift and that that shift would
be into aquarius and that the divine feminine would come back as the energy that would create
a thousand years of peace that's what she told me it'd be trouble first but in time that peace
would come to this world all right so it goes aries torus gemini cancer leo virgo libra
scorpio sagittarius okay aquarius followed by pisces okay so we get a long way to go before
we're in torus again interesting but you know the lady in in egypt
is depicted hathor with bull horns or a bull next to her many countries the lady is always
depicted as with a bull or either have bull horns with a solar disc or beside the bull
so it goes hand in hand with her throughout many countries what did diana say about the lady
did she have any speculation about who she was yeah they quickly referred me to the fadima lady
and the lady of guadalupe the lady of lord's france and fadima and there's several others
there's one in egypt that i don't know the name can you pull up the lady of guadalupe
yep um now the sphinx there's been people that have speculated the sphinx was originally a lion
yeah what's weird is regulus is in the leo constellation
regulus is in the leo constellation so when the leo constellation comes up
in a lens with that brightest star called regulus is there images i think it's leo
pretty sure it's leo okay this is the lady of guadalupe yeah so the yeah that was the
first time you saw the lady and when did she did she give you a specific time when things
were going to change with humanity she's you know i've seen her more than one time and um yes
yes i didn't hear from her except at easter of 2013 she came back
okay yeah regulus it is a constant star it's the star of leo the lion heart yep and when she told
me when that star aligns on the horizon before daylight and in the gaze of the sphinx it would
be a shift in the knowledge of humanity a new knowledge and that's what she told me
but there would be trouble along the way first and they gave me the images of war
i even wrote that i saw israel bomb iran and syria and we're looking at it right now i put
that in writing for years i'm not talking today i did it i've said this for a long time
yeah and it's it's coming it's happening
let's hope it don't but it's looking that way at what point did you start getting visited by
people in government and people in nasa or cia 2007 2008 so right after yeah well i didn't report
the incident until october so it happened in january of 2007 i come home telling this and my
wife was so afraid the kids were scared they didn't know what was happening the church um being in a
pentecostal holiness church i was a deacon in the pentecostal church so you can imagine pentecostal
church is way different that's dr povenmeyer how povenmeyer
so they immediately related it to the demons so my wife is trying to keep the family
under control and hush me up about it so i didn't talk about it for 10 months other than my kids
orbs would be in the yard at night two in the morning i'd wake them up and bring them outside
and say look your daddy's not crazy there they are right so um my wife began to experience it
i think in the well what time was it in 07 when she got shoved in the kitchen it must have been
in the fall it was a few months later she got shoved in the kitchen yeah yeah twice dad had
been praying you know that mom would have an experience so she would believe him and she was
doing the dishes and no one was awake or around and some something shoved her into the sink
and it scared her so bad she said don't ever pray for me again
shoved her twice but i don't blame her yeah so i didn't speak about it for the first 10 months
and it was october um that i had cable finally we didn't even have cable i couldn't afford it
had no tv other than local you know you get a few channels with a rabbit ear
and so we got cable and i started researching ufos how do i tell somebody who do i talk to
i've got to get this out of my head or i'm going to go crazy because my heads hurt really bad
every time i tried to think about the subject i would go into almost uh pass i did pass out
very often it would it would hurt so bad i would pass out in front of everybody
it was it my brain had a lock on it and um so it was october i saw it a move on ad on the
history channel about uh stanton friedman this nuclear physicist was talking and the first time
i'd seen a show like that i thought he's pretty cool if this guy would tell it i'm going to tell
so i googled them and found their application to submit a report and i wrote it out
two weeks went by i attempted to push that button and i knew if i pushed that button i'm gonna lose
my wife that's what i thought i was under that much stress so after two weeks i agonized
finally i hit send and i felt this relief but i didn't expect to hear anything back right so
within a week i get this call within days a couple of days i get a call from move on out
of california saying we want to come see you like right away and i'm like oh no you can't do that
i just wanted to say it right so i told them no and they kept calling me and talk and calling
and calling and come january of 08 or right around the first of january um they wrote me again and i
finally said i've got to tell this i can't hold it no longer so i said yeah you can come
and it was february of 08 when the first person showed and that's when i told my wife was sitting
there on the couch while the investigator was there and she looked over at him and she and i
hadn't talked about this period only me and the kids she was always busting at me don't get them
out of bed you know they gotta go to school and that's when she asked uh steve the investigator
if you ever seen any shadowy beings and i've been seeing them and i got shoved in the kitchen
and i said my prayer is working i've been praying you would experience this and she looked at me
and pointed her finger said don't you ever pray for me again like that we all thought it was funny
but that was the first time you ever heard her talk about shadowy figures yeah
she wouldn't talk around me she would around them but she wouldn't me and she was trying to hide it
you know but um it just became uh within two weeks um within two weeks of the move on coming to my
house in february they had already talked me into doing a documentary with the discovery channel
this will vindicate you the whole neighborhood and know you're you're not lying about it so they
talked me into it and that was a bad mistake bad because it turned the opposite way i don't think
they ever believed it would happen again i didn't think that because it don't normally happen somebody
see something that's it but it didn't stop it came back and did you ever see any of those
three-foot childlike beings again yeah yeah i sure did in fact there's a picture of them
i'm trying to find it i can't it's there seem to find the photo but and you you mentioned the first
time during the river experience when that first being explained to you he wasn't there to harm
you he was only there to help you right was there any other communication any other times that you
saw them or experienced them yep two nights later this was on uh it was a monday night when
we had the experience on the river chris jr and the group wednesday night my wife wasn't coming
home to friday right so we're staying the rest of the week there just jr and i and wednesday night
um i'm struggling with chris jr because he's in shock and he's had a really scary experience
right um he was in a bad way and so um wednesday night it was about nine o'clock eight thirty or
nine at night suddenly we're at home he and i watching television just dad and son and these
same dogs start barking again same way scary part so i ran to the back door and could look out over
the whole property out through the back full glass back door and there was a christmas tree farm
beside us a big one they had new trees where people would they would send them out you know
cut all these trees down but it was a section of that christmas tree farm that was overgrown you
see the far back right corner on the woodlands our property line but on the other side of that
excuse me was this huge christmas tree farm i can see it looks like a wall of trees yeah so um
the trees were so big that they grew together so there was no walking through the place there
were 40 foot tall spruce pine trees but underneath you could get down on your knees and there was no
weeds at all it was just these short little pine needles and there was a section three feet of
height underneath all them trees you could see for a long ways and so i just crossed the fence
the lights were flashing pulsating in the christmas trees the whole tree was lit up treat the farm
and i knew what it was because we'd seen it monday night on the river these white big white orbs
flashing and um i don't know what got into me but it was a change in my life at that moment
because i had been a hunter i was raised with a rifle and a shotgun i shot my first deer at
five years old i was shot in the back at 10 years old had a near-death experience nearly
you know i was the luckiest guy in the world and when i was 10 years old blew a hole in me
but it's big big as an orange shot in the back with a shotgun yes from me to you
that's a whole nother story the scar is still the size of like a big orange or a grapefruit
yeah right straight in line with my heart right there if i pull up my shirt you can see lead
right here through the skin yeah that was the first near death and so i don't know why
but i was angry i just seeing my son get upset again all over because now we got two nights later
these lights in the backyard again and it's taken me two days to kind of calm him down and now he's
freaked out bad oh my god he's just really freaked and so i just had this bit of rage
come in me and i walked over to the gun cabinet and i grabbed a little holster 44 magnum rifle
a little short saddle gun i used to bear hunt with i'm on record boone and crocket record book
for shooting 660 pound black bear wow north carolina so big it was a record at that time
uh still in the probability top five but um
i took that gun and i said you come with me general he said no i'm not i'm not going out
that door he said please don't leave me dad i said son i'm going to end this tonight that's what i
taught him i was just being a father i guess so i walked back to that back far back right corner
and i went through that little opening you see walked another 50 yards to the along that side
and there was a fence there old hog fence that the trees had fallen over in one spot so it
wasn't used anymore but it was crunched down and i knew it there i didn't want to cross that fence
until i got back there so i could step over it so i stepped over that fence and the first 10 yards
of that tree farm was nothing but pine so there was a buffer area of pines and then there's the
wall of christmas trees sure wall i mean there's no going through it you couldn't drive a car
through a bulldozer so i got on my knees and i started under and i could see this orb is about
50 yards away we're not even that far 50 60 feet 70 feet maybe and it was pulsating i could see the
bottom three feet of it that's all the view i had three feet of view under there so i crawled
dragon neck guns under these trees until i got about 20 feet from that orb 20 maybe 30 feet
and the electricity from it the buzz the static my whole body felt like needles the hair was
standing up and every bump goose bump on me was just tingling and the energy was so strong i
couldn't go any closer i just turned around and i backed away walked back out of the forest
crawled out and i got to the pine trees where the fence was crunched i stood up and i went to step
over that fence and the minute i went to step over that fence there were two of these beings
disappeared right in front of me one on i mean they're standing like three feet from me
and just enough gap i could walk between them and immediately i felt this
shame come over me shame that i had this rifle why i brought this to fight something that
there ain't no fighting right so i took the gun and i tried to hide it behind me
me and what they put in my head was what changed me from that point on i never
hunted again i don't harm bugs i have uh away with animals now nobody understands
i have 50 100 ducks wild ducks will fly in and fly right up to me if you come out there they're
gone but they'll fly right up and eat from me feed them wild mallards and if anybody knows
about mallard ducks they're one of the most skittish creatures in the world they fly it
you know thousands of feet high at 80 miles an hour and you need duck calls and blinds and
decoys in the water to get one to land well i have whole flocks of them fly right in and eat
i can feed them but that wasn't like that before but these beings told me that
they changed me they told me that um the way they put it in my head when i say told me they
don't really talk they put images that you know it's just telepathic i guess you could say
but it made me understand that the whole world is um is a living is alive everything from the grass
to every single animal bird tree all had a consciousness they even put images and to me
to me of the cells in the body like and within the human body there there you don't tell
your body what to do something outside of us is telling our body how to function the molecules
the the um each cell that divides from one cell to the other has a conscience so um i'm just a
part of that i can't get the words out i want to say but it just changed me in such a way
that i began to cry about everything i've cried for the last seven eight ten years i guess
about everything when i see something get hurt it just kills me
but it came from that experience with these beings on how they told me how everything's a living
consciousness and i don't have the right to take its life that um we live in a mutual
holistic way like the your stomach for example you have bacteria in your stomach that digest
chlorophyll plant material the human can't do it but this bacteria does and it secretes the nutrients
that you get from that plant and it survives because you're feeding it the plant material
right so it's a mutualistic way we live and it's like a tree gives you wood for a house it gives
you shade for the sun a nest for a bird oxygen debris and the list goes on so everything has
a part of life on this planet and it's not up to us to destroy it and abuse it
and it's i could talk about this for days wow yeah it changed me and um this was in the very
beginning how long did it take before you though were obviously the word had to get out but like
how long did it take before one of these guys like hal pavenmeyer from nasa to show up and and was
he the first one to show up and why why did he show up um remember the we got past this i guess
but february they came and did the report by june they were doing the documentary by late july august
i think it was how shows up at our house knocking on the door and i was away in town and my youngest
boy ryan answers the door there's a six foot four guy giant man standing at the door
yeah it was just ryan and i and he came and he was like is chris blood so here we're like uh no who
are you no calls no no no letters just showed up unannounced drove all the way from florida
cape canaveral just on a wind and knocked on the door that's two and a half hours from here
yeah it was 13 hours to our house and so he drove and ryan calls me and he flashed some badges so
we let him in and we just like sat at the dinner table with him until dad came home
what was he talking what was he saying to you what was he asking you i don't remember everything
i was pretty young but he was just i mean mom came so we were talking and she was just asking
him questions and ryan was probably taking the lead i don't remember i was pretty shy what he did
was is um well to begin with this is in the book for the first five years we had been involved
with the ufo world on a limited scale you know they everybody heard about us they wanted us to
come speak they wanted to come visit and i let a few people come and the men in black was a big
thing back then that was about the year it all came out and so everybody was saying the government
will kill you don't speak to this one don't if you see somebody from the government that don't speak
i mean they put the fear of the government in my whole family and so who was they the well the
people associated with with the move on the people associated with move on which is the ufo world
basically you know so once that show came out it brought everybody that's involved in the ufo world
knocking on my door bringing groups of 10 15 20 people sometimes and they would come i'm not
saying it was move on as people associated with them the ufo world so they were all about the men
in black they're going to kill you they're going to kill you so when the government guy house shows
up at the house automatically it was fear we were all afraid and i didn't want to talk to him i
didn't want to have anything to do with him and for the first few months i would never give him
any information but yet he took to my children and he loved this one more than anything i mean
he came to my college graduation birthday parties recitals like wow he would drive all the way to be
a part of our family yeah he was always there and you know what he told me he said chris now he was
that when he died he had been at nasa still holding security clearances for 60 years that's how long
he's been there he worked with warner bum brown before it was nasa he took his astrophysics
degree in astronomy and astrophysics from jail and heineck at ohio state university he was like 15
when he graduated college how's a genius yeah freaking genius he was and so um why was he
interested in this why was he interested in you because they knew what i was saying that the word
the triangle the triangle in the chest of the being that was a big thing a little child with
a triangle the lady was 2012 that that happened later but that even brought more people but it was
they'd known they knew the phenomenon was real they've known it don't listen to them on tv i
mean they say we don't know we don't have anything yes they do they all know was this personal for
him or was this business this was part of a nasa sent him this wasn't just him like a side hobby
well no i wouldn't say nasa sent him because he would always tell us not to say that oh okay
because he wasn't supposed to be very selective with what he would say yeah what kind of questions
was he asking you everything you can imagine he would ask each member of the family the same
question separately to see if they would line up and he did this for years and years and one day
decided he couldn't debunk it and just decided he loved us and that's when we started you know
gaining like a friendly relationship with him and he like integrated into our family
that was after years of him trying to debunk us pretty much so he was coming there to cross
examine you guys to find holes in your story to see if basically he was sent he told us he was
sent to debunk this story that's what he told us he worked with j allen heinick he was the debunker
and we heard many stories how he would find a hole this person you know son of a sheriff fake
something he called him that's what he did and um but he also would come and stay days while we
weren't there didn't know he's in town he would be at the newspaper he'd be on every house on the
street where this phenomenon first appeared to us in 2007 he investigated every house within a
mile or two of that place and that's who found the eight other witnesses that testified to him
on his when he was getting the information that they had seen something that night and
and so that's what he did when he filled a real finally realized it was he couldn't blow a hole in
the story that too many knew it was real and he became a part of the family and he began to see
the phenomenon with me we sat out in the back and watched it come over but we loved him how was a
great guy for our friends for my family my children we just loved a guy and he was coming
to our house thanksgiving of 2020 or 2019 2019 he was coming 2019 yeah and um we were expecting
him on friday for the thanksgiving that we can and he he he fell in his bathroom and hit his head and
went in a coma oh no who is this guy
go ahead that's uh colonel john alexander
the men who stare at goats john alexander that's that one yep that's john you see our zoom in on
it a little bit you see my hat there that's i've got a whole box of those john wears one two
cia so okay explain this story how did you meet john alexander and
what was your relationship with him would john start salt the first chapter of the book
and um this guy's like a legendary military general right yep he's a colonel colonel yeah
what do they call him dr death yeah that's his name yeah he was an assassin in the military
isn't his phd in like death uh you know near death studies from harvard i think he's still
alive yeah yeah i talked to him this week wow yeah we we stay in contact i mean we love john
john was at my house not long ago in fact we're going to spend that oh wow that's joe mcmonagall
cia spy number one remote viewer number one double o one double o one that's him
joe mcmonagall he's a legend that's at the monroe institute by the way yeah
which we uh we love to be how were you introduced to him and what was his interest in you john
um it was 2015 i think this lady by the name of pam nance
uh she's a research scientist for the government and her home base is
uh wake forest university so pam calls me i was introduced to her by somebody uh and then i've
called her back long story short she says chris um i'm researching the paranormal
me and my assistant ashley she said we're researching the paranormal
and i just got to tell you she said i've been on pilot mountain in north carolina she lived from
winston-salem works at white forest right there in winston-salem right so she said i was on pilot
mountain or mount pilot like the andy griffin show mount right she has a cabin near there of
her home place from way back and she said that she and ashley would hike up on pilot mountain
and sit under the stars and turn on this voice box they call it a spirit box i've never heard
of such but it's a little device about like the size of a cell phone that has this awful
noise that comes out of it it sounds like uh like static static yeah white noise
but it's it's ticking tick tick tick tick like so and what it's doing is scanning millions of
frequencies and they these investigators believe that and i know now that disembodied spirits
or voices can come through that thing so she said she was on pilot mountain and she would
ask it questions and it kept saying chris ufo chris ufo and it said it over and over over
several days she would hear the same thing chris ufo even said hope mills which is where we live
so she gets on the phone with uh mufon and finds out who is chris and the ufo well they gave her
my number right away so she comes to the house and we're out at the burning tree first we did
um about an hour and a half interview in my study and she had all her equipment running
and then we went um and not to get ahead of myself but while they did the hour and a half
study inside they got like 60 or 70 voice communications audible that was recorded on
a recorder just coming out of thin air so we go out to the tree and we do this investigation
and i'm just holding this box in one hand spirit box with a cord hooked to a digital recorder
so this is recording what this is saying and you can hear this thing so she talks me into standing
at the burning tree while my wife her assistant pam and ashley my wife and stephanie my niece
there were four ladies standing you know 10 feet from me looking at me i'm leaning against that
burning tree and i'm holding this thing and we start asking questions crazy thing this thing
started talking and it would answer my question it would say my name and four or five voices would
come through it they recorded 350 audio clips and she said i've never seen anything like it
she said if i went to the charleston jail to do a ghost hunt she could take six of these recorders
and let them run for hours each one and they might get one voice out of you know 40 hours of recording
where we got over 350 recorded clips but one thing it said it said chris the pope is in danger
help him you must help the pope it was saying this we got it on recording and she even made
a powerpoint with this with all these clips you can listen to them are they online no okay i've
got them okay but um with all this happening um i knew that the putt was going to philadelphia
he was already had been into washington and was making his trip to new york city and he was going
to go to philadelphia was this pope francis i think it was francis right when they were going
he was going to make a speech at the congress owed of the original congress hall in in philadelphia
so i call a friend that called me last night the guy you asked about who it was they called
yeah i said i called this guy i said hey larry you won't believe this i said uh this thing
this lady has and i'm i'm talking to him right after all this investigation i said this thing
keeps saying that the pope's in trouble he's coming to philadelphia but he said you must help
him it was saying this not you can hear it you must help him so immediately my friend
says well maybe you should come to to philadelphia and uh let's see what we can do about it
so a couple three days later i'm in philadelphia and when i walk in his house there stands john
alexander first time i ever met him and that's when we started remote viewing the whole pope
first chapter of this book and they actually arrested a guy for trying to blow him up i even
told him he was going to use a bomb i saw where the boat ramp beside ben franklin bridge i drew
it all out and they verified it and so they got secret service involved then john calls joe
mcmonagall and joe says the same exact thing that i say and so from that point they shut down
philadelphia closed every access into it and made people walk from the jersey side across the
ben franklin bridge you had to walk in you couldn't drive and they arrested a guy for that so that's
how i met john and it was a real thing what happened there and that got the attention of
a lot of people did you ever speak with the pope i never have personally i had words i had messages
relayed to me from the vatican through diana and my friend from nasa jim taylor and uh he sent me
pictures of orbs and of saint francis with these orbs appearing and he had these hands were zapped
and at that time i couldn't use my hands i could barely button my pants i didn't get my kids to
button my pants and i couldn't tie my shoes couldn't hardly pull my pants up my hands were
just in plain this is the arthritis this is rheumatoid which is an autoimmune disease um
so yeah the other nasa individual you met after how how long was where on the timeline did you
meet him i met him in 20 it was either late 2012 or early 2013 and um what happened there i was at
a a gathering in an old lock cabin in upstate pennsylvania on the delaware river on a lake
we crossed the river and to this beautiful historic cabin they had thomas hiddinson's
bedroom suit there right so big money and taylor had heard i was there and he was out in la
california and so he heard i was at that meeting and he wanted to meet me and he called and said
i'm coming from la i'm heading to huntsville but i'm gonna swing by pennsylvania first to meet you
i want to i want to talk and so he showed up that afternoon i'd been there one day we got there
friday saturday evening he shows up and we became very close friends from that point on and
after he left from there he flew out the next morning back to huntsville so he come in one
evening met me made arrangements to come to my house and to meet my family and a week or so later
he was in fadville at my house and the rest is history from there so tim he was what was
his background where did he work what was his what was he studying and what was his interest in you
tim is uh he's an amazing guy he's a genius and he's a very kind-hearted person
um he is an engineer for nasa that he's probably been at nasa now 40 some years over 40 years
and he runs all the launches he's the man he's an nr o guy national reconnaissance office
and and sorry to interrupt but let's just clarify for people what that means national
reconnaissance office national what do they do national reconnaissance was a very secretive
organization until a few years ago when they were discovered and it went public but he
he was a part of the air force a part of nasa and the cia all three so he holds the credentials for
all three and what they do these guys they're the top ranks they have the highest security
clearance is they're so high they can't even travel they can't go in the hospital and have
surgery unless somebody's escorting him because he might talk so they're the eyes on the sky
nr o guys see it all they have if there's anything flying in our space there's a select
few of those guys that get to see it i mean it's compartmentalized down to just a handful so they
they own all the satellites all the spy planes they run the launches because this every time
they launch something something from up there come check it out swim right up to it or
fly up to it and make sure it's not something that's sitting shouldn't be and i'll stop with
that so let's just say okay well that's something we're gonna have to talk about a little bit later
swim right up to it okay yeah all right anyways we defined nr o so he was a
an aerospace engineer working for nasa for 40 years and 40 years now probably he was there
30 years when i met him and what did he say to you what kind of things was he was he asking you
when he when you guys first met um he was the kindest person understanding somebody i liked
he never doubted me one of the worst things to do with this subject and everybody feels that you're
you know a new person on the block is so afraid to tell anybody because of the way you're going
to be perceived you're crazy right right he was never like that he was and what really was the
difference and i'm sitting here with a lead scientist from nasa the one of the top guys
from nasa he runs the launches he is he runs the launch he runs them all this guy he's in charge
he's the dragon he has a dragon tattoo on his arm his console is called dragon console i had the
number to his dragon console yeah his his console is named the dragon which is his space in mission
control where he stands and runs the launch he's the dragon oh wow yeah and so to have that kind
of person questioning me about what they look like not are you sure you saw this
not i don't believe you it was none of that it was what what did they look like describe them to me
were they this way were they that way did they walk this way they knew they knew all this stuff
uh and so for right away i found somebody that um that i appreciated that could help me understand
and he he felt so sorry for chris jr that his mission was to meet him he wanted to meet jr
he came and he spent a lot of time with him
and changed his life because jr had the worst problem being 17 years old with people telling
him he's a liar you know that's the worst thing you can do grandmas and grandpas even saying i
don't believe you you know were you on drugs or something and it wasn't the case and so this guy
comes and he knew it was real and he went right straight to my house and he met everybody briefed
us with an official briefing on a laptop with our name our eyes only the bledsoe family he tested
each one of us with metamaterial and to see if we'd have a reaction to it and he he counseled
jr for a long time and changed his life because now he had some pride he had somebody to believe
him and if nasa people would do that then that's a really big deal so that's how that he briefed you
specifically what do you mean by that you can tell them well you can see in this photo it was the
day of my homecoming game i had i was running for homecoming and so we were all called into my
brother's room one by one to watch this briefing video he had this powerpoint that said for the
blood so eyes only and it had different photos and things that he would explain to us that i
probably am not going to say or share and then he would hand us all a piece of metal and we would
you know hold another piece and see if there was any sort of reaction and he would test this all
privately and separately so we wouldn't know what was happening so he could get more of like a
i don't know like a real reaction so we didn't like pretend or something and we all felt
something but when dad held the material even though we all felt like electricity he was like
seizing from it because his experiences had been so intense the photos he was showing you or the
stuff that he was showing you was it like trying to cross-reference things that you guys had seen
with things that he had documented or you know some some of it was area 51 which i can't say
nothing about but he would show us things and then ask questions why do you think that's like that
why you think that door is nine foot tall
and i won't say any more there but let's just say
because it was official briefing i probably shouldn't go very deep and why do you think
it's so classified well it's always been the most classified subject higher than the atomic bomb
and it's been that way forever do you think it's a good thing that's so secret
well i think it's the cat's out of the bag now and they can't hold on to the secret they're going to
try it because they have no choice there's nobody at nasa qualified to walk up in front of the
television and say this is this and that because it takes an act of congress to change their whole
mechanics before they can do that so then these organizations can't tell it and they're not going
to congress is up there wanting them to trying to demand them but their protocol says no so it
takes a whole lot of politics to to maneuver around to get the air force to ever open up
about anything it's its own entity basically and for technology and for state security
national security that's why the government's not open about it they don't want to talk about
it because it's technology involved with this stuff is incredible and they're not about to
give it away to just anybody so explain what happened again when he handed you this piece of
material well he handed me i was the last person in the room so imagine my five my wife and four
children and jenny i wasn't in the room when you held it but go ahead but most everybody was in
there they were sitting on a bed or on the round out of couch in his room but um when i walked in
the room everybody was watching me and quiet i couldn't say a word and up on top of the dresser
and you know the dresser is tall not the the nightstand not nightstand but the dresser he
had the laptop set up there suppose i'm looking up at it and he goes through the whole briefing
watching his powerpoint and asking questions and then he goes over to the chair and picks up a
backpack reaches in it he pulls out this little piece of metal it's about a half inch square
size of a poster stamp thin i mean thin and he put it in my hand and it just looked a square of
gray metal he said what do you think of that i said looks like aluminum i don't know i didn't
know what it was so he reaches in his backpack and he pulls out another piece and he puts it in this
hand and it's like aluminum foil it looked like aluminum foil you could crinkle it up but it
wouldn't crinkle it would stay wavy but it wouldn't crease so i messed with it and it just
sit there but the minute he put it in that hand as thin as aluminum foil yeah this one was thicker
it was a piece of metal this was aluminum foil and he described this as the insulation he said
this is the insulation like i already knew what he was talking about right but when he put that
in his hand it made a connection through my body to this hand and my arms began to thump like that
and suddenly my eyes just started to black out and he reached in my hand and took it out
and i got my vision good and he said he was this close to my face he said why you
i said do what what just happened he said why you i said what do you mean why me he said
i would have known you were lying if you hadn't had a reaction he said i've never seen a reaction
like this he said i've only ever seen two but yours was by and far different than anybody's
why you i never understood what he meant by why you but he said it three or four times
and from that point on we become friends and done some traveling together and i ended up with him
where is this it's at cape canaveral that building right there that door
is it's very famous at nasa that is the astronaut crew quarter and that building
was built in i think in the 50s so when they were 60s when they put the first rocket in space
when an astronaut rides that rocket they can't they have to be in quarantine for like six weeks
i think so they don't get a cold and the doctors so they have a crew quarters that have bedrooms in
there and a conference room and bathrooms and a doctor's office and when they go in there they
live for weeks with their wife and children and the same house den mother that arranges food and
so there's a lot more pictures of inside that place but he told me that in fact when when we
walked in the front door of it the den mother come up and said how who are you i said i'm his friend
he said how'd he get in here who'd you point to your whose friend tim oh it was me and tim
walked in there and she said who are you i said i'm his friend she said well you know there's only
300 people ever been in this building that's only one u.s president no congress nobody just
300 since its existence that's including all the astronauts and the family members in other words
she was asking why i was going into a place with such security and i couldn't answer it but i
enjoyed the tour i got to sit where john glenn said or uh all of them got to hang out in the
whole place and got to sit where they put their suits on and and then they filmed me coming out
the door that door is where all the astronauts would walk out holding their gear with the suits
on they would walk out that door and get in a an airstream camper van a gas-powered one and they
would be transported from that door to the rocket before they took off so that's a really famous
photo out there so they treated me like royal and i'll give you a secret he told me
he said um he said your life will never be the same when you leave from this place it'll change
you i said what do you mean by that he said well every time these astronauts went to space something
come back with them and it's here it's still here something comes back with them yeah
it's it's invisible but it becomes visible every now and then they see orbs all over the place there
sure do near the at the launch site they see orbs i have pictures of what comes back with them
i don't know i know it it it heightened everything happening with me
i experienced with the phenomenon grew greater understanding of it grew it's the spirit
there's a lot of misunderstanding about these orbs and aliens they um maybe it's technology maybe
but to me it's more like a spirit they're like spirits like ghosts but they can come
full physical did he ever clarify what he meant by why you no he never did he's a secretive guy
man he's he's like a ghost to him that's that's why diana wrote his book wrote her book she didn't
put his name in there oh yeah he was tyler d in american cosmic but you know that's
that was then now the subject is he probably don't like me talking about him but that's okay
it's part of my life and i'm sorry you a good friend of mine tim he never so he never clarified
anything about like them trying to learn more about it and like them being interested and like
why were they interested or why did they make themselves so visible to you and not other people
yeah we went over that a lot you know and and you said there was two other people that experienced
the same thing you experienced with the medals he didn't tell me who he just said i've seen two
other uh in my life i'd seen two other reactions but nothing like yours i remember something from
your book i don't remember in what what it was a reference to but i remember there were you
mentioned a conversation that you had with him when you were at cape canaveral and he
said something like they weren't interested in anyone else like they're we know about them
they're not interested they don't care about us right okay so when he first came remember we were
afraid of government people we were still had how there and i was still petrified about this guy
so i asked him remember we were afraid of the government so i was being tight-lipped and i said
why are you here you know thank you for helping my children thank you for helping junior but why
are you here why do you need me why does the government need me because i was still worried
about the government right everybody's talking that they're going to kill you people have died
and i heard all this but that hadn't been my feeling everybody i'd met had been really nice
people he said because we see them he said we see them but they don't nothing to do with us
zero and we want to study them we want to know more and we would like to study you
and we would suggest you don't go to any ufo events don't go to any conferences don't get
involved because people that go to those tend to take on each other's stories you get somebody
that sees a light fly by during the car and the orb goes over suddenly they involved with names
they're from the galactic federation they were the pleiadians they were the octurians they did
this they did that they know everything about when they only saw a light this happens in the ufo world
and a lot of those things people tend to know more than the experts do you know what i'm saying
yeah so he said we see them but they have nothing to do with us and we'd like to know why they want
you we know they like you we know that and we just want to investigate something so that's
how that happened do you do you have any idea the answer to that question why do they like you
why do they want to communicate with you and not with anybody else i have no idea i've asked that
to a hundred times and how palvin meyer told me one day and he was always very tight-lipped
to how was he would ask a million questions and tell you one answer right that's the way
always was and i'm like how why are they here why did they want me why are they around me like this
all the time uh he said because of your family that's what he told me he said they're probably
your family what that means i don't know and i'll tell you something else how told me serious is
all get out was how mapped the moon he wrote the book on occultation occultation grazing i don't
know how you say that word occultation grazing in other words he wrote many books on the moon
okay so he mapped the moon he mapped the landing spot for the apollo mission
he said you got to land here and he drew out the coordinates that's what how did he studied the
moon more than anybody in the world he's the expert on the moon so we were talking one night
out watching the stars and i'm like hell i said is there really something on the backside the moon
he looked at me and he said they're buildings up there big ones and we didn't build them
and they're ancient ancient ancient so help me that's what he told me and i didn't ask
any more questions but he wouldn't answer he told me that he said there are structures up there
that we did not build and they're very old this coming from the world's expert on the moon
did you ask him if the moon landing was real i never did i never did but he says it was yeah
so i believed him wow wow he had his technology is still on the moon
that he put up there something for lasers to shoot off of and there's stuff up there
scientific equipment that he was responsible for putting up there didn't he say the buildings
look like mushrooms some of them i thought that was really weird some very ancient buildings
that look like mushrooms on the dark side of the moon that's what he said
i said tim um what do you think about the moon is there there's something going on
up there is there structures up there he said he said do you think that it
landed by chance in the perfect spot where it eclipses the sun and it doesn't
ever change its face to the earth it stays locked in a position he said none of that was
by accident he wouldn't elaborate anymore he said but there's something going on up there i can't
say but it's not by accident i knew the moon was a spaceship damn it so wow yeah that's what he
told me so what is it how is it all i don't know we're at the beginning of studying this thing and
what is it we're dealing with who is it how all i can tell you is how it reacts to me
and um wow demonstrate that part so okay getting back to what he told you about music
and keeping music in your head right when why did he tell you to do that because uh along about
2015 i think 2014 or 2015 somewhere in there i get a call from a lady i showed you a picture
today of chris jr walking in a field with him yes and a lady by the name of chase clusky
chase is uh very well known in the ufo world chase cluck clutsky clutsky i have her photo here i can
chase and her husband pete pete worked with the u.s navy in the intel right so
just so just so happened pete's uh tim's at my house and so the day that we were tested would
the bottom one there they are that guy on the right is navy u.s naval sub commander
naval intelligence and tim is right national reconnaissance office nasa
evon my wife and of course emily and this was the 10th grade right uh 11th grade he told them if
they wanted to visit they had to come to my game so they all came and watched me so um
yeah so after that event there uh when was this homecoming october um yeah it would have been
like september october of 2013 so i think it's we fast forward to november of that year
uh chase calls me and says chris you ever heard of saint paul's i said yeah
before you tell me let me tell you something i said chase i said last night saturday night
i was uh sitting on my back patio had a fire going just me laying back looking straight up at
the sky and two orange orbs appeared red ones just like you saw last night those same color
they just appeared just appeared sitting stationary above me up way up and they came on
down and when they got to the top of the trees they stopped now there's these two orange balls
suddenly they flared off straight towards saint paul's just above the trees she said oh my god
i can't believe this i should have known she said um saturday night this was monday night she called
me she said saturday night um i got a call yesterday about a ghost hunter group from
willmont in north carolina willmont and ghost hunters willmont and paranormal i think the name
of the group was they were in saint paul's at an old plantation house investigating ghost
and they walked outside into the woods and there's this old rickety a house that the farm tenants
used to live in it's old i mean it was fallen in but they were in there in the edge of the woods
and these two orange balls of light flew right over their head right over the trees
and it freaked them out when they saw it and suddenly one of them said that this tall being
peeped around the tree at them and they pulled out their guns one of them was a police detective
one was a prison guard but they started shooting at it they were shooting at this
they didn't just had a glimpse of it so they were shooting in the woods you know at this thing
first ask questions later right and so i said uh i said oh my lord she said would you go with me
over there i'm coming next saturday to investigate i said yeah i'd be glad to go with you so saturday
comes friday i'd already called tim i said tim i've got something and i told him the whole story
about seeing the orders at my house and then over saint they went to saint paul's and this
happened to these people he said pick me up saturday morning from the airport so i went to fable
and picked him up saturday morning and we rode over that's the picture you saw them walking
across the field tim chase and chris jr okay so we walked across that field went into these woods and
what i noticed immediately was that the whole place had been timbered except that where the
house sat it was a grove of trees but behind it on behind it had been timbered out and
they went in through the swamps and the cypress pond and destroyed it and it was just a mess in
there and i got the impression that it was because of the destruction of that environment
is the reason they were there who knows why but that's what i told jen he said you think they're
still here i said yeah i think they're still here they haven't gone anywhere he said
what they decided to do was to recreate the ghost hunt that night they wanted us to go
with them and do a ghost hunt so james like i'm going back to alabama so i took him three o'clock
to the airport and he flew back to alabama come in just for the day and that night i went back over
there at six in the evening to do a ghost hunt with them and so that evening i show up and i'm
with the ghost hunting group there are eight of us i'm the eighth person so you got chase and pete
and myself and then five members from womanton the ghost hunter crew came so we were going to
create the whole thing so eight of us they finished the house thing and then we walked
across the field to the the old farm tenant house and here if i can explain it to you
yeah because it's i wrote about this in the book when you walk in the cabin is old and dilapidated
just a one room basically one room cabin it is um 10 feet into the forest in a real thick forest
so you can't see it unless you get right up to it but once you get into the forest there um there's
this old cabin when you walk out the back door couldn't even go in the front you had to go in
and out the back door the front was boarded up but when you step off the steps of the back door that
cabin you walk about six or eight feet is all and then there's a ditch a real big ditch is six
six foot deep and it's dry trees growing up in the ditch it's old but the ditch goes all the way
down the property right behind the cabin less than 10 feet from the back door so they were telling
us after we were recreating everything we went through the the little house and they had all
their ghost hunting equipment inside and they said now we're going to go out the back take you the
same way we went before and tim and i discussed the possibility that these beings were still there
i assumed i told him i thought they were and why they came and uh he said well tonight
to get in a little more depth
um he explained to me that they uh that these beings
uh can hear your thoughts and they can stay hidden from you by knowing what you're thinking
so if you happen to see one by accident they can rewind your memory basically by a device that they
have that i've seen the patents on it patents yep but if you were to sing this song
not let them know what you're thinking might get a chance to see one that's what he told me i've
held this i'm telling you this first time publicly about these little details so that night we walk
out the back door with the ghost hunting crew and i'm in the back i'm in the eighth guy in the rear
chase is imprinting me so she's seven i'm eight but pete he navigates under the world with
submarines right he's got a compass on his arm and so pete's got us in tow and we got to go out of
the back of that cabin and walk across the hundred yards is all of woods that's really thick in that
spot the rest of the forest to the right and left has been timber but we got to walk through that
clump of trees to get to a power line when these big high tension power lines you can see for a
mile the other direction right so it runs parallel with the the cabin field only 100 yards you walk
through it takes 15 minutes to walk that section from the back of the cabin to the power line
it's important i say that because when we started through the woods everything was fine
we're all perfect talking carrying on excited made our way to the power line so when we get
to it we walk up and down the power line for an hour knew we were testing all these equipment
they had these ghost hunters just recreating the whole thing so when it was time to go back
to the cabin we had to go straight east 15 minutes and we would end up at the cabin
we went right back to the spot we went come out at right where we exited onto the power line
we started back in right there pete's in tow with his watch navigating so i'm behind them i'm singing
my song singing singing singing and i noticed everybody got out louder in your head in my head
i noticed everybody got nervous kind of weirded out and they're you know i saw what looked like
they were drawing their guns again getting ready to and what i've learned about this that they can
put fear in you these beings can control what you think so they can make you afraid make you
go a different direction if they don't want you here right they can put fear into you i'm just
repeating what i was told we're starting in 15 minutes across pete's leading the way
i saw him get nervous and that's when i started singing
suddenly i saw this green orb look like eyes peep around the tree i tap chase on the back and pointed
at it she saw it immediately with me next thing i know pete is right at the ditch so when we walked
through that ditch nobody else saw this just chasing us all right she remembers it but when
we crossed that ditch we had 10 feet to walk i mean you could see it was from here to that wall
it's the cabin right but when we got to the ditch and we walked in that ditch when we come out the
other side of the ditch we step back out on the power line and that freaked everyone out it freaked
pete out he's like what just happened he's a he's a submarine commander navigates under the ocean
it blew him away what had just happened i knew what had happened so you basically stepped out
exactly where you started yep yep we pulled it east heading for 15 minutes we got to the ditch
we walked in the ditch and out onto the power line and there's no ditch on the power line side
so what happened they couldn't figure it out but i saw the being and i knew right then we were
missing time what they did is they wiped our mind on the trip across so i didn't tell them that
because once we got to the cabin again we went back across went in the ditch and come back out
the cabin so we made two trips across that power line from the power line to that building
so monday comes along chase calls me chris you'll never believe this i said yeah i will
chase we lost 15 minutes didn't we she said no we lost 12 minutes and they recorded it they had
helmet cans on they had all these stopwatches and they know that we lost 12 minutes of time
with that group of people that night and tim was there tim was there that day oh the day that was
the night after he left yeah and they'll tell the story the same group of people chase tells it
tells about missing time with me that's not the only group that's done that this happened with
several okay so fast forward to when you were going through the security doors at
cape canaveral at nasa there was a black a black glass building that you go that you pass
it was like a hut like a guard shack a guard shack right beside this fence you know you got
mission control and a fence around it we got fences within fences but when you get to the
main building where the launch is going on right they had razor wire and a barbed wire fence
about 10 foot high all the way around that thing with guards standing there with machine guns
and to go through that gate you got to walk by this guard shack and it's about eight by eight
black the middle is black and the windows are black you can't see in it at all but it was like
it was like when you walk by that building they can read your thoughts never told me who they
or what they or how they he just said they can read your thoughts so just sing a song
and that's why i first heard about it this was before the ghost hunting trip so i already knew
about it he just told me to do it again when i was on this was before the ghost hunting trip yeah
what was in the building that could read your thoughts i've had that question ever since i
have no clue this is the kind of way these guys will communicate they give you a little bit is
it a lie or are they throwing me off on a wrong course but they didn't you know it seemed pretty
real what he was telling me so once you were once you got into the building the launch control
center where where tim goes right what what did he show you in there the specific room was there
did he show you specifically where he is and and what he does and what he works on when he's there
yeah so if you can imagine mission control is basically a square it looks like a square
it looks like one of those construction site trailers you would bring on a job but bigger
in a square and there's a hallway right down the middle and glass on either side you got this
hallway with glass big long hallway with glass and if you look to the right is nasa scientist
controlling the launch so you got all these 50 people or however many is in there standing
or sitting at each console like you see on tv same thing on the left side is an exact duplicate
of the right but the left side is all air force so the air force is involved big time with nasa
that's part of the nr o thing i think right so there are all these cadets all these young
soldiers are there learning to to control launches and i got to meet the general there she came out
in the hallway and spoke to me and i was even told how to address her before i got to meet her
and uh which i did and that was pretty cool but there's a room that's a closed off room only
tim goes into how big is the room i don't i didn't get to go into it but i saw it where it was and he
explained to me that was his office and in that office once the launch goes off he has to stand
in his control when that rocket leaves and everything looks good he goes into that room
and it's for his eyes only and the other guys in the nr o that are involved in other ways in other
words when that rocket leaves the ground they have ground-based cameras that looks like giant
binoculars that you sit in and they can sort of swivel and film this rocket right but once it gets
up so high it gets gaseous and they can't see the detail and they want to know every angle of that
thing they want to see every bit they can see in case something goes wrong they know how to fix it
right and um it's how they found that o-ring that leaked and caused the explosion with the shuttle
remember when it blew up they could see challenger yeah they could see the the fuel coming out where
the o-ring stretched but when that rocket gets to 50 000 feet they have um what's called a wb-57
which is a really big it's like an old u-2 spy plane um the huge wings and it just hovers up
there about 50 000 feet a group of guys in ro and they intercept the rocket so when it's going up
and starts going over that rock that wb-57 is right behind it filming it because the ground-based
cameras don't have clear now this airplane has it when it gets on up there about 100 000 feet
they have uh you could see the picture of the 104 starfighter that's it right there
that thing can fly right on up to about 100 000 feet following that rocket that can't
and they chase it keeping a film on it a camera on it the whole time and the rocket's going so fast
it'll outrun it right and it loses sight and then comes the satellite cameras pick it up
and when tim goes into that door his eyes are on every stage of that camera as it's going up and
so he sees if anything from somewhere else up gets nosy and goes up and takes a look or even
shoots it down because it's happened before it's got they've gotten shot down i've seen one
and you saw one get shot down i saw the video
or did is this one that we all know about some people do you won't find it it's been
scrubbed but and what was it shot down by the video i saw was um you see i get a little nervous
here was a rocket this thing was going 15 000 miles an hour and when it arcs over you know
they don't go straight off they go up a ways and then they go over and they fly out gradually
climbing up as they go around the world they don't leave it what i saw was when this rocket
left over the pacific coast i think it was launched out of vandenberg when it went up out of
started over all of a sudden this little flying saucer appears
flies right up to it intercepts it as it's going 15 000 miles an hour flies around it
and a little white lizard beam comes out and shoots it from every side as it's going around
it at 15 000 miles an hour suddenly the whole rocket malfunctions doesn't blow up just quits
and tumbles out to the sea i saw that
what was on this rocket that's what i asked him he said why do you think they did that
i said you have weapons on there and he wouldn't answer that he said well it might
have been a mock warhead but it wasn't live on man yeah
so i saw it with my own eye so that rocket that one out of vandenberg is known it's known there's
people that have seen it before i think i've heard vague vague stories told about that before
it's real i've seen it did you ever have you ever heard or spoke to gary about uh this the research
he's been doing on and the brain scans he's been doing with people that have experienced the
phenomenon where he's noticed a certain part of the human brain i think it's the caudate
potamon or the in the basal ganglia that is uh it's extremely dense with neurons it's different
yeah i'm surprised he spoke about that because that's been kind of secret for a long time
because that's been kind of secret for a long time
yeah well you know they study my brain they're going to start studying hers this year
emily's oh really yeah well i can't say no more but we're just going to say yeah
yeah so so what do they do what's going on here in this photo that i write about in the last
chapter of the book that's uh that's at the monroe institute that whole deal
was um created basically around me that whole week we were there yeah they wanted to
get me up there and see if we could film the phenomenon it's never been done right nobody's
never walked out and had it come and and they film it like that so if they get a video it's by
accident but we were going to do it intentionally and so they invited emily and i and uh some other
people friends of ours that um that came and the rest of the group was while they were dining or
having fun i'm in the lab being wired up right the lab wrap yeah and so when we go out at night we
had orbs appear and they had never seen anything like it they filmed they got sensors sitting on
tops of the mountains random generators and all and they were going off the orbs were up here
and um there is an orb that we filmed a friend of ours named rob freeman he came from canada
he brought a two hundred fifty thousand dollar camera that he bought just to film the phenomenon
so it's all this was a big apparatus of cameras and spectrum all kind of stuff i couldn't even
tell you it was a big setup so um he walks up to me and he says chris he said you know what you've
changed my life he said i want to apologize so i stood up and i said thank you rob uh don't worry
i know but i don't i forgive you i reached out and i hugged him and as soon as i hugged him flash
somebody said look flash so rob runs back to his camera locks it in on this object turns it on and
for 45 minutes that object never moved it said flash flash the star field moved across the sky
but the object never wiggled so you can find that called the monroe flasher on youtube and
that was from that night when rob and i uh and we made a great bond i mean i'm gonna be with rob
again this november yeah the monroe flasher on youtube can you you got you got safari maybe
we should look at it oh wow this is like uh some sort of like analysis video somebody made talking
about it okay now these are so this is that 250 thousand dollar camera that this guy brought out
here yep see if it flashes there it is you see it in one spot you can enlarge the screen you can
see it better it varied in intensity to how bright it flashed yeah wow it's so tiny well it was way
up there right but it got bigger and brighter at times a lot brighter about the same distance
is the one we saw last night no these are further up further this is way up there
but the thing is that there was 45 minutes of it and there's parts of that is a whole lot brighter
and bigger but mufon canada which is where he's from certified it true and all and so
but that was a story there that what we were doing was filming with scientists government
scientists a whole lot of them using sensors and all to record this for the first time now were
they using some of the same technology that andy was using during the filming of that show where
they were kind of tracking it against the faa and against satellites to make sure it wasn't planes
or satellites i didn't see one of those they may have had it because they had sensors on the
mountains and so on right but yeah can you play that video from last night it's on there it's in
there it's uh there's like i think there's three videos but there's two of them is it in here
yeah it's in there it's the 50 oh no never mind steven has them okay steve i do
steven's got him he'll get him queued up so yeah so we sat out there for maybe
30 minutes before before we saw anything and then all of a sudden these things started appearing
on the horizon and there was a couple a couple things that happened over our head looked like
shooting stars yeah that's as orbs a lot of times because they'll they'll go straight up
see if we got audio going on here
what's cool is this uh this there's the surf you can see yeah oh it's uh the contrast is like crazy
it's like darkened on the screen yeah you see the horizon okay there you go
so so the planes were far above this this was very very low on the horizon and you can see
the planes that are there were airplanes above it uh find the one that's the longest one the 52nd
one that one has it a two in it there are two orbs in that right right and the first one's
right on the water in fact i don't doubt that it didn't come from the water
it didn't come from the water
as you know what's weird is you just had asked me about that
right before right about the water what do i think about the water and then we get one
right on top of the water so that thing was right above the horizon and it was
getting really bright and then getting going invisible going dim yep and airplanes don't do
that nope nope and and you could we could we know that because there was literally airplanes
coming in for landing that would turn on their their bright headlights for that their landing
approach or whatever it's called in that 52nd video you can actually see planes all around it
flying up above it there was one there top right you see that little flash that's your that one
was flashing yeah let me see if i can get the the the older one the the the bigger one yeah
working because that doesn't make sense why it wouldn't so what what is the connection
do you think you talk a lot about in your book this sort of which which it got me
wrapped up in this edward this ed casey thing um with the healing power what is the connection
with this ability to heal how real is that and and and was tim involved in any of that with
some of the stuff that he was doing with the medical research and the medical patents
well yeah in a way um how that came about was in 2013 easter again one year later remember 2012
on easter i had the lady experience right she came and told me about the red star or the star of
regulus and um um granted me the ability to record this stuff she did it it came straight
from her 2012 well 2013 she comes back this time she takes me these beings take me
somehow i'm transported from my home up through the top of my house i saw the rafters i went
was pulled up into a ball of light next thing i know we're um
touching down from this orb and walk out of it into this desert environment looked like utah
i have been obsessed for five years with utah more than that now my kids know this
okay so here's the video you got it pulled up steve yeah it doesn't play on the computer but
it does plan dropbox so here okay here we go
okay so you see a is that a that's a plane that's an airplane two planes now that thing comes right
out of the water yeah right up out of the ocean there's a planes around it
now it's going to disappear but if you'll look to the right of it here in a second there's a
second one right close to it that appears there it comes now it's going to appear down disappears
than that one yeah what that like it gets real bright
yeah those are your orbs and see these planes right above it they can see that that's why
they're so elusive i mean we there's three planes four planes in the picture and then you got this
one or and then i think it goes out again right yeah yeah just disappeared
there but i don't know how you can explain that away with logic you can't you can't and if you
maybe tonight we go out sky watching again maybe i'm hoping something comes much closer like
real close well we were we were right on indian rocks beach in front of a lot of really bright
buildings and condos and there was lots of airplanes so yeah we were on the main flight path
right right but um it's pretty amazing for that to show up with all of that around
yeah i knew it was a hamper though because all these planes around now what do
them like the most hardcore skeptics say about these things do they what do they try how do
they try to explain these things well you know there are hardly no skeptics anymore
i don't really have that issue um okay um the main thing i hear now is this demon you're dealing
with demons because they've already accepted the fact that there is something there happening
it was like satellites or at one point someone said swamp gas ball lightning yeah all this
ball lightning yeah but now it's like oh there maybe is something happening but it's evil
yeah it's got to be evil it's got to be a demon there are videos on youtube you can watch about
ball lightning where people show these balls in their house these light that explode they show
up and they float around and they explode away but in your situations there was no thunderstorms
there was no lightning no and and this is every day i mean yes i've recorded this stuff every
single day i showed you my sonics happen there are 2700 videos in less than 24 months
that's a lot and i could have taken twice that because half the time i don't even record we see
we'll see 10 times more than i ever record because a lot of times it's so fast you can't get it on
camera it'll come by you it'll appear 10 feet away and zoom right by your face that quick
happens with crowds of 20 30 70 70 people i've had it appear around and 20 feet away and it happens
at significant moments so it's like why would ball lightning respond to specific questions thoughts
emotions right and and yeah so this is a new day the people now are knowing there's something there
and so the skeptics have mainly gone bye-bye most of them and the ones that are skeptical more
would be the scientist because they just the paradigm don't allow anything there right in
fact i think between you and i one reason they don't that they've hid this so long and don't
want to tell it because it's not the people that would melt down it's not me and you it's not
alice in the mobile home park down the street or the average person they would say oh boy
wonderful and then tomorrow they're back grocery shopping yeah but it's the scientific community
it's the academic world that has spent their life in college and teaching people about evolution
and all these far old things that they're still teaching that so far they got to change everything
so half the community that's teaching this would be lost where do we go from here
you know so i think the meltdown would be there more than the average people another and another
thing people say about this is that if this was to become accepted in within humanity it would
destroy all religion but what you see now with like going back to even the vatican is that
they are looking into astronomy i mean there's a there's an observatory at the vatican and
they're looking at the stars and they're talking about the idea of extraterrestrial life and you
know they even say like if god could have created us and it could create ants and caterpillars why
couldn't create other beings that are somewhere else in the galaxy that are even intelligent
right you can't limit god's creative freedom and and you know the vatican is kind of becoming
you know the religion it it is not counterintuitive it is not counter to the idea of
extraterrestrial life or another sort of multi-dimensional life form or being or entity
that lives parallel to us so when you think about that i don't necessarily believe that
it would have a negative effect on established religions today i think it will for the the
strictness of people you got religions that are pure cults that um you know only we're going to
go to heaven you know these baptists over there they can't make it or these these are them you
know they're you know you believe like us or you're going to burn in hell they don't even
rationalize when it comes to this stuff it's just straight by that book and they'll be the ones that
would have the most to deal with i think because they don't have room for any deviation
of possibilities other than what that book says example in our area north carolina in the mountains
you have these snake charmers snake handlers churches that get together and they pull out
rattlesnakes and they're sitting there dancing with rattlesnakes and about every year two or three of
them fall over dead but they still believe because the book says if you believe in Jesus
you can drink poison and you won't die or you can take up a serpent and he'll bite you and you won't
die but yet they get several a year fall out dead because of it but they still go right back and do
the same thing and if you brought anything else into their belief spectrum you're probably going
to melt their their brain didn't you also say that some like sometimes beings come out of the
orbs yeah i have a video one coming out of an award do we have that i have it on my phone right
here um i don't know how you're gonna i can download is this the same video dad this photo
no that's not it now that's a pretty interesting photo though if you want to show that well i'll
find this well i have this one that we showed them yesterday oh is this the one of the person
walking through the woods it was very dark but yeah this person right here you can see is our
friend lori yeah and um we're uh i wasn't there but this was in a wooded area behind our old home
so it's a little shady here but you can see the light daylight outside beyond the trees but this
figure here was not anyone in our party um so whenever they looked at the photo later there
was just this fully fledged figure standing in front of lori and also this peculiar flash of light
appeared um right behind her right turn your airdrop on if you know how they're
it's on and i'm gonna send you what you're gonna see here this video she's getting now
okay is this the video thing coming out of the orb no she's should be getting it now okay this
video then that one okay now let me tell you before you start this what you're gonna see
okay i write about this in my book there was a lady by the name of sharon very close to
me in this family we met her i met her in a chapter in the book about how this bible college
tried to set me up and it backfired on them the whole audience left with me and left them sitting
but one of the ladies there was sick had kidney cancer and her cancer her she had one kidney
already removed and her second kidney was already massive size with cancer and her
chemo wasn't working so she was looking at death and i met her on saturday night it's in the book
there's a lot about it but um sunday morning or monday morning she went in for a scan and it was
gone her kidney cancer was gone and um she was healed from it so a couple years later she calls
me and we stayed in touch but she had cancer had come back in her lungs and she had stage four
lung cancer and um she called me worried she had to go in for a scan on monday this next monday
and said can i come to your house can i come for prayer i want you to help me because word had
gotten around about this healing thing which we bypassed earlier oh yeah we need to go back
yeah so she shows up from two hours away on friday evening with or saturday evening with her
half a dozen friends it was about five or six of them in total all ladies
i had three native american friends we were born in i was born in robinson county which is
uh where the tuscaroras are from north carolina's tribe is there so wonderful people i was raised
with them all my life and three of them actually called me and said can we come by we want to see
the burning tree i said absolutely perfect time to come because i have a lady that's sick and we
all said prayer for so they show up at my house and uh sharon is standing on my left
and her friend one of them standing on my right where i'm right between these two ladies
and everybody else is meandering around it's about eight or ten people there more
and you'll hear the natives standing at the burning tree singing singing there whatever
they're singing so chant and at 31 seconds in the video you'll see an orb appear
six foot away right in front of us and it's rotating they're always spinning
and it comes right up to me five or six foot from me and then flashes when they flash like
that is when these beings step out of these orbs so the being comes out of the orb and now the
orb is inside the being so you can see this translucent figure with the orb inside
and so that's how they come i've seen them many times do this and it moves to my left out of
screen right in front of sharon and on monday morning all her cancer was gone but one tiny
little speck and she's cancer-free today how long after again how long after was it all gone
it was it was gone all these masses in her lungs were gone but one tiny little speck
how many days later the weekend that monday morning wow okay so you'll hear them singing
here and then watch at 31 seconds it'll flash but there's you have to stop it and play with it to
see the six foot tall seven foot tall light being that comes out of that orb okay i'll try my best
so
can't hear it
right about here oh i got one finally now slow it down everyone don't you see the orb that's the orb
all right there's the being during the flash and they don't show it as good on this screen
for some reason yeah the screen is very bright on here but yeah if you can look at that you can see
um the full-blown being legs arms and all really yeah i don't know if i can turn it to you
see how bright that orb is yeah so wait where's the beam there's the beam to the left of the screen
this is inside the being now this or can you go frame by frame if you hit the side arrows on the
keyboard see on the on the bottom left of the keyboard itself yeah go yeah you can go frame
by frame there go back the other way to what appears come on back you'll see the orb appear
and approach us all right now right here the orb appears i've already backed up so i'll back up again
and then to before and it flashes and then we're before now okay this is headed forward okay now
we're going forwards orb appears flash there's one flash yeah it's like one frame yeah now it's
gonna go away so go back to that one that so during that one frame is when you're saying you see the
being yeah yeah but that frame right there is the being and now the orb stays inside of the being
and you can see if you look at it on a good shot a good camera or a computer you can see
a translucent figure move and the orb is with it yeah right there we can only see like a sliver of
something right but you can see the difference on this computer right yeah you can huh but that
that was right that was in 2014 i think remember i couldn't share anything before 2012 right after
2012 i began to share it with everybody but when 2013 comes along the lady comes again
and she takes me to some desert place which i perceive as utah i'm pretty sure it is i've been
obsessed with it and i think she's going to come back and i'll be able to film her there
that's bizarre yeah it's pretty crazy so sharon um what did you make of her being healed of the
cancer of literally two days later um that's why she came that's why she came yeah and
see let me say this in 2013 when the lady came back and i went about this take me to utah
when i saw her she imparted another thing on me that i didn't may have had it before but i
didn't realize it until two weeks later this is how it arose and this is what got nasa tim involved
with the health thing um easter 2013 i had the experience with her again may the fifth i think
it was just a few days later less than two weeks later this investigator from canada calls me and
wants to come by and visit he's on the way to miami and we live right along 95 so it was five
minutes off 95 for him he said can i stop i'm leaving washington going to miami i'm just sure
stay a night if you want so he did and my labrador nelly was um this is nelly she was walking along
beside us we went out to the tree and he must have took 20 pictures of the tree and we talked for 15
20 minutes standing there nelly was laying on the ground beside me we get back to the edge of the
patio we walked all the way back about 75 yards out there so when we would get back to the patio
my kids are on the patio hanging out sitting around grant and i stopped right at the edge of
the cement nelly stops and she's laying there beside me she walked everywhere we went she'd
walk and stop and lay down so i looked at grant i said grant kids are here you want us to help
you get your bags you can go ahead and put them in the house and use the bathroom whatever he's
like yeah why not so he's between me in the house i'm looking at him at the back door so he turns
his back and he starts towards the door nelly stands up off the ground and when she walked by
i saw blood shoot out of her neck in a long stream and it wet the whole side of his pants
went right by grant and wet his pants and i had pictures of it and she left the trail of blood
going in and ran in the back door now dogs will get in front of you and try to go in before you
do well that's what she did door was wide open blood spraying everywhere and i freaked out oh my
god what's happening to my dog and i ran in and i tackled her she got five or six feet in the back
door when i grabbed her blood all over the floor and it a laminate floor it's like slipping on
grease and i picked her up it was all i could do to get her up because i was dealing with rheumatoid
then and it was just a struggle i made it to the patio and i laid her down and i looked at her
neck and she had a hole maybe inch and a half two inches long a gash across her vein right there
and blood is just pouring out so i laid my hand on her neck and blood pouring up through my
fingers like this and feel her heartbeat and she wanted she was just kind of squirming but
she won't fighting too hard i look up at them and i realized that she was going to die i knew it
because they wouldn't call a no ambulance there wasn't no time to get her to the doctor we lived
20 miles or 20 minutes from anywhere and everybody's freaked out grant sitting there taking pictures
he's recording this whole thing and i said what am i going to do and i looked up at the sky and
i said lord what am i going to do she's going to die right here and as soon as i said that i felt
this energy come through my hand and i felt her go completely limp and when i raised my hand there
was no more hole in her neck nothing it was gone everybody witnessed it and it freaky there i was
not there no but all her brothers was a weird story to come home to though yeah i will say but
there was a lot of witnesses to it grant and a ufo investigator from canada is one of the most
famous out there he's the one that saw it all he took that picture i didn't and there are more
pictures of it of the blood going in the house and all and um but we couldn't figure out what happened
at all how did she get the hole in her neck what did that uh what i didn't know who to call so i
called tim i said tim the craziest thing that's happened today you won't believe this
that's uh this is the same dog it's so pixelated on that screen but anyhow he told me he said chris
he said maybe the phenomenon was showing you you have a gift that you need to try to do something
with and so that changed my life that year to um this was 2014 to uh where it is today that's what
i do i've done more um i'm trying to help people who are sick than i ever reveal or talk about it's
every day of my life i have people write me people who are sick people i go and visit and
and try to help and i've seen some miracles happen why me i don't know what caused it i don't know
but it is and it happened and immediately tim's like you need to follow this and that's what got
me involved with him with um his encouragement to help get me to help others and to working on his
project he was working on for stem cells and it just led from a two three weeks later a month later
i get a call from the guy in that great big house you were wearing it wondering about and said we
have a child in washington that's sick and he's from a prominent family and uh we want you to see if
you can help him i'm like lord i don't know what to do this is all new to me i have no clue what
has happened how did this all happen why you know what do i do he said well you just need to come
try i'm like well it's fourth of july my family's coming home the weekend all the kids we're gonna
do something and uh he's like what's more important you know hanging out and partying
or helping some child that is it's got to make a wish he's going to die he's not going to live
past 12 13 years old i said well you got me there so next day i was on an airplane to washington
and i was sitting at that young boy in the bottom right there to his left is jim semivan
this whole party is uh that was his bar mitzvah was the heads of the cia the director my brother
ryan and this is mike morel the deputy director this little boy is right in there group of people
and so when i got to his house i was terrified i don't know what to do i know where to start
you know i've been asked to do this what the heck do i do i don't even know how i help the dog
much less to help a child or somebody sick and so i've sat there with him and his mom and dad
for several hours just talking and feeling out the situation and silently praying lord help me
um you got me into this how do i deal with this what do i do and this voice said not an audible
voice but just something spoke to me and said just hug him just reach out and hug him
and so i waited till the perfect time to do so and i reached out and i hugged him real good
and he couldn't eat couldn't eat hadn't been able to eat most of his life at all if he eat
he would throw up he had this mitochondrial dna disease which was your body just doesn't
digest food and get the nourishments from it so usually they don't live past 12 13 years old
they're dead and so he had to make a wish and this group of people pulled around him
and he's in college now he's completely healed he's fine wow yep
mm-hmm
and it is a lot more to it in that party right there you see all these people there are hundreds
in there people hundreds of washington washington dc the most prominent intel folks um judges doctors
cardiologists his grandpa was their cardiologist and i'm sitting at a table
um next to jim's table there's just these big round white tables with cloths with jewish flags
and it was just i never been to a bar mitzvah but um the table behind me i heard this ruckus
and the band they were dancing just like that whole crowd you know they knew how to party and
they were having the best time i'm sitting watching my children have fun and
i heard this ruckus next thing i know um jim's wife debbie grabs me said picks me up basically
and pulls me to this other table and said you got to help this guy and he was slumped over face down
i mean alcohol completely uh turned white and they were trying to revive him couldn't get him away
and uh they drug me through the crowd and i put my hands on his shoulders very inside did he
he set up and took a big breath and they looked at me and said my god you you saved him that
that happened in that party
wow yep
we're dead that's heavy in front of these people imagine
that's washington how do you how do you even deal with that like being you
and that happening like how how do you even comprehend that i don't
i don't
yeah
that's amazing man
man that's helped a lot of people and he he doesn't always talk about it because
he's afraid of sounding like you know that he does special things he doesn't want the credit for it
but he really has put a lot of energy and a lot of effort into helping people um not always in
front of people either you know behind closed doors right most of it's private he's very
very emotional when it comes to that understandably
this little boy he's in his 20s now he's a junior in college wow yep
but now i don't know i don't know dan i have no clue sorry dad it's always interesting when
when people ask us what our experience is you know they expect us to say we see ufos and aliens
but it's so much more complicated than that and it comes down to this sort of thing as well how do
you explain that to someone in a 10-minute you know conversation that it also is so spiritual
and there's like a healing aspect to it it's so multifaceted that i don't think people can really
wrap their heads around it but if like anyone could try to understand from a base perspective
it's just like that this is a benevolent spiritual experience that is open to everybody
that for some reason we are you know i guess semi-responsible for sharing and promoting to people
is there if it were evil why would we be why would he be able to heal people you know yeah
yeah well i don't see it as me doing it it's this phenomenon maybe whether you're a vessel
or whether you're doing it it's like happening around us and so i'm not saying necessarily you
have powers or anything but there is evidence and facts that you for some reason are surrounded by
healing and if this were an evil sort of phenomenon why would this happen yeah be happening
it's it's really hard to comprehend all of this i mean it's it's so mind-blowing
yeah it's it's incredible it's incredible um and there's there i know like we talk about this a
little bit last night but um there's people who try to gain this or or tap into this phenomenon
the same way you do right like i know tim there's diana talked about in her new book how tim
he has like a protocol that he tries to follow to try to like cleanse his spirit and and meditate
and be in the sunlight to where he can sort of people can can learn or train themselves to tap
into into something else that you are just intuitively you're already hardwired into it
yeah and in one way or another well that's what this they're studying my brain for right they know
it's connected um on the history channel thing the scientist said he's can just you know buddhist
monk studies 30 years of his life to get to this enlightened state and they said well he just goes
in it instantly just at my fingers and i'm there and i don't understand it i don't know that i'm
even doing that i just i don't i don't understand but that's questions i don't know and right i try
to stay away from that i just had the i have a mission to share this and the way it comes
you know well i can't wait to go out and watch the sky with you guys again tonight
tell you that much yeah thank you so much for coming on here and sharing the story we just
talked about it for like four hours i think yeah um i will link your book ufo of god below for
people to check it out i highly recommend it one of the most gripping books i've ever read it's
phenomenal appreciate that thank you for writing it and thanks again is there anything else that
i should any anything else i should tell people about to get a hold of you guys or find you guys
online yeah you can find my website is ufo of god.com and there you can find a link to amazon
to buy the book or you can go straight to amazon or wherever books are sold i guess
but um you can find me on tiktok i post about this stuff my name is blood so baby
because i'm the baby you know um so i post stuff relevant to the story on there and then i have a
website um called emilyholloway.com where i teach voice but we do have one announcement
before we go and then we'll we're good so the also on my website you can find my instagram
where i post videos there's a few hundred videos or photos on there i'll make sure i link all those
below yeah and um this uh i think we can just go ahead and talk about this without getting into
any details this book has been uh is in the is in the process of making a motion picture
oh wow yeah exciting yeah this is our first we got the go ahead to just say that much and that's
all we're allowed to say okay this is the first time publicly we're admitting that there is a
motion picture teasing me i can't wait it's under development right now okay well you have to keep
me posted rumor is it might be three parts three shows wow yeah exciting stuff see where it goes
well cool i hope uh i hope this helped get the word out and uh again i can't thank you guys enough
thank you honestly i appreciate it wonderful all right goodbye world