When you calculate the speed that this thing goes by, by the way, it was bigger than the offshore
oil derrick it was passing by. This has to be moving between 450 and 550 knots underwater.
He reported that they have specific psionic teams taking these things, at least bringing
them into range to where they can take them down. Is that something that you've been read into in
the past? What would be another reason other than national security for it to be classified?
We were going to set a trap for these things. We knew that having a huge nuclear footprint
in the middle of the ocean would be irresistible. Have you seen, heard, or know of any other egg
type crafts at ATIP? Yes. More than one? Oh boy. Have you ever noticed, seen, heard of,
or heard whispers of any type of language or symbols apparent on these craft? Yes.
If I show you a picture, can you confirm or deny? This is an image, this is zoomed in.
This is really interesting. When I was at the Pentagon, I spent considerable time
researching ancient script. You were aware of craft that had script on it at ATIP? Yeah,
it's pretty undeniable at this point. Was it written or engraved in these crafts?
No, it wasn't engraved, it wasn't written. If you're holding on to that type of clear imagery,
it really cements the idea that it's a planned dissemination to the public. You got to peek
behind the curtain, we did not. It involves our own potential religion, it involves life and death,
it involves why we're here, it involves the questions of the universe, it involves the most
important things that humanity has ever asked for, and you potentially had one of the closest
encounters with the answer. This is important. That's what I'm trying to tell people. Don't put
that responsibility on my shoulder. I'm just like you. I'm not a messiah, man. My job is simply as
a purveyor of the information. How you interpret that and what you think about that, brother,
that's on you, not me. Some people's frustration, my guess, is that you have that luxury of
formulating some type of answer that they would love to formulate themselves. Makes sense? Yeah,
good point. And there's also a lot of trust me, bro. You're going to get hate, by the way,
as I promise you, just for having me in your studio and having this conversation.
For me, this is not only a pursuit for them, this is a pursuit for myself as well. I want to know.
There have been some people who have made suggestions to conduct illegal activities to
cover this topic up, and it's going to come out in a few months. I do a lot of work behind the
shadows, behind the scenes, whether it's a new whistleblower that maybe I've been aware of for
the last few years or a secret project that will hopefully blow the lid on a lot of this,
whether through a documentary, getting the right people to have the conversation.
Can you shed any light on what's to be expected in this documentary?
There's people that are being interviewed that have never come out publicly on this topic.
That we've not seen on the trailer?
We've not seen on the trailer.
Jay Stratton does say.
I have seen with my own eyes, non-human craft and non-human beings.
Do you know what he's referring to? Have you yourself seen NHI? Why doesn't the government
talk about Balbazar? 2027 has been thrown around. Can you shed a little bit of light on this
just so we can stop being paranoid or we can start being paranoid?
Let me see if I can thread the needle on this.
Sure. How can I phrase this in a way that you can answer this?
Are you aware of more than one type of NHI?
Okay. Let me see how I can answer this.
Wow. Accuracy is very important.
What I'm gathering from this is
there are potential that some of these NHI might look a lot like us.
What else you want to know?
You know what this reminds me of? Reminds me a bit of like an interrogation.
That's kind of what I wanted it to be. I call it the skiff.
I love it. Obviously, not a skiff.
Too many recording devices here for it to be a skiff. We know that.
But it wouldn't be the first time you, sir, have ventured a skiff, would it?
No, unfortunately. This is a lot nicer than a skiff.
Is it?
People are like, oh, you've been in skiffs and SAPF facilities. I'm like, look,
actually, they're really boring. Most of them don't have windows. They don't have any electronics.
You can't bring anything in there. So yeah, I mean, you can't even play like Solitaire on
your computer, right? Because all that stuff has been removed out of it. So I was like, oh, shit.
How's the coffee compared to the skiffs?
So I think you probably already know this. Being Latino, genetically, there's three things we do
very well coming out of the womb. One is drinking strong coffee. The other one is being able to dance
salsa and merengue. It's genetic for us.
You dance salsa and merengue?
Yeah. And then the third thing, I look more like a weevil wobble out there on the dance floor.
And then the third thing I probably can't talk about because it's not appropriate.
Those are the three things that Latinos can do very well usually.
I'll take your word for the last two.
Yeah. My days of dancing, unfortunately, once you get older and your knees start to fail,
you gain a little bit of weight in the places that really aren't very conducive for dancing.
I hear it. I hear it. I'm definitely also absent on the dance floor.
All right. Let's get this started. I'm here with Lou Elizondo. Is it Luis Elizondo?
You know, Chris, you can call me Bob, Bill, Joe. I don't care. My real name is Luis. I hear that
usually when I'm in trouble with my wife. Okay, gotcha.
Most people call me Lou because I look like I'm from Iowa. People realize my family's Cuban.
They're like, what? You don't look like a Luis. I know, I know.
Lou's got a nice ring to it. I'll call you Lou so that people who are listening know who I'm
talking to. Thank you so much for being here, first of all. For those of you who aren't aware
of Lou and what he's done, I highly recommend you check out his book, which we got here.
We'll be signing a few copies as well, and I'll let you know later in the episode how you guys can
grab them. But if you want to pick one up, there's a link below. Lou, bestselling author,
Eminent was amazing. I read through it, and I also listened to the audio version.
I'm sorry, you had to deal with that. I tell people I have the silky smooth voice of a
cement truck hurtling down a country road with no brakes.
I think you did a great job. I think it also helps sort of personify your story and humanize
it in a certain way that we get to hear it authentically. I always prefer that. I remember
listening to Communion by Whitley Strieber, and it was him reading his book too. It just conveys,
I think, a little bit more of the gravitas of the story when it's the person themselves narrating.
I appreciate that, but I also want to say thank you for taking the opportunity to speak with me,
and I also want to thank, even more importantly than you and me, is your audience.
You know, I think these types of interviews are very important because it allows all of
us to connect. I mean, obviously, not everybody listening is right here with us, but I hope they
get the sensation that they really are part of this conversation. We're only having this
conversation really because of them, and I think it's really important that we recognize
the value of, you know, we live in amazing times right now. You have the ability now,
whereas even just 10 years ago, mainstream media, right, major, major networks like where I live
down ABC and CBS and NBC, you have more people tuning into you than most of these mainstream
outlets. So you have a very important voice, and the audience is arguably the most important
aspect of this, right? These are people that want to hear what you have to say week after week and
whatnot. And really, that is why we are where we are today in the conversation, because this has
been a, whatever this conversation is, it's really been a, it's been a grassroots movement.
And ultimately, it is because of your audience and people like that, we are where we are today
in the conversation about UAPs. Yeah, well said, and thank you. Thank you for saying that. And I
think, you know, part of the reason people are listening, you know, if not to tune into me, is
definitely to hear from you. And I think right now, especially, you know, we've been faced with
a lot of news recently in the UAP space specifically. And, you know, it's been,
it's been snowballing ever since the latest congressional hearing, which obviously you were
a big part of. And you attended, if I'm not mistaken. I did attend. Yeah, it was kind of
surreal for myself. I did have, you know, an immense amount of imposter syndrome, being
a Canadian magician, content creator, sitting in the front row, you know,
course side seats to something so monumental was, I mean, humbling. Of the 366 sightings
included in the report, 171 remain uncharacterized. And many high ranking individuals in the military
and intelligence communities believe UAPs demand greater attention.
Are contractors, are they pulling technology from this? Are they reverse engineering this?
But more importantly, after that, you know, it's these congressional hearings are very important,
but arguably what's more important, it's what they do with that information. And where that sort of,
you know, I'm sure you're sick of hearing this, but where that moves the needle.
And I think recently, you know, we've had a lot of people come forward, numerous people have come
forward to share their stories as well, in hopes to move the needle. And so today, I've got a lot
of questions that I'm hoping that we can get through. Sure. And you've been, and I got to say
for the audience listening, and by the way, if I'm ever looking over here, it's just to make sure
everything's recording because I'm a one man team here. So if ever, if you ever see me looking like
this is because I'm looking over my shoulder, I'm looking over my back, it's paranoia.
Yeah, sounds good. We're safe here. But one thing I did want to mention was that Lou, prior to the
interview, said something very important. I think a lot of people should know, and this is not
something that's usually recorded, but Lou said, I don't want to read your questions before.
You don't have to cut anything out. Ask me anything you want. And if I don't answer something,
I'll tell you why it is I can't answer it. And I think that's just so important that you respect
the journalistic integrity to that extent, especially after being put through ringer
after ringer podcast after podcast and being grilled on things that you legally can't talk
about. I think it just goes to show some level of character there. And I think a lot of people
would omit that in an interview, they wouldn't, they wouldn't allow that they would want to have
final say they would want, you know, certain boundaries to be put on, especially in the
position that you're in. Well, that's because they're trying to protect themselves. And in reality,
this conversation is much bigger than any one person. And this is what I've said over and
over again to people, I could get hit by a bus tomorrow. And disclosure, this transparency
effort that we're all a part of must go on the show must go on. And so my part of this
is very simple. Speak the truth, whatever that truth is, speak the truth, and let the
chips fall where they fall. And I think it's important from a journalistic integrity perspective,
that that be maintained and preserved at all costs. And this is why I've always made it a rule.
Say, look, you're not going to pay me to do anything like this. You know, great, if you
pay my hotel, that's great, you know, but other than that, I'm, I don't get payment for this.
People are like, Oh, you're making all these monies doing this. No, I'm not. I'm actually
doing it for free. I'm actually leaving work aside to come out and have these types of
conversations where I don't get paid. And then also having questions that are a lot of people
want to know ahead of him. What are you going to ask me? Are you going to ask me any trick questions?
You know what? To hell with that. I don't care. Ask me whatever you want. And if I don't know,
I don't know. And I'll tell you that honestly, or if I can't tell you, I'll tell you that too.
And I think that this topic demands that type of, I cannot in good faith demand transparency from
the United States government. If I myself am not willing to be transparent, right? It's hypocritical.
You can't, it doesn't work that way. So I appreciate that. And I'm sure my audience
is going to appreciate that as well. So for the next few hours, folks, strap yourselves in.
We're going to try to get through these questions and hopefully, you know, get some answers for
those of you, you know, seeking some answers. Let me start off. Let me just start off by asking a
question a little bit off target here, but are you familiar or have you been familiar in the past
with any 4chan or Reddit leaks, quote unquote? I am, I am familiar tangentially with the forms
of 4chan and also Reddit. I am not a subscriber and that's not a good or bad thing. I'm not
necessarily, you know, poo pooing it or promoting it. I just, I, my bandwidth is very limited. Also,
I'm an older guy. This is gray, not blonde. So I'm a little dude. I'm not overly technically
proficient as most people will tell you, especially my wife. You know, when people are using
scientific calculators, I'm still using an abacus, right? I'm an older generation. So
more than the typical social media engagement now, if it involves Reddit or 4chan, it's beyond me,
but I am aware that sometimes information comes out that can be very interesting.
And you say that can be very interesting. Has there been a time where you're like, oh damn,
that guy slipped up. He shouldn't have said that. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. But you know what? At the end
of the day, look, I think, I think sunlight is, is the best antiseptic sometimes. I think it's
the best way to get rid of an infection. Sure. And so I've never proposed or never supported
the idea of leaking anything, anything classified. I am a patriot. I still have my security clearance
and I will never support the leaking of classified information, but there's a difference between
information that is classified for righteous and legal purposes, right? To protect sources
and methods and whatnot. And then there is the abuse of that system where people will classify
things simply because they're trying to hide or cover malfeasance or embarrassment, right?
And that's a problem because that, that information shouldn't be classified and it's
being classified in an illegal manner. There are very specific prohibitions because in the past,
my country has abused the classification system to hide the truth from the American people,
whether it's Iran Contra and Oliver North or even recently my, some of my work in Guantanamo Bay
and maybe some of the methods used to get information from, from individuals.
And there was no reason that should have been classified. The only reason why they classified
some of that was because we're embarrassed. We didn't, we didn't want to admit what we were doing
and how we were doing it. And so in those cases, when that information comes to the public's
attention, I'm okay with that provided they're not violating any laws of real classification,
right? If information is classified illegally, then that really isn't classified.
So when it comes to the UAP subject, what would be another reason other than national security for
it to be classified? Wow. So, okay. Great question. But it's not a simple question. It's not a simple
answer either. It's multifaceted, a bit like a diamond really. And so you have to, in order
to understand this topic, you need to understand a little bit about the history and where our
country was in the state of the world at the time, right? So really the UAP topic for the
United States government really started to kick into high gear right around the end of World War II
and the development of the atomic bomb for our country. That's when we really started noticing
an increased frequency of UAP interest in our capabilities. Now, where were we at the end of
World War II? Well, the U.S. had just become really a global superpower and had the opportunity to
dominate a lot of the world politics for about 10 years. That was until the Russians very quickly
afterwards developed the atomic bomb too, right? So now it's no longer U.S. preeminence. Now there's
this competition and what begins the Cold War, which by the way, most people don't realize,
wasn't really a Cold War at all. It's pretty hot. We had proxy wars going all over the place,
whether it's Korean War and Vietnam and things like that. And it was kind of this winner takes
all chess game. Now you have a beautiful chess set here. Your audience can't see it, but
you can imagine this Cold War as being an invisible chess match with the Russians. And you
had the United States on one side and NATO, and you had the Warsaw Pact and then Soviet Union on
the other side. And it was kind of this winner takes all mentality. And so what we didn't want
to do was broadcast to our enemies, our adversaries at the time, that we were dealing
with this UAP topic. We didn't want to let them know what we knew about it and more importantly,
what we didn't know, where those intelligence gaps lay. And furthermore, the Soviet Union felt the
same way, but we both understood each other enough to realize that in the 60s, when we started to
develop really the Northern tier radar systems, early warning systems for nuclear attack,
both the Soviet Union and the United States realized that, hey, we better come to the table
at least a little bit on this, because what we don't want to do is set up these radar systems,
very sophisticated radar systems. And then all of a sudden a UAP is picked up by one of these
radar systems, either ours or the Russians. And all of a sudden we could get confused for some
sort of nuclear strike or nuclear attack. So there was enough, I think, wisdom there where
the United States and Russia, in a secret memo, in one of the paragraphs, they actually say,
look, if you happen to see something before you press that nuke button, do us a favor,
give us a call, because it might be a UFO and we don't want to start World War III,
because either one of us confuses us some sort of provocation. And then you have the other issue
during the 50s and the 60s and the nuclear age, nuclear family in the United States.
Our government was dealing with a lot of things. We were dealing with civil rights. We were dealing
with equity issues between genders. We were dealing with anti-war movements with Vietnam
and even before that. And you had also had the hippie movement, which was really kind of this
anti-establishment effort, just kind of, can't we all love each other, anti-war.
And so the government was dealing with a lot of stuff. And they were concerned that this topic,
the UAP topic, was a destabilizing conversation, meaning all it's going to do is add fuel to the
fire and add mistrust to the American public. Especially once you start lying for decades,
you have to double down on that. Because if you don't, what happens is you tell the American
people, we're just fooling you guys. Yeah, we've been actually monitoring these things. We just
didn't want to tell you. That doesn't hold very much water, especially if you're a government
bureaucrat or a leader. So what do you do? You say, well, shelve this. We'll have this conversation
later. Meanwhile, let's see if we can deal with this topic in a secret manner.
Okay. So sorry to interrupt. Are you saying that the subject is being classified under the disguise
of national security? Well, it was. That's part of the problem. And we had backed ourselves in a
corner for decades. Now came a point where, okay, these things, everybody's beginning to see them.
How do we deal with this? Do we come out and let the cat out of the bag or do we simply try to
suppress this information and maybe deal with it down the road? And so you had the US government
involved in the collection of UAP data, but lying to the American people. And look, there's maybe
some valid reasons there. I don't agree with them, but I can understand them. Some of them was like,
look, we need more time to understand and figure this out. Also, there were some studies done
commissioned by the US government that the results were very simple. Look, this is a
destabilizing conversation. If you tell the truth to the American people, you risk
literally potentially the collapse of civil society. People are going to do runs on banks,
they're going to panic, they're going to lose their faith in their religions. Why do the normal stuff
that they normally do and pay your mortgages and whatnot when there's this other topic out here that
is potentially existential? That's really the only word I know how to use really, because it's
something beyond. And when people put their faith and confidence in a government, the biggest
vulnerability to any government institution organization is when the people, the masses,
lose faith and confidence. So this is true with any government, not just the United States,
any government. This is how they survive and religions as well. So you can't afford to lose
that. If people turn around and they realize you've been lying to me for all these years,
you know, we already don't trust the government. Now, we're really not going to trust the
government. Oh, by the way, you want us to fight these wars, and you want us to do this and do
that and this and pay taxes and whatnot. So I think the mindset at the time was much different.
We had this Cold War with then Soviet Union, and we weren't prepared as a nation to have the
conversation at the time. Do you think that then that's part of the problem is them,
you know, admitting that this is real is also them admitting to the cover-up?
Yeah, well, you have to, right? You have to say, well, yeah, actually, we admit that this is real
and it's been going on for decades. And then what happens? People say, well, why did you lie about
it? What about those people who told the truth? And now all of a sudden they lost their jobs,
they lost their security clearances, maybe they got a divorce, maybe now they're homeless living
on the street because of all that. But isn't the worst outcome of the two that we discover it's
real and call them liars than to them fess up? I think the time has come. We have to have this
conversation. I've always said that that secrets, a lot of people think secrets are like fine wine
where the longer you keep a cork on it, the better it gets. I disagree with that. I've always said
that secrets are perishable. They have a shelf life. They're like vegetables in your refrigerator.
They'll stay good for a while, but if they stay, if they outlive their shelf life,
they begin to rot and they begin to stink. And now you've got a bigger problem on your hand
because now you got to clean up the mess. And so I think that therein lies part of the conundrum
that we've been keeping this information suppressed for way too long.
My government at least now realizes that it's probably time to have the conversation because
it's only going to get worse. The longer we can look at the JFK files, right? Right now in the
United States, the amount of faith and confidence we have in our government is at an all time low.
That's a fact. They don't trust their government and that's a problem. And the longer you hold
on to the ghost, the worse it's going to be. You're going to have to pay that piper,
that compounding interest will eventually be more than the loan itself. And so I think the time has
come and I think some people now, there's a critical mass within my government that recognizes that
we now really, really, really have to be open and honest with the American people.
We're at an apotheosis of the UAP subject. Very interesting. I'm going to jump all over the place
a little bit here with these questions, so be prepared from hitting different angles.
Got it. Going back to the 4chan stuff, I myself had a deep dive into a lot of this stuff because
I thought it was really interesting and I read through a lot of those back and forth AMAs or
Q&As that they had on those different platforms with my audience. And there was one that stood
out to me in particular because it related to something that you had touched on previously
in a podcast in the past. And we're talking about a giant submerged UFO.
This particular 4chan leaker said that he worked on a team that was looking into what he called
an MCU, a mobile construction unit that was in the ocean, in the Atlantic Ocean,
that builds these UAPs and sends them out, and that they come in and out of this mobile construction
unit that's massive, that's in the ocean, and that moves very rapidly. He goes on to say the
downed crafts were recovered and that these crafts were built to spec, in his opinion,
they were built exactly for the things that they had to do, the jobs that they had to do,
and it would seem so did the beings inhabiting or maneuvering these crafts. My question is,
you've talked about this video that exists of this giant craft moving very rapidly underwater.
Is there a possible connection to this 4chan leak?
I mean, we can't say there's not. All I can tell you is what we know. I can't tell you what we
don't know. That old saying, we don't know what we don't know. What I can say is that without
getting in trouble myself, that it wasn't just me. There are a lot of people in the U.S. government
that have seen this video, so it is real. Let me set the stage for you if I can. In the late 1990s,
there was this effort by the U.S. government. We would test our cruise missiles technology,
and particularly in the Caribbean when I was there at Puerto Rico. Every so often,
we would launch these cruise missiles over the ocean in an area that was predetermined,
no boats or air traffic. Then when they would run out of fuel, they'd hit the water splash down,
and then they would sink. Then at a predetermined time, they would blow their ballast,
they would rise to the top of the surface, and then a helicopter crew would be dispatched to
go recover them, bring them back to the Navy base, and they would be cracked open and exploited,
meaning they would test for the telemetry and the fuel consumption and did the missile operate the
way it was supposed to operate. Now, most people know that Tomahawk cruise missiles,
some can be modified to carry a nuclear payload. That's one of the advantages of these cruise
missiles. There's a helicopter crew. I won't say the person's name because they haven't given me
permission to say their name, but they're legit. They're real helicopter pilot. Imagine a helicopter
crew. You've got the pilot, the co-pilot, the crew chief in the back, and you've got a Navy
frogman dangling from a line. As he's going down the line, he's going to put a hook on the missile
because it's blown its ballast and fly back. As this frogman is dangling down the line,
the helo crew notices, and the frogman, something black. The water begins to churn,
and something black and round, as described to me, something black as a devil and the size
of a small island. Submarines are linear. They look like your pen there. They're kind of long
and skinny and look like a tube, almost like a toilet paper tube. This was still in round
disc shape. Begins to come to the surface. Now, you understand that the trench of Puerto Rico
is the second deepest part of our ocean. It's only second to Challenger Deep,
which is part of the Marianas Trench. I think it's like 22,000 feet deep. The height that
some commercial aircraft fly, this is how deep that water is. There's nothing really out there.
This thing begins to rise to the surface of the water. The water's churning. The helo crew goes
into a panic. The frogman is literally trying to climb the line back up because he's scared like
hell, and I get it. Right as this thing is about to break the surface, the missile gets sucked
underwater and then the whole thing disappears. The helo crew goes back and that missile to this
day remains unaccounted for, this cruise missile. Very shocking to the air crew. Try explaining
that to your leadership of what happened. Is it some sort of Soviet technology? Is it something
else? Is it our technology? What the hell took our missile? Where did it go? How did it get there?
How did it is able to come up and steal our cruise missile? Several years ago,
I have to be careful of the capacity I say this in, but there was a very, very, very classified
video. Now, the fact that the video exists isn't classified. Where it was taken, how it was taken,
the methods, very sensitive, so I won't go into that. But it's very clear we had a capability
where we're looking down into the water and there were these offshore oil rigs. These are
huge platforms. Think of British Petroleum and some of these other folks had these huge massive
structures out in the middle of the water or the ocean. They're just like the size of a small city.
If you've ever seen one of these, they have helicopter pads and buildings and hospitals
and they're on the middle of the ocean. They're huge. In this video, very, very clear,
there's a still of the water churning and then there is the video of this perfectly round disc
shape object, black, whizzing past one of these things underwater. Now, there's no waves. There's
no disturbance on the top of the water other than the still of this water kind of looks kind of
roiling, if you will, in the very beginning. But when you calculate the speed that this thing
goes by, by the way, it was bigger than the offshore oil derrick. It was passing by.
It was bigger than that. Its diameter of the circle was bigger and it was assessed to be
moving between 450 and 550 knots underwater. Now, imagine that for a minute. Are there technologies
out there that move very fast? Yeah, we know the Russians have the super cavitational torpedo and
they have got capability, but to have an object that big, where you're talking tremendous forces.
No friction. Right. Huge, whizzing by one of these offshore oil derricks at phenomenal speed,
that's a technology that we don't have. And that is extremely, extremely compelling. When you see
it, you realize, whoa, what the heck is that? This first encounter I think was voiced by Graves in
the past. Was it Ryan Graves or Fravor? One of the two had talked about this encounter where they
went to go get Fravor. One of his buddies that we know. Is there footage of that encounter?
I haven't seen it. But there has to be, because if it's a helicopter, it probably has some type of
weapons radar footage. Back in the 90s, not necessarily. You would want to document your
recovery missions, but if it's something really routine, you're not always going to have a camera
on there simply because it's routine. You've done this a hundred times. It's just the hundred
and first time you're doing it. But it's possible. Oh, it's possible. Sure. Absolutely. But I can
certainly ask the pilot. I know the pilot. I can certainly ask him. Secondly, the other object,
have you seen this video? Which one? The one whizzing past. Yeah. I saw myself. By the way,
my colleagues did too. What was your reaction in the room? What was the reaction like watching that
video for the first time? Not what you might think, because we have seen so many videos of UAP that at
this point it was just added to- Yeah, but this one's in the water. That is what made it, for me,
that is what probably put this up a little bit in the, wow, what the heck is that? We had heard
about USOs before. We never really had any direct evidence other than sonar pings from submarines
and Navy captains and anecdotal information like that. This was the first time that we saw one on
camera. So it was kind of like, wow. But also keep in mind, we've been so saturated for so long on
this topic when I was working in the Pentagon and my colleagues, that you almost kind of become
desensitized. I know it sounds weird. No, I understand that. As someone who knows how magic
tricks work, I get to see methods all the time. I've seen things that other- Which by the way,
you are one hell of a magician. I never really appreciated the trade until I saw you do some
of the stuff you do. That's pretty incredible. Thank you. I appreciate that. I'll show you some
more stuff a little later. Secondly, you said this object was round. How did you have that
perspective? Was this a satellite footage? I can't say the source. Remember, sources and
methods are very sensitive, but let's just say we had the fidelity enough where it was very,
very clear what was going on. But I mean, if it's round-
Yeah, it's round. Okay. So you had a top-down view of it?
It was a top-down view. Anything more than that, I probably can't talk about. Now, my hope is at
some point it might become public. They'll have to strip out metadata and maybe some other things
there because people on the internet get very clever and they can figure things out.
Absolutely. Leave it to them to figure out the puzzle. It's crazy.
And you know what? I think that's great. There's several times that have actually been corrected
for the record by a bunch of internet sleuths. So I think it's fantastic. I actually welcome that.
We need more of that if you ask me. Oh, that's the whole point of the internet.
Last thing I want to touch on on this particular thing is, is footage the only intel you have here
or do you have corroborating data with this specific siting? You have sonar, you have radar,
you have ... Do you have other corroborating intel or is it simply just this footage?
Unfortunately, I can't go into detail because that shows the type of capability we have
in certain areas. Can you say, yes, we have other intel?
We have other intel. I can't say the type of intel.
Sure. But you could say there is other corroborating information.
Yeah. No, we had teams of very, very specialized analysts with TS Clearance. This is not private.
This is by the way government. This is still in the possession of the government with government
people analyzing this. More than two points of data?
I probably can't talk about that right now. Okay.
I know it's frustrating, believe me. I know your audience is like, what the hell? Why can't you
just say that? No, but I mean, just saying that gives us some type of idea.
Because people can extrapolate. The more sensor data you have in a place, the more of an interest
it is for us, chances are it's more of a hostile environment. Human intel?
Again, I really can't go down that path. I had to ask.
Okay. So we're talking about this underwater stuff. First of all, to me, this is really
interesting because if we're talking about the type of propulsion or the type of capability
that these crafts are using, technically from what we're seeing in the skies, it wouldn't
matter whether they're in the water or not. Right. That's what some of the scientists
have speculated. Look, the medium in which it's traveling is irrelevant. If you understand
physics, you understand technology, then you understand that sometimes the medium you're
maneuvering in is rather irrelevant. Including physical?
Potentially. Potentially. So potentially these crafts can go through
mountains? Potentially. Again, I'm not a trained physicist.
I took physics in college. You'd have to ask some of the smart folks in the intelligence community
who've kind of come up with some of these scientific models. What I will say though,
is that for the purposes of this discussion, we can't forget the simple fact that something
less than 15% of the ocean floor has been mapped. Meaning we know more about the surface of the moon
than we do what's in our own oceans. And let's not forget, look, my generation, I remember this. I
remember the notion of a giant kraken in the ocean and sea monsters as being silly and oh,
this is all just wives' tales. And it wasn't until we actually had proof positive of the
giant squid of the Pacific that there are giant kraken, right? It just turns out that
these aren't sea monsters. They're part of nature and our normal paradigm, our normal reality in
which we live in. So we're always learning something new about what could be and what
is in our natural environment. And the ocean is certainly no exception. Is it possible that
there's something down there that's been speculated? Sure. And is it possible? Yeah,
sure. And you've seen it. Yeah. I mean, we've seen things in the water and we know that we're...
So the Navy had a program for a long time. So the Air Force had something called the Fast Walker
program. I can talk about that. It's been declassified. The DSO office had this effort
to try to track things from space. And one of the things was UFOs, believe it or not.
The Navy had something similar and they call it the Fast Mover program. And they would pick up
information. They would pick up data, in some cases sonar returns of things that are moving
at a very, very high velocity, almost seems to be stalking or trailing the submarine only to
pass by the submarine very, very fast and then disappear. Tim Gallaudet mentions this. Tim does
and not only Tim, a lot of folks do. In Naval Intelligence. Absolutely. Yes, sir. Do you think
Naval Intelligence has more intel on the UAP subject than a lot of these other intelligence groups?
I think they've been more forthcoming. I'm not sure they're being... I think they've been more
forthcoming. I'll tell you, I talked to a Navy captain of a boomer sub and he was telling me
the story how they were picking up on a sonar, an object moving 450 knots underwater, which is really
fast, faster than most. It's insanely fast. And he said it was bigger than us. It was bigger than
a boomer class submarine that they're on, right? And so I asked him and I feel kind of silly,
but I'll share this with you because it's true. I said, it's kind of an amazement. What'd you do?
And he looked at me with a straight face. He said, Lou, we went around it.
Okay. I can see that. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Makes sense. Dumb question, I guess.
Yeah. You avoid it. Are there current discussions about the possibility of at least some of the NHI
slash UAP phenomenon being artificial intelligence? Well, I don't think we can rule it out.
Have you seen any evidence that might suspect that that is the case? Like there is some type
of AI controlling these things. No, my background, but let me caveat here. My focus was more on nuts
and bolts of craft. It wasn't really with the occupants or other folks that were looking at that.
But let me also give you a very real example of why it's not far-fetched. Right now we have the
capability, you can put a helmet on and we can fly drones remotely using a helmet, using our
thought patterns. There was a gentleman probably earlier this year who gained some significant
notoriety. He was a quadriplegic and they decided to give him an implant that allows him to play a
video game. In this particular case, I think it was Call of Duty. And just using his brain
and his thought patterns, and it turned out that he wanted it being almost better than just about
any gamer out there because that interface was instant between his brain. No bandwidth.
Right. So we are already using technical means to manipulate matter. Now, taking away the
spookiness of it and telekinesis, no, it's technology. Not telekinesis, it's technology.
It's simply the ability to interpret brain waves in a certain way and electrical signals,
neuroelectrical signals and bioelectric signals and translate that into an action using technology.
So we as a simple species are already doing that. So does it make sense that in the future,
not only our own species, but anybody else who's technologically proficient would do the same?
I mean, it's clearly a more efficient way of doing things. By the time the signal goes from the brain
down through the muscles and then it causes a response and a reaction, there's a delay there.
That's not really efficient, is it? And also the signals can be misinterpreted, right? So it makes
sense to have that type of technical interface. And we are already doing it as a species. Now,
you get into the artificial intelligence aspect of it. Can NHI somehow, could it be some sort of
form of artificial intelligence? Because it could potentially predict what you're doing
if it already has information on what you've done. Right. Absolutely. And so,
if you look in Commander Fravor's case where this Tic-Tac object sort of got anticipated almost
to his waypoint, part of that could be, oh, it can read the future. But part of that is
it's just really good at mapping out the past. Right. Or exploiting the data systems on board
the aircraft as well, right? So there's options. I think artificial intelligence is a brave new
world for us because for the first time, we may be on the verge of creating true sentience,
but not biological, based upon silicon and not carbon, right? Based upon electricity and not the
bioelectric processes in the human brain. So artificial intelligence is, anything's almost
possible because we're just now beginning to scratch the surface on what it can do.
And we've already seen some of its capabilities, which are very compelling, which could be
disturbing for some people because then that brings in other questions of like really free will
and fate, right? Which is really uncomfortable as a species for us to consider because most of us
look at life and say, well, I've got a series of choices. You don't know what choice I'm going to
make ahead of time, unless you're like you, who's a magician, right? You kind of already know that
to some degree because you set the stage, you set the environment where only one choice is possible,
right? But they think it's free will. That's very concerning for a lot of people because we
don't like that idea that we're not in control of ourselves and our environment. And so when you
talk about artificial intelligence and the capabilities of it, that's something we're going
to have to deal with in the very near future because maybe we're not as free will as we are.
It's also something as an intelligence you'll have to exploit, right? Because you have to,
because the enemy is doing it. So we have to, the adversary is doing it and they're doing it quite
well. So we need to do that. We also need to figure out a way to defend ourselves
also from artificial intelligence and how to, which is very fascinating to me.
If artificial intelligence has a 99% certainty of something happening because it's done all the
calculations and algorithms and looking at our previous behavior patterns and whatnot,
then is there a way to spoof? Is there a way to circumvent that? Is there a way to
do something that artificial intelligence hasn't predicted yet? That's how you're going to survive
because if an adversary knows your next move on the chessboard and knows how to win the game and
put you in checkmate, then you've got to figure out a way where they don't know what your next
move is, right? And so that's kind of the situation we're in now. Yeah. I think the best way would be
to make them think you're playing chess. That's right. So, well, this is really interesting and
it leads me to also understand because you said you're tracking nuts and bolts. This is part of
what you were doing. Before I ask this next question, I also just want to ask, are there
more videos of submerged vehicles out there that you guys have access to?
Well, is there more evidence information? Yes. So video is something very difficult when you
talk about underwater. Sure. But you have more data. A lot more data. A lot more. Yes,
there's some video evidence. But underwater is much more difficult than in the atmosphere
because water will affect the electromagnetic spectrum a little bit differently and especially
with electro-opticals. So that's why we use sonar. We use sound waves instead of radar
under the ocean because sound waves travel very well, whereas electromagnetic signals
are much, much more difficult. So you're not using the same tools to quote unquote
see something underwater. You're using technical equipment to give you a sight picture of what's
there, but you're not actually physically seeing it. You don't have a photon of light bouncing off
something coming back into your eye or a camera lens and interpreting that data because light
doesn't travel. Look, if you've ever been to any of your folks out there, your audience or scuba
divers know this. Once you get past 300 feet underwater, it's virtually dark. You can't see
anything. Light stops. Now there's some animals and fish that have very sensitive eyes and
they can see much, much deeper, but for the most part, the human eye is restricted because
light waves and photons of light eventually get absorbed by the water. So it doesn't travel as far
as it would like when you look at the horizon. It's maybe 11 miles away. Underwater, your horizon
is maybe a couple hundred feet. But that sonar information can be just as valuable. Oh, yes.
Sonar data can be high fidelity, like incredible fidelity.
Are there reports of these giant craft down there that you've speculated that the information is
pointed to that these things might be massive down there?
Well, we've heard already from Tim Gallaudet, Admiral Gallaudet, that these things have been
a mystery for the Navy for some time. You don't have to even look at the United States Navy. You
can go back. There's anecdotal information even by some of the great explorers hundreds of years
ago. Sure, Nick Columbus. That's right. That's right. That experienced strange things under
the water. I spoke to some civilian fishermen in Mexico when I was down there off the coast of
Ensenada, kind of between the little island there called Guadalupe Island, the island of Guadalupe
and Ensenada. They report these luminous objects, these balls of light all the time under the water
and sometimes even pop out of the water and then fly away. These are people who have no interest
in being sensational. In fact, they love their privacy. They don't even want to be associated
publicly with this, but they've experienced this. There's log books of other seafaring captains and
people who've reported very similar experiences going back centuries.
Does that make it a place of interest for the government?
Well, it should, but no. Government's interest typically is from a national security perspective,
meaning how do we protect our people and how do we maintain a strategic advantage over our
adversaries? This is one of the ... People have always asked me, well, Lou, how much research
did you do into UFOs when you were at ATIP and historical stuff? Did you talk to this ufologist?
No, I didn't, because really when you're talking to a three or four star general,
they don't care what happened in the 1950s or 1960s. They want to know what happened yesterday.
You're really narrowly focusing on the incidents that involve military equities and as they're
happening now. If you go to a general and say, well, here's a report from 1966, they're going to
say, what the hell are you throwing me that for? I don't care. I want to know what happened yesterday.
Their focus is on the here and now, but I think that's part of a mistake because I don't think
you can get an accurate understanding of the here and now unless you understand a little bit
about the past and realize that there's pattern. As an intelligence officer, we're all about
patterns. Kind of like magicians, right? There's certain predicted patterns and if you understand
those patterns like putting together a puzzle, you can figure the puzzle out. That's why it's
so important that we do take a historic look at this. Now, some of the information is going to
be bunk or junk, but some of it may be very, very telling. Most of it happens over water, it seems.
Yes, water. There's two really interesting patterns that we've seen over time. One is,
there's an interest in our military capabilities and our nuclear capabilities and technology,
and also large bodies of water. There seems to be an overwhelming number of UAP sightings in and
around bodies of water, which kind of answered the question you asked me about the Navy. Are
they most proactive? Are they seeing the most? No, but they're all in the water the most, aren't
they? What else do you have? Well, you've got, let's say, the USS Nimitz or USS Roosevelt.
That is a huge nuclear footprint. In fact, in some cases, when that fleet goes out with the
nuclear carrier and nuclear submarines and other nuclear powered boats with potential nuclear
weapons and other technology, that's a bigger footprint than the entire state of New York
from a nuclear perspective. You're on the water, which is why we early on in the Pentagon set up
this Operation Interloper, which I can now talk about. Pentagon's given me permission to do it,
where we were going to set a trap for these things. We knew that having a huge nuclear
footprint in the middle of the ocean would be irresistible to these UAP because we had
experienced it so much. The idea was to set a trap, set up a ... Now, when I say trap,
you're going to say, allure, right? We had the intelligence community approval and the joint
staff to do this, the approval from the joint staff. This was a very, very comprehensive
effort that we were proposing and was almost unanimously accepted because they were seeing
the same issues we were seeing at ATIP. We were going to create this lure, and unfortunately,
at the last minute, they pulled the plug. They pulled the plug on the project?
On the project, yeah. It was called Oplane Interloper.
There has been rumors that the government hasn't been too shy about creating these type of lures
in the past to attract NHI activity, to attract UAP activity. Namely, now, this goes into a lot
of what Jake Barber talked about. Now, before we had psychics, now it's psionics, before it was
UFOs, now it's UAP, before it was extraterrestrial, now it's NHI. It's all these other terms,
but all three of these terms were used by Mr. Barber in his recent three-hour podcast with
Ross Coulthard. I wanted to get into that a little bit because I think you've already touched on it
and had said that these objects that he's describing, these egg-like objects, they're
not these weather balloons. They're not ours either.
They're not ours. He reported that they have specific psionic teams taking these things,
or at least bringing them into range to where they can take them down.
Is that something that you've been read into in the past? Have you been read into any of these
programs regarding psionics? Let's break it down, I think, for the purposes of your listener,
what psionics means, because you obviously know what it means, but the word psionics is something
that is not a general term. It's a sci-fi term.
Right, it's a sci-fi term. Psionics comes from the base word of psychic,
psychology, psychic, whatever, and dealing with the brain and potentially
human cognition and things like that. There is some speculation. Remember, we talked about
technical interfaces with brainwaves, so that technology already exists.
If you were a super-sophisticated society, would it make sense to create technology that you could
potentially interface with, manipulate, work with using brainwave functions instead of necessarily
wasting the time for the signal to go down to the hand and make a movement?
Which, by the way, is not very precise. I think there's an argument to save for that.
Then you have to ask the question, has the US government in the past been involved with
psionic-type research or psychic research? The answer is, again, a definitive yes.
Of course.
We now know through programs like Stargate and Grill Flame before that.
The Center Lane.
The Center Lane, that's right, that the US government and her adversaries have had a long
and deep rich history in using psychic research and using it for the purposes of espionage and
the collection of data. That's a fact. Anybody can look that up. It was actually very, very
successful. Then you have to ask the question, well, fine, but do we really accept that now
in society? The answer, again, is a definitive yes. Look at a lot of local police force
will employ psychics. By the way, to a great deal of effect, they've actually solved murderers and
found bodies using psychics. Now, people can poo poo it all day long. The bottom line is it works.
Now, how it works may be a different story. We can debate that all day long, but
the bottom line is proof is in the pudding. Statistically, there is something there,
whatever that means and however it works. We've already crossed that bridge. We don't have to
argue that. It is what it is. To your question, specific question, is it possible that the US
government employed certain individuals who had a predisposition to some of this psychic phenomena,
whether you call it remote viewing or channeling or psychic or what, a username du jour,
to try to interface with or communicate with a non-human intelligence? Well, I think it'd be
foolish to assume that we didn't or we wouldn't, given our previous history in human cognition.
The question is, has the government found success in there?
I can't answer that. I don't know. I'm not surprised that the allegations are there,
because certainly if I had unlimited budget and I was in charge, I would try throwing everything
at it, trying to figure it out how it works. People will say, well, that's a bunch of hooey.
The bottom line is, you know how we tell if people are dead or not in hospital?
Brainwave function. When there's no brainwave function,
people are presumed to be dead. Now, what is brainwave function? Now, some can argue, say,
well, they're actually still alive. Yeah, yeah, yeah, maybe. But for argument's sake,
we use brainwave function to determine if a human being is still alive or not.
And to detect brainwave function, it's nothing more than electrical process going on in the brain.
And we have technology that can detect it and actually say, yes, there's higher functioning
of the brain or no, this person's in a vegetative state, very little chance they're going to come
back. That part of the brain is shut down. And how do we know that? Because we have technical
equipment that can detect it. We know that. That's a fact. And that's technology we accept
all the time every day. So does it make sense that if that is real, that there is an actual
physics behind brainwave function and we can detect it, which we do, does that also apply
to something else that may have some sort of brain or higher brain function? And is there a
way to interface with their form of brainwave function and therefore setting up tests where
you could have people try to, if you will, interface or some have even alleged that there's
some sort of conjuring capability there. I don't know that to be fact. I know there's a lot of
people out in- Yeah, or hijacking.
Hijacking, right. It's certainly very interesting. And there was even in the Russian something
called psychotronics. I'm not sure if you're familiar with that, but the psychotronic weapon
development system. And by the way, the CIA also invested in that, might know that to be fact.
And that is the ability to use human brainwave functions with a piece of technology to affect
matter. Now think about that for a minute. People talk about telekinesis. The bottom line is that
there are ways to interpret brainwave functions using technology, a technological interface,
and then affecting change. And we talked about that with even the God helmet and
other experiments we're working on where we can use-
The cause of the revimir and- That's right.
All these other experiments. But back to Mr. Barber, because what he's coming out with
recently seems to be, I mean, it seems to be obviously a lot for a lot of people
because not only did we go into, he was part of a team that recovered a craft that was of
exotic origin, but also talked about being recruited as someone with psionic ability,
also talked about using other factions that are non-governmental contractors
and using their technology to help down some of these things when they're in close proximity.
And then also about other crafts that were recovered that somehow had some emotional
effect on him. And it gets wooed really fast when listening to a lot of this stuff. And I know there
are a lot of listeners out there that when they hear of anything other than UAP, they're out
because it took them so long to even get to UAP. But we do have to understand that something's
piloting these things. These UAP, maybe they're flying themselves, but at some level, something
is piloting these things. You can't have a conversation about
extreme advanced technology without then having the conversation of who built it,
how does it work, why are they doing right? And these are the follow-on questions. Yes,
I understand it can be disturbing for a lot of people. And people say, well, our government
never would be involved in anything like that, using individual to do certain things. And well,
if that's what you think, I don't know what to tell you, but there's lots of examples where we
have. I mean, we've done some pretty heinous stuff and experiments on human beings without
their permission. Look at the CIA's use of LSD when we first did that. Canada had a hand in that
too, by the way. Look at the syphilis experiments, where we allowed human beings to die when we had
the cure simply because we wanted to see what happened. So there's a long laundry list of
malfeasance and things that people have done in the name of national security that wound up being
absolutely atrocious and heinous. And yeah, if there are children who are predisposed to having
some sort of psychic capability, as stated by some individuals, are there individuals in our
government that would try to exploit that? I think in the past, probably, sure. And I've got
my personal reasons for saying that. But I also want to be very careful not to be conspiratorial
because I don't have firsthand knowledge. I've heard the rumors, and I was an atip of this going
on, but I was never part of that effort. To be clear, you heard of the rumors of the
psionics teams? I heard rumors of psionics teams. Or you heard rumors of the psionics
team bringing down craft? Not bringing down craft, of trying to use human brains-
To try to interface with some of these things. Interface with whatever that is, correct. But again,
I wasn't there for those experiments, I don't know. This is just kind of the hearsay that I
heard when I was an atip and then afterwards. It makes sense when you look at the government's
interest into people like Chris Bledsoe and why that would be so valuable if he could just summon
them at will. If that was the case, then that would be absolutely a leg up on the competition.
Sure, sure. There's a lot of weird stuff as a kid I experienced. I don't never talk about it
publicly, but there's been times I kind of scratched my head and said, was that coincidence?
Was that something else? Did someone plan this? It's certainly not outside the realm of possibility.
By the way, for the record, the whistleblower that you're referring to that came forward,
he is who he is. He was a special operator. He is an American hero. He's done a lot for his country.
Now, whether his observation and his perspective is accurate, I think he's telling his truth and
I think people need to understand it. He put himself to a lot of risk,
Jake did, for having this conversation with America. Now, for the record, I've never met
the guy, but I have special operator friends of mine who I've worked with that were actually
there with him in providing some security support and have said, hey, this guy is legit
and here's his background and these are the missions he's been on. He is part of that elite
group of the best of the best of our country. I know it's kind of difficult for a lot of people
to absorb that you have this guy that's coming out kind of out of the blue and making these claims,
but I think everybody deserves to be heard. Have you seen, heard or know of any other egg type
crafts at ATIP? Yes. You have more than one? Boy, yes. There's a story I'm dying to tell you.
Hopefully, I can get clear at some point to say it. That has to do with this?
It has to do with egg-shaped vehicles, yeah. Have you ever noticed, seen, heard of or heard
whispers of any type of language or symbols apparent on these craft? Yes. If I show you
a picture, can you confirm or deny? It depends. Can I try? Sure. I'm going to put my old main
glasses on. For the record, this is gray and not blonde, so I'm an old dude. I need
as much help as I can get. This is an image. This is zoomed in.
Someone has taken the liberty of pointing some of these symbols out and saying that
there is some type of resemblance to this language.
This is really interesting. When I was at the Pentagon, I spent considerable time
researching ancient script and hieroglyphics and symbology and
even cuneiform to see if there was any similarity on what was
seen on the outside of these vehicles, which appear to be some sort of glyph or rune, if you will.
I am not familiar with this actual one. But you are familiar with there being symbols on
the outside of the craft. Yeah, which by the way is significant. That means something.
Let's break this down from a human and a scientific perspective. What is the pearl?
I see your notes there. What is the purpose of written script? What is it?
To communicate. That's right. To communicate. More importantly,
there's a way to communicate. When you are reading notes or you see a word,
I'll just kind of give it away. How do you detect it? How can you read written script?
Because you have eyes. It's a visual thing. People who are blind can't read.
They use Braille. Whenever you have reports that a UAP or UFO has something written on it,
there's a few things that you can surmise immediately. First and foremost, that they're
communicating something. You don't write something unless there's a meaning behind it, whether it's
Chinese character or ancient Elizabethan English or even going back to some of the older forms of
written communication. You're conveying an idea, a thought, or a directive, and you're doing it
through visual sight. That means whoever that is intended to see and whoever wrote it, chances are
they have eyes or they use the electro-optical spectrum to discern their environment so that's
not too dissimilar from humans and other animals on this planet and that there's a higher brain
function. Dogs don't use writing. They don't read dictionaries. It's only a human thing. In fact,
of all the animals on our planet and all the primates, the only animal that actually use
written communication are human beings. Ever since we were living in caves and we were painting
animals that we hunted and painting our palm print, the human print on that side of that cave,
we're the only ones that do that. So when you come across in this particular case a UAP that
has some sort of writing on it, there's some assumptions and presumptions that can be made
immediately and that they're maybe not that dissimilar from us. Now, maybe it simply is
like if you ever had a Jeep and you have those upside down stickers, if you can read this,
flip me back over, right? Maybe it's something like that. Or if you can read this, phone home
for me because I'm in trouble. Or maybe it means something else. But yeah, we looked at that at
ATIP as wondering if there's some sort of intent that we can glean from script.
Because you were aware of craft that had script on it.
And not just me. No, there's a lot of script.
Yeah, it's pretty undeniable at this point.
Was it written or engraved in these crafts?
No, it was engraved. It wasn't written.
Did it look not too dissimilar from what I just showed you?
Much more precise than that actually. I mean, there's no doubt about what you showed me there
is someone's interpretation of what could be either script or it could be just scratches
and the ablative process of- It was very blatant.
Oh yeah, looking at that. It's like, hey, that's there for an intended purpose.
You've seen these on egg crafts?
Let me do a polite pass on that. It was on a different craft, but the egg craft is something
that is people are now just saying, oh, this is a new form of UFA. No, it's not.
And not just us. There are people, if the story ever comes out,
we have been dealing with this shape for a long time. It's not new. People think it's new.
It is not at all. In fact, there's some very interesting intelligence information about that.
I cannot go into any detail. I'm very hopeful that information will probably come out soon enough.
Not by me, but some scientists who actually research some of this stuff.
And it is not new to our intelligence community either.
We've been hearing about egg crafts with symbols on it since Lonnie Zamora.
We've also spoken to Chris Bledsoe, who he described his as being an egg as well.
So these things tend to pop up, but more than that, in both of these stories,
they have some type of intelligent being on the inside.
Well, if you think about an egg, it's almost nature's perfect solution.
The egg shape, there's a reason why it is what it is.
Yeah, it's perfect.
It's perfect. And it's extremely resilient to external forces.
Try again, there's an old trick where you take an egg and try to smash it with your fingers.
It's very tough to do. And so there's a reason you could even surmise the reason why
some of our early space capsules almost had that little bit of an egg shape to it,
because it's very resistant to Earth's atmosphere when you're coming in on reentry.
It's a very efficient shape. It is naturally aerodynamic, naturally.
So there's a lot of advantages to having something the shape of an egg.
In fact, if you look at World War II and Zamora bombs, they look like eggs with fins on them.
There's a reason for that. It's because of the efficiency of that shape.
It's really interesting that we're talking about this, because to me, this just communicates that
we also have specific data on crafts that are very close up, very HD, very...
I mean, that type of information leads me to believe that the information that we were given
with the tic-tac, the gimbal, the go-fast was all just preparatory.
Because if you're holding on to that type of clear imagery, it really cements the idea that
it's a planned dissemination to the public. But let me ask you something. If you were in charge
for just a day, and you know that this whole experiment only works because people have faith
and confidence in you, right? This is a term we call catastrophic disclosure versus controlled
disclosure. And I know people hate that idea. You have no right to control that. Look, if really
there is even a remote possibility that this really could be destabilizing conversation,
then it is the responsible move to handle this in a very methodical manner.
Sure.
Right? Because you don't want to disrupt... At the end of the day, people still have to pay
their mortgages and pay their cell phone bills. You've got to go to PTA meetings. You've got to
take the kids to soccer. I think we all get it. But it's the admission of that, I think,
that people have a hard time with. It's not so much the act of it.
But brother, look, you already had a former director of national intelligence,
state for the record, that these things are real, whatever they are. You had a former director of
the CIA. You had two former presidents of the United States. You've got other elected leaders
in other countries all saying it. I mean, people say, well, when are we going to have disclosure?
I say, look, you already have it. We've crossed the brubicon already. Now the question is,
what are we going to do about it and how are we going to have it? It may not be the flavor
of disclosure you want, but you already have the government. Look, you have the setting up of
Arrow. Yeah, I know there's some hiccups there and they still kind of dorking around, but that'll
be fixed very soon. You have a new administration in the United States that is very proactive in
this topic, wants the American people to know the truth and think the American people can handle
the truth. And by the way, same with our elected officials. For the first time, we have a bipartisan
issue that both Democrats and Republicans can agree with and say, yeah, you know what? Americans
deserve the truth. So we've already had disclosure, big D as people call it. It's just maybe not the
flavor people are expecting. Well, I think a lot of people are just of a simpler
sort of mind where they're like, well, just show me what you got. And I think that's what it really
comes down to with a lot of people's frustrations is not that... Yeah, transparency. It's a
transparency issue. Exactly. And this is what motivates me. I agree. Look, I think we need to
level with the American people. I think we need to level with the world. And let's face it. Look,
if we know they aren't adversarial, that is. Right. Well, even if they are adversarial,
we need to know. And look, the dumbest secret there is, is that the Canadians have been dealing
with this. The US has been dealing with this. The Mexican has been dealing with this. South
America has been dealing with it. Europe's been dealing with it. The Russians and Chinese.
Is it the worst kept secret at this point? Is it possible that maybe this is the one conversation
that can actually get countries that are adversarial to each other, say, look, for this one thing,
let's agree to agree and let's work together on this. And I will make a treaty. I promise I
will not exploit this technology to hurt you. And you have to do the same thing. Let's work
together scientifically on this, because maybe it'll help us as humanity move forward. Clean
energy solutions, for example, or better medical. Look, one only has to look at the 10 years of one
decade that we had this space race with the then Soviet Union, right? Now Russia. What happened
during the Apollo years? We went from 1960, 1969 to putting a person on the moon. And we did it
almost routinely, if you can imagine that, right? What happened as a result? Well, over 6,200
industries, not products, industries were a result of that one decade of competition
to get into space and ultimately get on the moon. Things like the LED light bulb, things like the
CAT scan that have outlived their initial intended purpose and have changed the wellbeing of humanity
for the good forever, right? And that's just 10 years of trying to get to the moon. Can you imagine
this type of technology, the potential benefits it could have for our species? Now with that said,
there's the counter argument, right? Of course. Every time, like nuclear energy. Yeah, it can
power a city, but it can also destroy it. So you can't ignore it because there are rogue nations
out there that will say, well, if I can fly from here to there almost instantly and not be seen,
I can put a weapon on that thing, right? And now all of a sudden, uh-oh, Pandora's box has been
open and there's a liability there. So maybe we need to have an adult conversation with the rest
of the world. And I'm not talking like United Nations. I'm talking bigger, like no kidding,
hey, guys, we got to get to the table on this because we're going to wind up, you don't want
to die. We don't want to die. We don't want to kill each other with this. This is like for real,
real psych nuclear weapons, right? You know, let's, let's not use them if we can. Yeah,
this is the, like the Manhattan project on steroids. That's right. But if we're smart,
we'll use it. We'll do this as for peaceful purposes. Yeah. For once for once. And I think
we can, and by the way, the reason why I have hope is not because of my generation. My generation is
paranoid. We screwed this topic up long enough. We've hit it, we suppressed it, and then we ruin
people's lives for it. It's your generation because when I had to have secret conversations
about this topic in the Pentagon, it was always because we were afraid of the reaction we were
going to get, the visceral reaction and the fear. Your generation, which is the generation of my
daughters, seem much more open to this. It's much more, hey, listen, we really need to get to the
bottom of this because there could be a benefit here. We don't want to go to war with Russia. We
don't want to go to war with China. Can we all just get along for once and try to work this out
because this involves all of humanity? And that gives me encouragement. That's why I think the
time is now to have this conversation because unlike before previous generations like mine that
completely botched this topic, your generation actually seems to be more open and more responsible
about it. And I think it's partly because of this type of technology. When I was in high school,
if I wanted to learn about the Andes Mountains, I had to go to a library, pick an encyclopedia
off the shelf that was probably 10 or 15 years old already. Luckily, maybe the page was still there,
wasn't ripped out for some other kid's project. I got about a paragraph and a half about the Andes
Mountains. Now, in virtually any language, instantaneously, in any part of the world,
you can pull up on your phone all the information you want and have volumes and volumes and volumes
about the Andes Mountains, how they were made and the precipitation rate and the population and
erosion rates and all that stuff. You have more information at the tip of your hand for the first
time. The world is connected like never before. There's great power in that because
for the first time, your generation can understand how your generation in China feel,
and you can communicate and how people in Iran feel and people in Russia and China and the UK
and France and Germany. And if you don't understand the language, it'll automatically be translated
for you. So that communication barrier has been evaporated. And also the cultural barrier. You
guys are far more accepting of new ideas, new principles, new perspectives than mine. Look,
I grew up in a generation where I was on the tail end of literally where we had separation
of races. Can you imagine that? How foolish and silly is that? And now it's like, my God,
what the hell were people thinking? That was an associated norm. That was an expect norm.
When I was in the military, we were always told, don't ask, don't tell. And homosexuality in the
military is bad. Well, it's silly. It's stupid. Why the hell did we ever care? Why? Because we
were ignorant. My generation made these dumb rules because we didn't know better. Your generation
is not that way. You don't have these preconceived notions of what should and shouldn't be. You use
common sense. And I think that's why the timing is like never been before, because we've never
had the technology before. And we've also never had a generation like yours before. And those two
perfect storms allow us to have a conversation like this. Great. I mean, that gives me some hope.
One of the scariest things that I've ever heard was, I think it was Hal Puthoff who said this,
and if the government discovered a drop of water, the first thing they're going to do is figure out
how to drown you in it. Yep. And part of me is thankful for that because, and you can say what
you want, but if we didn't invent the nuke first, this podcast would not be happening.
That's right. And that's pretty much a fact. And we've been speaking a different language,
perhaps. Absolutely. But at the same time, you bring up a really interesting point.
There is this weird, if you look at it from a biological perspective and a sociological perspective,
I guess the best way to describe it is tribalism. Ancient mankind had a small circle of people
within their tribe, maybe living in a cave, living in a hut, whatever. And that was a reality. And
everybody else were enemies, right? Because we were living in an environment where we were resource
starved. So either I ate or you ate. And if you ate, I didn't. And so we had this weird competition.
And then as society expanded into the village, it became now a village mentality. And we still
write books now. It takes a village, right? So our society, our little myopic society that we
encapsulate ourselves in, and everybody else is out there, the enemy, and we're going to stick
together. And then you had the urbanization. And once we entered this point of agriculturalism,
and we weren't nomads anymore, we gravitated to a central region and attracted more people.
So that population density became greater until eventually you had regional areas. And then
eventually you had borders of nations, right? United States, and you're Canadian, and you're Mexican.
But as we continue to push our boundaries, we begin to realize that we're really all the same.
And this is something that I've tried to tell people, look, if you're ever in space and you
look down at the earth, you don't see the lines between countries. We're all together. We're all
you know, we will say, well, I'm American. What does that mean? You know, because people in South
America, they're Americans too. They're just South Americans versus North Americans versus
Central Americans. We're all in this together. But we're fighting instinct because our instinct
is to be tribal. Our instinct is my loyalties to my people, my country, my family, my this, my that.
And that was in order to survive as a species, we needed to, animals do the same thing, right?
You have a pack of wolves and they stick together and they go after everything else. And so that is
part of the Darwinian survival and evolution of all things biological because why we live in a
resource starved environment, it's either them or me eat or be eaten. But we're now realizing
if we want to evolve to the next phase of our existence as human beings, where we rely on this
and you know, not this, not bronze, but our brains and our hearts, we have to overcome that instinct
to control, to dominate, to do all the things that nations and religions do.
In fact, that is the one thing I think that is stopping our evolution to the next phase of human
reality, which is, do we have enough sense to get rid of some of these instinctual habits that we've,
by the way, required to survive to get to where we are now? Like you said, the bomb, right? Thank
God, as bad as it was, thank God we had it and not them. But have we been able to outgrow that
to the point now where we can actually all have a conversation together and say, look, we're all
brothers and sisters. I may not agree with you. I may not understand you. You may not agree with me
and understand me, but we can agree that humanity's survival as a species demands that we begin to work
with each other, communicate with each other towards a common goal and stop this infighting
and competition. And maybe at some point we'll get to a point where we're not in a resource starved
environment. We are an environment where we don't have that competition and we don't need to have
that competition. Yeah. Yeah. Great. And I think that, you know, Reagan said it too at the UN
meeting there back in the day when he was like, it would take, you know, an external
extraterrestrial threat for all of us to like be, you know, realize that, hey, we're in this together.
Maybe, hopefully it isn't an extraterrestrial threat that we're facing. Okay. I have a question
here. I have a few more questions that we got to get into. I'm just still fascinated with all the
things that you've seen. And I think that's where, I think, and I'll speak for a lot of people here.
I think that's the broadly in a general sense why people are so fascinated with people of
in your position, because you got to peek behind the curtain. We did not, right? So we,
to a certain extent, careful what you wish for. I know. That's another question I have, but
for now, like you have, you know, access to the mechanism, you have access to at least a portion
of the mechanism and you get to peek behind the veil. And all the rest of us are curious, right?
We're curious because it involves mankind. It involves our own potential religion. It involves
life and death. It involves why we're here. It involves the questions of the universe. It involves
the most important things that humanity has ever asked for. And you potentially had one of the
closest encounters with the answer. That is a great, that's heavy, man. You don't put that on
my shoulders. Are you kidding me? That is what it is. That is why people are so passionate about
this. That is why people get fired up, whether good or bad or angry or happy or they get fired
up because this is important. This is the big question. And, you know, there aren't so many
people that have come forward to talk about that. And the second we get somebody, you know, is the
second we need to grill them. It's the second we need to put them through the wringer because
you're playing with my emotions. Right. And truth, whatever that truth is, and you're going to come
out and if you're going to say this is the truth, then, you know, you better prove it. Exactly. And
so, you know, you of all people can understand the amount of, you know, frustration and vitriol and
all of this stuff combined because deep, deep, deep down, everyone's just hoping for an answer.
That's just deep down. But my role isn't to provide answers. My role is just to provide
information. It's up to you to find those answers. And this is what I try to tell people.
Well put. You know, it's don't put that responsibility on my shoulders. I'm just like you
and I'm fallible and I'm a human being and I, you know, wake up and I spill my coffee and,
you know, I'm not a messiah, man. That's not, that is, my job is simply as a purveyor of the
information. Here's the information. Here's the data. Here's the facts. How you interpret that
and what you think about that, brother, that's on you, not me. But a lot of us are not willing to
make that answer as long as there is information being withheld. Oh, agreed. No, you're right. And
that's why we're doing what we're doing. Right. Here's the information. We're going to get more
out. We do, we do want to make those answers and hopefully, you know, we don't look to anyone else
for answers and we can come up with those ourselves. But as long as we're aware that
there is information that is being withheld, we can't fully formulate a proper answer. And some
people's frustration, my guess is that you have that luxury of formulating some type of answer
that they would love to formulate themselves. Makes sense? Yeah. Good point. So, you know, forgive
me for always, you know, prying into what it is you've seen, but that's the underlying value in
this is that some of us just want to know more so that we can make our own answers. Sure. That's
fair. And I think that's a really good point. And that's, you know, I guess indirectly,
some of why I do what I do. You know, I want you to have information so you can make your own
assessment. And this is why people say, well, Lou, what do you think? You know what? To hell with
what Lou thinks. It doesn't matter what Lou thinks. What matters is what you think. You know, my job
is easy. This is why, you know, I used to tell people when I was a former special agent and when
I was a special agent in charge, our job is very simple. Provide the information to the jury,
let the jury decide. It doesn't matter what I think about it, but it doesn't matter how I feel
about it. What matters is what does the data suggest? What does the math suggest? What are
what is the collection of data and observations provide? And then you allow the people to make
that decision for themselves. Correct. Right. And I think it's the problem we have right now
in this UFO community, which I do not consider myself a ufologist. I'm not a researcher of UFO.
It happened at the job. That was it. Paid by the government, American taxpayer dollars.
Um, I think it's, it's critical that people be allowed to make their own interpretive decisions
for themselves, because this is people, of course, people say, Lou, what do you think?
Doesn't matter. What matters is what you think. Here's the data. You figure that don't be so quick
to give up that, that sacred right you have to think. But once again, we don't have that data.
Right. Well, we get some of it. We don't have it. You don't have all of it. There's a difference.
You do have some of it. Yes, we do. We do have some of it. And I know it's frustrating because
people say they want more. I get it. I understand. Well, it's because it's, it's like chocolate.
And it's not, and that's not on you that it's frustrating, by the way. And I know you shoulder
a lot of that. And, and, and to, you know, to a great extent, it's very unfair, because you have
been forthcoming with more information, I think, than most people would have gotten in a lifetime
of research. You know, thanks to, thanks to the things that you've done coming forward.
Thank you. I am trying. Absolutely. Absolutely. And that is undeniable. And I'm willing to fight
anyone on that. You know, but the, the problem is once, once we scrape the barrel, we're like,
okay, well, what's next? Right. And we know there is a next. We know there is something, right?
Right. Okay. I think part of the frustration, and let me completely transparent with you guys.
I do a lot of work behind the shadows, behind the scenes, in order to get to like where we are now,
whether it's a new whistleblower that maybe I've been aware of for the last few years, or
uh, maybe a secret project that will hopefully blow the lid on a lot of this, you know, whether
through a documentary and getting the right people to have the conversation. The problem is when you
do that in the dark, people think that you're hiding something from them. They don't realize that,
look, it's not you I don't trust. What I don't trust are some of the elements over there that
don't want this conversation to happen. And I can't have the conversation with you without
them hearing it. So I have to do things behind the scenes and in the dark until they become
revealed, right? Yes. And people look at that as, oh, well, that's Lou being secret. That's Lou,
you know, obfuscating the truth. That's Lou controlling a narrative. No, it's not.
What it's doing is allowing me the time and the ability to present the information where someone's
not going to take it away from you. And that's, that's why I do a lot of what I do when you,
when I leave these breadcrumbs, people say, I don't want breadcrumbs. That's why you're doing
that. Look, if you look for the last seven years, everything I've ever said has come to pass
without exception, every single thing. And I do that deliberately so people know, look,
I am fighting for you. I'm working for you behind the scenes. I just can't tell you everything that
I'm doing right now, but eventually you'll know. And I'm trying to, you know, I know people say,
well, but it's been seven years. Yeah, but we've done more than seven years than we have in the
last 70. I mean, guys, I'm working my ass off. Believe me, I'm putting myself in a lot of risk.
I lost almost everything pursuing this. You know, and like I said, how much are you paying
me to do your podcast right now? How much are you paying me? Zero. That's right. Find any podcaster
that I've taken a penny from, you know, it costs money, baby. It's, I'm taking time away from my
family to have this conversation with people and people don't realize that, you know, he's a grifter.
You don't know a grifter. If I was a grifter, you know how much money I'd have right now? I'd
be flying a Learjet. You know, I deliberately don't do that simply because I don't want to
pollute the topic. And I respect that. And I think, you know, just from my observation,
I try to remain really sort of unbiased from all of this and just look at it from like a
spectator perspective. And I think there are a lot of other bad actors in this specific area.
Oh yeah. There's a lot of people that caught in industries that have been selling a line of bull
to people for a long time and now they've got a double down, triple down. And there's a lot
and there's also a lot of trust me, bro. Yeah. Right. And people are sick of the trust. Yeah,
absolutely. And because there's a lot of it. And so, you know, I guess the reason there's probably
so much frustration. You're going to get hate by the way, as I promise you. Yeah. Just for having
me in your studio. I'm aware. Having this conversation. Oh, he's a grifter. He's full
of crap. He doesn't know. I mean, I've been called the same. I'm aware and I'm currently unfazed by
it. Because for me, this is not only a pursuit for them. This is a pursuit for myself as well.
I want to know, right? And whatever means I have to get that information is the means I'm going to
pursue. But they would also be lying if they said they wouldn't want to be sitting right here and
talking with you right now. Interesting. I think a lot of people probably, yeah, if anything to
throw a tomato at me, probably. Fine. But if it means getting a little bit more, a little closer
to the answer that they're so desperately seeking, then I think it's worthwhile. But you know, the
answer, here's a great point. The answer doesn't come externally. And this is why I've told people
before. If you really want to know what's going on out there, you first got to know what's going on
in here. Yeah. And this is the filter for everything we see and we conceive and we perceive.
And so you have to stop saying, I demand the truth. Give me the truth. Look in the damn mirror and
say, first of all, what can I do to be a better father, a better husband, a better citizen? And
let me be the best that I can be. And then hopefully that whatever that is makes more sense.
Because as long as we have the pride and the ego that so many of us carry around and the
inability to look in the mirror and say, you know what? I don't really like that aspect of what I
see. We're in a society where it's, oh, you have to love yourself. Oh, you're the best. You know
what? That affirmation is BS. We need to be hypercritical of ourselves so we can be better
people. I'll share. You know what these tattoos here on my arm, and by the way, I don't normally
like tattoos, but I did it for military and other stuff. What this says? It's Latin. It says accept
and pint it to you. It means with regret. Because there are people out there that live their lives.
I have no regrets. You know what? You're a moron then because then you're never going to learn
a lesson. I have lots of regret. I've done things that I wish I didn't have to do. Now,
if I was put in the same situation again, would I do it for my country? Damn right, I would.
But I regret the fact that as humans, we had to even be put in that situation. I never want to
forget the faces and the lives of other human beings that maybe aren't here anymore because
of things maybe I've done. And so no, I want to remember their faces. I don't want to glorify
that because I'm still a human, you know, and I did things because I had to, not because I wanted
to. And I think we have to be self-reflective. I think we have to have the courage to look in the
mirror and say, you know what? I can be a better person. You're not going to be perfect. We're
humans. We're never ever going to be perfect. But it shouldn't stop you from trying to being a better
human being. And I think that is maybe one of the keys to unlock this greater mystery. You know,
we can't, how are we going to, I'll give a perfect case one. I had a general about two and a half
years ago now. It's been a while. He says to me after giving him a briefing on this topic, he says,
Lou, this one, I was a US Space Force. He goes, look, Lou, I really don't care about this. All
I care about is if this thing lands on the White House lawn, do I go ahead and extend my hand out
to shake its hand and in friendship or do I point an M16 at its head?
And I looked at him and said, my dear general, you're missing the point.
It's not an either or solution, right? Both of those may be the wrong way to react to this.
We need to do a better job of understanding what's actually going on. In order to do that,
you first have to understand how you're wired yourself. What makes you tick? What motivates
you? Because that's going to depend on how you interpret that data. Is it friendly? Is it a
threat? Or is it something completely different? And so we all have to be on that same sheet of
music. We all have to have that honest conversation with ourselves. You know what?
We're not perfect. You know what? I'm not the best person out there. You know what? I'm not
the prettiest. I'm not the richest. I'm not the most influential. And yeah, I've got some bad
habits. Maybe I don't clean up the bathroom or I drink too much or I'm a gambler or whatever that
is. But be honest with yourself, man. And then make the effort of trying to learn those lessons
and become a better human being because maybe that's what it's going to take to really understand
out there. You got to first understand here. I love that. I love that. Thank you for sharing
that. And I think that's a great point. And it's one of the most refreshing things I've heard
in this topic because even Jake Barber, we'll get back to him, he had this
sort of this providence, this holy moment when he perceived him being in contact with whatever
emotional feminine energy entity was in this craft, but that changed him fundamentally.
You could see that on camera. He almost broke down into tears just even talking about it. It was
very real to him. And he said something. He said something to the likes of everybody should feel
this in order to understand that perspective is everything. I don't disagree with that. I think
he's absolutely right about that. I've always stuck to this. If you understand someone,
it is impossible to hate them. And I will die by those words. Think about anyone in your life who
you dislike, find annoying or hate, and now really try and understand them. Really try and walk a
mile in their shoes and try to be empathetic to what it is their entire story is from beginning
to end and current. And that's hard to do. It's really hard to do. But if you can do that, even
if you can get close to doing that, you find yourself feeling all sorts of other feelings
for this person that aren't negative. Well, and think about if you've ever been guilty of that
same behavior, which chances are we have because we're human. But we don't want to do that. And
sometimes in life, we want to have someone we can point the finger to. Well, of course,
because they're human beings. And it avoids us having to point it at ourselves. And accept
responsibility. The harder thing to do, like I said, is look in the mirror and accept responsibility
and say, you know what? Shoot, I could have done better. I did not give it my best. And I know it.
And I need to I need to work on that. Right. And you're not without your flaws. And that's
something that that you've also been vocal about as well. Right. Is that, yeah, mistakes happen.
Things happen to people. But you got to own up to it, man. You're still you haven't given up.
No. And you know what? Accept responsibility. Remain accountable. It's not that hard. Yeah,
it sucks. You got to swallow your pride. But guess what? That's the only way you're going to
succeed. You have to under you have to have those lessons learned. And if you don't. Right. And for
me, I had to be dumb enough. I had to put on my arms to remind myself of it. You know, you're going
to be you're going to be doomed to repeat the same mistakes over and over and over and over again.
And something magical happens when you actually accept responsibility. Even though it's a gut
punch to the pride and ego part. All of a sudden, you become free. It is it is freedom in a way that
you would not expect. But it's very, very liberating. And it's also very, very, I think,
encouraging. And it's it's it's helpful. Because you all of a sudden get more out of life.
You begin to appreciate things you wouldn't before you walking in a park and you look at a little
flower that's growing underneath the tree and also wow, that's that's magical. How many times have I
walked by here and never even noticed that or cared. Right. And now all of a sudden, wow,
beauty is right there. I don't have to go searching for beauty in a Vogue magazine or,
you know, a New York runway. It's right there. Nature's beauty right there. And here I am this
entire time taking it for granted. Right. So I think, you know, this is what I know to frustrate
people. People always say, well, if I want to really know about that, what's your one suggestion,
Lou? So stop worrying about that. Stop worrying about that. Stop. Start worrying about what's in
here. And then maybe you'll unlock the secrets. You'll get a fresh perspective. Yep. All right.
Let's get back to the nuts and bolts. This is great. I love this, by the way. Thank you for
addressing that. Okay. Bit of a fun question. Okay. If you can get access to any archive
out of the 19 intelligence agencies, if you can get full unrestricted access to any of their
archives. And we're talking DOE, CIA, DOD, whatever it is, DIA, whatever. What agency?
Well, it's a bit unfair for me because I had a very high security clearance. And you had access
to a lot of stuff. But I think for me. Okay. If you were in my position.
The CIA. And here's the reason why. Not because it's, you know, the CIA. It's not domestic.
It's not domestic, but more importantly, they share a lot of information from other agencies
goes to the CIA. So it's not just CIA information you'd have access to. You'd have access to a lot
of other agencies, both domestic and foreign information that the CIA has access to. It's
kind of a belly button, if you will. And so if you can get into there and really have full open
access, you would learn a lot. Is the DOE interesting as well? Absolutely. It is. Look,
by law, anything that gives off a certain amount of radiation falls under the DOE.
Is there? Okay. So we're speaking about lures earlier, right? And how the ocean, big bodies
of water, but also, you know, possibly strife and conflict, nuclear war, these things seem to
attract. Are there any environmental factors that attract them? Yeah. What are some that aren't the
ocean? What are some other environmental factors that you've seen activity in or atmospheric?
So there is a lot of information on this topic to suggest that uranium mines are a particular
interest and other mines as well, believe it or not gold. Now, if you think about it, why gold?
Not from a monetary perspective, but what gold is, you know, gold is a very interesting metal,
which, by the way, makes it valuable, not because it's printing, it's gold,
because the property, the reason why NASA and the Air Force use gold a lot on the inside of
radiation properties, all sorts of properties. Right. I got to be careful what I say here, but
gold has some very interesting properties. And there has been some information to suggest that
UAP are interested in mining operations, both uranium and gold. That was also suggested by the
4chan whistleblower who talked about the underwater construction unit. Yeah. Interesting.
Very interesting. I mean, if it's just my brain's jumping to Ariel, the Ariel school,
they were close to a uranium mine as well. That's not the only one.
Yeah. I'm sure there are other mass sightings. There's some reports, governmental reports.
I can probably tell that they've been released through FOIA now, so they were classified. CIA
reports on mines in the Congo, gold mines, where these things were seen by many, many people.
Wow. Australia too.
Oh, I mean, okay. So there's one thing being interested in the material, but there's another
in extracting it. Have you any recorded data of observing these UAP extracting anything?
No, I haven't. It doesn't mean it's not the case, but not in my experience. I haven't seen
actually any extraction of minerals from the earth. Okay. The 4chan whistleblower said that
the technology they used was laser somehow, and that lasers were really interesting and that China
was actually using some of these lasers and had figured out how to bore these holes and to mine
things that left the United States baffled. So are we sure it's actual laser? So laser
is very interesting. It's in a visible light spectrum and it's a very specific frequency
of light. So green laser only uses green. It looks green because it's green and the photons
are coming on very specific frequency. Blue lasers, red lasers. There's things that can be
confused as lasers directed energy that are really not based in photons or the emission of
actual light. Then you also have a, in some cases, what they call a Doppler shift. So
part of the discussion we had in ATIP was some of the biological consequences of people getting too
close to the things and suffering injury. Exactly. Doppler red shift, blue shift,
what could be coming out in let's say a certain radio frequency when it goes through a certain
process and perhaps leaves the UAP or the UFO, it gets Doppler shifted into a higher frequency
that now becomes interpreted as visible light or possibly even energy like it could hurt you.
X-ray for example. So when someone says, well, they're using laser technology.
You could look that way.
Yeah. Is it really laser technology or is it something else that we are now superimposing
our own understanding of physics and go that laser when really it might not be a laser per se,
but it's interpreted that way.
Yeah. It has laser like properties.
Right. Right.
Okay. Has there been through what you've been shown any reason to believe that
the NHI or the UAP that you've been observing has a distinct and perhaps adverse effect on our
religious beliefs? Well, you don't have to look at aliens and UFOs. A lot of things can threaten
religion. But was there anything specifically that, because there has been talks of Jesus
in Bibles and stuff?
Let me explain it this way. There's nothing that I'm aware of that threatens or hinders
my own interpretation of spiritualism and religion. But we can look back in the past,
for example, look at Galileo Galilei when he first proposed the non-Earth-centric view of
our solar system and proposed the heliocentric view of our solar system. What happened? Well,
religion responded very violently and almost put him to death for it until they recanted.
At the end of the day, we realized Galileo didn't do anything to threaten religion.
It was mankind's interpretation of religion that was being threatened. Not God or the notion of
God, but mankind's understanding of God or the great architect or the great beyond,
right? Whatever you want to call it.
I guess more specifically, my question would be, has there been anything in what you have studied
that would confirm or deny religion?
Everything I've seen only reinforces the notion of-
The notion of religion, but nothing specifically. There's no specific data that points to
any of the major religious events or any of the-
Well, we have to be careful because it's very subjective, very interpretive. Let me give an
example. I hear over and over again, people say, well, the Bible's full of UFO encounters. Look at
Ezekiel's wheel. Okay, great. Or it could have just been someone's dream. Or it could have been
a vision that wasn't related to UFOs at all. We don't know because we're separated by space and
time, right? We weren't there. How do we know what the writer or the author was thinking at the time?
You really don't. There's a lot of subjectivity there. Look, I think if anything, this topic only
reinforces the notion that there is certainly a degree of order in this universe and that the
cosmos is incredibly vast. Let me give you an example here. I've said this a few times
before. There are two barriers to human beings really understanding the universe.
In fact, if you look at the entire- There's five fundamental senses for which we judge
our environment. If you can't touch it, taste it, hear it, smell it, et cetera,
we really don't know it's there, right? That's the only way we have to use technology to help
enhance some of that, but we only have five senses. Let's look at human vision for a second.
What is human vision? Human vision is a very, very narrow band of the electromagnetic spectrum
we call the electro-optical spectrum, right? Really tiny. You can see red and we can see up
to blue, and that's it. We think we can judge the entire universe, but that's only 0.0035%
of the entire electromagnetic spectrum, meaning most of reality lies beyond our ability to perceive
it. Now, are there animals that can? Sure. Honeybees can look in ultraviolet. There's
animals that can see in infrared and whatnot. We as humans can't, so we rely on technology.
Where I live in Wyoming, beautiful night skies. Take a look at that night sky and you'll see all
these stars. Now look at that same night sky through a radio telescope and you start seeing
things you can't see normally. You see large gaseous clouds and nova and things like that
that are just as real, but they lie beyond our ability to perceive. Then you've got a scalability
issue. You and I are sitting in this wonderful studio you have here, having this great
conversation between you and me. And when you look at the scale of the universe, so the visible,
most scientists believe that the visible universe, visible horizon, it's about 40 billion, billion
light years across. Now, to understand that and really perceive that, what does that mean? Well,
that means take a photon of light, which travels at the speed of light, 186,000 miles per second.
Seven and a half times around our entire planet in a second. Now think how far light can travel
in a week and in a year. And now take that, multiply it by 40 billion, right? Incredibly
vast. And that's only 10% of the actual size of the universe. Most cosmologists agree that the
universe is 10 times bigger. It's just that it's so vast, light will never reach earth. So that's our
visible horizon of 40 billion, but really the universe is probably over a hundred billion
light years, maybe even much bigger across. And we are this infinitesimally small speck
somewhere in the middle. I would encourage your audience, if they ever get a chance,
get on Google, look on Google images and type in pale blue dot. What is that pale blue dot?
That is earth. Everything you ever thought, dreamed, hoped, cried, laughed occurred on that
tiny dot. Every moment of history that we know of since the beginning of time occurred on that
planet. Everybody who's ever lived and died on that tiny little blue dot hurling through the
vastness of space, right? That's very uncomfortable for people to look at and realize that and how
vulnerable we really are. Real perspective. Now let's do the reverse. Let's go down.
Let's look at Avogadro's number, 6.2 something times 10 to the negative 23rd, a hydrogen atom,
a proton, neutron, and electron for hydrogen. That is times 10 to the negative 23rd in size.
That's roughly the same order of magnitude as we are to the universe. And it's inside
every human being, meaning most of reality is either too big or too small for human beings to
really interact with and grasp. And in fact, we can as a species, if we're lucky, one or two
orders of magnitude up or down, and that's it. That's our reality. The truth is most of the
universe is beyond our ability to even perceive it because it's either too big or too small.
And so by that definition alone and the fact that we only look at 0.0036% of the entire
electromagnetic spectrum, some incredible number, we can perceive 0.00000, keep writing those zeros
all the way down, 1% of the entire universe in our reality. And we know most of the universe and
reality lies beyond that. And so that's fact. That's not supposition. That's reality. And
we have to understand that this is an awfully big and complex universe. And there's other things
besides physical distance. We talk about physical distance, but you understand quantum mechanics
and quantum entanglement. There are some things in the universe that really don't follow the rules
of a three-dimensional space and time. It's inconsequential. It's irrelevant. And I know for
us as a human physical species, that is our reality. It's hard for us to perceive a reality
where space and time is irrelevant. But the fact is those universes exist. And so we have to really
recalibrate the way we think about things. If we want to imagine the unimaginable, we first have to
redefine what unimaginable is. A lot to think about, man. That's a big pill to swallow.
Lou, you have a gold standard case that you look at, that you think back on. They're all different.
There are so many gold standard cases. The ones I can talk about because people know about it,
like the Nimitz incident. But the other ones, okay, platinum standard. Because if you can talk
about the Nimitz and you consider that a gold standard, I mean, there's got to be something
above that. A lot. And there's a lot. In your mind, when you hear of a case or you see a case
or you see a photo or a video floating around or whatnot, you have a Rolodex that you can compare
it to, that you know for a fact is anomalous, that is confirmed an anomaly. Are we going to see
some of those cases in the near future? That decision's not up to mine, but I certainly
hope so. Let me give you an example without saying something specific. Let's say this coffee cup,
let's take a look at this water bottle. Let's say this is birth. It's round, completely round.
Yep. The way that gravity works is there are expected trajectories of things coming in and
out of orbit. And especially with a satellite, let's say on retrograde, it comes in. That's how
we know it's going to burn up over the Pacific Ocean. That's how we know at what time you can
see the fireworks show in the sky, right? And the rocket reentering and burning up and the satellite
and whatnot. There's an expected path that things take. Even ICBMs and missiles, if we were to
launch on Russia or Russia were to launch on us, there's a very predictable pattern because
it's physics. What you wouldn't expect looking at this as the earth is something, because most
things come in as an arc. You wouldn't expect something going straight down and then popping
straight back up because the amount of energy required to do that is enormous.
Beyond our capability.
Well, certainly beyond our capability now. And so when you see that and you have the data,
and it's not just looking at it, it's hyperspectral data and there's other ways
to collect information besides the human eye. I remember that's only 0.0036% of the
spectrum, right? That's a little narrow window. Let's get a big window here. Let's get all the
data, baby. Give me all the frequencies and I want to see everything. That's when you have
something really special because sometimes they say seeing is believing, but your eyes can fool
you. Look, you're a magician. I mean, this is your trade. Sleight of hand, making something appear
to be one thing when it's really something else. So we need more data points. We need data to
include beyond the visible spectrum. And that can tell you a lot. It can tell you heat, right?
Things like infrared and what something is even made out of because depending on the trail and
the color, just like we look at a star and we can tell there's a planet around it. Why? Because we
can tell actually the atmosphere of that planet and what it's composed of because as light from
that star travels through it and then eventually hits earth in our eyes, we can say, oh, that
planet is primarily nitrogen or that planet is primarily hydrogen. That planet is composed of
methane because the light behaves, it's absorbed by the type of gas. And so when you see something
coming in and out, and if there happens to be a trail on it, you can look at that and you can
analyze, okay, this thing is, this is what it's comprised of because of the color, because of the
length, because of the heat, all sorts of different things. So without giving away specific capabilities
here, hyperspectral technology can be very, very informative. It can tell you a lot more than just
simply seeing something on a camera. And so those are the ones that really get very compelling.
Especially when you also have footage.
When you, I mean, when you see, when you like, when you browse stuff and you're,
and you're shown things online, are you ever just like meh because of what you've seen?
But that's, listen, but that's not because it's not compelling. It's because I've been
desensitized. Because you've been desensitized.
I have, right. It's just like, you know, a cop who comes across a crime scene and people are like,
oh my God, that's horrific. It's like, meh. Okay.
You know, it's, and it's unfortunate because that's just the reality of us. It's just like
anybody who watches shows and horror shows on movies, you know, someone might say, oh,
I don't like watching horror. That's disgusting. Someone says, that's not really that bad.
It, you get desensitized.
It's like a magic trick. It's like knowing how a magic trick works. And it's funny because
I actually got to ask Bob Lazar that question. And he said, for the same reason he said,
it's exactly like a magic trick. Why doesn't the government talk about Bob Lazar?
Well, probably why they don't talk about me. I can imagine, you know, we go against the grain.
I've never met Mr. Lazar, to be honest with you and for the record. So people say, well,
what do you think of Lazar? I don't. I have no way to judge. I've never met the gentleman.
You know, I think he's saying his truth, whatever that truth may be, just like I'm saying mine.
Sure.
You know, but look, the government has spent a lot of time doing the same thing to me. When
I first came out, they even denied that ATIP was real. They even denied that I was part of it,
right? They're like, I think somebody even accused, it wasn't even at the Pentagon. I'm like,
dude, are you kidding me? There's my desk. You know, there's a safe that's got all the stuff in
it. So I suspect if he's enduring the same thing, it'd be for the same reasons that
they tried to obfuscate. You know, there's a saying we have,
first of all, you deny everything, you admit nothing, and then you make counter accusations,
right? And so there is this spectrum of efforts that happen when there's an inconvenient
conversation to have in a government. The first thing you do is they deny it. And then when they
can't deny it anymore, you know, they'll start trying to take away someone's credibility,
like they do with Dave Groove, 24 hours of him coming out. And this, by the way, is American
here. This guy, I worked with him at Space Force. He is exactly who he is. We had the same briefings
together. We saw the same UAP data, right? So he comes out and says the truth. And within 24 hours,
two guys from CIA leak medical data and try to use his PTSD against him. Now, how disgusting is
that, right? And totally, by the way, if I were to go ahead into government and release someone's
private data, I'd go to jail. That's HIPAA violation. Also, there's PII information there,
personal identifiable information there. There's medical, radical.
It's being doxed by the government.
That's being doxed by the government. Shame on you. And you wonder why people are pissed.
You wonder why people like me do what I do. That's why. Because that to me, let me,
this is a, you're getting to a point now in this conversation that is very near and dear to my
heart. And I want to share something with you. A lot of people know in my book, I talk about my
mother passing away. And no, I'm not plugging the book. That's not why I'm here. I'm just simply
saying that people know that because I was forthcoming about it. What some people may not
know and I only just started talking about it was the death of my father. My father was a
revolutionary in Cuba. He was part of the Bay of Pigs. In fact, if you type in my name and type
in the word Bay of Pigs, you'll see his prisoner number. And he was a tortured and tormented soul
because of it. But his later years, he got, he became very introspective. And so about a month
before he passed away, he passed away two years ago on Father's Day, I had the opportunity. I knew
he was dying, but he wouldn't tell me, but I could tell he was dying. And I knew my time was limited.
So he came out to visit me and we had an opportunity to take a road trip together.
So we're going to drive back down to South Florida together. And about halfway through the trip,
I asked him a question and I look back and I feel kind of guilty about it because
I was kind of flippant, not expecting the answer that I got. And I said, Dad, what is the greatest
threat to humanity? Now I'm thinking to myself, is it a natural calamity, an earthquake? Is it a
nuclear war? Is it a biological pandemic like COVID was? And he looks at me and he says,
thought about it for a second, he says, corruption. Corruption? I said like financial corruption? He
says, no son, corruption. Corruption in any form is the act of trading away one of your core values
in exchange for something else. And whether it's religious corruption, moral corruption,
governmental corruption, if you have corruption in government, then what winds up happening is
you wind up chipping away, eroding the very foundation of a democracy. And when that occurs,
it's a very, very quick and slippery slope down to total tyranny. And it's something my father
actually had direct experience in. And so when you have in the government, corruption and people
making decisions that they don't have the authority to make for reasons that they don't
have the authority to even consider, and doing things like they did to Dave Groosh and myself
and other people, that's a problem. Because now the entire democracy is at risk. This is not just,
hey, the government trying to insulate us. Hey man, you're now going beyond the constitution here,
which is something we all agree with. And you're telling me now the constitution doesn't matter
and that I have to play by the rules and you don't. Hey buddy, I don't know if you remember,
but 1776 happened. People have a vote and if you think that they're going to sit here and
tolerate corruption, there's an old saying from Bob Marley, you can fool some people sometimes,
but you can't fool all the people all the time. And if you think you're going to do that, brother,
that's not the government I signed up for. That's not the constitution I signed up for. I didn't go
to war to allow you to do that. Because now, don't look now, but you're the enemy, right?
And they have hijacked what the values of our country are and they're making decisions they
don't have the authority to make. When they're not informing Congress, they're not informing
the president and they're lying, that's a problem. You can justify it all day long. I don't give a
crap what your answer is. It's still wrong. There are laws and things you have to abide by. And so
when you see that action of people trying to defame somebody, that is egregious. And to me,
look out, because you're now going into a territory here, into some very dangerous waters,
that you're doing things that are against the very ethos of what it means to be a free society.
And you don't have that permission. And by the way, I went to war for it before. Don't think
I'll do it again. Our Congress and our executive branch deserves better. And if you are some mid
level bureaucrat making decisions on behalf of the president and Congress for which you're not
allowed to make, watch out, baby. You're going to have some serious explaining to do, as we like to
say. Yeah. And rightfully so. I think the pursuit of that, and especially in defense of people who
have given up something for the freedom of people and the freedom of choice that people have,
I think it should be valued and protected and upheld to a standard that I think most people
should be on board with. I think that just goes with that saying. It's egregious, like you said.
I mean, I'm going to have to ask 2027. No, I don't want people to keep saying 2027.
Oh, Lou said 2027. No, I never said 2027. Stop, guys. I never said that. You know what happens
is people in the internet have got way too much time on their hands. They will clip together
interviews I have to create a false narrative. Okay. So let me know, then what is it? Bledsoe
says, Bledsoe has a hard date, by the way. He says Easter Sunday, 2026 is like his date.
I've heard people say 2025 is when we begin this, whatever. And it's obviously,
the gold post is going to shift depending on what's been said. Recently, Jeremy Corbell,
in his special and his three-part special, at the end of it said that the government was intending
on having some mass siting or like a giant mothership come in and that this is going to
happen and then 2027 has been thrown around. Can you, for everyone's sanity, shed a little
bit of light on this just so we can stop being paranoid or we can start being paranoid?
Let me see if I can thread the needle on this.
Sure. Take your time.
I know a lot of people, this is nothing new. There's entire religions that are
that plan for doomsday, right? The end of the world is coming. Then you have,
oh, this is Y2K and then, oh, it's the end of the Aztec calendar, right?
Now, there is some speculation and I won't say specifics that there may be something later on,
but the problem is I wouldn't go to the bank with it and what the specifics are because it's,
first of all, it's hearsay and it also was, yes, there was an official effort by some people in
the government to actually look at this data and there were some products produced. That's a fact.
I won't go into more detail on that, but it wasn't 2027 and it was based upon certain observations.
I'm very careful because what I don't want to do is people are going to take this,
they're going to hang on to these words and say, Lou says something's coming.
No, I'm not saying that. What I'm saying is that there were some people who were
anticipating something happening and it was officially considered by some people
based upon certain things and a product was written. Anything beyond that, I don't want
to discuss because I think what happens is people take that and they take it to the bank
and that's very dangerous. You don't want to give any credence to something that could be untrue.
Anything could happen. A tornado could hit your studio in 10 minutes from now. It could.
It probably won't, but it could. We have to be very careful. There's no such thing as absolute.
But it's when you say something was observed that people's ears tend to perk up.
Yeah. I can't go into more detail than that because, first of all, I didn't collect the data.
I wasn't part of that effort. Thirdly, that's not really for me to discuss, but I don't think
people need to panic at the disco. We've been down this road many times before. Let's stop
speculating. Let's stick to what we know and if it turns out that there's a revelation based upon
of us all working together on this, then fine. Maybe this is what it is, but we need to make
sure we don't do ourselves the injustice by predicting and predicating things. I think
that's a dangerous move and I think unless the government comes out and says something,
hey, you need to pay attention to this, then we probably should focus on other things.
Most people would probably agree with me, but if the government did say that,
we might be questioning why they said that. Right. Sure.
That leads me to another question. Do you rule out the idea that you
might be being used to further some type of governmental agenda?
Always. Always. You have to consider that. I have rocked the boat sufficiently and I've made
decisions that if that was the case, I don't think they would have anticipated. I probably made their
life very, very difficult. If I was supposed to go on some sort of agenda, I think I'd probably
strayed from that agenda a long time ago. I say 2027, but what if this future revelation
is something like that? Then it happens.
You're not immune to that is what you're saying. No.
Look, you don't know what you don't know, right? That's right.
How do you know what you don't know? Is it possible there's some sort of master scheme
there to manipulate Luis Elizondo and a few other insiders to get our message across? It is, but
I'm also familiar with those techniques and I think I would be able to see at least one telltale.
No one's that good where you can keep the secret forever. It would be really, really hard to do.
Have you ever had disinfo come across your desk?
Not at the Pentagon. Foreign disinformation, sure. That happens a lot,
but actual disinformation on the UAP topic, not at all.
Not at all.
No, in fact, nobody wanted to talk about it. You're not going to get disinformation.
Disinformation is usually when people are at least talking about something and you want to
affect a decision, but when no one's talking about it-
But you're aware of projects. Are you aware of projects of the UAP narrative being slightly-
Yeah. Look, they did in the 70s. Air Force OSI penetrated civilian organizations in violation of
DOD 5240.1 and other rules and regulations, possibly Executive Order 12333, and conducted
intelligence operations and propaganda and manipulation against the American people.
By the way, what happened two days ago? A document came out from the CIA proposing it's okay to kill
Americans if we want to go ahead and predicate a war and have an excuse to have a war with Cuba
and an invasion. Now think about that for a minute. Who the hell are you to propose killing
American citizens for a political agenda? Dude, that's worthy of a coup, man. Well,
that's not American values. Don't look now, but you've now become the enemy that we all hate.
You don't have the right to do that, and this is what fires me up. There have been some people who
have made suggestions to conduct illegal activities to cover this topic up, and it's going to come
out in a few months. It's just telling you, because I was victim to some of it. When the
American people find out the length that some people in the government are willing to go to
to keep something secret, it's going to blow your mind. Scary. Yeah. Honestly, it's disappointing.
I don't think it's reflective of the government. I think it's people in the government. Let's not
forget, government is made up of people. There are some good people and there are some bad people.
That old saying, absolute power corrupts absolutely. Maybe that's what we're dealing
with. I want to be careful that I'm not accusing the government. I'm not labeling the government
or mad at the government. What I'm mad at are those rogue elements inside our government
that are making decisions that are not in the best interest of the American people and, frankly,
that are against our constitution. That is what motivates me to continue doing what I'm doing.
If I have to pay the ultimate price for it, then so be it. I knew that a while ago.
Like I've told people, the only thing that's going to stop me is a bullet in the head or
maybe I got hit by a bus or a car accident, which has happened in the past.
But I have to pursue the truth. I think any real patriot who served time serving their country
feels the same way. At the end of the day, we owe it to the American people. We owe it to our
government. There's no excuse why a president wouldn't be briefed on something. There's no
excuse why oversight committees in our Congress can't be briefed to something. That's exactly
what's happened. That's a problem. That's not a reflection. You can't say that's the government's
fault. No, that's people in the government. It's their fault. There are some people that will go
to great lengths to keep information quiet. And it's not just the people in the government
because what we've seen, I think, more frequently and more rampantly is these people who are working
with the government. Oh, yeah. The proxies and the media, some elements even in the media.
I think those tend to be a little bit more dangerous. Well, we saw this right before
this last election, right? I mean, there are people in the media who knowingly lied about
people. We just had a case, a landmark case against one of our major networks here,
where there was a veteran where they tried to slander and lie about him and defamation.
And he won the case, right? And this is a huge media organization that was super well respected.
And it turns out there were journalists who had an agenda. And then, I mean, look at everybody
who's surprised by it. Nobody, right? Nobody's surprised that the media would go through that
length. But sometimes we are surprised to find out that these other contractors are involved
in things like this, the big ones, the Raytheons, the Lockheeds. I mean, there's a few of them out
there. One in particular, and feel free to answer however you want to answer because you've been
asked about Lockheed in the past. You've been asked about, you know, a lot of people are familiar
with the Wilson Davis memo and all the stuff that went on there about like the inside program and
people doing reverse engineering. What about EG&G? Where did they go?
You know, I'm very careful not to mention companies specifically. I went through a year
process through the Pentagon to even reveal a few of the names that I did in the book.
And I was given very clear instructions not to deviate from that.
Because of your association with the Pentagon?
No, because of their association with the Pentagon.
Because of their association with the Pentagon and that some of these
companies who've been responsible for doing some not very nice things in the past,
I've been asked to, you know.
Have you, are you aware of EG&G even being part of the picture?
I know the name. I don't want to speculate one way or the other what I might have heard
or what I didn't hear.
Oh, I'm not asking for speculation.
Sure. Yeah, yeah. No, no, I just, my point being is that, look, there's,
anytime you mention, especially in this topic, if I mention a particular name,
there's liability issues, right? And you have to be very, the legal, real legal consequences.
So unless you get it approved by the Pentagon, like I did, you got to be really careful.
You can have the lawyers coming after you.
So you got to be really, really careful.
And, you know, when you're someone like me who I'm living fairly modestly.
Isn't that convenient for the government though?
Like, I mean, it seems like, it seems to me,
because these private corporations are protected.
They are protected.
We're not allowed to knock on their doors to find out what they're working on
because it's private, it's got IP that we don't have access to.
And so legally, and there is that fine line of like, well, I mean,
then you can just knock on anybody's door and take anybody's technology and proprietary,
you know, information.
But in this specific case, which is why, you know, people are trying to pass this UAP act
and trying to see that, like, hey, if there is recovered technology,
then we should have access to it.
Right.
Congress should be aware of it and et cetera.
But the fact is that there is a law preventing us from doing that.
It seems to me that that's a very convenient law.
Well, and this is part of the double-edged sort of any capitalistic society, right?
You have free and fair competition until you don't, right?
And so in theory, everything is free and fair competition,
and that needs to be protected, and I understand that.
You know, I'll tell you something fascinating here.
Do you know where the word corporation comes from?
I've never thought of it.
Corpus, meaning body.
Body.
In the United States, you can actually, when you look at the tax laws,
a corporation has the same exact rights as an individual.
Interesting.
And so when you have a lawyers group of lawyers creating this corporation, this corpus,
they're creating a living, breathing entity according to the rules and the rights of our
country.
They have to be recognized as an individual, and so they're afforded the same rights.
And only when the conjurers, the great conjurers, the lawyers come back and they de-establish
a corporation, and it is no longer a living body, right?
It's a living thing.
And even then, there's some rights that translate to that.
People understand that in the United States, corporations have the same rights and privileges
as individuals.
It's just like a human being.
Rights to privacy.
Very convenient.
Well, it can be abused.
It works until it doesn't.
So I want to make this clear.
I understand why, because the US is a capitalist society, and that's how we thrive.
And we've all agreed to that.
That's our social contract, that this is the type of government we want,
and we want the right to certify.
I have a company.
I want my company to be protected, right?
I don't care what it does.
I want to be protected.
And I want my private information to stay private.
Right.
So that's not a bad thing.
The problem is when it's abused, and there are some gray areas, and that's why you have
rules and regulations on how corporations, whether it's S Corp, C Corp, LLC, and I'm
not going to go into a class here about corporations, but it's something I know a little bit about
because I was involved in it.
And so we have to respect that.
And then when you have a corporation, just like a human being that's got security
clearances, that's working on national security type issues, they're even more protected,
right?
Because we don't want adversaries to get a hold of that technology, which is, again,
understandable.
I get it.
The problem is when people in those corporations, not the corporation itself, people in the
corporation are making decisions, just like people in the government are making decisions
that are not consistent with the ethics and expectations that we have in these organizations.
For monetary gain and power, mostly.
Correct.
Okay, I got maybe a couple questions left, and then we're going to hop into the questions
from the interns, if that's all right.
You've been great so far.
Thank you so much for sticking through this with me.
Sure.
Coffee helps, by the way.
I can get you another one here shortly.
Okay.
There is a documentary coming out that you've been a part of that we just saw that's been
making the rounds, The Age of Disclosure.
It seems like a big one.
It seems like a Dobs or Dream team.
There's a lot of people in that lineup.
Can you shed any light on what's to be expected in this documentary?
I haven't seen it yet.
I'm very eager for it to come out.
I have been part of facilitating a lot of the people who are in that movie to come forward.
It's been a long project, probably about three years now.
It's been done, as most people now know, Sub Rosa, in secret.
Because it's very important, and there's people that are being interviewed that have
never come out publicly on this topic.
That we've not seen on the trailer.
We've not seen on the trailer.
I think people can expect...
You know what?
People are funny, right?
Some people come back and say, wow, this is the definitive documentary.
And then other people come out and say, meh.
Nothing burger.
Yeah, because you're not meeting their expectations, right?
Sure.
And so I'm very, very...
What I think it does, it certainly moves the needle in the right direction.
Everything I try to do is to move the needle in the right direction.
I think this film project is another example of some very brave Americans coming forward.
First-hand witnesses?
I don't want to give too much away.
I'll let the audience decide for themselves.
I want to be very careful what I say and what I don't say.
But I do believe it's going to change the conversation irrevocably.
And I'm very excited for it to come out.
Are you aware of any new footage of UAP or NHI being featured?
I can't discuss the details of the film, like I said.
I have to ask on behalf of the audience.
Yeah, sure.
I have not seen the film in its complete form,
but you have some very, very significant information in that documentary.
Jay Stratton says...
Not just Jay.
Okay, well, I mean, that is interesting.
But Jay Stratton does say that he has seen an NHI.
Do you know what he's referring to?
I do, but you have to talk to Jay about that.
I don't like speaking on other people's behalf.
Okay.
You've probably noticed that in other interviews.
I'm not a kiss and tell kind of guy.
And I'm the kind of guy that if people want to throw rocks at me for that, that's fine.
No, I respect that, actually.
I think that's probably the best move there.
But is it safe to assume that you know what he's talking about?
I don't like to presume or assume anything.
Great.
Just have to...
Have you yourself seen NHI?
Let's just share that one for a little later.
Little later, like after this airs?
Maybe never.
No.
Again, I am very restricted on what I can say and how I say it from the government.
I still am very loyal American.
This conversation is continuing and I think more will be forthcoming in time.
And I'll leave it at that.
Can I ask one more about that?
You can ask whatever you want.
Because that's the one I want to know.
How can I phrase this in a way that you can answer this?
Are you aware of more than one type of NHI?
Let me see how I can answer this.
Accuracy is very important.
Being aware of is not necessarily the same as having proof of.
Roger.
Some people, let me give you a case.
By the way, even that proof of doesn't...
Even there's a double-edged sword with that.
There's people that will say the earth is flat.
They're flat earthers.
No matter what you tell them, earth is flat.
The fact that the earth is round is not a truth for them.
When ancient sailors used to talk about sea monsters in the great ocean,
Pacific and the Atlantic, and people said, well, that's not true.
That's just their observation.
And it turns out that there are blue whales and great white sharks and giant squid.
It was just our interpretation at the time that made it difficult.
We said, these are monsters.
Well, the reason why people didn't believe in them because we call them monsters.
She said, hey, look, there's a giant mammal out there that looks like a dolphin,
but it just got a lot bigger.
That's different than saying there's a giant monster out there that does this and that.
I know I'm being evasive on this and I'm trying to answer your question without...
Well, what I'm gathering from this is
there are potential that some of these NHI might look a lot like us.
That's certainly potential.
We do camouflaging all the time.
And as I mentioned on another interview some time ago,
you can go to a zoo in Beijing right now to the panda exhibit,
and you'll see that the zookeepers wear these fuzzy little panda suits.
And they do that because they don't want to perturb or disturb the pandas in their
local environment.
And so they feed them and they do whatever they do,
but they have to wear a panda suit to do it.
Now, is that a panda?
No, it's not a panda.
It's a human, badly acting as a panda.
And probably the pandas realize it, but maybe they say, I'm getting food.
I don't care anyways.
But it's an attempt to blend in.
In intelligence, camouflage, and I don't mean camouflage,
necessarily physical camouflage like in a military unit.
I mean mental camouflage.
The ability to assimilate into an organization or a society is very important.
And that's how spies work.
Spies do their job because they're like a magician.
They get away with doing things that most people don't perceive or see.
And it's a way for us to protect ourselves and to do things.
So it's not unusual.
You know, I want to give you an example, and I might get in trouble for this.
So there are certain circumstances in the military where military personnel
don't advertise their affiliation with the government.
It doesn't say U.S. Army and Sergeant Johnson on there.
They go in with sterile uniforms, and they do that for a reason.
Because they don't want the affiliation of a formal government
entity to be known.
That in itself is a form of camouflage, blending in with the society.
Army special forces do this all the time when they go into a country to train
individuals in weapons tactics and things like that.
You don't advertise, I'm a special forces guy, right?
They got the long shaggy beard for a reason.
Because they don't want to look military.
They're wearing civilian clothes and jeans and carrying a Kalashnikov for a reason.
Without getting into a lot of detail, right?
So is it a hard idea to say, well, look, if something is visiting us,
would it want to blend in?
There's certainly an argument for that.
Oh, okay.
There's an argument for that.
Is there evidence pointing to that being the case?
Not proof.
Let me stay on the fence with that.
Because again, knowing how people are predisposed to take information and
run to the hills, Lou Elizondo confirms the existence of hybrids, right?
That's what I'm trying to avoid.
Because Lou Elizondo is not-
You said it, not me.
Yeah, I know.
Lou Elizondo is not confirming the existence of hybrids for the record.
Okay.
You heard that.
But I'm saying, is it a possibility?
Sure, it's a possibility.
Camouflage is not just a human thing.
Animals in the wild do it.
Fish do it.
Lizards and chameleons do it.
It's part of our natural ability to blend in.
If you ever want to see a master of disguise, look at an octopus.
They do it for survival.
People say, well, you have to be a smart thing in order to try to camouflage and blend in.
Not necessarily.
That's not true.
No, camouflage is seen throughout.
There's a reason why my background is microbiology and immunology.
Let me give you a perfect example.
There are parasites and there are microorganisms that are parasitic that mimic healthy human tissue
to evade the autoimmune response.
And these are bacteria that will have brains and high functioning thought processes like we do.
This is at a very basic elemental scale of our reality, of nature.
Nature is a master of mimicry, and there's a reason why even plants
will sometimes have attributes that mimic other plants.
Yeah, but we're not talking about plants.
Well, in a greater context, I'm trying to answer your question with that answer.
Is that a distinctly earth thing or is that any form of life that evolves to a certain point
uses camouflage to blend in?
And we don't have that answer, but it's something that's being proposed.
It's something that's being looked into.
It's certainly something that has been discussed.
But obviously, as someone who's in this topic, you're also aware of the other kind,
the one that's a little bit more blatant in terms of observation of not being from here.
Are there images or videos of these beings?
I don't want people to take this the wrong way, so I'm going to abstain from that answer,
and it's not because I'm trying to be evasive and be like, oh, Luke confirmed. No, I didn't.
There's a very specific reason why I'm on the fence with this.
I'm hoping it becomes more apparent soon, but I'm very careful not to commit one way or the other.
Have I heard it? Yeah, of course.
People that I trust and know and have had the conversation, yes.
But I also haven't myself experienced that, so for me to say yes or no,
so what I'm doing is proposing if people are having trouble understanding the question,
they only have to look at Mother Nature to see countless examples
where biology does it for them automatically.
So is it that much of a stretch to, we have stealth aircraft right now that can be confused
as a bird because of its radar profile and radar return, and we do that on purpose.
Camouflage is something that is animals, all life forms, on Earth at least,
have been using that in mimicry since the beginning for survival.
Okay. We'll get off the NHI stuff. Thank you for answering those questions.
I know I didn't answer it. Your audience is going to be really pissing me for that.
I mean, I think your reluctance to answer some of these questions provides us with enough
information, and I'm not going to assume anything, but I'm going to say that this topic is being
taken seriously. All options are on the table until they're not.
Yeah. When it comes to pilots, obviously, you guys are thinking about that. Obviously,
there's a department that is all about the pilots. If you're the nuts and bolts guy,
someone else is the pilot guy or girl.
Consider me more of an airframe kind of guy.
Okay. Airframe kind of guy. Okay. Makes sense. But I mean, even your background in microbiology
does make it really interesting because- I know. I've had a lot of people approach me
about that like, come on, it's not a coincidence on your background.
Because there was another 4chan whistleblower who claimed to be a microbiologist and he had,
I mean, this is something I could maybe run by you eventually and have you look at what he wrote,
but he basically dissected a gray alien and says he was at, what was the, I forget the location,
but essentially took these grays and from eyes to mouths to nose to the pores on their skin that's
to create this like ammonia type stuff to the forefingers and the entire being.
This was posted to Reddit and this is a massive file. It's very complex to look at. I've shown
it to experiencers and to abductees and it seems to coincide with all of the red flags that they've
perceived as well. I would expect there at least to be, is there a department that is looking into
just NHI? Without getting into trouble, let me ask you a question. Sure.
Let's say hypothetically, you're doing something and one of your vehicles crashes and so what do
we do? We do a recovery mission where we go and say, okay, we're going to recover our craft and
get the pilot out of there. How would you feel if when you get back and not only has the plane been
taken away, but when you say, well, how's our pilot? They say, oh, yeah, about that. We chopped
them up into a bunch of pieces and studied them. Okay. What you're saying is that there's nothing
left to give back. How would you feel about that? What would the reaction be? Again, I'm a nuts and
bolts guy. I'm not a biological guy. You're saying that's not a good thing to put out there.
Probably not because how would you feel if you're out in the jungles and one of your buddy's
helicopters crashes and it turns out that the natives not only dismantled your helicopter,
but wound up chopping up the pilot into a thousand pieces and, oops, sorry about that.
Yeah, that's a whole other can of worms. If that turns out to be potentially the case,
if it turns out to be the case, that's not a great way to have diplomacy.
Right. Understood. Yeah. Okay. Interesting stuff, man. All right. We're going to get to some
questions from the interns. Probably a little lighter. All right. Hold on a second. Let me
prepare myself. I'm a Gemini like long walks on the beach, pina coladas. Okay. Let me turn on this
camera. And while I set up the other camera, I thought it was interesting that we were sitting
with the person who's partially responsible for turning the term UFO into UAP officially.
So I thought it might be time to make UAP UFO again. You can pick these hats up at area52.shop.
Hey, this is actually funny because it kind of has to do with what we were just talking about.
Okay. Oh, that's cool. Survey says.
Your Q I think is supposed to be an S. Oh yeah, it could be. What does it say here? Oh yeah.
Do you believe any sort of cohabitation between our species and the alien species exists?
And this is from 0811. Correct, sir. So to 0811, let me throw this at you.
Most anthropologists agree that modern human species, homo sapiens sapiens has been around
between 200 to 400,000 years. Our earth is roughly four and a half billion years old,
according to most scientists and geologists. And so we have really only been around in modern form
for a very short period of time. And we've only been looking to the heavens with technology to
actually allow us to look and only been off this planet for the last 60 years, right? Out of that
400,000 years. And we've always been asking the question, are we alone? And we know life here on
earth is prolific. It's everywhere. It's all the places we never expected to be. It's miles
beneath the Arctic ice. It's in the bottom of the ocean by the black smokers. There's life forms
that every time we try to define what life is, mother nature wiggles her way out of the box.
There was a time when I was taught that all life derived from photosynthesis. Turns out that's not
true. Go to the bottom of the ocean. There's animals and critters that live off something
called chemosynthesis around the black smokers, these very, very hot upwellings of water and
minerals in deep oceans. There's bacteria that can live on the skin of the ISS space station,
where the radiation levels are through the roof in the extremes of temperature, right?
Every time we try to put mother nature in a box, we learn that we're wrong. And so in our quest to
find intelligent life in the universe, in all that time, is it possible that life found us first?
Is it possible that because the same way we detect planets with their atmosphere,
someone detected us and said, hey, that's a really special little planet out there.
We need to figure out what that's about. And it's not that this cohabitation of our species
is something recent. Is it possible there's a long history of there? In fact, when we were
proto-humans, is it possible that some sort of advanced species was already observing us?
Mm-hmm. The universe is very old. Even the Earth being four and a half billion years old,
the universe is much older. We're a third, maybe fourth generation star system, which means the
stuff that made our star came from another star, which came from a supernova, which before that
became from a hypernova, which before that became from... So even our Earth is relatively young in
the scale of the universe. Is it possible that in our attempts to find intelligent life out in
the cosmos that it has found us first? I think it's certainly possible. In fact, I think it's
more than likely. Yeah, we are not alone. Okay, next question here. Let's see how this one goes.
Cattle and human manipulations. Mutilations.
Yeah, mutilations, right? Cattle and human mutilations don't seem to get discussed.
What's your take on this? And this is from Sensubin?
Yeah. Sensubin, okay. We know of the observables in the Pentagon. We always talked about the five
observables, but we've always maintained there's actually six. One of them is biological effects.
So I think the issue here is the word mutilations. We are superimposing two different things. A
mutilation is usually something very negative, and it's usually a crime. And so we hear about
cattle mutilations. Why? Because a cattle is the sovereign property of the farmer.
And if an animal gets hurt or injured or destroyed in a deliberate fashion or whether it's by an
animal predator or human or anything else, it's a mutilation. Human mutilations usually have
something called human experience, not a mutilation. Most of the people, they refer to themselves as
quote unquote experiencers, will relay either very positive or very negative sensation. But
but mutilation is usually not ascribed because it's not permanent. It doesn't result in death
like it does for a cow, for example. No, there's been some examples.
Yeah. Well, yeah, there are some outlying stories of individuals have been-
With similar effects that the cows had. Sure. Well, the cows aren't aware.
Usually the cows and horses aren't around to tell you their story. What we're left is with a body
that's in the process of decomposition, advanced decomposition, in some cases,
that appeared to have some sort of surgical precision without loss of blood and instant
cauterization of blood vessels, right? Without a trace of-
Without a trace, right. And I've spoken to an individual who worked for the department of,
let me see if we can get him in trouble. He was a USDA person who happened to be also a
veterinarian. And so he worked for the government, but he was also a senior
veterinarian out somewhere out west. And I had a chance to speak to him and he told me point blank,
look, what's happening to some of these cows? It's not natural predation and it's not us.
Something is doing this. And we're very concerned within his office.
As far as humans, there are people that we have like Dr. Gary Nolan, who focused on the biological
effects, however you want to describe that, right? Sure.
However you want to describe that. Where there does seem to be, at least in some cases-
Brain scarring and-
Correct. So where there's been specific morphology. Now, the question is, we have to ask,
is it deliberate? Look, it could just be a product of the technology. If I stick my head
too close to a microwave oven while the microwave oven is on and the door is open,
don't be surprised if I get severe negative medical consequences. I'm putting my head next
to radiation, right? It's not the fault of the microwave. It's just doing what it does.
If you get near some advanced technology that you don't understand, don't be surprised if
something happens, right? If I'm at an airport, I jump on a 737, hey, no threat. But if I'm at
an airport, I jump onto the tarmac, the runway where that airplane is and its engine is throttling
up, what's going to happen? Well, I'm going to go deaf. I'm going to get burned. Bad things happen.
Is it the fault of the airplane? No. It's my fault. I got too damn close to it, right?
Yeah. That's for humans, but for the cattle part, I mean, that just seems...
Right. Well, so let's go back to the question. Cattle and human relations don't seem to get
discussed. Well, not publicly. Well, but we're discussing it now, right? And what's my take on
it? My take is that there are some similarities, but there's also some very significant differences
from what I have learned and been privy to. Again, I am not an expert on bovine. I'm not an expert
on equine. It wasn't part of the... It could just be like the, I guess the...
Because it's scary when you see these animals. Yeah. Well, it's disturbing. It really is.
Incredibly disturbing. And they're lovely animals. You didn't ask for that. And when you see them in
the state they're in... But don't we do the same though? Not to be obvious, but don't we do the
same to those animals? To rats, we do the same to those animals specifically. We eat them. Yeah.
Brother, we put them in a place where they're with a bunch of other animals. They know they're
going to die. Correct. We put them through this awful little runway where they're forced to run
down. And the next thing they know, they've got a bull in the brain or they're getting a throat
slashed and they're choking on their own blood. You're correct. So when we say cattle and
mutilations, that's awful. Well, what's really awful? We do the same thing. But we also don't
advertise that. And that's my point. I think for the same reason is why it doesn't get discussed.
We don't talk about the deplorable conditions in these farms that these pigs get slaughtered in.
Yeah. Terrible. Terrible. But we don't talk about it. We don't advertise it. Could it be that that's
the same reason we don't talk about these cattle mutilations? Well, possibly. We also don't know
that maybe these cattle are being selected. Maybe they're being dispatched or perhaps killed
before that happens. We're assuming and presuming it's all happening at once. These poor defenseless
animals, they're just being tortured. That may not be the case at all. It could be they're being
euthanized. And then they're doing it and then, okay, well, let's put it there in a far corner
there where it'll naturally decay. Well, the dumb humans come across it, okay, but that's
what we're doing. We as a species do that. We mutilate animals all the time. Go to some of
these, I want to be careful here, don't upset anybody, but go to some of these wet markets.
Have you seen the way some of these animals are and they're living and breathing and conscious
and they know what's going to happen to them. Dogs, cats, animals, birds, cattle mutilate.
If you ask me, that's a hell of a lot more humane than the crap we do.
Yep. All right. Good take. I like it.
And we do it to ourselves too, unfortunately.
That is true too. Okay. Last one from the audience here.
That's a good one.
It's like a game show.
I love it. They said, I'm an old, I'm old school, so I remember actually the shows,
the game shows that did that, right?
Yeah, the train stations.
What is more interesting regarding the UAPs and related phenomena, the sky or the sea? Wow.
And this is from Dennis W. Dennis W, good question. All of them are good. Let me see if I can do this.
Well, interesting is subjective, right? So if you're, well, to most people,
if you're an aerospace person, then the atmosphere-
What I mean to you, this question is directed for you.
No, but I'm saying here, I'm looking at it through a specific lens.
I see, I see.
I'm caveat first. So people know that I'm not, the reason why my perspective is the way it is,
because it's to me in my background.
Okay, I got you.
So if you come from an aerospace background, the things in the sky are very, very interesting.
If you come from an oceanographic perspective, let's say like Tim Gallaudet, then the undersea
things seem to be more interesting because you are an expert in those areas. And when you see
the UAP performing the way they're performing, whether you're an aerospace guy or an undersea guy,
it's pretty amazing, right? So you're like, oh, wow, how is that possible?
I mean, yeah, the air stuff is interesting, but the water is so dense and you can't,
how is that possible, right? And then the aerospace guy says, yeah, but we're going to,
the things are coming in from outer space and then you understand the physics involved.
And so it's important to caveat that because one is not more important than the other.
It's no different than you driving your, what's more interesting when you're driving your car?
Do you like driving your car in the rain or the snow? Well, it depends, you know,
if you're not used to driving in the rain, you'd rather drive in the snow. If you're not used to
driving in the snow, I'd much rather drive, you know, am I from Florida or am I from Buffalo,
New York, right? So it's going to be different for people with those backgrounds. For me,
I find very interesting the stuff that is in the sky, but not for the reason you might think,
not because of my background in aerospace, because frankly, it's a cop-out, it's easier
to collect the data. For me, it's, look, we've got so much things, airborne capability,
space-borne capability, ground capability, radars and all this other stuff. And it's easier to
collect the data and more people see it underwater. It's very tough. And unless you have a collection
capability right there, chances are you're not going to catch it. So it's not as frequent and
not as often. It doesn't mean it doesn't happen just as much. It just means that we don't have
the persistent surveillance capabilities that we do above the water. And people will look,
we're terrestrial things. We live on land, right? We can see the sky. We don't live underwater.
We're not a fish or a shark, right? So for me, I find what's in the sky very interesting,
but only because the data is more available and it's easier to make a determination what is
conventional technology. Someone's being, they're confused between that, no, that's actually an
airplane, 737 on its way to LA or that is a satellite or that's part of Starlink or that's
part of a, whatever that may be versus undersea. It's more of a puzzle up there. It's more of a
puzzle up there. Underwater, we have less information, but it's also to me more scary
because it means it's a lot closer, right? These things are from the ocean. Now it's like,
wait a minute, we're neighbors. Next time I'm on a Carnival cruise ship, heading to the Caribbean,
is it possible one of these things are below us, right? That's an awfully deep ocean, like I said,
and it's interesting to consider. It's a really good question, but my answer is keep in mind,
it's very subjective. B, it's unqualified because I'm not an expert in the ocean.
Sure. And C, it's a cop-out for me because it's easier. There's just simply more data for me to
go through. Yep. All right. Great answer. All right, man. Dude, we almost pulled three hours here.
Did we? Yeah, that's crazy. One more favor I'm going to ask you. I'm going to ask you to sign
two of these. Well, three of these, one of them is for me, and I bought two extra ones because
we're going to give some away. I love it. To the audience. We're going to give them a chance to
get a signed copy here. Guys, simply, if you'd like to win one of these signed copies, make
sure you're subscribed, like this video, and then comment below your favorite part of this podcast
or this discussion. Some piece of information that you found interesting that Lou let slip through
the cracks, and I'm going to choose one of you there, and the other one is going to be an intern.
So if you want to increase your chances on winning one of these, because there are far fewer interns
and there are people watching this, you can go ahead and join our membership by clicking the join
button or go ahead and go to patreon.com slash area 52 investigations and join for five bucks a
month there. And we got all sorts of extra stuff, but I'll be choosing one of our interns to win the
other signed copy. Thank you so much for watching. And Lou. Thank you to all of you. I don't know
what the primary camera, but to all of you, thank you. Thank you. Thank you for your time. Hopefully
I didn't drone on and bore the hell out of you. Talk to my wife. She'll tell you I go the hell
out of people all the time. But thank you truly. And if you don't mind, just so you know, you are
making the difference. This is only possible because of you. And not only are other people
listening, but governments of the world are listening to you. So thank you for your courage
and having the curiosity in this topic, a topic that was once perceived as being, according to the
American Psychological Association, as being an extreme form of deviance.
Thank you for being curious. Thank you for your courage, being part of this conversation with us.
And we do it for you. So thank you and God bless. Thanks, man. You got it, brother. Appreciate it.
Absolutely. My honor and privilege.