Hello, I'm in.
I had a friend who was working with me at my counseling center for many years.
He revealed to me that he was in fact an alien, which sounded superficial, and he could have
been a good liar until he was able to demonstrate that he was more than just a human.
And he was friends with me for many years, and I never knew it until he was able to demonstrate
this to me.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome back to a very special episode of Debriefed.
My name is Chris Ramsey, and today I'm here to introduce you a conversation that I had
recently with Randall Nickerson.
I just wanted to come here to sort of preface the interview.
For those of you unfamiliar with Randall's story, him and his sister Glinda have been
abducted multiple times.
They were featured in the 90s on shows like Oprah and Good Morning America.
One of Dr. Mac's patients, Randy, here says his abduction occurred while he was awake.
They had put me out for a little over an hour, and when I came to...
And yeah, I have a hard time with this.
Why?
Because I don't want to believe it, and I really don't.
It...
I mean, it's totally made me question what life's about, and it's stirred my life up
a lot.
It was a very popular case of abduction, which pretty much upended their lives, especially
Randall's.
To this day, Randall has a pretty hard time talking about it, and has since basically
turned his entire life into reporting on and investigating the UFO and NHI phenomenon.
Now, this was a last-minute podcast.
Nothing was planned.
He just happened to be in town, and out of respect for Randall, he didn't want to talk
about his own personal abduction story, and I didn't want to press him on that either.
But Randall's story isn't simply defined by his abduction.
See, Randall is also an amazing filmmaker and documentarian, and recently he put out
the documentary, The Ariel Phenomenon.
From all over Zimbabwe, we were phoning the BBC to say, we've seen something weird.
There were three of us that saw it.
Myself, the copilot, and the pilot in the other aircraft.
No wings.
No nothing.
Shiny over thing.
Ariel, school 19th, September 94.
Did you tell me what you saw on Friday?
The silver thing in amongst this clump of trees.
We saw this black figure running.
His face was like this, and his eyes were down here.
I just thought it was some kind of failure from a different point.
When you looked at those children, they were absolutely credible.
And whereabouts was it?
Dishonored in the trees over there.
There was a big group of kids pointing and making noise and shouting and screaming.
The panic spread.
Am I safe or am I not safe?
These are Harvard psychiatrists.
Meet Dr. John Mack, a believer in aliens from outer space.
We came away convinced that an extraordinary event occurred here.
I think they want people to know that we're actually making harm on this world.
Would you like to see him again?
Yes.
And if you saw him again, what would you do?
I'll ask him some questions.
What would you like to ask him?
I'll ask him, what is he doing on Earth and what does he want with us?
Basically picking up John Mack's work of where he left off and continuing his research into
the mass sighting that took place in Rua Zimbabwe.
Over 60 children reported seeing this craft and two beings exiting this craft.
They subsequently drew images and even wrote down exactly what they remember happening.
And I also just want to say that at times Randall during this podcast will seem a little
bit reluctant to talk about certain things.
And that definitely stems from his own personal experiences.
So this is just to give you a little bit of context on who he is.
He recently also appeared on the Danny Jones podcast and I highly recommend you check that
out if you want to know a little bit more about his personal history.
Stick around after the podcast if you like.
We recorded a little extra podcast for the interns only and you can do that by going
to Patreon or clicking join on the memberships.
And yeah, thanks for watching.
First of all, thank you so much for doing this Randall.
It was a pleasure.
We got to know each other in the last couple of days, spent New Year's together.
Just a joy to meet you and to get to know you as a person in the little time that we
had.
It was just really pleasant.
So really made my New Year's meeting you.
So thank you for that.
For those of you who don't know Randall's work, we're going to be talking about a lot
about something that's extremely fascinating.
One of the biggest cases in history in terms of mass sighting, Randall's a really good
filmmaker known for his documentary, Ariel Phenomenon.
And it just highlights one of the most significant sightings in human history that was ever
documented initially by like John Mack.
And then you kind of picked up the torch and continued that and then developed relationships
obviously with the people there.
And this case, you know, not only is just awesome in terms of data for people who are
interested in ufology, but for you became a really big part of your life.
Like that you, this case is really, really close to you.
And so, you know, for me, it's a bit of an honor to even be able to talk about this case
with you because I think like you'll be the closest person to that event that I'll possibly
ever meet.
Right.
So for me, this is this is really a once in a lifetime opportunity.
So thank you for being here.
Thank you.
I mean, I really appreciated meeting you and love the magic, bro.
It was really, I've enjoyed our time together a lot.
Like I feel, yeah, I like you genuinely like you as a person.
Thank you.
I appreciate you.
You know, and that's nice.
Yeah.
It's very disarming in a sense, you know, like, hey, I can be myself with you.
You know?
Yeah.
I appreciate you.
I do appreciate you as well.
And didn't expect to do an interview or anything.
Yeah.
I'm like, hey, I like this guy.
I know.
This is last minute.
But the magic thing is cool because you actually, you know, people might not know this about
you, probably don't know this about you, but you like dabbled a little bit in some sleight
of hand.
And, you know, we kind of connected on that the first first time I met you.
I was like, I do magic.
And you're like, oh, and like, you're like, I did a little bit of that, too.
So I noticed when I was performing to like people, I see how you were looking at something
and how you're reacting to something is very similar to how I would react to something.
So you already had like a mind for it and understood that there was something behind
the trick.
Mm hmm.
So that's cool.
I'm still trying to figure out how that got on my I could get if it was one mark or that's
a crop.
Uh huh.
Yeah.
Like, I'm like, damn.
That was really, really cool.
I'm glad you like that.
It's a cool gift.
You know, I reminisced on it on the drive home and how it's such a cool gift because
you even said that you told me, you know, to be able to impart sort of wonder onto people.
It's just like a really nice gift to have.
And it just reminded me so much of that and like thinking about that because, you know,
I forget that sometimes to take it for granted that it's just a trick, you know, but I set
out learning it to give that gift of wonder.
And so thank you for reminding me of that.
That was it really made me think I was like it is I am lucky to have this sort of I don't
want to call it a gift, but you know, I've practiced it a lot.
But to have that to be able to share that people break the ice with people, I don't
know.
You know, it, it, it helps.
Yeah.
I mean, I don't even know where we would even start with this.
For people who aren't familiar, this was 1994.
Yes.
September 16th, 1994.
And it was in it was a town, right?
Town of Rua or?
It's on the border of Rua in a Gurumandi actually, but Rua is right.
It's right on the border at a primary school.
Basically K through seven.
How far removed from like the population is this is this school?
It's a little bit off the beaten path, isn't it?
It is.
Yeah.
You know, you get out there, there is villages, you know, and densely populated, Rua is very
densely populated village.
But it's, you know, the farmers actually started it in 91 because they were sending their kids
to Harare, which is the capital.
And is it the capital?
I think it is.
Oh, unfamiliar.
Sorry.
Yeah, no.
I like to double check my work.
Harare Zimbabwe, yeah.
So yeah, the farmers were, you know, wanted to set up a school and there was a house and
then they built the school over the years.
And then they, you know, brought so the farmers kids, missionary kids, kids from all over
in the villages as well.
And it's just an amazing, it's a beautiful.
It's like a college campus.
It's huge.
Really?
Real estate wise.
And so it's a beautiful school, beautiful people.
You know, it's not wealthy.
You know what I mean?
In a way, it's just not that way.
And people don't do it for that reason.
A lot of heart there.
And the people I met, I mean, all of them, the kids involved in the story, like when
I started way in 2007 and slowly got to know these people and the teachers and parents
and everybody involved in this case, yeah, you get to know them and love them as people.
I just have to mention because one of our, one of the kids had passed away, Emily.
Just it affected a lot of people.
She was 38 years old and just loved her as a creative person and heart.
She's in the film and I spent a lot of time with her and just saw her do some really just
giving from her heart to people that had less, you know, or were struggling, like little
moments I would see that and I don't even know what to say.
I think everybody that knew her is still in shock that she's no longer with us.
And I have to say the other kids too, like I call them kids, but they're, you know, they
were kids, but they're just, I feel like they, it's not been easy for them, you know, to
come forward or have me tell their story, you know, and then all these other people
come in with different intentions because, you know, when I was working on it, I was,
I knew it was a great story.
And then when other people found out, they kind of jumped in like, oh yeah, we want this,
you know, and they didn't have the same caring.
They see money signs.
Money signs and fame, you know.
That was never my purpose for now.
Clearly, yeah.
I mean, even with, you know, you look at the final product, you can tell, you know, there's
heart there.
There's heart in your interactions.
And you know, I mean, there's one thing that I'll say, first of all, sorry for your loss.
I'm sorry for that and I know that, you know, I heard that you guys are very close and Luigi
as well, who's here off camera, by the way, he was also very close.
They're a family, I mean, they're an amazing family.
Wonderful people.
I went to the funeral and oh my God, like they are just tragic.
I mean, there were tears in that.
I don't think I've been to a funeral that I've heard so many people crying.
Yeah, she had a lot of effect on people and anyway, but the family just put out love and
respect to the family.
Yeah, that, you know, as someone who is coming into this space with, you know, intentions
to shine a light on some of this, partially for my own curiosity, you know, admittedly,
but also to give people voice and make this a little bit normalized and stuff, you know,
going into this, but there is a sticky sort of situation that you can put yourself in
when speaking to experiencers because the last thing that I want to do is feel like
I'm exploiting anyone, right?
And that's, I think, I think just like extremely important to be aware of because, you know,
when dealing with people, you're not only dealing with people who are, who have seen
something amazing, you're dealing with people who are, you know, traumatized and, you know,
the last thing you want to do is, you know, be pushy or be like, but, you know, from your
angle coming into this, like, how aware were you of that?
Like a probably, I mean, hyper aware is my guess, but like, did you, like, how did you
navigate that?
You know, just like being very honest with them, like, I'm not here to, I'm here to really
hear your story.
Like, I'm not here to exploit it or to kind of understanding that what it was, was impactful.
I mean, anybody you talk to that's had this happen, they are going to remember it till
the day they die.
They will remember that time and that's the kind of experiences and it affects your whole
development depending on how old you were or whatever happens.
So just trust, you know, trying to say, you know, I really want to hear what, what, what
you went through.
It's been hard, I think, throughout history because people really don't understand what
people go through, the ontological shock of having, like, that's not supposed to exist
or be real and all of a sudden you can't go back there anymore because you've seen it,
you've seen it and it changes a lot for those people.
They go through so much that people don't realize it's sort of callously misunderstood.
And in that process, what happens is those people, you know, over time say, I don't want
to talk about it anymore, people don't understand, I'm not going to talk about it anymore.
So they get quiet over time, the more they are public, the more you're, you pay consequences
for that.
Yeah.
And it's unfortunate because it's really important that, that what witnesses have to say.
And I mean, that's, it's a great point and on top of that, you have also people trying
to actively shut you up, you know, which is like the counter, you know, energy to that.
You got people who are like, no, you need to share this and you got people being like,
if you share that, something bad is going to happen to you.
And so, you know, that's such a murky territory to, to navigate as a filmmaker, as a documentarian,
but also it's just a person trying to talk to somebody with an experience.
I mean, it's just such a touchy area.
It is.
It's very personal.
And with children even more so, I would think, right?
Yeah.
How were the, how were the parents with all of this?
When you were, you know, were they involved at any capacity?
Did you see any pushback?
Did you?
Oh yeah.
Yeah, very much.
There, there was, well, it was mainly around religion, right?
And then it depended on, the fascinating thing about the school was the diversity in that
school, religious wise and people from all different colors and backgrounds from different
countries.
It was just, it was a really interesting mix of people.
You just don't really see in a lot of schools.
Yeah, it was very international, I would say, and you had, so you had the indigenous people
and you had missionaries and you had government, their children, you know, all over the place.
English, Australia, you just had every, so anyway, the piece is, that was interesting.
And then how each parent, the parents or how they interpreted it from what they were brought
up with.
Yeah, so, yeah, you had a few parents that were very pushing back big time, but you had
a lot of parents that were, that my child, you know, were very supportive of their children.
Like this is not, my child would not do this, right?
Like they knew their children well and they stood up for their children.
Wow.
That was, like it's not even in the movie.
So much footage and interviews that I did that just didn't, it would have been a three
hour movie.
Yeah.
I mean, time was our biggest problem.
I wouldn't have minded.
I know we've been, that's the next thing is, you know, we wanted to do the director's cut.
It's still, yeah.
That's difficult though, as someone who, you know, I do a lot of editing myself.
Like when you're, when you got so much, you know, quote unquote gold, you know, in a project,
like chopping that up, it's got to be tough.
And they call it killing your babies.
Killing your babies.
Yeah, that's what I say too.
Yeah.
It's a tough job.
Is there, is there any scene in there that you kind of regretted not leaving in?
Was there anything that you were like, maybe that should have been in?
Not, I mean, for that time, we had to get it to, you know, it was an hour and 41.
Was that the mandate?
Basically an hour and a half, 90 minutes.
So we were a little over that, but that's the best we could do without, we had a three
hours solid.
Yeah.
Wow.
And so given the time constraints, I think it was well done.
Chris Seward was amazing editor and story editor.
But it was a challenge whittling it down.
Once we had the three hour, we're like, damn, this is really, really good.
But you know, people have to use the bathroom around that time period, an hour and a half.
So that's kind of why it's all based around that and the tensions, man.
But yeah, there's many scenes, you know, I was just showing Luigi and a few other people
the scene with Emily making the decision to go to Africa, which we didn't include in it.
But it's just, I love that scene.
Wow.
Yeah.
We shot it at NORAD up in the St. Adolf, I think.
The old NORAD base.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
So yeah, there's so many of the scenes and, you know, we had a good half hour just on
the spiritual, the natives, native indigenous chiefs and medicine men who we went to see.
And Emily went to see several of them with us.
And that was a very large piece that was really well cut together, but it was a half
hour.
Right.
Just that.
Because that's fascinating.
This is not new to them.
It's not new to them at all.
They weren't surprised by any of it?
Oh, not at all.
Wow.
They've seen them themselves.
Did you find?
That was amazing because I'm shooting about Ariel.
And then the chief starts talking about like little details and I'm like, oh my God, he
has seen them himself.
Like and I want to stop everything and go, I want to, I need to take this guy and toss
him, you know, and I didn't get the chance to do that except with a few people, a few
of the medicine men chiefs, the village, you know, doctors, basically.
That's exciting.
They were so familiar with it.
It was just.
That was Emily with that.
Like the fact that like, was that comforting to her?
Was that?
Yeah.
Very much.
It must have been like so validating being like, oh, finally someone who gets it.
Like.
Yeah.
So we, in the movie, we show bits and pieces of that, but it was much more in-depth than
they.
Yeah.
That was, I mean, it was fascinating for me to be over in Africa.
Three trips I went, by the way, just three times I was, I spent a year and three months
in Africa.
Wow.
Living there.
What was your, what was your favorite thing about Africa aside from, I know that the people
is amazing and the scenery is amazing, but what's, what's something that just like you
took home with you?
The wildlife.
When I wasn't doing interviews, I was out.
Drive it self-driving.
Really?
Oh yeah.
What were you seeing?
Like.
Oh God.
Everything.
They got everything out there?
Oh yeah.
Really?
I was out there for days and days and days.
Wow.
Between interviews, I'd be like, okay, I found this child or person, one of the witnesses
or their parents or somebody else that witnessed it in the area, and I'm like, okay, I've got
three days and I would go into a park, you know?
Wow.
When I first got there, I went on a proper safari and I learned as much as I could, and
then I started meeting more people that basically were telling me this is what you don't do.
Yeah.
And do.
And then I got up enough courage to start going on my own, and then I, big thing was
camping with a Bushman, camping in a pup tent.
Out there.
Oh my God.
Are you hearing all sorts of stuff at night?
Like we were at the campfire, you know, you set your truck up, or the Range Rover, and
then your tent and the fire in a triangle, because you need to, you know.
Defenses.
Yeah.
And so you'd see the reflection of the eyes of the hyena.
Whoa.
They come up to the, about 50 feet away from the site, and they just lay down and just
watch for opportunity.
And then you hear the lions roaring, and you can hear them from miles and miles away.
They're so loud.
They rattle at your chest.
So once you, once that fire goes out, you better be in that tent or the vehicle.
So we were, and it's a, it's a serious, I have not had anything more serious than that
at Shard.
I bet.
It sounds incredible.
There's certain rules, you know, you don't allow them to see you.
They can smell you, but don't leave, you can't leave anything open window-wise.
You can't be like on your phone with the light shining your face at night type deal.
Can't let them see you.
Yeah.
Because if they see you and smell you, they're coming.
Oh.
It's just, yeah, it's a whole different thing.
And if you're near any body of water, you got to worry about the crocs because they
come out on land at night.
Wow.
They'll go like a mile away from the water at night.
Really?
Wow.
Yeah.
That's terrifying.
Everything.
Okay.
It has the potential to do that.
But, you know, it's so funny.
You'd be camping.
Sorry.
I'm going on about this.
No, it's fine.
It was, it was, it was just magical.
Yeah.
And there was something weird about being there was like, I kind of know this, you know?
You felt familiar.
It oddly felt like I somehow, at some point I, I was familiar with that feeling.
Yeah.
I mean, it felt like home and a weird, I've never felt that.
It was like a past life type thing, maybe.
Maybe.
Yeah.
I just, I'd never felt that anywhere like that.
But yeah, that's, oh.
What was the, what was the night sky like there?
I mean, I'm guessing because of the lack of light pollution, you must've had like some
amazing night, like sky watching.
Yeah, very much.
You ever see anything out there?
That's all I'd be thinking about.
I'd be like seeing that many stars, checking out satellites and whatnot.
Well, yeah.
The thing about, everything's backwards because you're upside down on the ball.
Oh, weird.
So the sun rises in a different direction.
You see, you know, Orion upside down.
Right.
The moon rises, goes the other way.
It's, when you really pay attention, you're like, wow, this is, I'm on the bottom side
of a ball.
And so your perspective is completely, that fascinated me.
Seeing a new sky.
Yeah.
And the skies are just so dark.
Like you can see everything.
Wow.
Yeah.
I try to spend as much, they, they spend a lot of time outside, you know.
I probably would too.
Yeah.
Oh, it's beautiful.
The only thing you do have to worry about is the, everything killing you.
500 pound cat.
Being food is a problem.
Being just a, being just like a food with, with, with technology on you.
That's all you are.
Yeah.
All right.
So getting back to this sighting, this, okay, I'm going to encourage everybody to just go
watch the documentary.
I'm, you know, given a play by play, it's just much better to just go watch the documentary,
go get familiar with it.
You know, see for yourself, the, the truth that is spoken by these witnesses, that is
for me, I think one of the most compelling pieces of evidence.
And in today's day and age, even more compelling than possibly a 4k video, because that can
be faked.
You can, you can film something on 4k and I can ask chat GPT to like cook something
up pretty much.
You know, we're, we're almost there, but you can't fake, you can't fake these interactions.
And you know, as someone who's studied human psychology, you know, for magic and you can,
you can just tell, you don't even need to be an expert, but you can tell when you look
at someone, especially children, that, you know, and then I will, I will say as well
that like, sure, kids will embellish, kids will, you know, and lay it on thick sometimes
too.
But the core of what they're saying happened.
This happened to them.
What piece of information for you personally, were you like, oh shit, this is real.
Yeah, that's interesting.
So I, you know, I had just John Max material in the beginning, which was very moving, for
sure.
A lot of things I didn't understand what they were referencing, because it was from a different
culture.
So I kind of like, well, I think once I found the school was still there, and then I got
on a plane very quickly, like I have got to go there.
And that kind of opened up, you know, I wasn't convinced either way.
I mean, I knew these people were telling the truth.
It's pretty obvious that they're, you can tell, you know, I mean, people know when people
are truthful.
Yeah.
It's in the eyes and behavior.
It's hard to fake that.
I don't know if it's even possible.
I've never, never seen that really.
I got a good BS detector and yeah, that's what I first saw.
And then I was discovering more, well, then I first met the teachers that were there when
I went there.
And the first time, and yeah, I was like, well, what do you think?
It definitely happened.
I'm like, wow, that's interesting.
Like there were still three teachers that were still there, that were there at the time.
And I didn't know what to expect.
I was just showing up and doing like a pre-investigation, like, you know, and there were many steps
like of the teachers was, that was the first thing.
Then I started talking to the first witnesses, found all those people, and there was a progression
and I kept hearing the same in the eyes and the truthfulness of it, the directness of
it, that it was kind of a step process in a way.
The more I found out and the more people I met that had seen it, and it wasn't just the
kids at school, it wasn't just some of the teachers, it was a lot of people from outside
that area, which also wasn't in the film really.
Some of the archival was there, but there were others.
Just local interactions?
Yeah, within a range, within a radius of that location.
Yeah, because there was a lot of sightings in that area that were reported prior to that.
And one of them was, I had to look at what was going on in space because I had to look
at everything.
I mean, what was going on in space?
What satellite rocket bodies were coming in?
We had sent up 130 rockets that year, so that means every three days something's fallen
through.
And a lot of stuff falls in Africa.
A lot of our launches end up in the Indian Ocean, and they have actually a whole museum
over there of rocket bodies and things that have fallen out of the sky that we have launched
or other countries have launched because they land in the desert in Africa.
Big pieces.
And so I looked into all that, and that was fascinating.
And the space shuttle was up that day.
So this is a huge piece.
So it was STS-64, was up in orbit that day, the very same day Ariel happened.
And they were doing the first untethered spacewalk of a human being from the shuttle.
It literally started two or three hours after the incident at Ariel.
It looks like you've got an object right in front of you, Mark.
Can you look out there?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Never mind.
It was monumental.
It was also one of the longest spacewalks at the time, also.
The Russians had been up a few, like a week earlier, and did their long spacewalk.
And then when we went up, and then we were testing this untethered, it was jetpack.
The first time we ever tested it in space.
So you could fly around without being tethered to the craft.
So it was a major, it's in the museum in Huntsville, Alabama.
It's an incredible coincidence.
Yeah.
I find it highly interesting because if anything, it was a human, a first for humans, a milestone.
They're in a museum for that reason.
They're in Huntsville.
Both of those safer packs, they were called Safer.
So that became a study for me, a lot of world events, what was going on at the time, what
was on movies, what was on TV.
Nobody knows all that.
I had to really dig deep to see.
Find the prosaic explanation.
Yeah.
I was good with that.
That was where it led.
I was okay with that.
One of the things that really kind of moved me a lot was when I started to find the grade
one, grade two, people that were young at the time.
The ones they didn't interview because the headmaster made a decision, which I kind of
think was proper at the time because the younger kids were really much more upset too, right?
So they decided to keep the grade ones and twos and younger out of it.
They didn't interview them.
They didn't have them draw pictures or anything.
Then I started to find those kids and they're telling me what they saw and their perspective
and their memories.
That was really fascinating because they never got a chance to ... I had to find out, were
they actually there?
Yes.
Okay.
I got their name.
I know they were there.
Got the school pictures.
That's her.
That kind of tipped it for me.
Not that I didn't believe everybody else.
That was the point though.
That was like when you got there, you were like, this happened, this is real.
Yeah.
I just remember that, those interviews, because they never got a chance to speak about it
and they had never forgotten it and it was the same thing.
It was also the other witnesses too, but it was just ...
Certain excitement that they had talking about it that felt a little bit different.
Were they just eager to share it or were they also reluctant?
No, there was a lot of reluctance I had to deal with.
There were kids that were ... Yeah, they would not share ... There was no question it left
a very big impression on them and affected their lives.
These kids had also seen not just the craft, but ...
Creatures, yeah.
I came out of that, yeah.
And then I saw a lot of people struggling with religion.
What did this mean?
Was it the devil?
Was it ... I saw a lot of that struggle.
Yeah, so there were quite a few reluctant people.
I found more of the reluctance from the males than the females to me, Frank.
It's always like that for some reason.
Men are like we're guarded, we're more sure of reality it seems like and for some reason,
I think naturally women are just a little bit more open to esoteric explanations of
things or spirituality in that case or just open to other options.
Maybe that softens the blow for them, ontologically speaking, like they don't go through the same
brick wall that we do.
I agree.
I think that is a thing where it's ... Males just have a very much harder not being in
control.
There's all the stigma or whatever that are put on men more than women.
Women have their own thing too.
I definitely noticed that quite a bit, the witnesses.
There was definitely moments where I was just like, oh yeah, this definitely happened, definitely.
There was obviously just like any major sighting, there's always a government presence that
tends to impose itself to try and control the situation.
What was it like with that?
I know there was that, but how much did that deter you or inspire you to keep going?
From the Zimbabwean government?
Yeah.
Well, I had to be really careful with that.
It's a dictatorship.
At the time it happened, Tim Leach from the BBC finally found him, and Gunter, who's the
last surviving investigator who was on the scene, they all did excellent work at the
time.
They really did, but he had gone to the military to see, did you guys have this on radar?
Which they said their radar was down, and then people would report that I think they
were flying F4 Phantoms at the time, older hand-me-downs.
But people were seeing them flying really low altitude like they were looking for something
through that whole area, a lot of witnesses to that.
When I was in the country the first time, that was 2008, I wasn't supposed to be in
the country.
That's when the New York Times reporter got arrested.
When I flew out of-
Wow.
Oh, yeah.
It was political violence.
People were being killed and tortured.
That was the, I was also, was that not, I'm thinking 2008, 2007, 2008, was that not-
Egypt soon after.
Yeah.
Was Iraq as well during that time, or was that before that?
I mean, there was a lot of global-
That was 2009.
Yeah, there was-
But there's global tensions.
Maybe at the same time.
Yeah.
Up and around that time.
Yeah, so I wasn't supposed to be there.
There's a State Department warnings and everything, and I stayed in a shack, no water, no heat,
I mean, cold water, and thanks to Nikki Carter, who was wonderful, helped me through.
She took the risk I took, no doubt about it.
I wish she could come on some of these shows.
She was originally one of the reporters who also interviewed these kids, so going back
to the footage, I had John, only had John Max footage in the beginning, and then I started
to find other interviews done by Nikki Carter for SABC, the Dutch did it, there's another
guy from Germany went over there and recorded 42 of the kids, interviewed 42.
So I ended up with six or seven different archival sources, like, oh my God, that's
brilliant, and so that was one part of the whole thing, was just collecting what happened
at the time, what did people say, what did each individual child witness say, what did
the teachers say, what did the parents say, so I had a ton of that, and then it was real
time, 20 years later at that time, of a lot of those same people, and a lot of new people
I had no idea about, that had also witnessed this, yeah, that, oh man.
It's intense, it's an intense thing to happen to so many people, you know, you touched on
that this was like an international kind of, there was a lot of diversity in this school,
that obviously has to have something to do with the reason, right?
Boy, you know, I don't know what the reason, I still do not know.
If you had to take a stab in the dark, engine failure, or would it be, it would be deliberate,
wouldn't it?
I think it was deliberate, but my biggest thing to me is what was going on up in space
at the time.
I've been told, and I did find this, I did confirm this, somebody from, who's out publicly
a lot now, a military man, he said, you know, there's a lot of uranium mines right around
that area, and I didn't really, I wasn't out to search for the reason, but I did check
that out, and that is correct, you know, he's like, they're really interested in nuclear
material, and it doesn't really matter to me, but it's interesting that that was told
to me by that person, so, but I don't, I still don't know, I wasn't out to say, I have the
answers to this, right, I don't, and a lot of the witnesses don't, but they do, you know,
they saw what they saw and they reported it, it was very consistent.
You know, this is just one incident out of, guys, only knows how many around the world
have met so many other people, you know, that have seen this from every single country on
this planet, same kind of thing, whether there's two of them or, you know, and also, one of
the things I've found really interesting with the research was the number of schools, primary
schools, essentially, mostly schools of that age range that had had similar incidents
all over the, all over the world, and I started collecting all these newspaper clippings,
people would send them to me, Westall, Chile, my gosh, there's so many, really, yeah, probably
Brazil I'm guessing as well, Brazil, oh my gosh, and I keep hearing more about it, somebody
did write, Preston Dennett, I believe, wrote a book on school sightings, we were, yeah,
he was kind of doing it at the same time, so that's an interesting aspect is the children
and why, yeah, that's a whole nother.
Yeah, I mean, there's also, you know, the idea that if you're going to ask someone a
question, right, and you want them to be truthful, two types of people you can count on is a
child or a drunk, right, this is, you know, you don't, you don't count on a politician
to tell you the truth, you know, or anyone else with an agenda, yeah, you got to people
who have, you know, no sort of social inhibition, it'd be nice to have leaders that actually
told us the truth, it really would be nice.
Yeah, absolutely, but, you know, unfortunately, I don't think that's just part of our system,
so we got to depend on people like yourself to report on it, you know, for those of us
seeking it.
Have you felt since you've been there and since you've looked into that particular case,
have you seen a difference in how the world looks at the phenomenon?
Oh, yeah, very, very much.
And has that changed how you sort of investigate the phenomenon yourself?
Now?
Yeah.
We were in the edit room working on the final in 2017, we're all sitting there and there's
a TV up on the, you know, there's a whole deck of screens up top, and the TV is in
the center on the news, and we're all sitting there editing the film, me and two editors,
Chris and Rick, and all of a sudden, the New York Times thing is on the news, and we're
sitting there like, holy shit, like it was a moment, we took pictures because we're all
like, this is big.
And we're working on a movie at the same time about this very subject.
And it was interesting to see that transition and how it's continued to now, I mean, I go
out, if I go out to dinner or something, and I run into friends, we're talking about it,
like they would, they would never ever, you know, some of the guys that hang out are mechanics
and hardcore, I love them, race car driver, whatever.
People that do hardcore physical stuff, they're not the one, they don't tend to believe in
anything they can't hold in their hand.
And now we're having conversations like that, I never thought would happen, to be honest.
Wow.
Yeah.
So it has changed a lot.
And then watching that change through the making of the film, because when I started,
nobody was really like me.
But you're also, I think, an important part of that change itself, like, I mean, you're
also to thank for that, like, you've taken some steps in your life and in your career
to, you know, obviously be public about a lot of things.
And you know, that on whatever capacity moves the needle, right?
A lot of people have, but a lot of, you know, people have been speaking up about this for
since the 1950s.
If you look at the documentaries from the 1950s and 60s, it's the same thing.
They've got footage of it, you know, like, it's the same.
When I was, Dan Aykroyd had helped me, like, he did a trailer for me and spoke about it.
It's there and I know viewers that are watching this, they will see it and they will feel
kind of vindicated and they'll go, you know, boy, those kids are telling the truth.
And I was telling the truth when I had my experience and it will, it's going to provide
a lot of reinforcement.
He kept saying, he's like, there's nothing new here.
We're just rehashing what we already know.
And he's right.
I didn't realize what he was saying at the time until I started going back to all those
old documentaries.
I was like, oh my God, it's the same story, the same things that people have reported.
We are in a different day, I think.
We're getting a little more truth.
I get a kick out of it.
Like, well, we're trying to remove the stigma, right, Congress and the DOD and Air Force.
But at the same time, we're going to give you a little truth and then throw you off
a little here.
It's just like, yeah, let's get to it.
You had a, you know, back in 56, whatever it was, was it Major Sampson, Sampson, what
was his name?
Kehoe?
He came forward like, and he was like, yeah, this is not our technology.
And he was saying a lot of the same things we're saying today about, you know, the drone
incursions where it's like, it's not ours, it's not theirs.
What does that leave you with?
You know, and that's kind of, like you said, we're repeating that.
But I think more people are listening now.
And I think more people are, and maybe it isn't even such that more people are believing
it, but more people are publicly believing it.
Because I think down to your core is, you know, we're all human, and we all kind of
have the same outlook in that we don't want to believe that we're alone.
There is that desire to not be alone in this place.
And so I think deep down, you know, we all kind of want it to some extent to be real.
But back then you just wouldn't vocalize that.
Yeah.
You know, and so there was a lot, it was a lot easier to suppress something.
I think in an era where people didn't find it socially acceptable to share these ideas
and thoughts.
True.
It's a lot harder to keep that in the pot.
You know, it's overflowing, it's brimming, we're trying to get it out there now.
And people are more willing to come forward, more celebrities, like look, Dan Aykroyd,
and you know, it's important to have these voices.
Absolutely.
I found it interesting, this whole the drone thing, because, you know, all of a sudden
everybody's, you know, is watching the skies and videotaping, you know, a lot of it's airplanes,
a lot of it is drones, right?
But there's a few, I'm like, well, that is definitely interesting there.
You know, so I don't think we've had that many cameras pointed at the sky all over the
world.
That's pretty unique.
And, you know, I'm not saying anything, just sort of like observing, like, this is interesting.
I mean, it could be a way to throw everybody off, like, oh, it's just drones, people are
saying, right?
But this has been going on for.
I mean, incursions like this have been going on since the 50s.
Yeah.
I mean, the military base thing and these secret sites, that's a big deal.
Lake and Heath back in the 50s, 80s, you know, well, Brentwater, and even, I mean, sightings
in Jersey, actually, which is big sightings.
thing is World of the Worlds, that was in New Jersey, 1938, like, testbed, like, that
was the first thing it hit me, it was like, well, that's interesting, New Jersey gets
it again.
Yeah.
How are people going to react?
Yeah, it's just a modern Orson Welles thing going on right now.
Maybe.
What the sightings that I'm finding really interesting are out in Arizona, Oregon.
Have you heard the ATC, Air Traffic Control?
Yep.
It's like six, seven pilots.
Yeah.
The radio, the communication between the pilots, this thing going coast to coast in seconds
and going out to the ocean.
Yeah.
Right.
We're seeing three or four targets, you know, they're all altitudes up and down, it's pretty
crazy.
Just had another one show up about my one o'clock, about a thousand feet high, zipping towards
us and then back out towards the ocean, it's red, red in color.
Moving at extreme speeds, I don't even know how to describe that, but I'm 661, I'm on the
clock.
I'm on the clock, Roger.
You are cleared to maneuver as necessary, I left the right to avoid the USO out there
and all the reports you're giving us are good information, appreciate it.
So I've interviewed witnesses who've seen that exact same behavior.
Yeah, wow.
This is covering massive distances and doing really crazy stuff.
And you're a pilot yourself.
Yeah.
And so I don't know if anybody knows that, but like that's interesting because as a pilot,
I feel like you're just a little bit more credible on these sightings, you know, just
from that standpoint alone.
Well, you have to be, you know, you see a lot up there.
Yeah.
And you learn, that's another thing I get a kick out of too, like people, a lot of people
have never really studied this guy and they're out there with cameras.
Yeah, Star Lincoln.
Oh, I had a guy come in a couple of weeks ago.
He's like, dude, look at this.
You have a line like that's Starlink though.
Yeah, I've got a few of those.
I mean, there's a lot to see out there and a lot to understand.
And then when you see an actual anomaly, it's pretty clear, you know, and then you still
have to go through the process of examining and eliminating.
You do.
And you just have to.
But yeah, it's an air safety issue, you know, to be able to know what you're looking at,
knowing where a plane is going.
The reason they have a red and a green light on each side is it's crossing this way at
night.
You know, if you're seeing that red light, it's going that way.
Right.
Yeah, because you're up there, you're not really sure what's moving.
If you're moving, if it's moving.
That's right.
Yeah.
I mean, that's super interesting because, you know, that makes like that you mentioned,
even the Oregon pilot, you know, mentioned, like when you hear something like that as
a pilot, you take that more seriously.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Because you know everything they're saying.
It's vetted.
It's like.
Well, and they know that pilots do not talk like that unless they're saying something.
I mean, and the interesting about that, we're talking about the 13 minute drop.
Yeah.
So the controllers, a senior, more senior controller comes in and then there's a bunch
of controllers around.
Does it take a picture?
Can you send me a video?
Yeah, exactly.
I got my number.
I love that.
But that's exactly what would happen.
It's so interesting too, like the community I'm around of pilots, like they're very, they're
pretty cool people.
Hmm.
Pilots see quite a bit, but they just do not talk about, they don't talk about it.
It's touchy being a pilot.
You know, we spoke about this a little bit yesterday when, you know, if a, as someone
who has like, what is it, a class two or three, you know, you've got to watch what you say
because you could lose your license because you're, you're essentially, you're a threat
to, you know, many lives being, being a pilot, a commercial pilot.
It's commercial.
Yeah.
And so if you say like, oh, you know, I have a history of dealing with depression, like
there goes your license.
Yeah.
So you got to, you got to keep your mouth shut about things like that and you got to
suppress it.
And that's really tough and puts them in a really bizarre situation when their people
were trying to count on for specific information.
We just, they just can't talk about it.
Yeah, that's very true.
You know, it's for class three.
It's like, yeah, I mean, that's general, general aviation.
But the commercial pilots, yeah, they, I've talked to many of them, interviewed, you know,
even one of the pilots that saw what he saw the night before Arrow, that night, flying
back.
And this thing was, I mean, we were here and we saw the thing coming from here and it must
have gone down here towards the Free State, Orange Free State, Lesotho and onto the East
Coast there.
And I had a friend of mine who was going to format on us in another aircraft.
He called us on the radio and said that he could actually see us and he was coming up
and we must keep a lookout for him.
And I actually said to him, well, I can see you on the left-hand side of the aircraft.
And he confirmed that he was on the right-hand side of us.
And I said to him, well, if you're on our right-hand side, what is it we're seeing on
the left?
And on our left-hand side was a ball of light.
I don't know what it was.
And he saw it.
My co-pilot saw it.
And we noticed this thing go from the left-hand wingtip across our track and disappear across
the horizon.
And that took about three or four seconds.
I posted that interview on our website.
He showed up without any of his ID or who he was flying for because of many of that
reasons.
But he shared it because it wasn't just him.
It was his co-pilot and another pilot.
Oddly, in Africa, they'll fly in formation because there's just different rules over
there.
You'll have two commercial jets flying side by side.
That's an odd thing to see if you're looking up.
Well, yeah, it's just the rules are a little different.
There's places where there is no radar coverage at all.
Yeah, there's huge vast areas.
There's no radar coverage.
So you can kind of do what you want.
But anyway, it is an issue because it's discussed.
It's discussed among them.
Like being a pilot yourself, you've heard stories.
Oh, yeah.
But usually it's followed up with, yeah, don't tell anybody.
Could you share one of the stories without giving away who said it or would that give
it away?
Boy, I'd have to think about the...
There's been a lot.
I don't want to put you on the spot.
If there's anything that comes to mind, though, but...
Yeah, let me think about it.
Sure.
The interesting thing is because they know I fly.
We can speak the same language.
We have the same kind of understanding.
They may have a lot more hours than I do.
I love these guys that have 35,000 hours.
I've got 1,600.
Whoa, yeah.
It's a big difference.
Big difference.
But yeah, anyway, that's a whole other topic.
But it's important because they don't have a voice.
And I'm hoping that particular incident that was recorded on ATC, I hope those people get
interviewed.
Or I hope they're not reprimanded either.
They shouldn't be.
Well, they shouldn't be.
Because they have so many...
That's the amazing thing about it is I think there's five or six, maybe even more than
that.
They're all calling in.
People chiming in.
It was exciting.
I see it too.
Really?
Yeah.
Yeah, a friend of mine sent me that.
And I'm like, well, yeah, I've interviewed a Navy man who witnessed the same thing when
he was active duty, him and another engineer on the P-3.
So the same behavior, it would come up and then it would just zoom out at ridiculous
speeds.
Impossible speeds.
Yeah.
And then repeat the behavior.
Like, what are they doing?
What are these things?
It must be so wildly different also to see it from that perspective because being on
the ground looking up is one thing.
And sure, you can spot anomalous behavior, but there's so much going on above your head.
Like you said, there's rockets coming back into orbit.
Elon's got 4,600 satellites up there.
There's a lot.
There's asteroids.
There's things burning up.
You're catching reflections off certain crafts that are just orbiting the planet that are
reflecting off the sun.
So you're getting glimmers.
But being at that altitude and seeing something straight on I think is such a different and
interesting perspective to this because now you can confirm that it's not in space because
being on the ground, you have no point of reference.
It's either a big object that's far away or a small object that's close, like I don't
know.
Being level playing field with this thing, watching it go, I mean that must be just a
much more intense experience.
So even with Ariel, the radar coverage in, well actually they did catch it on radar on
the corner of the scope, but they had it on their own.
They have your radar in the plane.
It's limited.
TCAS for Collision Avoidance for commercial.
They picked it up on the TCAS.
So did those people in that clip we're talking about in Oregon I think.
Yeah.
So they had it on their TCAS, but the radar station didn't have it on.
So it's telling you this object is in very close proximity, but at the same time radar
doesn't have it as a primary target.
That's interesting.
Because the same thing happened the night before Ariel.
A lot of the pilots talk like, I got it on my TCAS, like Collision Avoidance, yet you
guys don't have it on radar.
South Africa, on the one pilot I did interview, they did have it on radar.
He went to the tower right when he landed.
He's like, did you guys get this on radar?
It's like we had it on for like two seconds, but it was going so fast that we don't know
where it was.
Well, and he saw it.
That's what he saw.
I mean, within two seconds, I think it's four seconds, he's at 25,000 feet.
So your horizon's massive.
You can see a lot of, and within four seconds it completely crossed the horizon and at kind
of a straight line, not like a meteorite or anything like that.
He thought it was another aircraft coming up next to him.
Anyway, those are interesting interviews because the pilots are, that's, they are, they have
to...
Incredible.
Yeah, you got to pay attention.
You have to know what you're doing.
Your life's at risk.
Other people's lives are at risk if you have passengers.
Yeah, there seems to be a concerted effort to, within the last few years anyways, at
least to sort of bridge that gap at the FAA and allow for commercial pilots to report
these things and create this funnel where they can now...
I know that Ryan Graves is working with that as well.
I think it's very important and it's cool that he is working with it because he's someone
I believe that we can sort of trust on this issue.
He seems like a straight shooter, understands some of the capabilities of these crafts
and has heard a lot of testimony as well.
A lot of people come to him, so I think it's important, but ultimately if you look at things
like even the O'Hare incident, was it 06 or 07 or whatever it was, and everything was
confiscated, it was like they just right away shut that thing down and it was a hiccup.
But that was a mass sighting as well.
But that got controlled real quick because it happened around an airport.
That's the other thing is there is a fear, I'm pretty sure, among pilots and among air
staff in general, not just pilots, but radar operators and even ground crew that you shouldn't
speak of this, you shouldn't talk of this.
It's true.
A lot of people are fighting for those jobs.
Right.
Yeah, it's unfortunate because we lose a lot of information.
That's what drives me.
Every little bit of data is important, information, testimony, witness what you witness,
paints a picture, and so many people just don't come forward.
Yeah, that's the other thing.
A pilot, F-111 Air Force, they witnessed a vehicle up at 25,000, again 25,000, it's interesting
because they are seen at an interesting altitude between 20,000 and 30,000 feet, a lot of them.
We stay up at 35,000, 40,000 for most of our commercial flights are up there.
But a lot of the activity is around 25, which is fascinating to me.
Because you wouldn't see it if you're in a plane, maybe?
No, it's just, maybe, it's just not, I don't think that's the, it's just interesting.
There is an altitude that is, people see that anyway, it was a F-111, and they had it on their onboard radar.
And they saw the target coming toward them.
This is an interview I did.
And it was on a head-on collision, that was the worry, because it was heading right toward them.
And they were in the clouds, so they couldn't see it.
And then all of a sudden the clouds break open, and then it comes out of the clouds, and it's huge.
What's it? Oh my God.
Oh my God.
Like a black cigar-shaped, and he's estimating, you know, 700 to 900 feet long.
Yeah, it's a big deal.
And these empanages, that's what he would call them, like big circle-y or circular like hangars.
You could look into it, and you could see the shadow.
He explains this.
Boy, I don't know if I should be talking about this yet.
But, yeah.
So, I mean, they were both afraid to even report it, you know, when they landed.
And they did, they kept quiet about it.
But he's been thinking about it ever since 1981.
Of course. Why wouldn't you? That's haunting.
I mean, you're so vulnerable being up there.
And, you know, he wasn't alone. He was a navigator. Sorry.
He was the navigator and the pilot.
They were like, did you see that? You know, they both saw it.
Wow.
Yep.
So, there's a lot of interesting things that get seen.
I just don't get, again, like that would have been helpful to, you know, why?
You know, do we already know all this?
Do we not need that information, or is it the concern for public panic?
That they create the stigma.
Do you think it's a concern for public panic?
I do.
That's the main reason in your mind?
That's what I've heard over and over.
Yeah. It seems to be, I mean, that seems to definitely be a reason.
Like, I mean, you know, there's so many examples, if you look back in history,
where ontological shock has literally crippled people.
And, you know, they've probably played the scenario out a billion times
in a billion different ways, whoever the people are in the program, you know,
to make sure that, hey, we don't want to destroy the economy or start a war
or whatever it is.
But, you know, part of me also thinks that, like, man, humans,
humans are just greedy sometimes too.
And, like, I really, I don't know, this is just a gut feeling,
but I really feel like they're just like a small group of people
that just don't want you to know.
Yeah.
And they're just like, nope, that's ours.
You can't have it.
And they got money, they got power, they got, you know,
and that just gets them off.
And I, because, you know, a lot of us could handle it.
Not the entirety of it perhaps.
But I think, you know, if you go around asking people,
there are ways to disseminate information that are probably a lot
more, that's a lot easier than what they're doing now.
You know, this whole, like, leak and deny and, like,
it's just so bizarre of a behavior.
And then, like, even with, like, the drone stuff happening,
they're like, we don't know what it is.
This seems like a really sloppy job, you know,
if you were to give out some information.
I just think there's, like, an easy way to do it.
And for some reason, whatever that reason is,
they just don't want people to know.
They don't want people to know.
Well, it's, you know, it's already been disclosed, essentially.
People don't even realize that it's already happened.
But, you know, they don't have to, I feel the same way.
Like, you know, do whatever you guys want.
Keep doing what you're doing.
You don't have to share everything.
Just tell us that there's intelligent life in the universe, please.
And I think the end result of that,
it's going to be shocking for a lot of people,
and it's going to be a transitional period
that I think everybody goes through
when they actually see it or come to terms with it.
And then there's going to be a lot of excitement
about, like you were saying, like, oh, man,
wait, we're not alone out here?
That opens up space to a lot of excitement and exploration,
and I think that's going to move us forward
in a way we've never seen before.
So I think it's...
Yeah, there's things I probably agree
that they shouldn't share with us, but...
Isn't that positive overall?
If humanity finds out?
Yeah, I think so.
It's going to be some hard pills to swallow, so to speak.
But, yeah, I think we're already there.
We're already...
I mean, it's no accident that we're in space.
You know, we're just getting off this planet.
We're starting to explore, and, of course,
we're running into these things more often
than these things are paying attention, you bet.
It's a critical stage of our evolution.
Right, we hit a certain technological peak,
and now they're popping up,
whether it's, like, nuke or space travel.
It feels like they're like, oh,
they're finally getting out of the playpen.
Yeah.
Yeah, I believe that.
Do you believe they've been here for a long time?
I do.
Like thousands of years?
Yeah.
Is there any part of you that believes
that they are responsible for us?
I don't know.
Boy, there's so many pieces to that.
It wouldn't surprise me.
I just don't know.
So I kind of have my own little, like, speculative,
like, okay, let's, how is this,
there's some pretty spectacular things
that have happened in our past that are still there,
you know, as pyramids or, you know,
just really curious technologies.
So I don't know.
I mean, that's kind of the, I'd like to know that.
I think if, you know, if there's a lot of things
that I think if we find out, we'll be like,
oh, that makes total sense.
Yeah.
The puzzle pieces fit, you know.
It's like revealing a magic trick, really.
Yeah.
You overcomplicate things sometimes in your head,
and you're like, oh, he must have had this
electromagnetic thing up his sleeve.
And then I'm like, no, it's just like an invisible thread
or something.
And then they're like, oh, yeah, of course, you know.
But we overcomplicate things sometimes
because, you know, we just overthink.
Yeah.
It might be a lot simpler.
I think it is.
And people make it more complex, well, for various reasons.
Yeah.
To keep advantage over others or profit.
You know, a whole bunch of things human beings do.
But I find it interesting, the whole timing of all this,
where all these things that we have to deal with
are all coming to a head, you know.
We're out.
We're getting off the planet.
We've got a climate issue, big time.
And then, I don't know, it's just so,
we're at the edge of a lot of things.
So if you could place yourself behind a rock somewhere
at any point in history and have, like, the best view
of anything being done, whether it's a visitation
or some monumental event, besides Rua,
where would you put yourself?
Fly on the wall.
No one will ever see you.
And you get to have the best view.
You get to soak, take it all in, whatever that thing is.
I mean, there's several.
I mean, immediately think of around the building
of the Great Pyramid.
I would have loved to have seen who was involved or her.
How that was done?
Well, I'd like to see who was there,
besides the human beings.
If that, I don't even know.
I would just, boy, that's a, have you been to the pyramids?
Never been, no.
Oh, my God.
No.
You have to see that.
I would love to one day.
It is, it's just, you leave there a different person.
Because as close as I've been is Coral Castle in Florida.
Oh, I haven't seen that.
I'd like to see that.
Yeah, it's OK.
But it is, it's one of the wonders for sure, wonders of the world.
They're colossal.
They're really just, pictures don't do it justice.
They don't.
Like, you know, the Statue of Liberty is like, oh, geez.
It's a lot bigger than, you know, when you see it,
when you see it, you're like, eh.
But, boy, you see the pyramids, you're like, oh, my God.
These things are, wow.
Yeah, there's this, they're like megalithic.
I've seen pictures of people in comparison next to them,
and they just stand next to a rock,
and they're not even half the size of the rock.
And you're just like, wait, I don't know what?
Like, it's really hard to comprehend on photo,
but in person must be just, yeah, I guess it just, yeah, it just shows you.
It cements that idea of how can we do this?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's pretty stunning.
Tell you, I'd like to see.
Where would you like to be?
Holloman.
Oh, yeah, in 1954?
Yep.
I'd like to be behind a little rock somewhere in a safe area,
and just kind of, or maybe in that helicopter or whatever.
Just be, yeah, boots on the ground somewhere there,
and watch that happen.
Yeah, I would love to know, what was that?
Yeah, going to the jeep.
What did they tell us?
Yeah.
Well, here's my question.
Is there any small talk?
Well, I mean, I'm sure if there was a conversation,
they said some very frank things.
I would like to know what they said.
If you could ask one question, what would it be?
That's something you want to keep for yourself?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's fine.
I do have a personal law.
And I think I know the questions.
Yeah.
All right.
How about we take some questions from Patreon?
Is that cool?
Sure.
All right.
I'm just going to hit record on the other camera here.
One second.
All right.
I'm going to pull these questions up.
This is from our interns, as we call them.
They are allowed because they pay a fee every month.
They get access to a lot of perks.
And one of those perks is asking the guest a question.
So I've only got a few here because this was like a last minute thing.
But we'll try to pull some out.
I think we might have answered some of these, honestly.
Oh, OK.
This is actually a good question.
And this isn't a question that is normally typical.
So I do like this one from Jaydenity.
Jaydenity.
Yeah.
Jaydenity, maybe.
I don't know.
What do you think are the strongest counter arguments skeptics present?
Now, specifically, the Ariel thing.
What's like a strong counter argument that a skeptic would present?
Something you've heard.
And then maybe elaborate on how you could counter argue that.
Mass hallucination was one.
So I went and spoke to a lot of psychiatrists.
And it was really interesting.
Like, well, we don't really know what that is.
Right.
Like, we don't have examples of it's not.
Anyway, I was OK because I wanted to see what are the other examples of this.
So that was one.
That's one that you can't just easily dismiss either because it's just so last resort.
Well, blanket statement.
Everybody's on drugs or something.
Yeah.
Is there a problem with that?
Or are the other witnesses, like the pilots that were up there.
Yeah.
So they're having the same mass hallucination.
And then the people in the village are also having that.
I mean, it just didn't appear that way at all.
And then I guess military aircraft is like is maybe the other one.
That was the other one.
Satellite rocket body reentry, which I looked into quite a bit.
And the problem with that was that you had a lot of people.
And there's no question that probably did happen.
But there was something else seen there.
Throughout that whole week.
Yeah.
Not just at the school.
Right.
All over.
Because clearly whatever happened at school wasn't a crash.
No.
That was not a rocket reentry.
And it was interesting because I did find people that saw a reentry.
And then I found other people.
And the thing was these were not unqualified witnesses, so to speak.
They were people that worked at the airport.
People that, you know, veterinary.
Just different people.
They're not stupid.
And they witnessed hovering.
They witnessed a lot of things that are not what a reentry looks like.
Yeah.
Or space debris coming in.
So yeah, I mean, that was the other thing I had to entertain.
Well, what else could this have been?
And I still keep kind of an open.
Yeah.
But what are you left with?
That's the crazy part.
What are you left with?
If you take away those things, you're like, what are you left with?
You're not left with much.
If you're jumping to mass hallucination, it doesn't leave you with many options, I feel.
That's kind of bottom of the barrel stuff there.
Yeah.
You know?
Yeah, I mean, the whole thing about the simplest explanation is usually the correct one.
The Occam's razor.
Yeah.
I do believe that is true, but maybe not with this stuff.
You know, maybe we're seeing something.
We can't put everything under that category with something as extraordinary as this.
And people are putting their reputations on the line.
And we're seeing a lot of that right now with these people are coming forward that are F-16 pilots, F-18 pilots.
I mean, people with some serious credentials that could go to jail if they're lying or be dismissed from or lose their clearances.
Even if Congress says, well, we got a whistleblower protection act or whatever, it's like that doesn't mean really anything.
You know, if you feel like you're being threatened.
Very true.
I mean, I hope they do something because that is happening to quite a few people.
There are private funds now which are coming out like the UAP Disclosure Fund, I think,
and some other private organizations that are gathering money for whistleblowers.
Right.
Because one of the things that like aside from life-threatening interactions, they're also just threatening to have no pension.
And that's like a big deal if you got family and you're trying to take care of them and you can't enter the workforce again because your reputation is tarnished.
Who's taking care of you?
And if you see how much the government takes care of veterans, well, then you can kind of draw a clear line and see that, oh, you might also be left out to dry.
So, you know, it's good that a lot of these private organizations are beginning to at least take some action.
Yeah, that's wonderful.
That's necessary.
All right.
We have  I think we answered this one.
I mean, I'll throw it up.
Maybe you got something else to add to it.
But
Sure.
We did  I think we did talk about this.
How cool is that?
That's awesome.
What was the purpose of the Ariel sighting?
I find the interesting part, and it was a very real thing, are the messages they get the kids.
What made me really convinced like that really happened was the males that did not want to talk about it.
Yet they had had that images put into their head about, you know, the destruction of the planet, what we were doing, stuff like that.
That was a very real thing.
You know, I initially thought, well, maybe this is what happens when you see something weird and odd.
You start thinking about your own environment and it causes all kinds of  you know, I kind of explored that quite a bit.
But when I started to find kids that were  talked to me about it but did not want to discuss it on camera or didn't want to talk about it at all, yet they admitted that that happened, that was pretty interesting.
And so, you know, why kids?
Why tell them that?
I mean, they're going to grow up.
They're growing up now and just  how are they influencing society from what they learned?
They're all over the world.
It's very common for people that have had encounters, the very same thing.
It's not just that.
It's a pretty common aspect to this, that you're shown certain things about your own species, what your own species is doing to this environment.
Kind of takes the heat off you as an alien entity, too, I feel.
You know, if you're like, oh, you think I'm scary.
Yeah, look what you're doing.
Exactly.
Look how scary this is, right?
Kind of softens the blow a little bit, maybe, you know, to be like, no, no, no, we're not the bad guys.
Yeah.
It's like every zombie movie I've ever watched.
It's not the zombies you've got to be afraid of.
You know, it's the people.
It's the humans.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Well, I mean, I always reference it to wildlife and how we  you know, animals overpopulate an area.
When the deer overpopulate, they start to get disease and they start to have other issues.
So we call them to keep that from happening.
You know, there's just tons of things we do with  because we can't have a conversation about what you're doing.
We know a little better than they do about certain things that aren't going to happen if they go too far in that direction.
Yeah.
And you know, it is interesting, too, that like just like giving the children these images and talking and visiting the children, you know, they grow up.
They're affected by this for life, you know, as you know with your interactions with them.
But they go on to also sort of become in their own ways ambassadors for the phenomenon.
Yeah.
Right?
A lot of people out there.
Not just that incident.
You don't just forget it and move on.
I mean, look at even  you know, you want to look at Travis Walton.
Yeah.
He's not going to go and get a regular job.
No.
Yeah.
And now this is his life, you know.
And so they must be aware that they have that effect.
True.
But you don't get paid for that.
No.
Right?
Yeah.
It's kind of a  you know what I mean?
And if you do, you get ostracized, apparently.
That's true.
It's  but it's such an important thing to share.
And boy, so many people.
And what they do have to share is really that wonder.
We talked with magic, right?
The awe.
But it's actually real.
Yeah.
Like it's a real
It's not pretend.
It's not.
And it's going to take time.
But I just think of all these people that have come forward, so many.
And I don't know how we  I don't know how we treat those people properly.
That's been on my mind a lot.
Because they've been through so much.
They're misunderstood, mislabeled.
I don't know how we as a society, as a species, integrate those people.
I mean, they should be  in my mind, they should be treated like veterans of a war,
you know, in a sense.
Right.
And we're kind of making light of it.
Yeah.
And we leave them out there.
You know, I'm glad that Burroughs and, you know, they've gotten medical care for what
they went through.
Think  you know, that was a huge deal.
Randall Shum.
Yeah.
And  but there's so many other people that  they just don't get the proper care.
Psychologically, you mean?
Yeah.
Psychologically.
And physically, yeah, in some cases.
Yeah.
Which has been mentioned in the hearings as well.
That, like, hey, if this isn't happening, why are we treating people for wounds?
Right.
Exposure to certain things, like, okay.
Kind of insane that we're treating wounds of a pretend phenomenon.
Yeah.
Okay.
I think we've got one more here.
Well, I think this is kind of exactly what we just touched on, which is synchronous.
This is from Hex0811.
Yeah.
Is the population ready as a whole?
I think so.
I think 20 years ago, no.
30.
You know, I think the  hmm, there's so many parts of it that have made it possible
to get to be at this point, which is the web, you know.
The world has gotten a lot smaller.
Religion is not as dogged in a way than it was before.
We're already out in space.
There's many things that have come together, but I think so.
I think it's what's going to propel us into the future is just say, okay.
And we're going to have to take that slow.
I mean, that's the thing about confronting a superior  you know, let's just say that.
An alpha species is very humbling.
And let's see what that relationship is.
And man, the thing that I get, I always think of as like, what have they seen already?
What other places have they been, other planets that they know about, you know?
The knowledge.
The knowledge base, which would save us a lot of time figuring it out.
They know that, though.
I would think so.
Yeah.
Just so strange.
It's so strange because, you know, you get to the end of these questions, and there's
always something that just doesn't compute.
There's always something that's like, this doesn't equal zero when I put them together.
What parts?
I mean, for me, it's a lot of the why.
It's a lot of the why.
The why just doesn't make sense from what I've heard, you know?
That's the question I didn't answer, is the why.
Yeah.
And I mean, that's the big question, you know?
We're past the, even the what, or the when, or the where.
It's really about the why, and it's not like, you know, why us?
That's the whole thing, right?
Because you have to imagine that there's a big universe out there.
There is something special here.
There has to be.
It has to be something unique, and I would kick myself for saying this years ago because
I'd be like, wow, you're just being egotistical.
You're being human.
You're thinking we're special.
You know, we're just like everyone else in the universe.
But it doesn't seem that way.
It doesn't seem that way.
It seems like we are a valuable, call it asset.
Call it, you know, you want to call it experiment.
You want to call it byproduct.
You want to call it whatever.
But there's something extremely valuable here that they are clearly interested in.
Yeah.
Why bother?
And why hide that?
Why not let us know?
Why hide that?
Why are they hiding that?
What is there to know that is to our detriment, that is not to our benefit?
From these...
Yeah.
Why is it...
If it was to our benefit, what's the Harman telling us?
I think I know the answer to that question.
Yeah.
I think it's delicate to expose yourself to a species that doesn't, not as advanced as
you.
Yeah.
And I think they're very, in my personal opinion, from people I've interviewed, it just, I think,
it appears they're very aware of that.
I could be wrong.
It could be...
The covertness of it is very interesting.
Because it's not completely covert.
Not quite.
It's like...
They could do a better job even.
Right.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It's like...
It's almost like they don't care that much.
Or they kind of want to give you a hint.
Yeah.
And that's, I guess, part of this whole hidden agenda that we're, I guess, not ready to be
privy to or whatever that is.
It's just a little frustrating being someone who, deep within, understands that there could
be some good from this and that we'd probably, like Reagan said, we'd be a lot more, we'd
be treating each other a lot better if we understood that there was something out there.
I agree with that.
100%.
And so it's just strange that we don't get that.
There's got to be something else then.
Profit?
Yeah.
It goes back to like...
Who knows?
Fear sells.
Yeah.
Anyway.
All right.
Well, do you mind sticking around for like an extra 20?
We're going to cut this one and then just do like a little talk on Patreon.
Is that cool?
Sure.
And we can talk about some other stuff.
Guys, if you want to head over to obviously become an intern or a member, you can click
all the buttons below and follow that.
We're going to continue the conversation.
But I also highly suggest you go check out Aerial Phenomenon, an incredible documentary.
Is there anywhere they can follow your work?
Is there a link that we'll add below?
AerialPhenomenon.com.
Yep.
That's our primary.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's available on Apple TV and Amazon.
Go support Randall and his work.
I'm looking forward to what you got going on next.
And whenever you decide to share that with the world, I will be here and I will be waiting
on BetaBreath.
So I appreciate you being here.
This has been a lot of fun.
Same here.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.