Agent Ramsey we've got a new investigation for you something your department should have a look at
I'm sending over the information as we speak you'll need to travel to North Carolina pack your bags
Throughout human history the appearance of luminous orbs in the sky has ignited wonder fear and
speculation these ethereal lights hovering darting or pulsing with a strange intelligence
transcend folklore and defy easy categorization they challenge our understanding of reality itself
stirring questions about consciousness dimensions and the unknown forces shaping our existence
what if these phenomena are not mere anomalies but deliberate messages encoded in light and mystery
amid the myriad of accounts of contact and unexplained encounters fewer as polarizing or
profound as the story of Chris Bledsoe his journey took a dramatic turn in 2008 with an
extraordinary event an encounter not just with luminous orbs but with its occupants and what
followed was a cascade of disbelief and ostracism as his family became the target of ridicule
relegated to the fringes of their community this eventually inspired Chris to write his
best-selling book UFO of God in it he recounts the events that upended his life but more importantly
he unpacks the spiritual and existential questions those experiences forced him to confront
Bledsoe's story isn't just about UFOs or alien craft it explores the deeply spiritual
intertwining divine intervention ancient archetypes
mysterious healing abilities prophetic messages and even a burning tree this tree just spontaneously
combusted in our backyard it's a modern day odyssey but this is no mere personal account
Bledsoe's experiences have captured the attention of powerful institutions
including the US government and even the Vatican why would agencies rooted in geopolitics and
theology take an interest in a rural man's encounters with orcs could the truths here
be so profound that they might blur the lines between science and religion in this investigation
we'll trace the arc of Bledsoe's encounters from his initial contact to the intricate spiritual
revelations that followed what is it about his story that bridges the gap between the skies and
the sacred and why does it matter now more than ever oh my god oh my god look at that
okay just landed in Wilmington in sunny Wilmington hello this is Ryan Bledsoe we're
gonna go see his dad we're gonna hang out and uh yeah this is this is the kind of weather we got
landing in Wilmington right now we've driven through a torrential storm it's like a tropical
storm or something that passed through today but we're good we're on the other side of the rain
almost there uh time is it's 8 30 at night keep you posted
good morning got in last night and we spent some time with uh with chris and ryan's mom and
uh chatted until about three in the morning had some lively conversations about the topic
the phenomenon and everything and just catching up really getting to know each other which was a lot
of fun um today we're going to be filming some stuff here some interview stuff and
then we're going to be heading back to ryan's house we're all end up doing his podcast also
i talked to ryan finding out more about the story a wholesome family just super caring super loving
they allowed me into their home last night and uh i mean we just had just a great time talking no
expectations not expecting anything except a good conversation and just uh just hanging out so good
morning the day of the event that changed everything was january the eighth of 07
i was a builder always been a builder my wife's family were builders my dad was a builder
other than growing up on farming and building is what i did career was to be a pilot a commercial
pilot which i have achieved that um but i never i quit flying because of having children i wanted
to be home with my children so i was in the building business in a big way went desert storm and
the 911 thing happened 2001 i was caught with 72 houses under construction i was a big builder
a lot of houses we built 100 a year so now i'm with these houses and the world trade center
collapse and being in fedville north carolina which is home of fort brag fort liberty they call it now
predominant military town it dried up the housing market nobody's buying
really you're seeing just broad-based declines across all of the major technologies
and that means life as most americans know it is about to change in some cases dramatically
they don't know if they're going to be in iraq or iran or where they're going to be
next week so the military just shut down so here i am with nearly a hundred thousand dollars a month
going out in interest and overhead and no houses sell up
so i saw a train wreck come in i was suffering with crone's disease
since my early 20s 26 or 27 and developed that and by now 2001 i went from happy and
you know living on a golf course in a big old house with a pool and kids playing golf at the
country club you know i grew up to all of a sudden i see the end coming i'm losing everything and i
did i lost it all by 2005 i had gone through about 18 million dollars worth of apartments and condo
or houses everything i had and rental property to to to pay the interest and all until i
eventually sold the company i'm sick with crones at the worst point of my life
because the more you stress the worse that disease gets recovering from a near-death
experience in the hospital by a doctor that over-medicated me
to try to get back into the workforce now i'm not able to work i'm dealing with this
sickness and now the worst depression i'm starting over i'm 46 years old now i've
got to apply for free lunches for my kids in school that's how bad it got
me
and so january the eighth of 07 i was had finally started back trying to work a bit
right after christmas my crew went down to the coast and finished the house and brought a check
back so they show up to my house so that day the eighth and they want to celebrate called me about
two o'clock said hey boss we'd like to go fishing you want to come celebrate with us
i said why not it's just me and chris jr and my wife and other three kids were out of town
were with their mom and so we we waited on them well they called me i went to their house i picked
them up they're between me and the river's three and a half miles away by car and their houses were
kind of in between that so it went out of my way much to pick them up and plus i had the only
four drive that could get down in this bottom so now we're walking along we're parked on the river
we cross the cornfield and i kind of give you an idea where we were this is cornfield on on our left
and in the middle of this field is a little tube road that drives across this field to the far side
to the trees and when you get to those trees the river's down in there so you go down the hill
through a gate a metal gate sits right on the crest of the hill this is flat cornfield and the
river dives off down in and this gate's sitting right up there on the peak of that hill right you
don't notice it till you're down looking up all you see is the sky and this big old metal gate
right i drove down in there about a quarter mile down to the end of a cul-de-sac we park
by three o'clock they were sitting on the bank fishing and i told them i said i'm going to walk
down in the forest and just meditate i'm not into fishing didn't tell them what i was thinking
i'm crying out lord help me what do i do i'm 46 i'm sick can't afford to
feed my children now i need help this is the mindset this is the important part that everyone
understands what we're dealing what i was dealing with so i go in the woods i find a big old tree
along the river on a gully and i sat down for about an hour now it's 4 30 4 45 and it's getting
dark in the woods the sun sets at 5 30 in january around here so down under that canopy it's already
dark in there so i walked back out to where they were fishing and asked them did they want to stay
or fish some more and um they wanted to fish we just got here boss let's fish more
so i said okay we need to get a fire going it's going to get cold tonight got a fire going in about
10 minutes to five now i told them once i knew they had the fire and they're sitting there on
the bank with the fire they're facing the water with their poles and the fire right behind them
i was always an organizer trying to organize people so i thought they're okay
now i'm going to walk up the hill
so i told them that's what i was going to do i was going to sit up there to dark
and watch for wildlife to come out in the field maybe a deer would walk out a coyote or turkeys
and uh they're telling why but that was the excuse i use all the while i'm struggling mentally
what i do how do i feed my children i'm depressed worse than ever
i'm struggling with thoughts you know just a bad place to be i'm broke i have nothing
anyhow and i got a little spooked because i heard something walking in the woods beside me
which nothing really spooks me at night like that as i grew up hunting and from a young age
in the woods and and never afraid but all of a sudden i'm got a little spooked
because when i'd stop it would stop and i couldn't see in the woods it's so thick
but i could hear it and it sounded like two feet at times walking and um so i'd stop and i'd look
and i got on my knees three times to look under the shrubs trying to see past the barrier of
shrubs that line most of the roads and fields around it so i get on down to the the dog leg
left toward the west so i'm parallel in the river for a little more than an eighth of a mile now i
got an eighth of a mile to go up to the gate and and i'm facing west so i can see the sky
and the sky is not black the stars aren't out but i knew the sun was probably beneath the tree
so i walked up that hill and when i got within 30 feet of the top of that hill
i began to see what i thought was the sun the top of it and the higher i got up that hill
the more of the sun i could see and by the time i got to where i could see the whole thing i thought
man that don't even that that's weird
i could see what looked like the sun the same size when you can look at it in the evening it
doesn't hurt your eyes but it was more blood red and it looked like fire going around it and for
the first minute i thought oh that i'd struggle with it you know this has got to be the sun
so i'm i take a few more steps up that hill and now there are two of these i can see much more
wider view and i've got two suns that look just alike and they're just above the trees just beyond
the road so there's 200 yards of field and they're probably 100 yards behind that up
just above the trees just set in there two big glowing orange tangerine orange the blood red
tangerine orange the blood red it kind of in that mix of colors and they're swirling around
and around fire and little tips of flames are shooting off in all directions so i'm freaked
out now i never seen anything like that never thought about ufos all i thought about it was
losing my business and being sick and dealing with that so i squatted down and hid myself
i had still more hill in front of me i'm not to the top yet so i'm using that as my advantage
you know i've ducked down and i look up and they're there i don't know how long i sit there doing that
but it wasn't long that i had gotten afraid enough that i got worried about the boys down the hill
and chris jr so i thought i've got to run i just can't take this any longer you know i didn't know
knew i was there so by saying that is a very big part of this for example if you see a light fly
by a star or a satellite or whatever it is even though it's an orb you see it it's different than
just seeing something than something responding and seeing you and coming in your space and say
i see you see now you got this power that you can't imagine that has you on its radar so i turned
to run and when i did i had to look back one more time so i'm i actually turned my body while i'm
hiding squatted down behind that hill and i'll turn real slow and i'm facing down and i know
i've got to go down that way no flashlight through these weeds and ruts you know so i'm making this
plant to get away i committed i'm running now i had to look back one more time and so i
raised up i looked back to take off and that's when everything changed this third setting sun
right above me just appeared and shot down the very minute it was so time that i knew without a
shadow of a doubt that it saw me and that i was on its radar and that's when the chills set in
and the fear set in and the feeling of being like a lab rat or uh you know something and
something that i couldn't get away from something that's got me so next thing i remember it's the
last 50 feet to the fire i can see the fire is very low now it's just a tiny little fire
and three men standing around it looking down no longer fishing and i'm coming out of the
dark right they don't see me coming but i can see them and when i got really close to them i
shouted i said hey guys you would never guess what i just saw immediately one of the guys said where
and there and i won't say the words he said have you been i said what do you mean i was
just up at the hill no you won't see yeah i was i haven't gone but 20 minutes oh no you've been
gone all night i'm like no way i was going 20 minutes no you've been gone all night
then i realized chris junior's not there so i said where's junior they said well he's been
gone two hours looking for you we can't find him either
so i took off from them running shouting for him so he's in the far back of the cul-de-sac
missing that's the last time they saw him i ran back there shouting for him
worried he's lost in a big head of woods that is very rugged and goes for 60 miles to the beach
or more of this woods
in this clip taken from a podcast hosted by one of chris's sons ryan called bled so said so
ryan and his co-host nick get chris jr to open up about his experience for the first time in
over a decade now chris jr's discomfort in recalling the encounter immediately becomes
apparent as he repeatedly fails to vocalize the event which is clearly still very traumatic
well so it started out we were you know all fishing on the river right right we got
wondering where's dad at so i'm with a couple guys and down this dark path i happen to see these two
red glowing balls of light it was really dark out and i happened to be looking down that way
and i saw these two orbs you know about this big about waist high off the ground just floating
so all i could see was these two bright red orbs side beside where were they when you first saw
down the path there coming down the road yeah two just little you know they're not very big
just a ball of light red ball of light talking to this old fella gene he's the one that was like
the red was so quiet i could hear a rat yeah cotton ball piss on a piece of cotton
nothing animal it was quiet it was quiet it was just you could have heard a rat piss on a piece
of cotton that's how quiet it was i'm telling these guys about this and and they're like
oh i don't see nothing quite playing with me they thought out they literally did not see these red
balls of light i was pointing saw them and tried to tell the guys i tried to yes yes i tried to
point it out to them no no no they got in the truck and left me out there oh looking for dad
yeah oh because dad was missing for four hours yeah i thought i would stay just in case he came
back okay got in the truck and left and i knew these things were in the woods you know or i knew
they were still there so um i just went into the wood line you know thinking i'm gonna get i guess
get a better view of them or and um
you know i was by myself and um i'm gonna get back on track yeah so i went in the wood line and um
i saw these two little guys come out of the out of the woods right along the side of the right
where the river was i'm sorry dude that's totally totally totally totally fine
and then next thing you know i didn't see any more orbs i just saw these little creatures come
walking out the woods it was really dark and just like little creatures a little skinny
and i could see the you know they're i guess their body but not like uh what they were wearing
i'm struggling with all this you know i'm a panicked dad now where's my son so i start
making my way into the thickness the shrubbery stick around the edge to get into the woods i
didn't have a flashlight i'm panicked shouting for it i thought if i could get in there i could
find them all right i'm i was standing in the wood lines and i in the wood line and i saw these
take your time bro yeah take your time we we want you your comfort level is the most important
seriously well i've never talked about it yeah i get the worst anxiety when i think about it
and that's why i stay strapped okay well i saw these two little guys
i never can talk about it it's good man
we can seriously stop if you want to and about that time these two little three foot tall
three or four foot tall little tiny little midget men come out of the woods and they're tiny little
people very dark almost translucent you know like it like a shadow almost they had big red eyes
yeah they were abnormally large for their size yeah their head was it didn't look symmetrical
i don't know how to put in the words what i'm thinking i'm in the wood line and and they're
they come out of the woods for me and i'm across this little field right so they're on the river
side and i'm on the opposite side right in the edge of the woods they uh come straight for me
they knew i was there they could see me in the wood line and one of them was looking at me at all
times he was describing these creatures that would look at him and paralyze it i think one was picking
up cans and bottles and looking at them sticks and put them on the ground on their hands and knees
while one was always staring at that's what scared him to death he was looking me right now
looking me right in the eyes i felt like he was the whole time he was staring me down one of them
and the other one i remember seeing him bend over and pick up a bottle and uh he just kind of looked
at it and sat it back down there was a little glass bottle i just i remember the way that their
eyes moved it always kind of freaked me out one of them would just kind of go down and come back up
and then the other one would like one eye was always open at all times yeah like crazy sounds
yeah and but it was flat on the bottom exactly yeah it was flat like the eyelid itself
you know it would it would come down and go back up and at all times when this was happening i
couldn't scream or yell you know i couldn't cry or run or whatever i was trying to do all these
things couldn't move because i knew something was up i'm looking at these little tiny these little
tiny dark looking guys and i can't i can't do anything this is why i never i didn't ever
you know i want to talk about it because i my brain scrambles into it it's the only way you
can get over the truck comes back down the path that yeah dad's truck that the guys had taken to
find dad they look over really fast at this truck that's coming down this long path and
they both look over at it really fast and they they haul ass they run and on all fours into
a pile of cut down trees dad pulls up and these guys and they're hollering for me i could hear
him saying junior i hear him i'm i'd walked about five to eight feet into those bushes
is where i almost stepped on him and he'd come up from under those bushes grabbing onto me
and he's he's in shock he's in pennant like right over there and they don't know what the
fuck i'm talking about and he's like where have you been daddy why'd you leave me why'd you leave
me i've been looking for you all night i said son i ain't been gone for 20 minutes no dad you've
been going all night and he's weeping and he's crying and he's like these creatures they scared
me dad they scared me bad i'm like creatures he said yeah these creatures they had red eyes
and i couldn't move and i was paralyzed and he's telling me all this right i want to go home i want
to go home just take me home this is all he's saying i'm trying to explain to him and me and
dad both said at the same time essentially i saw a ufo and i was saying i just saw some like a
little alien or whatever yeah we both were saying that at the same time to one another
so i lead him back to the fire where these three guys are standing and now their eyes are biggest
pie plates because they're hearing jr talking freaking out about creatures and i've been going
all night they've been looking for me and i'm talking about these big balls of fire in the sky
so about that time one of the guys with me shouts and says look and we all look up
and there were eight or nine stars that looked like stars the brightest ones you see in the
night sky they just appeared in a big circle above us and somebody points up in the sky
and we all look up and there are a ton of different little lights in the sky
and they all are doing this weird thing and they flew out away and they come back together and they
went around in circles it looked like somebody choreographed them you know was directing them
how to work see what what looked like bright stars you know they were scattered one you know
across the treeline and i could just you could just see them descending slowly and then a couple
of them shoot down over the side of the river and it just like dropping like i said you know
it looked like a piece of a hot steel or something you know they were oranges and then you could see
separate other colors it was orange and maybe yellow i remember being one on the left uh right
one in the middle and one toward the left from that tree to this tree they were right there you
could see them just perfect right there we're sitting there looking at this and then three of
these things come out of the sky all the way to ground and landed in front of us on the other side
of the river that's when it freaked me out now so hey guys look y'all see them y'all see these
i got some paranoia to open my pocket now and that's when the phoenix said you know
okay we gotta go we just all loaded up in the truck pandemonium sits in and we all jump in my
truck leaving fishing poles and everything and we took off out of there we get back up to the top
of that hill come over that hill very fast almost went airborne going over it accelerating up that
hill and i had to gem on the brakes because in front of us now are the same three orbs but
two of them were in the exact same spot the first two red balls of fire but the third one that
appeared it came down as the one that took me that took me for four hours now it's sitting in
the road blocking our path to the highway it was a light right on it was a big light it was just
another big low-end light it was like oh but didn't you know like i said it just kind of just
hold your hand up like that kind of try to remember it what if from the distance
i could put my hand around it like that maybe it's about five feet off the ground just sitting there
hovering and it looked like an egg or a football laying on its side standing up but like something
it was more like a tic tac sort of i didn't know what a tic tac was but what got the government
on me there's a whole fleet of them look on the essay was when i did report this
i reported the length to being approximately 45 to 50 feet long it's shaped like a
a pill or egg or a football you know the light going around this thing was mesmerizing i mean
it was like this these blades are look like crystals the light actually just doing this
around and around and it's just sitting there doing that everybody's freaked out i was just
kind of in my own world some of them are crying some of them are begging we didn't have a phone
but they they were pointing at shit and screaming and yelling and it was fucking chaos
so happened to be a house back in there to our right i drove across the ditch up in their yard
tried to signal them their tv was playing through the front door you could see it
their cars were there nobody answered the door the very next day the guys went back to get our
fishing poles and stuff they went over to his house because he knew him they played football
softball together one of the guys he said we were home all night you didn't come to my house
like yeah we were we were blowing the horn at your front door all this was investigated by NASA
people from NASA and the intelligence world very thoroughly about that time after we discovered
nobody's there i back out of their property back out on the road now i'm back facing this thing
and we're not going anywhere it's blocking the road about that time we heard three gunshots
and on the third shot this thing pivots and here it comes down the highway and comes right up over
my truck silent and it was so low i could have shot it with a slingshot through the top of the
sunroof it made no sound so once it passed overhead it kind of pivoted to the north and
fired off like it was out of a cannon and went out of sight so i hit the gas and away we're
going we're going home and the weird thing was i'm no longer afraid i'm in this different
my mind is seems like time has slowed down and i'm looking at everything from a different
perspective i'm not afraid i'm curious i'm watching them like wondering why they're so
afraid they were freaked out everybody badly but one of those unique things about this the miracles
that happen is um on the way to take them home between where we were and the first guy's houses
are two miles away and then about four miles five maybe to the follow follow but a mile from
where we were is where i was shot when i was 10 and the first near death and a little less than
a mile from where we were is where i read a bit in the book about my first wife was killed in a
car wreck uh turned her car over end over end and was thrown out and i happened to be
uh riding down that road i'd been out of town all day come home and i found her didn't notice
her until i stumbled on her just saw the car laying on the side and she died right there with me hold
her and um so i felt guilty all my life about that that i should have been home it wasn't my
fault i wasn't there so everything a person and the traumatic the trauma of
seeing her mangled up you know it's bad
it has
but the joy was is right when we got to that spot and we got to pass by the spot
to drop these guys off this thing this thing was hovering right directly over top where i found her
and i slammed on the brakes because it was right for i mean it was literally we were almost up under
it right it was there above us and just above the power line and it freaked everybody out so bad they
started beating on the seat and screaming go go go and i jammed on the brakes i'm trying to stop
i want to get out and look because i'm reliving that whole thing that happened 20 years before
20 years before and this vision came into my head they did this and they told me that
don't it's not your fault you don't need to worry about that anymore she says fine
so that was the first time in 20 years that i felt relief from it not being my fault
so
now i i hit the gas i wanted to stop they wouldn't let me i drop them off i take them on home and i
drop them off so chris junior and i go back home and we get home about 11 30 and he's running
through the house like a madman turning lights on i'm in my study trying to find out if it's
been on tv if the military's coming and about that time i hear this sound go over my house and
it sounded like a helicopter and i just knew that fort brag was because the way it came
is from brag and the way it was going was directly to the river so in my mind
fort brag's on the way yeah here they come
my dad raised dogs all his life he hunt hunted with dogs until he died he still had 15 hound dogs
and a kennel behind his house we lived side by side back then on six acres and behind the
house was a head of woods and then there was the dog kennel all of a sudden all these dogs start
barking so i thought immediately somebody's breaking into dad's garage so i told creature
no we're gonna i gotta go out there and see who's breaking into dad's shop he's like no dad please
don't go out there don't go don't go beg of me and i had a chesapeake bay retriever sitting on the
back steps hair standing up and she's barking towards the direction of the kennels i said look
i'm gonna send her ahead of us we'll sneak down the path and see what we can see and he
did not want to go but when i open that door i'm going he grabs me by the back of the shirt and
rosie took off down into i went out about 40 yards and looked back to see if we were coming
and she went on it so jr and i will make our way quietly across our property back into the woods
and up we snuck up to the dog kennel now it's so loud you got 15 hounds and a retriever barking
every breath and we're standing where i can see them and i said i'm gonna send rosie in in the
woods we're trained dogs they do whatever you you know i can make her attack somebody and you and
i need to run back to down the path to the yard to this big oak tree and we'll use it to hide behind
and let the dog come on out push whatever's in there out i take off running he's got me by the
shirt we get to the grass to the out of the out of the woods out onto the back centipede
i gotta make a left now hard left to go to the back corner to cut this dog off and i slipped
because of a frost on the grass and jr turned loose i thought he was just to turn loose and
was still behind me i got 100 yards to run right so i ran on back to this back of this property
thinking he's behind me undoubtedly he had had all the excitement he could handle
and he made a right and went back to the house and went in the house while i went left and went to
the back of the property so i'm still thinking he's behind me right now i run up to this tree
i hear the dogs come in i'm in front of the dog now and i run up to this tree in a full run
because it's just going down quick right and i run and i hit the tree stopped myself and i'm
panting trying to be quiet because they could hear you know any animal whatever to hear that
would go the other way the very second i run up to that tree i'm trying to catch my breath
i turn around and i look to see if jr is coming on up behind me and this is when everything
changed it was no longer jr back there but behind me about four feet behind me
is a very little creature that he described on the river with the glowing red eyes so now
behind me four feet behind me is this little translucent glowing toddler no higher than that
it's glowing the color of the moon like the moon that soft white glow but it was so shiny on the
outside the outer surface of this being was shiny like glass gleaming and underneath this shirt
or whatever it had on was a triangle shape like a triangle very important symbol to some people in
the government i immediately thought i was dead i was so afraid when i saw that and that's my backs
to it right i'm holding on to the tree and i'm panting and i see it and i'm like oh my god so
i didn't want to get closer to it so i sucked myself even right against the tree and i used it
to turn myself around and i dropped my hands down and i looked at it and i said i surrender
i don't mean you no harm i thought it was gone and here's the dog still coming closer and louder
and louder and louder and she's just in the woods good now and this thing's behind me and and when
i dropped my hands it said you don't understand we're not here to hurt you we're here to help you
and about that time it the dog comes busting out of the forest behind me right out of the street
i knew that was where it was coming and just being just vanished in front of me the dog ran
right on by ran a quarter mile i could still hear her running barking you heard this in your head
no i could hear the dog barking no but the uh the voice telling you the voice was an audible voice
in my head i heard it sound like a man deeply walked back to the house contemplating it should
i tell chris jr what i just saw he's afraid already i don't want to tell no more
so i took that to the house and and um i was very quiet about it
this also sparked chris's first miraculous healing event which he says cured him of his
crone's disease from that point forward that day i never took another pill for crone's disease
for the rest of my life i have no symptoms um i've been tested at chapel hill university
where did it go my books title ufo of god because of that very night i'm crying out to god help me
and these ufo's come out of the sky it is we're looking beings with glowing eyes and uh healed me
and forever changed my life there were several other healing events that had also taken place
which we'll get into a bit later i then asked chris if he could take me back to that day in the
woods what happened in those four hours of missing time for the first uh 14 months i could not think
about it and you could not convince me that i missed any time my son and the guys with me
were the ones that convinced me because they walked back to and they showed me to where they
had moved the truck and i had massive headaches thinking about it up to that point which was at
least a year between the initial experience and then the uh it was more like a year and a half he
would sometimes pass out if he even tried to think about what happened he would scream in his sleep
have nightmares cold sweats there were sometimes we would film him like he's talking about all
these strange things and it was like night terrors plagued him he couldn't remember and i would begin
to talk in my sleep at night a lot of times shouting and screaming afraid things they were
showing me so they brought in a psychiatrist from harvard a harvard trained psychiatrist that
was trained under dr john mack dr michael o'connell we loved him
and uh he said chris they put a block in your brain that um i'm going to remove that block
but i'm going to program you to remember everything that happened and so immediately i began to recall
things that happened but it was all images images images of things i couldn't make sense of what i
began to remember was first off was how they come and got me that that orb that shot down as
an orange ball beside the other two orange balls it came straight at me and it shifted into this
white egg came right up over top of me above me and i look up and all i could see was this
ball of light that just engulfed me around me and next thing i know i'm in a black room
and i could hear my breath and i was panicked and i was afraid i couldn't see anything in
either direction i couldn't even see me i got so afraid i could i could hear myself and this light
started to appear around me like a spotlight from above and i could see completely around me
my feet and all of white but i could stick my hand in the blackness and it would disappear
couldn't see outside of the light around me and soon this light started receding back
to where i began to see these three shadowy figures they were there with me and um well
that began a virtual tour it was a beautiful experience but they're describing everything
that they were showing me so i was basically in an orb felt like a bubble that i could touch the
walls but i couldn't see them i could see the stars under me and fill the floor but couldn't
see the floor is that clear i began to see always sees different places in the u.s they would be up
looking down telling me what i'm seeing one particular thing that stuck out was us looking
at the pyramids in egypt and i'm seeing the spanks from the rear so we're up in the air looking over
the pyramids at the rear end of this pain then i see hathor's temple and i see all these engravings
about nature and about animals and birds and their deities are animals and birds right
understand any of it but this is what they were showing me these memories surfaced during hypnotic
regression which you can listen to in its entirety on the bledso setso podcasts which i've linked
below and these images were from that regression which was featured on a tv documentary in this
documentary ufos over earth the fayetteville incident after regressing chris through hypnosis
and submitting him to a stress detector test despite the multiple eyewitness accounts they
eventually deemed that chris wasn't being entirely truthful it was tough it was tough not to believe
there is no doubt in my mind what i saw whatever this machine says i don't know
um and don't care but i know what i saw and this documentary then began what chris refers to as
the five years of darkness which led him to eventually write his best-selling book ufo of
god i was a deacon in the pentagon so whole in this church imagine that and me talking about
you know ufos automatically you're playing with satan himself that's the devil
so now for the next five years this is what i call five years of darkness it changed
everybody in our house for the first time in our life we were not open we avoided the dinner table
together our marriage and our family was on the verge of splitting up over this thing
so it's been tough but um it's not a train wreck yet
the community is accusing me of being crazy accusing me of endangering my family
that i'm bringing the devil into my house they called social services on me
and trying to separate me from my family they tried to get my kids to be out of the house
i shouldn't be around them so my kids are at home now and here's the thing the phenomenon never left
from that day forward it didn't never leave it was at my house and i experienced it in the woods
and now when my wife and kids are coming home they're getting the daylight scared out of them
because i've got orbs in the house i've got beans walking shadowy beans my wife will tell you she
followed them to the house and they go through the walls and stuff always an orbit up here
a flash and then these shadow beans step out when they walk through five years of this um
my daughter's coming home from school crying the teachers are calling them out in front of the
classmates and my boys were all 13 15 and 17 now they're made fun of in school they were at dating
age so five years of this it turned into affecting my children in such a way
that i was angry ryan weighs in on what that period was like for him i remember getting off
the school bus days after it happened my grandpa immediately told me when i got to his house
he said boy your daddy's been smoking dope in the woods and he's been seeing green boogerman
i was like what do you mean what are you talking about he said he's been going crazy he's been
seeing green boogerman in the woods so that night when my dad gets home i start asking him
about the green boogerman and he broke it down and he told me everything and even as a 13 year
old child i had this deep sense that everything he was telling me was true i could just feel it i
could feel his intensity and just his genuineness and my brother who was with him i asked him about
everything and they explained me everything that happened and there was a lot of confusion at the
time so i don't think they quite understood everything that was happening and i think they
were processing a lot but you also have to keep in mind that we were a very tight Christian family
and not just our media family but our whole extended family the community really and the
way that we were taught was that there is no such thing as aliens or even ghosts and as far as i
knew you know my dad my my siblings my whole family we didn't believe in any of this stuff
so when he's talking to me about these things i know he's he's coming from somewhere pretty serious
and for me it always angered me and from a young age i realized that i had to
and maybe it was a subconscious thing but i always felt like i had to
defend them defend their honor defend their integrity which i think is a lot of the reason
why i am going out and being as vocal and public as i am i don't know maybe it's helping the part
of me as a child who was tormented watching them suffer maybe it's trying to make that right in
some way overcome by guilt once again chris calls out to the heavens as he once did this time
he's met with something else an entity an entity that he and the government refers to as
the lady so fast forward five years later now we're talking 2012 and this is the lady
we you asked me about the lady everybody talks about this figure the lady
in my book this this lady got the attention of the vatican to every branch of the government
and to several foreign countries they're all interested in this experience so i'm at the point
chris to where i wanted to quit i'm feeling the burden of being a bad father and i brought this
in my house and my kids lives are ruined my boys are set back and they become isolated and ashamed
and so on easter sunday saturday night of easter of 2012 i walk outside about 9 30 and i had so much
sadness and shame because of my children what i was seeing happening with them i was ready to
end it all so i walked out that night i looked up at the sky and i started shouting to the heavens
i said thank you for ruining my life and so i quit i'm never going to talk about this again
i'm done with you thank you for helping me but now you've ruined my life my whole family this is what
i said that night i went to bed this is sunday morning easter sunday morning at three a.m i
heard an audible voice in my room very loud man voice i mean it woke me up out of a dead sleep
i set up in the room i said who's in here i heard that it was the same voice that came from that
little being five years earlier it said arise in this manly voice the next thing i know i
didn't know why but i could see movement in the room these shadowy beings they always look shadowy
whatever it does it can completely control us like a machine and it could turn you on and off
pause us like a video game they had this kind of control so i'm up and i'm getting dressed at two
o'clock in the morning completely dressed out the back door i got now i'm following these three
again three shadowy figures not saying a word i'm not afraid but i'm behind them and they lead me
out to this dog camp if one of these figures reaches out and hands me something i said this is
your shimashki and it was shaped like a five pound pack of hamburger one of those tubes you
know it's twisted on me that's what it is shaped exactly like that but it felt like a living
creature it felt like it had fur that was prickly like a hedgehog sort of i couldn't feel the legs
or head i was struggling to see it because it's in the dark and so i dropped it immediately on
the ground because it felt like it was prickly my fingers and this voice said no you pick that up
you must keep so i reached down i picked this thing up and i'm juggling it and when i look up
these figures are gone now here i am at the dog kennel with this weird thing in my hand i don't
know what it is if it's going to bite me or what can't really see it good so i open a dog kennel
set it in i close the door just told me to keep it i thought well it's going to be safe there
the minute i had set that the kennel close that door this wind all i can tell you it wasn't in the
trees it wasn't blowing around the whole place it was directly focused in front of me a blast of
wind like somebody hit you with a cannon or a leak blower or something blew me backwards
right into the grass the leaves and as i'm falling backwards i see
what looked like a translucent see-through cow bull cow run over top of me and i could see stars
inside it as it went over and that bit of message is going to be in another book what we discovered
about that a scientist that i've studied with a little and he mapped the great pyramid with
lidar and discovered that bull with the stars in it a huge one is painted on the wall inside
the king's chamber as a dna helix above it the only inscriptions ever found in that whole pyramid
they never found any until brother grant found us but it was the same thing that ran me over
that bull with the symbols of the stars in it so i land on my back the minute i roll over and i
start trying to get up to run i get up to my knees is all i got i push up to my knees next step was
to jump and go right but i was stopped because this cow was not there anymore but about six
feet from me maybe eight feet i couldn't reach her but it was a lady there and she's glowing
this beautiful bluish white color and lit up a circle on the ground probably 15 20 feet circle
and i'm inside that circle lit up and she's just floating three feet off the ground there's this
long white dress that i had a collar on opening white sparkly dress sitting down to the top side
feet and she was barefoot right here toes and this whole beautiful lady she was as human as
me and you and as beautiful as most beautiful woman you ever saw as she leaned storm and she said
you know i'm you know this is your burden you must bear you're going to tell this story
and if you do i will help you i'll always be with you and from this point forward
we will allow you to film our presence and share us with others
during another hypnotic regression chris goes into detail about what the lady's message was
so long story short the first regression was about the 2007 experience and it was
conducted at four hours missing time yeah it was it was conducted like a year later yes this one
is about the 2012 encounter with the lady and this regression was done many years 2018 she said she
was the divine feminine the manifestation of the universal force of love that she has existed since
before creation throughout all time you know throughout the universe that she's this force
that she is known as hathor but that throughout time she's gone by many names
and she said that there is a dark force that is basically scripting end times prophecy through
the book of revelations to try to manifest a cataclysm to wipe us out you know um that
they're trying to snuff out god but that there is this evil alien threat that that would be
the grand deception right and um she said he has to tell a story and if he doesn't then blood
would be on his hands you know something bad does happen and that there's going to be a star alignment
when the red star regulus aligns with the gaze of the sphinx just before dawn in the constellation
leo on the gaze of the sphinx in other words before daylight so before the sun rises
regulus should appear right on top of the sand as a red star is that at that moment would be a shift
into a whole new consciousness a new knowledge so i come home i mean i wrote this down and i
told it to quite a few people so they run these dilemmas to this program to see if it was even
going to happen as lo and behold easter of 2026 is when that's supposed to happen and so i put
that writing to some guys in the pentagon and um 2013 is when i told them that and now they're all
talking about 2026 2026 you hear it all over we've discovered yeah right i gave them the date you
know 12 years ago that something magic was going to happen what it is i don't know after meeting
this entity whom he calls the lady chris describes several other miraculous healing
events that had occurred and the first one was witnessed by ufo researcher grant cameron nelly
gets up off the ground and when she runs by him i saw blood shoot out of her neck like a
strange and i've got this dog i take her out the door and lay her down on the patio she got a hole
in her neck that long and it's gapped open that wide and you can see that deep and i could probably
stuck my finger that deep in her neck and how that happened nobody knows so i threw my hand on her
neck and i'm panicking holding her on the ground and trying to put pressure on her neck everybody
oh my god freaked out grant's got his camera out filming and when i knew that she was dead she won't
put him back in there was no hope and i looked up at the sky i said lord help her and immediately
i felt her just go limp and everybody saw it and when i raised my hand up off of this
her neck there was no more hole there it vanished and it vanished in front of everybody witnesses
even when camera filming that the other miraculous healing event was when chris was summoned to
washington by what sounds like some government entities to help a dying child who was given a
year to live and word got around about that and that drug that opened so many doors next thing i
know without getting into much detail about this i get a phone call in july um what are you doing
tomorrow i said tomorrow is july 3rd i said kids to be home he said we need you in dc
i said we who's we he said well we have a young boy up here that
is from a prominent family and he's very sick and in fact he is um he was given a make-a-wish
by president obama and he's had every bit they've exhausted every bit of care they can for him from
children's clinics from boston wherever and nobody could help him what he had according to
this guy was telling me he had a mitochondrial dna disease he was born with the inability to eat
and digest food they always die by the time they're 13 basically and um so
how i went from a dog getting mysteriously injured to a miracle happening in front of
everybody to now i'm being flown up to dc to some child that i had no idea what happened with me
how that happened i didn't do anything i just something up there did it long story short that
little boy um is now an american university he's about 22 years he's doing all right yeah
i can't help but connect several pieces of chris's story to the recent whistleblower
testimony of jake barber an air force veteran who claims to have assisted in the retrieval
of alien craft for the government who also describes an egg-like craft
and recalls a strong presence of a divine feminine i felt like i was possessed by the most
beautiful spirit i've ever been possessed by could this be the same entity or possibly even
related to past religious events like the 1917 sightings of our lady of fatima in portugal
sun started to roll like dancing from one place to another place where a lady described as brighter
than the sun appeared six times to a group of children and during the final apparition
on october 13th 1917 she was witnessed by over 70 000 people including skeptics and journalists
and it was documented as suddenly the clouds parted and the sun appeared as a spinning
multicolored disk zigzagging across the sky and seemingly plunging towards earth before returning
to its normal position the event later called the miracle of the sun was witnessed up to 40 kilometers
away this lady had also imparted the children with three secrets the last of which was kept secret by
the vatican until the year 2000 but many speculate is still incomplete sister lucia the last surviving
visionary was kept under strict vatican supervision for decades limiting what she could say publicly
and father malachy martin a former vatican insider claimed that the third secret was so terrifying
that its release would cause panic could this be why the government and the vatican have taken
such an interest into chris's story i'm gonna name an agency you just say yes or no whether
they contacted you whether you had contact with them is that okay something you're comfortable
with you don't have to name names all right cia um yes dia yes dod yes nsa yes and many more
nasa nasa yeah nro yeah national congress yeah nro really yeah ministry of defense
england the dod of australia these are all people who have at one point or another either reached
out or come here directly yep still to this day yeah and we're talking uh not some
um average low level guy we're talking about senior service executives from two star generals
from the dia wow here with family witnessed looking at orbs now as much as all of this
might sound trivial to some of you watching or listening to this there is a very important
component to chris's story which we haven't really touched on and that is the involvement of some of
the most important intelligence and space agencies in the world we are going to focus
on a few key people with whom chris has had a long-standing relationship one from nasa one
from the cia and one well the last one seems to have his hand in every pot let's start with
herald pavenmeyer or how he's a former nasa scientist and a prominent figure in the field
of astronomy and ufo research he worked at nasa during the era of verner von brown
contributing to the agency's advancement during the space race
pavenmeyer also maintained a professional relationship with j allen heinick the
astrophysicist and ufo researcher known for his involvement with project bluebook how before his
passing a few years ago had taken a great interest in chris's life he came in 2008 in the fall maybe
october september october just knocked on my door ryan and emily answered the door and uh
and he asked if i was home and of course i wasn't so they called me and i said well tell him to
stick around if he wants to wants to be an hour for before i get there i was home playing xbox
and i'm in my pajamas and you know probably playing fallout 3 or something and there's a
ring at the door and i go enter the door and it's this really tall he's like six foot four
six foot five and i was a kid so i was like whoa this this guy's intimidating right he said hey i'm
hal pavenmeyer i am a part of the press corps from nasa i drove 12 hours from cape canaveral
looking for the house of chris bledsoe is this the bledsoe residence and i'm like yes it is and
he shows me his badge it's nasa it says press corps right you know right on it so i tell my
mom you know someone from nasa's here and we get dad on the phone he's like keep him entertained
you know bring him in i'll be there in an hour well i was in fact very nervous at him the rumor
was back then in those days that the men in black would come get you and and that was all over the
news and the tv you know the men black movie was out then so we were afraid when he first came
and it didn't take long that everybody took a liking to him and he with us and
he was there for 11 years before he died how had a security clearance up until he died and had been
working with nasa for years 50 59 years i think and he he graduated ohio state university
when he was very young under j allen heinig and so that got him right in the back door
that's what he did he worked to debunk that was what his job was he uh he he's told me
many stories about even a couple of wrecked sites that he actually investigated and he was basically
like the guy that nasa would send if a reported case was getting serious attention from the
government it would send him and his role which he writes about in his book he would infiltrate the
family um get them to warm up to him and trust them and then he would try to covertly debunk
them so that's why he came and he's told us this he was open about this before he died
that he came to debunk us uh he spent days and days that he would go out and investigate
the whole surrounding area to and went to the faa and did all the
the stuff that they do and he could never debunk it and after a while he began to see it with me
so has he ever sort of tipped to you any sort of blowback that he had from nasa by being your
friend or by sticking around or has any of that ever come up well yeah he would he would often
ask me to keep his presence quiet right and so there were many years there that we took
the worst abuse from the neighbors from family and we couldn't tell them you know
that they were saying you're lying we don't believe you where i was hanging out down at
cape canaveral and had scientists at my house all the time we couldn't talk about next up
jim semivan now jim is a former senior officer with the cia's directorate of operations where
he spent over two decades specializing in national security and managing covert and clandestine
operations after retiring he co-founded to the stars academy alongside tom delong focusing on
the study of ufos and related phenomena he also befriended chris chris bloodsoe's experience
probably one of the most dramatic i mean this is just a wonderful wonderful man and i believe
every word he tells me and um about this and not only do i believe every word he tells me
he attracted the attention of a lot of people dia nasa cia other agencies everybody wanted to
get close to him uh but he also met um he met the entities themselves and he also met the lady
not many people meet the lady i i i will tell you that in some circles it's taken very very
seriously we've been friends a long time it was right in the middle of the drones right and they're
asking me what i was thinking about this whole thing kind of funny he's the clown with teeth
right he's that funny clown little guy he's a little guy and uh but he has teeth and we joke
about that and so he's he's very powerful and a lot of people are afraid of who he is you ended
up getting one of the most vip treatments i think any civilian will ever get uh you met a
gentleman by the name of tim taylor tim taylor otherwise known as the dragon is an enigmatic
character to say the least portrayed in diana pesolga's book american cosmic as tyler d
he was in charge of mission control at nasa has worked for elon musk as an advisor he once brought
diana and dr gary nolan blindfolded an hour in the desert to an alleged secret ufo crash site so
he takes gary nolan and i gary is a professor at stanford to be blindfolded it's a secret place
it's in new mexico it was a crash site from apparently the 19 some one of the ones in the
1940s he's had access to the vatican archives and claims that his biomedical patents of which there
are over 40 and have sold for hundreds of millions of dollars came to him as future
memories as he put it implanted by non-human intelligence he walks around tsa when he goes
to airports and he's once told the bledsoe's that the closest thing he can describe his job to
is the movie the adjustment bureau wild to say the least and he's apparently even briefed
president obama about the bledsoe's sending chris bledsoe a text with a picture of the camp
david stamp on a napkin something you can only get from the president's personal retreat tim's
an interesting guy uh to say the least you know this guy's got 40 biomedical patents he's worked
with nasa space x and all of the above he's been to the vatican archives but also not much is known
about it makes him a little bit of an elusive character you're probably familiar with diana
basolka's book as well and she mentions tyler we've come to the conclusion that that is tim
taylor what was your relationship with him at first and how did that relationship change over time
well tim um tim is a ghost right i think it was 2013 early 2013 when we met or late 2012 he knew
where i was i mean these people the intelligence world knows where i'm at all the time so somehow
he knew i was in pennsylvania in a log cabin on the delaware river and just shows up one afternoon
long story short without saying a whole lot more uh we met overnight he flew in one evening and
was gone the next day he wanted to meet and asked me if he could come to the house and meet the
family and i said yeah and three weeks later he was at my house and had a laptop and a bag on his
back full of credentials and did a gave us a briefing that on the laptop that said for the
bloodsoe family and had all the warnings and all that stuff and so that was in the days when
you couldn't talk about it was more secretive in the 20s 12s and 13s and 15s and up to about
2016 or 17 is when they first started mentioning it loosening up and i knew they were going to do
that in fact that was the plan i'd heard back then well i've heard plans of 2025 since i met
hal pavenmeyer in 2008 he told me then that they were going to have disclosure in 2025 that was
the plan i've been listening there's a whole lot that i haven't talked about such as nasa why was
i at nasa why did they get me down there how did i get in that's my crew quarters i got to meet the
general i got a special pin that only certain people have and they wanted to know from me what
in other words let's just say they're just now talking about the plasma those are the orbs that
interact with they're angelic beings because they're not just you know there's an intelligence
there's created some force created they were being harassed they're astronauts and everybody
were being harassed by these orbs and stuff and you were told that by it by ten about it way back
then when he briefed you when he showed up to your house how did he introduce himself like what
agency national reconnaissance office he had a he had a necklace with badges
credentials and they were individual air force cia nasa dod area 51 and more
he goes to camp david and meets with the president i introduced tim taylor to diana pesok and uh she
was scared of him for the first couple years until she actually met and they became friends
and then they went over to the archives and there was a ceremony in my honor that they held and
they put my picture in the picture of the archives when they went in the basement
they actually put a picture of me between the books of galileo and copernicus down in the
vatican basement so the whole thing was done as they were diana was working with investigate me
and so it's nasa so it was it was bigger than just getting in the door so let's go back to
this briefing now this briefing was a was a classified briefing i'm guessing i was told not
to share and there were stuff i was given or or shared by email and by
electronic means that i had to delete and there were things that if i tried to email it it would
flag them so you know as a fact i shared something with my wife photo i got and immediately i got a
call you know you're not sure that when he invited you to nasa what did you feel was the
sense of his importance did you notice that like people around him sort of just like open doors
for him or like how what was that like his code name is the dragon and he carries a big fat dragon
tattoo on his arm and when i went on that base he called out a temporary tattoo and put it on my arm
tattoo of a dragon and there we went about as in fact he had another guy from the n.r.o give us a
tour but he told us good not to go over the speed limit not one mile an hour because they had they
would get you and as soon as we get back after the launch was over and we go and pick him up right at
the mission control he jumps in as a driver and i'm not joking we went 80 miles an hour all over
that base and everybody would just wave him up i mean he's just in control does what he wants
he controls the launches they wanted me to tell them all i could about the nature of them and
why they were doing certain things why they were shooting rockets out of the sky
and i'm like do you have weapons on those things there is a famous video out there of one of these
ufos or objects or whatever it is taking down one of these rockets that they were shooting up
i've seen it who showed this to you tyler did following one such test launch lieutenant jacobs
was unexpectedly told to report to the office of major florence mansman on the screen was the
film we had shot the nose cone separate the shaft flew out in front of we saw this as obviously
reflections of light rippling like that and then we saw the dummy warhead flying along it's going
between six and eight thousand miles an hour at that point and it's on the the fringe of space
and suddenly into that that frame an object flew in chasing the chaff the warhead and so on at the
same speed and in polar orbit it fired a beam of light at the warhead the beam of light struck that
the object flew up shot another beam of light at the dummy warhead went around shot another
beam of light at it went down shot a beam of light and then flew out the same way to come in
at which time the dummy warhead fell out of the frame the lights came on and major mansman said
to me were you guys screwing around up there and i said no sir and he said what was that and i said
it looks like we got a ufo and he said lieutenant jacobs you are never to speak of this again it
never happened yeah quite a few well i saw these things i don't want to talk about sure understood
one thing is in the book there is mention of meta materials yep can you tell us how that came to be
and what happened with that it's well known that these orbs and i say well known the the military
knows it right they've got video of it somehow know that these orbs will often drip like molten
metal drip looks like welders welding and you know slag falling off of them they do that
i was at a friend's house at an organized group meeting up two hours from here they invited me
there and i'm in a group of strangers and this orb shows up up over her driveway over the house
and drip this metal on the driveway so i got the metal and you have pictures of that as well right
yeah i got this metal i had the possession of it i end up with a material and i kept it for quite
a while but some friends at nasa knew i had it and they knew that i was connected to another
guy up in ohio that had some scared to tell anybody what he had but he came home one evening
he sees a light over his house and and it took off and when he pulled up the driveway there's
something glowing red in the grass and he lets it cool down he picked it up and put in a shoe box
in there it stayed for 15 years but he felt comfortable talking to me i'm just an average
guy right so he told me about it and i'll let some folks at nasa know about it and they wanted
to go up and so i flew we flew up there and got a piece just a little piece of it for testing
and then tom delong and lou elizando wanted some of it and they called me and i ended up letting
them have three pieces as well it won't a year later i get a call that uh it said well uh news
to let you know you're not getting this medal back wow that it was classified by the military
you got confiscated and you just gonna have to chalk it up for one for our country as early as
two years ago i had people come in here from dc telling me if i could get another piece of it
it'd be worth a billion dollars they did send you something in return didn't they well i've got
quite a few different things in return there yeah all right it was like a pin well yeah well i can't
talk about that all right yeah you're talking about the triangle pin uh-huh yeah and there's
other thing too that i actually speak about but okay well that pin elected me into a club of
basically astronauts that have experienced the phenomena first hand not in a sleep or in a dream
or a regression it was there in the daylight or in front of me and you interact with it so you and
other astronauts have these pins yeah you're part of a small group that experienced it that's
incredible yeah what about the vatican yeah they've investigated me they've investigated you yeah
they're heavily involved in the uap issue aren't they hugely they have been for a long time yep
from the beginning and so is all the churches all the churches together all of them are deeply
rooted into this and they're in regular contact with our government and with me yeah a lot of
work for the government oh you always hear these generals in the pentagon they think it's demonic
they don't ever want to tell it right well right they're protecting the church right and their
belief and a lot of these churches don't want the connection that is biblical
there is something spiritual about this phenomenon 100 percent
you've spoken to some of the most important people in this country yeah some of the people
that the public might not even know are important we'll put it that way they have no clue and those
people know about this phenomenon yes and they know this is very real yes and they know this
is happening and this has been happening yeah so all we're seeing with this sort of disclosure
stuff that's on tv this is just like a horse and pony show right now basically little let's just
say i've been to harvard university and i've met with some scientists there that's the first time
i've ever revealed it on your show right now and i can't tell you any more there but i have met with
scientists i have been on their campus and there will be more to come about that so there are
serious people around me that know it's real that want to study this and get to the bottom now due
to the overcast we weren't able to skywatch at chris's that night which really isn't the
reason i went there in the first place but ryan wanted to make it up to me and asked if i'd join
him and a few friends the next night for some sky watching on the beach and here's what happened
okay not even kidding i was looking up at the sky we were following something moving okay i don't
know what it was your guess is good as mine but right in front of it this camera flash this really
bright flash just popped out of nowhere stopped didn't flash since hasn't flashed that was
incredible yeah so i'm looking at you you're vlogging you're talking about stuff that you're
seeing and the video is priceless because your face is like you know your reaction
and someone behind you is like what the hell is that what is that look what is that hey
hey
oh my god oh my god look at that no i missed it what was that
and by the time i turn around you guys are already like whoa you know you're all seeing it i felt
like i saw it last and i was just frozen like my hand was in my pocket on my phone and i was
thinking the thought that went through my mind was like don't take your eyes off this
that was incredible there oh look something's coming back did you did you guys see that
i am absolutely blown away right now what i saw i i've sky watched with hundreds of people in my
life and what we just saw is probably the craziest thing that i have ever seen with a crowd of people
outside of my family it was insane it was like it was like a long oblong sequence of orange lights
yeah that that was spectacular you know i'm still freaking out i spent my whole life at least more
than half of it looking at the sky that was a really big orb you know it was about this big
you know so say you look at the moon if if you're you know you're so far away from the moon but
you're looking up in the sky you hold your finger up there or a ruler it's about an inch this thing
was that big yeah at least it wasn't a dot it was like it was a long like on the horizon it looked
like like several inches this thing was huge it was one of the biggest things i've ever seen
in this space you know and you know orbs and crafts and stuff and it looked like these massive
orange balls of fire which is what my dad saw the first time and then it happens again these
strangers complete strangers they start walking towards us on the beach and they're like did
y'all see that they got the coast guard on the phone no we saw like a row of nine you guys saw
it you guys saw that yes yeah i didn't see that you saw it i didn't see that
and it's red you guys call the police wow yeah dude you probably didn't you probably did the
right move oh damn right what if it was a ufo we did pull out some aliens do you guys believe
in ufos man if anybody doesn't think that we're the only people in this universe yeah as big as
it is yep something wrong with yeah there you go so what's that one
and what's that one look at that
and what's that one look at that look at that right now did you miss that
a giant light right over the water oh really i don't know if i caught it on camera it was like
orange
you have a good night you too get home safe ryan there was another there was another one when they
were talking yeah there there look look look what is that
that is not a flare that is not a flare
and then the girl he was with you know tells us a story about how her father in 1968 was with his
buddies drinking yeah and three same beach at the same beach and three orbs went right over their
head and he passed out and woke up with like dots behind his knees is what she said he was like
hours later he woke up yeah that's crazy so my dad grew up here on bison beach right okay he and a
bunch of his buddies went down to johnny mercer's one night and they're looking out over the ocean
like we are they see these three dome lights come in and they start running up towards the dunes
and they look over them there's a bright light over my dad blacks out and he wakes up and it's
like missing time and everything but he's got these two dots behind his knees like he was abducted
no coincidence he swears to god on the story might have been stabbed or something you're talking
you're talking to the right people there's i think there's a reason we met on this beach tonight
all of us i think there really is yeah so we just saw we saw something absolutely anomalous
that appeared a row of like nine lights yeah this giant what seemed like a craft
that went away these people showed up and lo and behold again multiple orbs start appearing
yeah again i fully did not expect to see it again we saw it the first time and it looked like the
millennium fountain and it was crazy and i was like okay so that was awesome but no way we'll
see it again and what maybe five minutes later or so 10 maybe happened again when those people
were here right they were here right yeah they saw it oh come on they saw it the first time that's
why they came over they called the coast guard and and then after there was like a fireball
yeah and it was just hanging there it stayed in the air for like five seconds yeah like a rotating
orange fireball and if it was like i mean because what the guy at first he's like he thought it was
like a flare like somebody needed help out there but you would see a flare go up yes absolutely
and then it would go down yeah this just stayed there they appeared in the air they appeared out
of thin air stayed there at the same vertical beautiful never seen anything i've never seen
anything like that either i'm having a hard time getting over it guys
and to boot we got an eclipse tonight so not only is it a harvest moon
and a supermoon and a supermoon but that thing up there is going to be eclipsed in about 15 minutes
beautiful if there's one message you want to get out to my audience
that are tonight on a clear sky they're going to look up what's one thing you want them to know
um this phenomenon is here for us all it's a beautiful spiritual connection
and i want to add this one thing there's a pattern to it that you'll never hear discussed
i have thousands of people that write me that never report and of the i probably have eight
thousand emails i haven't even opened this is so many people reaching out that there's one pattern
that's predominant now you never hear this on tv you never hear any experts talk about it because
these patterns lead to conclusions right and that is that 99.9 percent of all people that i meet
that tell me that they've had this experience or they started seeing things all tell me
because i'll ask them after they tell me their story all right when this happened to you where
were you at in life tell me what was going on they'll all say oh my husband died i had a near
death experience my daughter died my son died my wife died or um tragic stuff very always suffering
and always trauma so what kind of force that can hear your thoughts and it knows your heart will
care about you enough to come here to to show itself to you and say i'm here we've been taught
that it's evil that it's got to be demonic and i'm here to tell you that's not what's happened to me
and it's still here and i have shared it with thousands of people from my book to in person
and i see nothing but the most beautiful letters of people pouring out of my heart saying
my life has changed i'm i'm i was an atheist now i believe and my whole life has been transformed
and i see it every day so go out tonight and open your heart look up to the heavens and and um
um know it have faith that something's going to respond to you because it it does it's there
it never leaves you don't have to go into a big ritual it's all right in our thoughts
accept that it's real and open your heart and love and and caring for your friends and family
that type of energy coming from you is what calls it if you walk out there skeptic oh blah
blah you know you can take a hike you're not going to see anything that's probably why the
government has a hard time seeing it yeah that's why right folks at nasa i ask them i said why are
you here you've got all the scientists and all the equipment and space shuttles and spaceships and
cameras and satellites what do you need me why are you here scaring my family
and the guy looked at me he said um he said we see it but it has absolutely nothing to do with us
will not interact or respond but it does you and we'd like to study that with you
so if you don't tell anybody that you're interacting with us we'll let you onto some
secrets and that's what the first well that i'm still interacting with people from there
as high up as the kid and we'll leave it at that
thank you my friend thank you chris i really appreciate your time you're more than welcome
anytime thank you final thoughts
this is tough and i want to start by saying that the more that this subject gets pulled into the
light the more we're going to be faced with conversations that are much like these so i
want to preface this segment by saying it's important to enter these conversations in the
future from the most neutral point of view that you can spare i've said this before but this
is a subject that is incredibly polarizing it's very nature puts into question most people's
core belief and so i think it's incredibly important that we remain respectful throughout
this discourse that we end up having whether through the anonymity of our online profiles
or better yet in person belief is an incredibly personal journey
it doesn't come from scripture and it certainly also doesn't come from a redacted file being
slid across the table belief comes from within your own personal experience here on earth
it is ever evolving ever changing i believe chris bledsoe had an experience that was witnessed by
three other people i believe his son also had an experience that has obviously left him
you know traumatized to a certain extent i know for a fact that he is in contact and has been
visited by very important people within the government on a personal note i do think that
some of the things he's filmed in the past have probably a prosaic explanation for i can't be
certain of that but i know that there are thousands of satellites above our heads and i know that
and i know that every year about a thousand pieces of space debris burns up in our atmosphere
and that includes old rockets and satellite parts there's a lot of activity in our skies
that much i know i'm not an expert so i can't tell you what the difference between space debris
and an orb is and i also can't tell you to believe someone when they say it is an orb
or it is an angel or it is space junk i think that is up to you to do your own research
and find out now whether that's getting some state-of-the-art equipment and a radar
and a camera and a telescope figuring out what that is or whether that's just going outside
and sending your love out into the sky to see if you can sort of summon one of these celestial
bodies that's up to you i think it's healthier if we continue this conversation forever because
i do think the unhealthiest thing that anyone could do is stop being curious and stop searching
use the information that chris and ryan gave you in this documentary and let that help nourish
some type of newborn curiosity or let it empower your skepticism and go get some equipment and
try filming it for yourself but i think one thing we can all agree on is chris's message of love
i think that's something we can all get behind and that's an important message
that we should all be sharing we've got enough people worrying about the militarization of this
topic i think it's healthy that we counterbalance that with some empathy thank you for watching this
has been an amazing journey and i'm glad to have shared it with you let me know your thoughts below
i've left the entire uncut interview with chris bledsoe for free on my patreon you can watch it
uncut and if you want to subscribe to the patreon and help encourage this channel it's five dollars
a month i will be adding some extra content there about this very investigation and obviously you
have access to the entire library of backlogged investigations as well thank you so much
and we'll see you next week for another episode of debriefed peace and love
you