But I would say that one of the most impressive
was this girl named Haley.
She literally did six different sessions,
each two hours long.
I took a random number generator
and I created random numbers,
like five, six digits.
And then I would come up with an operation between them.
It would be multiplying them or dividing them.
And then I would ask her to give me all the numbers
that are part of the equation.
When you say she would give you all the numbers,
this is without seeing the numbers, this is...
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay.
It was 162 numbers
and she got all but seven correct
and the seven mistakes she made she got on the second try.
Because we're instantly sending
and receiving information through space,
does that imply that we might be able to perceive
or even affect information through time?
Have you ever seen or heard of any examples
of these children sort of interacting
with something that, for a lack of a better word,
is non-human?
I've heard accounts that they're evil ones
and then that they're good ones.
But I was observing some children
who were really advanced in math
and they were autistic.
And I looked over at this one little boy's piece of paper
and he had drawn the head that looks like a gray.
I was just like,
oh, that's kind of an interesting thing
for a little six-year-old to be drawing.
Have you seen any interest from intelligence agencies
when it comes to your work?
Welcome back to another episode of Debrief.
Today, it is my esteemed pleasure and honor
to introduce to you a conversation
that I've recently had with Dr. Diane Hennessy Powell.
Dr. Powell is a distinguished neuropsychiatrist,
neuroscientist, and author renowned
for her interdisciplinary research
into human consciousness and psychic phenomena.
She earned her medical degree
from Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine,
where she also completed a post-doctoral training
in medicine, neurology, and psychiatry.
She has served on the faculty of Harvard Medical School
and participated in a think tank on human consciousness
at the Salk Institute in La Jolla, California.
Now, throughout her career,
Dr. Powell has explored the intersection
between neuroscience and psychic phenomena
with a particular focus on telepathy in autistic savants.
Her groundbreaking work known as The Telepathy Project
investigates reports of telepathic communication
in nonverbal autistic children,
aiming to understand the mechanism behind such abilities.
In her book, The ESP Enigma,
A Scientific Case for Psychic Phenomena,
Dr. Powell presents a comprehensive analysis
on various psychic phenomena.
But one of the most widely recognized
and perhaps most topical contributions to telepathy
is her involvement with the absolutely viral sensation
of a project known as the telepathy tapes.
This is a series of recordings
that documents remarkable instances
of telepathic communication in her research subjects.
Now, these tapes have garnered
significant attention recently,
even so much as reaching a top five position
on the Spotify charts with only 10 episodes.
It's filled to the brim not only with evidence,
a lot of evidence of telepathy,
but also with just really interesting human stories
about people who in our society
have been a little bit discarded or suppressed.
Through Dr. Powell's work,
they've literally given these people a voice.
I don't think I remember the last time
I gave something such a hard push in real life.
Like everybody I come across,
I'm like, you have to listen to the telepathy tapes.
So do yourself a favor and go check that out.
And now it is my pleasure and honor
to present to you a conversation
between myself and Dr. Diane Hennessey Powell.
I am joined today by Dr. Powell,
Dr. Diane Hennessey Powell,
who has been doing amazing research
in the field of Psy for a very long time,
namely recently on a very popular podcast
that's taken the internet by storm, the telepathy tapes.
So first of all,
thank you Dr. Powell for joining me today.
You're welcome, it's a pleasure.
Dr. Powell, I wanna start this interview
with a giant disclaimer and propose that our conversation
will be based entirely on the statement that Psy exists
and it is real.
I also wanna say that any speculation derived
from this statement will be for the sake
of thought experiments and encourage lateral thinking.
I know that your time is precious
and I don't wanna dwell on skepticism too much.
Yes.
So in your book, the ESP Enigma,
the scientific case for study for psychic phenomena,
you provide case studies and real world examples
of psychic phenomena, telepathy and so on,
demonstrated by people with autism, namely like Savants.
You also demonstrated this during the telepathy tapes.
If I had to ask you,
what is the most significant discovery
that you've come across while working with these kids?
Boy, there's so many.
I mean, it's one of those things where it's really unfolded
with one ability after another.
So I mean, it starts off with a parent telling me
that these kids have Savant skills,
that for example, they know things in science
that they were never taught
or they have several languages that they can read
or a lot of them are nonverbal so they can't speak.
But I'll hear these things and I'm told
that there was no exposure.
And that's something that is well documented
as Savant syndrome is that you can have people
that know things and you don't understand how they know them.
And so that I was sort of expecting,
but the first thing that happened was the first kind
of dominoed fall, if you will,
was having parents say to me,
and they're all telepathic, by the way.
And so I thought, oh, wait a minute.
Okay, so that's a confounding variable
because if I'm testing this kid
to see if he's a mathematical Savant
and I'm there looking at the calculator
to see if his answer is correct,
how do I know he's not just getting the information from me?
And I mean, some people would say,
oh, well, it's all non-local information.
Isn't that interesting?
But the scientist in me, the theoretician in me,
wants to, if possible, really define these things,
delineate them to really understand.
First, you have to sort of tease everything apart
and then you can see later if they're all the same thing.
If I saw the same brain activity common to all of them,
I'd say, okay, maybe they are all the same thing.
Maybe it all is just navigating space-time,
but maybe there's something else.
And the neuropsychiatrist in me knows
that there's this correlation between the EEG
and what our inner experience is.
So if somebody says they're visualizing something,
you'll see heightened activity in the visual cortex.
If there's people who say that they're hearing something,
I mean, there's a part of the brain,
the auditory cortex that you would expect
to have more activity that you can pick up.
And so there's this way in which,
I think as a neuropsychiatrist, I'm thinking,
okay, wouldn't it be validating
if you have somebody report,
well, this is what's happening for me,
and then you see the brain activity
is in correspondence with that.
And a good example of that is Laura Lynn Jackson,
who's a famous psychic who also does,
receives information as a medium.
And she reports that the information always comes
in her right visual field when it comes
from like, it's either psychic or medium.
I oftentimes get my left right confused.
Anyway, but one of them is where she sees
the information that's psychic,
and the other is where she sees the information
that is mediumship.
And then when you look at her EEG,
you'll see that the corresponding sections
of the visual cortex to those visual fields,
actually what showed a shift in the usual brain activity.
And so that kind of science can help
to validate these abilities if you see that.
So anyway, but I, and I'm curious,
if somebody is precognitive, which was the next thing.
First of all, I heard that they were precognitive,
and then it's another thing to actually have examples
in which it happens, where they say,
something's gonna, that they're concerned about something
and then it does happen.
So, and then I'd say after that, then they start,
the next thing to kind of come up is that,
oh, by the way, I get visited by people
that are on the other side, and I can get a reading
about this relative of yours who's standing
over in the corner there.
I haven't been able to do, I know how to set up studies
so that I could test for mediumship,
but at this point, that is really just anecdotal.
But what you see is that you just see,
if you think about the phenomena that's been described
in parapsychology, I think all of them are described
by many of these children.
It's just that they each have their own sort of specialty,
but what they all share in common
is definitely the telepathy.
That's fascinating.
And that's, I think one of the biggest takeaways for me,
especially listening to the telepathy tapes
is finding out that they all have this.
And everybody says this with such confidence,
they all have this, and it's just so mind boggling to me
that we can say that, that they all have this.
That is a big piece of data that we have to prove
that this ability exists.
That is a massive piece of data if they're all doing this.
Have you ever found within these,
especially the nonverbal community,
have you found that there is a correlation
between the strength of the telepathy and their condition?
Yeah, well, that's an interesting question.
I mean, one of the things I'd like to do
is I'd like to actually, in a formal way,
actually test that.
I mean, we can easily do that.
And, but what I would say is that,
I, you know, one of the reasons why,
I mean, obviously, there's no way I've tested on speakers.
But one of the reasons, besides the fact
that you hear how emphatically,
somebody who's working as a speech pathologist,
has like five of these kids in their office every day,
and they say emphatically, you know, they all do it.
You know, that bears a lot of weight for me,
because they would be the ones in the front lines
telling you, you know, that this is what they're experiencing.
Another reason why I think it's possible, quite possible,
is that really relates to this theory that I have
that came from the fact that the ones
who seem to be the most profoundly telepathic
are the ones who receptive language is intact
and their expressive language
was short-circuited during development.
They were developing normally,
and then something happens such that the area of their brain
that's involved in speech expression
gets excessively pruned, okay?
And therefore, they have what's basically
an expressive aphasia, which a lot of neurologists
are familiar with as, oh, somebody has a stroke,
and they can still understand language,
but they just can't express it.
And the expression goes for not just using your mouth,
but using your fingers as well.
You know, it's very connected.
And that's been the reasons why babies who are deaf,
I mean, they actually can babble with sighing, okay?
They're doing all these, you know,
just like the baby babbling,
there's a certain babbling that occurs
with the baby with their hand.
And if they're deaf, we see that they're using their hand
and we try to form it into symbols and language,
but we're so speech-oriented that we then start working
with them to get their lips to be that
which can create a much more rich symbolism, you know,
which we call language.
And so what you have here is you have this innate desire
on the part of this infant to communicate.
And when it gets disrupted, then they become really good
at what they've got left because the desire
to communicate doesn't go away.
And what I think is that I suspect that telepathy,
this ability to tap into the consciousness
of those that are in our surroundings,
that that is something that we're, it's innate,
we're all born with that.
And that ability to do that is a lot of how we then start
to make associations between sounds that we're hearing,
around us and some kind of meaning.
You know, it's like, it seems so miraculous
when you think, well, how did, you know,
we didn't always have Sesame Street teaching kids how to,
you know, and they're picking up the oral stuff first
before we even think about teaching them to read.
And if you've ever studied a foreign language,
it's like, there's a lot to figuring out
where one word ends and another word begins,
and you know, all of the, you know,
and the meaning of, you know, everything.
And you know, not everything's a noun, you know?
And so we're, and they're somehow picking up all of that.
And as I'm saying, this aha moment that I had was,
I was like, okay, you know,
the most profoundly telepathic are the ones who can't,
they have no choice.
That's the only thing that they have is
they just don't let go of the default means
by which they entered into, you know,
this existence able to communicate.
And what's frustrating for these kids
is that people can't read their mind.
And so they're experiencing all of this information,
and yet until they were actually given the ability to spell,
which doesn't require as accurate
of a sensory motor system.
You know, I mean, a lot of these kids,
their proprioception is off.
So they don't know exactly where their finger is in space.
And a lot of the physical therapy
and occupational therapy that they get is trying to,
and so the spelling activity itself,
but pointing to a big letter board,
is precisely to try to help to get them
to have enough accuracy.
And then once they master, I mean,
then you'll see that they're not hesitating
between each letter while they're trying to do the telepathy.
They're just going,
bing, bing, bing, bing, bing, bing, bing, bing, bing,
spelling out what it is that is being thought, you know?
And you're like, how is it, I mean, at first I'm like,
how is it that they can be spelling
what their parent is thinking?
And then you realize,
if they're tapping into their consciousness,
they're not just getting the message,
they're also getting the spelling too.
That's right, yeah.
Wow, that is so mind blowing.
It is, I mean, so I have so many questions.
Do you think that, because obviously this sounds like,
like you said, like this yearning to express oneself
is what's responsible for this.
And I would say express oneself as opposed to communicate
because the reception side is,
like, do we see that in people
who have a hard time receiving
that they would receive telepathic messages more,
or is it more about expression, like self-expression?
Do you think that we're more prone to develop these things
if our ways to express ourselves are inhibited
versus our ways to intake information?
Well, I agree with you that I think that there's
just as much an innate sort of drive for self-expression
as there is for communication.
But if you think about what's going on with an early child
who's totally dependent upon us for everything,
it's like they can't open the refrigerator door,
they can't, they can't,
there's so much they can't do
unless they learn how to communicate.
To survival.
Because a lot of things are,
it's a form of expression to be throwing a tantrum.
Right.
Yeah, I'm sure expressing myself
is I'm banging my head against the wall
because I'm so frustrated
because I can't communicate with you
that this is what I want or need.
And so I think that, yeah, as we get older,
the self-expression becomes more critical.
And that's, I mean, you get into the age of the,
even starting like the age of three,
the terrible twos and threes where the kid says no
and anything you say, there's a no
because they're wanting to see that they can
at least oppose the program
even though it's really actually
what they want to do anyway.
I mean, you don't get into struggles
with a three-year-old over that stuff
because they don't really mean no 99% of the time
when they say it.
Wow.
So, okay, that is super interesting.
Yeah, I mean, yeah, it comes down to, I guess, survival.
And it reminds me a lot about the work
that Dr. Edwin May did with Joe McMonagle
in that they would have,
the targets would be more accurately described
if like, for instance, someone's life was in danger
or if it involved children.
So it almost seems like it's consciousness's way
of wanting itself to survive.
And it's doing that by any means necessary
and by all means available to it.
Is that fair to say?
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, consciousness is, I mean, yeah,
the question is what is it that needs self-expression?
Consciousness needs expression, right?
And so what happens is that in the first several years
of life, I mean, particularly the first five years of life,
I mean, the brain is undergoing massive, massive development.
And what's driving it is, you know,
I mean, these things that we're talking about.
And if what happens is, if there's, something goes wrong,
there's so much plasticity,
there's so much flexibility to come up with
either a new workaround, you know,
or to, you know, some kind of loophole
or, you know, or maintaining a default system
that, you know, that worked,
but, you know, wasn't perfect, you know, in certain ways,
you know, but basically that consciousness
is going to try to fulfill those drives
and will work with what it's got
during that developmental phase, you know,
to make that happen.
And so that's why I'm so interested in, you know,
like, what's the brain wiring of, you know,
of some of these individuals who had their, you know,
had their language disrupted,
and then they have these abilities, you know,
how did they rewire their brains
and how does that rewiring relate to their specific set
of special skills, you know, beyond just the telepathy,
you know, the savant skills, you know,
which are more common in autistics
than they are in other population.
The other population that they're the most common in,
there's the blind.
Both of those are circumstances
in which you have something that gets disrupted,
something that is usually used by us to navigate
or to, you know, to get around for survival purposes.
And an alternative is, you know,
is rewired into their system.
Yeah, enhanced.
Yeah, they're even better at that.
I mean, like the, I don't know if you're familiar
with like the people who are blind who can echolocate.
Yes.
They can just click, you know, click,
and then detect the signal bouncing off of things
and they can do all kinds of things
that, you know, a lot of sighted people be afraid to do.
Exactly, I remember seeing that on,
I think it was like Ripley's, believe it or not,
or something like a long time ago.
And I remember myself like in my room,
trying to click and closing my eyes and seeing if I could,
and yeah, it felt impossible to me.
So it was that much more impressive when I, you know,
when I seen someone do it.
Okay, I want to speak about this particular phenomenon
that I've heard about through the telepathy tapes,
which I think really captivated a lot of people
and, you know, raised a million questions in my own mind.
The talk on the Hill.
This is, I mean, this is like,
it really feels like something out of a sci-fi movie
or a comic book or something.
It is genuinely, I think for me,
one of the most inspiring things
that I've heard throughout this project.
And to give maybe people a brief summary,
and maybe you can help me on this,
but it's essentially a place where these mainly,
I think, nonverbal communicators go to
in a state of sort of meditation
and communicate thoughts and ideas
and teach each other things.
And if I'm not mistaken, there are a lot of them
who do this, is that correct?
Is that fair to say?
Yeah, yeah, that's fair to say it.
What's interesting is that there's been more
than one group of individuals
who have brought up the Hill without,
before we had the telepathy tapes released.
So without it being that they heard about it
and said, oh yeah, I go to the Hill too.
And that's number one.
Number two is the fact that there's more than one Hill.
And one person put it
that there's Hills for different ages,
kind of almost like how high school,
you've got junior high, high school,
that there's different general age groups.
And that makes sense.
Socially, birds of a feather flock together.
So if you were to open up a big playground
and you had five-year-olds and nine-year-olds
and 15-year-olds, you know,
they're gonna self-assort by age.
And then another thing that's interesting
is that more than one child has described it
as having a library.
And that makes a lot of people then think about,
oh, is that the Akasha preference?
Or what is that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And they're sort of like, you know, they're studying.
You know, and a lot of this is occurring
while they're sleeping and dreaming sleep,
which we know dreaming sleep is more closely associated
with psychic abilities than a lot of other states.
And, but some of them can, you know, also, I guess,
during the day, they can, you know,
just kind of go up to the bedroom and shut the door
and kind of go to the hill and visit their friends.
But they need to be in a safe place like their bed to do it.
They're not just walking around, you know, going to the hill.
I mean, it's my understanding.
So is there a specific example
of some like verifiable case that has happened?
So for instance, like someone went to go learn something
and they came back with more knowledge
than they had prior to going to the hill.
Like, is there any, or has there been any form
of like telepathic communication between two individuals
that was later confirmed,
even though they didn't meet each other
and know of each other,
that they confirmed each other's existence?
Is there, has there been any examples of that?
I've been told that that has happened.
Yeah, I mean, I haven't been able to, you know,
personally, you know, witness it, you know,
do the controlled experiments that I'd like to do.
But yes, I've been told that, definitely,
that, you know, there are these, there are friendships.
I mean, you know, so there are certain kids
that have more of an affinity for another kid, you know?
So it's not that they're just going to the hill
and getting, you know, and talking with everybody,
you know, it's that they, you know,
they have some specifically more
that they want to see on the hill.
So there's that kind of thing going on.
And that, you know, and so that telepathy
between two people, you know,
whether it's happening on the hill or whatever,
I mean, that's, you know, harder to say,
but, you know, it's impressive that, you know,
if there really is, you know, telepathy happening
between them, which is, you know, there's no reason to,
I mean, discount the people who were reporting that.
Sure.
And, but there's, you know, there's just so much about this
that, you know, they're interconnected with one another.
There's just so much about this
that just needs to be explored.
And so that's one of the ones that,
that's one of the ones I want to, I want to set up.
I mean, the experiment that I want to set up
for the documentary is I want it to make,
I mean, I'm going to be doing other experiments,
but I want it for the documentary.
I want to have the best possible demonstration
of this phenomenon possible.
And to me at this point,
I think one of the best demonstrations would be
to have two kids, totally separate individuals,
you know, being, you know, where, you know,
two different states, you know, across the country,
whatever, but they're totally apart from one another.
They're each working with their best facilitator
for their communication, but that's not the person
who's holding the thoughts about, you know,
that the kid's supposed to read.
It's, let's see the two kids and communicate
with one another and see what happens.
And so that's an experiment I really want to set up,
among others.
Yeah, I mean, that sounds exciting,
and I'm sure everybody would be very excited
to see something like that happen.
You know, it's so interesting how we're kind of sort
of casually strolling by the idea
that these kids are reading their parents' minds.
It's such a, like a post-psychic disclosure world
that I feel like we're living in right now,
which, and I didn't even get to revel
in like this psychic phenomenon yet.
So I freak out from time to time,
just even thinking about this, like internally,
and it makes me very excited.
But could you perhaps, just for the audience
that maybe isn't familiar, give one example
of some type of test, of the many, many tests
that were performed, one example,
and of the sort of variables that were controlled
during this test and what the outcome was?
Sure, I mean, so the child, actually,
that I spent the most time, some of the children
that I spent the most time studying,
actually aren't even part of those telepathy tapes.
Those children that are in that are ones
that Kai wanted to, she wanted to be there
from the very beginning, you know,
that she didn't want to see somebody had already tested.
But I would say that one of the most impressive
was this girl named Haley, who was somebody
that she literally, she literally did six different sessions
each two hours long with two separate therapists
where we had a barrier between them,
a visual barrier between her and the therapist.
And she loved numbers.
And so, and she didn't like it to be just, you know,
simple numbers.
And so what I would do is I took a random number generator
and I created random numbers, like, you know,
five, six digits, you know, different, you know,
anything between, you know, zero and, you know,
10 million kind of thing, and then any, you know,
whatever numbers came up, and then I would come up
with an operation between them, you know,
either be multiplying them or dividing them
or finding a cute root or whatever, but those numbers.
And then I would ask her to give me all the numbers
that are part of the equation.
Okay, so what is the equation in the first place?
And then she'd point to all the numbers, you know,
and what is the operation?
When you say she would give you all the numbers,
this is without seeing the numbers,
this is completely across the room.
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, but, you know, the therapist would be thinking
of, you know, the therapist would be looking
at the mathematical equation I gave her,
and let's say, you know, it was, you know,
one, five, seven, four times, you know, 302, okay?
And so she would say those two numbers,
she would also choose that it was times,
because she had the, you know, the, you know,
on her stencil board, she had, you know,
the thing for those kinds of operations.
And then I'd say, and what does that, you know,
and the therapist said, what does that equal?
And then she would give you the correct answer.
And so if you add up, if you just treat
all of those individual digits,
both of the numbers that were part of the, you know,
the mathematical operation
and the numbers that were the answer,
she did, I tested her for, it was 162,
it was 162 numbers, and she got all but seven correct,
and the seven mistakes she made,
she got on the second try.
All in a matter of, all in a matter of,
um, gosh, you know, 15 minutes, maybe.
I mean, yeah, and so that gives you,
because she's not there trying to pick up
some kind of subtle cue, you know,
or that, you know, she's just going at it, like, okay.
This is fascinating.
I mean, this is, it does look like it is
instant communication, by the way.
There's no bandwidth.
And that is something as, you know, I'm a magician.
I've pretended to have these psychic abilities,
and I'm pretty sure I could convince someone
that I have psychic abilities
because I've been doing it for so long, right?
There is a moral and ethical line that I do,
that I do respect, but, you know, for me,
it's always about dramatically playing up the idea
that, oh, you're thinking I'm getting a two,
but these children are doing it instantly.
There's no hesitation.
And so that brings me to the next question,
because when perceiving or sort of communicating
information non-locally through remote viewing
or through telepathy, like, because we're instantly sending
and receiving information through space,
does that imply that we might be able to perceive
or even affect information through time?
Oh, I, well, yeah, I mean, I, you know,
I look at both quantum physics and the theory of relativity.
You know, the theory of relativity tells us
that our concept of time is an illusion.
It's not just moving like an arrow does
in a single direction.
And so I think a lot of these parapsychological phenomena,
what they tell us is exactly what physicists
were telling us 100 years ago,
and that is that we're locked into,
our sensory system has kind of fooled us
into just thinking that reality is just
three physical dimensions and a very limited, you know,
view of what time is.
And so we know that space-time itself curves,
and it curves as a result of something called gravity.
We don't understand, you know,
we don't understand gravity entirely
by any stretch of the imagination,
but we do know that that was, you know,
Einstein's, you know, a description of gravity,
and it really, you know, it holds up.
And so, you know, similarly, we know from quantum physics
that you have certain conservation laws
that if you have two particles that were associated
with one another, they say two electrons,
and one has a spin that goes up
and the other has a spin that goes down,
that no matter how far apart they are,
if you switch the spin on one of them
to the opposite direction, that other particle
has to instantaneously switch as well,
because they're really still connected.
I mean, that's what it's telling us.
And I think they're still connected by other dimensions.
You know, that's-
Like a field.
I think, yeah, I think that the spookiness
of entanglement goes away once you realize
that things that we think are separate
in this very limited view of reality,
they're really not separate.
Similarly, you know, things that, you know,
we think of as being solid, we know are not solid
based on how much space there is in an atom.
Yeah, I mean, that's, you know, there's,
I think it was Einstein that said,
the only reason we have time is so that everything
doesn't happen all at once.
Yeah, exactly.
And that's really, that is, is it's a mental construct.
Yeah, it's a human interface.
Yeah, exactly.
And so that's so much of what we're talking about here is,
you know, is the human interface.
I mean, that's what drew me to neuropsychiatry
because what it did was it put me in a position
where I could have knowledge of the brain
and at the same time, spend hours talking with people
who would describe what their reality was to me,
what their experience actually was.
I mean, talking with people who are diagnosed
as schizophrenic is like talking to somebody
who's currently in a dream.
Wow.
But the difference is that it's a dream
they totally believe.
Right, yeah, why wouldn't they?
Yeah, and so then the funny thing is,
is that when you see these people that come in your office
that are diagnosed schizophrenic,
and they come in with proof of their reality,
and you're like, okay. Wow, wow.
You have to think of that.
Well, what does that say?
Is it that we're labeling people
as having schizophrenia or psychosis
who just happened to for whatever reason
be having these experiences more
but it's not that their reality
is any less real than our reality.
I mean, is that what that says?
I mean, these are the kind of questions
that I think that we need to ask ourselves,
but at the same time, there's some realities
people could be living in
that don't have good survival value.
And so then it's fine if they're a shaman in a cave
or somebody who's a guru on a mountain,
having everybody take care of all your basic needs
so that you can be spending that much time
in an alternative reality
that might contain information for us that's valuable,
which is a lot of indigenous cultures,
they valued these kinds of people.
What we did was we just automatically label everybody
as insane as they are,
as insane reports those experiences.
So I think that there can be survival value
in not ever having those experiences,
because you can always be on task.
So where you run into some problems
is when people are a blend,
where they have those experiences
and yet they're in order to have any kind of life
in our society,
we also expect them to be operating
from a more embodied perspective than they're capable of.
Right.
Yeah, I mean, that's one of the,
I think more tragic sides of this phenomenon as well
is that these individuals are so gifted
and we have so much to learn from them.
But I think with the help of people like yourselves
and people like Kai and this documentary and your work,
I think we'll be able to shed some light on their value
as human beings in our society.
Because I think for just a long time,
this really, really made me very sad
was looking at how these individuals have been treated,
not only in other countries,
but in even the United States, North America,
historically, and it hasn't been too good.
It's been appalling, it's been appalling.
People were using shock collars on these kids.
They would do the adverse of behavioral stuff
when these kids were in institutions.
And that is a practice that,
I don't think it ended that long ago.
It certainly was still being done
during the course of my career.
Yeah, other countries have been known,
there's been, people have been euthanized for these things.
And it's just an absolute tragedy.
So first of all, it's so good that you're doing this.
And I'm so glad to be able to help spread this message
because it deserves the attention.
Okay, I do want to ask about something
since we're playing thought experiments here.
I'm someone who definitely believes
in non-human intelligence.
And I wanted to ask,
because you touched on this
a little bit at the beginning of the conversation,
but have you ever seen or heard
of any examples of these children
sort of interacting with something that,
for a lack of a better word, is non-human?
Well, so I haven't personally witnessed it myself.
What I, I've heard accounts,
I've heard accounts that they're evil ones,
and then that they're good ones.
But they're putting it in terms of entities,
which who knows what they are.
And I remember once I was actually somewhere
where I was observing some children
who were really advanced in math,
and they were in this math club,
and they were autistic.
And I looked over at this one little boy's
piece of paper, and he had drawn the head
that looks like a gray with those classic eyes.
And I was just like, oh, that's kind of an interesting thing
for a little six-year-old to be drawing.
So that's the kind of evidence
that this is a possibility that I've seen.
And it's the kind of thing that,
I mean, obviously, we're gonna be wanting to know
what is it that these children are experiencing.
We also wanna know how can we support them best,
because a lot of their experiences
are quite frightening for them.
I mean, I just, in the last couple of days,
I've had a couple of parents who've contacted me
because they're desperate,
because they don't know what to do for their child,
because their child has had precognitions
that have come true that were not good,
and they're having precognitions of things that aren't good.
And so, but the problem is they don't,
it's like, is that gonna happen tomorrow?
Is it gonna happen a month from now?
I mean, what do you do?
You can't lock your father up or your sister,
but you're on house arrest
because you're afraid she's gonna go out the door
and something's gonna happen to her.
And it's like, so there's a lot of different aspects
to all of this that,
my background is both a scientist and as a clinician
and a compassionate human being.
I wanna see all of,
I wanna see so much manifest
so that we have the appropriate kind of support
for these individuals,
whether we're talking about their education
or we're talking about their emotional support,
because if you think about it,
I mean, how would you behave
if you experienced the world that they do?
Yeah, I wouldn't even,
I can't even imagine what it is
that they're experiencing and that's just it.
That's the, I think part of my fascination with it too
is that I want to understand
because I think there is value there
and there is something to appreciate
on a human level from our existence.
There's so much to learn in a world,
I mean, we're at a place in the world
where we're the most disenchanted we've ever been.
And this for me provides real magic.
This is, it's just, it's given me a lot to look forward to,
a lot to be hopeful for, for our species as well.
And I think, you know, I think I agree with you.
I think, yeah, the more eyes, the better.
The more work, the better.
The more help, the better.
Yeah, I can't imagine
what all of those things must be like.
And when you touched on precognition there,
reminds me, I interviewed Graham Nichols.
Not sure if you're familiar with Graham Nichols.
He does a lot of out-of-body experience work.
And, you know, he's worked with Dean Raden
and Rupert Sheldrake.
And he had a verifiable precognition
that happened as well during an out-of-body experience.
He was surrounded by multiple people, five of his friends,
and they wrote down, you know,
he said there was gonna be this explosion
on this street in London, in Soho.
He doesn't know when, but he's like,
he felt like he saw the explosion,
and five days later it occurred exactly where he had said.
And, you know, when I heard something like that,
you know, it begs the question, like,
is that something you can alter?
Is that, is there a reason you're getting this?
Is it, because he, I don't think he would have been there.
So what was really the point of it?
And like, so, I mean, there's, like you said,
so many questions, so much to discover,
so much to learn from, and for someone like you
to be in every single one of those directions,
I mean, that's a lot of responsibility.
That's a lot of work.
Yeah, yeah, believe me.
Yeah, but, you know, to your point, you know,
I just wanted to make the comment
that I became really fascinated by this work
by Phyllis Atwater, and she wrote a book called
Future Memory, and the way that she,
and I talk about this in my book, The ESPNew,
and the way that she describes Future Memory,
it sounds like, it's like she gets a glimpse into the future,
and it just plays like a movie,
and then it collapses down, and she gets these,
you know, visual shifts and different things
before it happens, and it's like she sees a movie,
then it shuts down, and then sometime in the future,
that moment arrives, and she can, like,
she knows exactly what somebody's gonna say, you know?
That she knows exactly what's gonna happen next.
It literally is like having had the movie from the future,
you know, and this is that idea of the block universe
where the past, present, past, all co-exist.
It really is like you've seen something from the future
that it's so vivid, and then the question comes up
when you realize, I've been here before,
can you alter the course of events?
And what she tells in her book is that sometimes you can,
and sometimes you can't, sometimes you're in a situation
where you can actually act on this recognition,
oh, this is where the bus is gonna hit that lady
walking across the street, and you can grab the lady's arm.
Or some things just seem to be part of,
whether it's a sole contract or whatever it is,
some things seem to, that you can't prevent them.
It's like it's in the hard wiring, and, you know,
and so I think that a lot of life is like that,
that we have free will, and yet at the same time,
there's a lot of things that are already, you know,
part of the script of why we're here,
and it can be hard to discern what's what,
but I encourage people to not think
that it's all just locked in stone, and you know,
it's like, okay, you know, I saw that end of the future,
and that means it has to happen,
because I think that maybe it's part of why we get warnings.
Yeah, I mean, that's a great point,
and it would be like sort of us warning ourselves
in the past, but like, you know, it's,
I read this book by Dr. Michael Newton,
The Journey of Souls, and I read a few of his books,
and you know, he mentions as well,
because you mentioned soul contract,
and he does mention something like that as well,
where when these souls are choosing their incarnation
or whatever it is, that they scrub through their lives,
and the further forward they go,
the sort of blurrier it gets
because of the amount of variables
are just sort of increasing the further away you get.
So it's almost like it's a probability factor,
but free will can still sort of impose itself
to a certain extent in the future.
You can see the past probably with a lot more clarity
than you could the future.
Okay, has any of the people you've worked with
demonstrated any ability of PK or telekinesis?
Have you ever seen any of that in person,
or have you ever heard of, maybe anecdotally,
of someone doing something like that?
Because I know they did some tests in the 80s in China
and in Tibet with these children, you know,
but that's so far away, and it's in a time where,
you know, it's kind of nebulous.
Have you ever seen any evidence of that?
Well, so I haven't seen it in person,
but what I have seen is there are at least
two or three different individuals who are not children,
they're adults, but they're on the spectrum
who contacted me a long time ago,
and they have sent me multiple videos of them doing things
that would be considered PK, you know.
So for example, having like pinwheels,
where you have like, you know, maybe three or four
different layers of different pinwheels, okay,
and being able to move some of them this way
and others that way, you know,
through, you know, just making a hand motion like this,
and then you'll see, you know,
and the fact that what's important about it being
multiple pinwheels is that, you know,
if it was just, oh, there's a fan behind her
that I can't see, you know, it's like,
but, you know, if you've got multiple pinwheels,
obviously they should be going in the same direction,
you know, if they're getting hit by something like that.
So, and then, you know, another form that I've seen
in videos again is somebody being outside
and pointing to the sky and having the cloud disperse.
Yeah, cloud bursting.
Yeah, I've seen that on video as well.
Yeah, these are, I mean, just more examples
of amazing things that are left to be discovered
and studied and tested, you know, that's quite exciting
because it does, you know, just the fact that this exists,
that this solubility exists, I mean, it opens up
an immense floodgate and, you know,
I think to that effect, that's probably, you know,
the reason why there's such a big pushback
is that this completely shifts the idea
of materialist science into an entirely new era
of undiscovered, uncharted territory
and that can be daunting.
It, you know, it can be shocking ontologically,
it can be all of those things, but, you know,
what better time than now, I think.
We might as well go for it.
I, 100%, I mean, 100%, I mean, I think we're overdue
for a paradigm shift, really, and I think that my work
is just, you know, the thing that's just kinda
potentially push it over, you know,
but it's been there waiting to be tipped over, you know.
But what's interesting is it's kind of,
it's almost like the, you know, the iceberg effect
where, you know, the iceberg, the part of the iceberg
you don't see underwater is melting, okay,
so you can be like, you can be in a, you know,
Kodiak, you know, right near this iceberg, you know,
and then all of a sudden the thing decides to flip on you,
you know, that's a big thing to flip, you know,
it's not like a slow little thing like this,
it just goes, and overnight, totally different.
Yeah, I expect something like that to happen very soon.
I'll end with one final question here,
and, you know, feel free to answer this
in any way you see fit, but I had to ask,
have you seen any interest from intelligence agencies
when it comes to your work,
especially in this particular field?
Well, first of all, I've always been self-funding,
and so I've never taken any money
from any of the, you know, three-letter agencies,
and I've been, but the reality is,
the reality is, I've been too public about this work
in scientific conferences
where I know there's a high intelligence,
I mean, just by definition, okay, I mean,
if you go to a parapsychological association,
you tell me you don't think there's anybody
that, you know, reports back to intelligence
at what they learned?
I mean, you know, it's, I'd be naive to think
that that wasn't the case,
and so, yeah, you know,
I think that they're interested in my work,
I mean, there's, but I haven't anybody, you know,
come to me and, you know, offer me a position like that,
I mean, I've been working, yeah, I've been wanting to,
one of the things, I have somebody who's interested
in funding my research who says that one of the things
that's the problem with being funded
by the three-letter agencies is that things remain
classified and you have no control over it,
and so he wants to see private investors step up
to the plate to fund research
that then becomes the public's property, you know,
it's kind of the, because that's been part of the problem
is that, you know, a lot of this stuff still remains,
a lot of the stuff still remains classified.
Still secret.
And so, but, you know, the reality is,
is that public perception has not diminished
in terms of its beliefs of this, if anything, you know,
it's grown.
It's increased, yeah.
Do you ever feel sort of apprehensive
about these agencies approaching these children perhaps,
like in the future?
As someone who follows a lot of this stuff,
and I've looked at all the Stargate stuff
and all the, you know, Grill Flame, and it goes back,
and MKUltra and all these things,
but do you ever, are you ever weary of that fact
or cognizant of that fact that, you know,
they might be approached one day?
Because I feel like that would be of great interest
to a lot of these agencies.
Well, I mean, one of the things to say is that
none of us want, we're very protective of these children.
None of us want to see them get exploited.
We really don't.
What we want is for them to have opportunities
to get an education and make the contributions
they want to in the world.
And rather turning them into, you know,
psychic spies or this or that, you know,
what they want to do is help solve a lot of the big questions
that we have that have to do with saving the planet,
you know, and, you know, they're very interested
in making the world a better place.
And I think that that's a beautiful mission
that we need to protect as much as we're protecting them.
Well said.
Yeah, I think that's a perfect way to end it.
You know, it completely sort of exemplifies
their mission statement and who they are.
I think, you know, you look at these children
and even these adults and the one thing you can tell
for sure is that they're all pure of heart.
And I think that is the biggest gift that they have,
you know, is showing us that amount of compassion,
not only for each other, but for this earth.
So a beautiful message.
Thank you so much, Dr. Powell.
You've been just an absolute delight.
I enjoyed picking your brain,
so thank you for letting me do that.
You're very welcome.
Thank you.
So there you have it, folks.
That is my interview with Dr. Diane Hennessey Powell
on telepathy and her work therein.
Just a fascinating human being.
And honestly, I commend her for her work
because it has to be so challenging
to not only get past the hurdles of communication
with a lot of these people,
but just even hearing their stories,
you know, listening to the telepathy tapes
was such an emotional rollercoaster for myself
that I couldn't imagine being subjected to that
on a daily basis.
It definitely takes a strong person to, you know,
be exposed to this type of stuff on a daily basis.
Folks, I would love to hear your thoughts on all of this.
What in this interview was the most interesting thing
that you took away from this?
Please comment below.
If you guys wanna see more content from Area 52,
more episodes of debrief, more uncut interviews,
more extra vlogs and all the other amazing things
that we have to offer,
check out our Patreon or our memberships.
You can join by clicking the join button below
or head over to patreon.com slash area52investigations.
You'll be brought into a secret little club on our Discord
where we have movie nights, book clubs, discussions,
future investigations, and so much more.
I'm really, really, really grateful
for all of your support.
I couldn't be here without you.
So thank you so much for making this possible.
Oh, by the way,
this is because of you.
Thank you for 100,000 subscribers on YouTube.
This made my day.
You guys are awesome.
I appreciate you so much.
Couldn't have done this without you.
This is my acceptance speech, by the way.
I didn't practice.
I didn't write anything down.
Yeah, okay, I'll leave it at that.
Happy holidays, everybody.
Merry Christmas and all that stuff.
And we'll see you on the next video.
Peace.