15 years ago I was in Albuquerque and we weren't on a road and we experienced something that night.
We rolled on the windows and we look out and we just see like this, I mean, UFO.
Sort of coming towards us and then it changed direction and then it changed again the direction and it skipped.
It disappeared.
Because this is also something mentioned by Bob Lazar.
And you had an opportunity to meet Bob. Did you bring this up to him?
I did.
Fast forward a few years and I'm in Washington so I'm like, you know what, I'm going to ask a big question.
So I told the lady in front of me and as I'm talking to her, the entire table stopped talking.
All the attention turned on me.
You know, I just want to ask you, is there something out there?
And she told me, you're not crazy, there is something out there.
I was like, boom, like, oh my God.
During COVID, after I retired, I decided to go on a journey.
I decided to do ayahuasca.
When it started, I start leaving my body, I start levitating and I'm not leaving my body going up like this.
I'm leaving it going up like this, looking down.
You're seeing yourself?
Yeah, I even see my friend.
He was texting someone.
I told him, I said, you were texting this person.
He said, how did you know?
I went over your shoulder and I saw it.
And I'm not alone.
There's something that sort of lifts me up.
And can I use, I'm going to draw it to you.
No eyes, no mouth.
And it was communicating with me, you know, who are you?
And it says, I'm you and everybody at the same time.
And the air you breathe and the water you drink.
I know why you're here.
You're curious to know about what is consciousness.
And I'm going to show it to you.
And then I see the map, the planet, the solar system.
It's like I'm going out.
Like I zoom out, you know, from where I was.
And I see the entire, the galaxies, the universe, the different universe, the different dimension.
The point that at one point I'm like, it's too much.
I can't take it anymore.
1994, I was probably about six years old.
And I remember my big sister running outside from inside our house.
I follow her out into the street.
We get out into the street.
The neighbors are out looking up at the sky.
Four or five houses down.
There's a spinning disc with spinning lights all around it.
And a spotlight coming down from the center.
It must have been like, I don't know, 40 feet above this house.
That was like five houses down from us.
Don't remember anybody talking about it afterwards.
The memory just ends right there.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome back.
Today we are joined by an amazing guest, Georges St. Pierre.
Georges, thank you so much for doing this.
This is unexpected, I think, to a lot of the viewers.
They're like, what is Georges St. Pierre doing on this podcast?
I'm happy to be here.
Thank you for having me a few weeks ago with Lou Elizondo.
I'm really happy that you allowed me to come here and have a conversation with him.
Yeah, it was incredible.
Obviously the things that are spoken about off-camera often,
we get into some deeper stuff.
More things that are speculative.
You can't really say it on camera because it's not sure.
But those are the fun conversations.
Yeah, it's a lot of stuff sometimes that when you talk about it,
a lot of people will roll their eyes back and it will touch your credibility.
But I'm passionate about UAPs and it's a subject that I'm very interested in.
When I found out that Lou Elizondo came here, I was like,
man, he's one of the guys that I always wanted to meet.
To have the opportunity to do it, to have a conversation with this guy, it was amazing.
When that happened, just the weekend before, I was in Washington.
That's right.
I had an opportunity to meet with some high-ranked military in the United States
because it was during the inauguration weekend.
I was not there really for the inauguration.
I was there because with some other guy of the UFC, John Jones was there, Bo Nicole.
Connor.
Yeah, exactly.
A lot of guys were there.
A lot of the professional athletes were there.
So I had an opportunity to go and I took it because I had the chance to meet different people.
It was a great opportunity.
I would have been a fool to not take it.
I would have taken it.
I think most people take that opportunity.
Of course.
I mean, it's a chance of a lifetime, an opportunity of a lifetime.
So I met a lot of people.
But of all the celebrities that I've met that weekend, I met Zuckerberg.
I met a lot of celebrities.
But for me, the thrill of my weekend, it was to be able to sit down with some of the high-ranked military,
some of the guys that, you know, when you want to talk about UAP's secret program and stuff like that,
these are the guys that knows the answers and had amazing conversation.
And still to this day, you know, a lot of these guys I'm friends with.
We text each other and I made some great friends there.
And it was just an amazing weekend.
Wow.
So wait, are you okay saying how did you get into that?
Like what happened there during those interactions?
Because, you know, it's weird to go out to someone and be like, so what about the UFOs?
How did that conversation start?
Well, so the way it started is the first dinner, it was a Friday night.
The first day that I arrived in Washington, I had a dinner at night.
And I get introduced to these guys with Tim Kennedy.
Tim Kennedy, Tim Kennedy is a former USC fighter.
Green Beret.
And he's the guy that on the field, you know, like he's like a cowboy, you know,
he's the one who do the dirty job on the field.
And he introduced me to a lot of these guys and to Sarah Averrano.
I get introduced to a lot of the people in different branch of the military there.
And we had dinner and a lot of the military people are big fans of mixed martial arts.
So they knew who I was.
I mean, to be fair, a lot of people know who you are, not just in the military.
But that's one of the reasons why I was able to get in touch with these people.
So the first dinner that we had, it was like about maybe 12, 15 people around the table.
And, you know, we didn't know each other.
You know, some of these guys, I mean, actually, except from Tim that I know for a few years,
all the other people around the table I had never met before.
And we all introduce each other, you know, like, and I didn't realize with who I was sitting until
at one point during the dinner, I was thinking, I was like, you know what, if I want to ask the question,
that's the time to do it, because I might never ever had another opportunity in my life to ask this question.
Maybe I'm going to look like a fool.
And they all going to make fun of me thinking, oh, I'm brain damaged or whatever.
Or maybe they're going to tell me what they are allowed to tell me.
So everybody was talking to the people next to them because it was a big table.
At one point, I was like, you know what, I had a conversation with different people.
But I talked to one of the person that was in front of me.
I asked her, she was a lady, and I asked her, I said, I always wanted to ask you this question.
I, you know, one day I told her one of the adventure that I had that one day and I was in a few years ago
before my fight with Matt Serra.
It's about 15 years ago, I was in Albuquerque and I was in a car and I was with Mike Van Arsdel,
who's a former UFC fighter, Rashad Evans, Ali Abdelaziz, who's a Khabib and Islam Makachev manager.
He was a training partner of mine and another guy named Alejandro.
He's a Mexican, but I can't remember.
I don't know what he became. I lost contact with him.
And Ali, Alejandro and I were in the backseat.
Mike Van Arsdel was driving, Rashad Evans was on the passenger seat.
And we weren't on the road and we saw something.
We experienced something that night that all five of us, like, it's undeniable.
Like something, we saw something like, and...
What did you see? Was it like lights in the sky or was it...
Yeah, it was a light sort of coming towards us.
And when it happened, I had an impression and I don't have the...
It's not a certainty, but I was under the impression that sort of the time sort of stopped.
Not the car, but the car kept rolling.
But like, you know, when you get so intensely...
Like you're mesmerized.
Yeah, yeah, like all of us were like...
We only had focus on that thing.
So it came towards us and then it changed direction.
And then it changed again the direction and it skipped.
It disappeared.
And for that brief moment, it's sort of like...
Everything else around us didn't matter.
It was only this.
We were like...
All of us, like silence and we saw this thing.
And after that, when it skipped and it disappeared, all of us were like,
Oh my God, what is this?
And the crazy thing about it is the way I saw it and the way my friend saw it,
it was different because there is no point of reference.
I saw something that there was no wings.
Like it was no noise, but we're inside of a car.
But I remember seeing an interview of I think it was Rashad or Ali Abdelaziz
talking about that thing.
Around 2010, I'm in Elk Creek, New Mexico.
And I'm with GSP, Ali Abdelaziz, who's now like the manager of mostly a lot of UFC fighters.
And we're right on the highway.
The traffic is starting to slow down.
And it like slows down to like almost a crawl.
And we're like, why is everybody stopping?
Why is everybody stopping?
And then we start to look and see where everybody's looking.
And then we roll down the windows and we look out and we just see like this,
I mean, UFO because of the way it was moving.
It just didn't seem...
I mean, it was that typical UFO movement where it was like moving
and then it like would stop and like define gravity for a bit.
It just stayed there for a second.
And, you know, the light pattern was weird as well, too.
And as everybody's sitting there watching it, it then just like shot off.
And the time that it lasts and it didn't correspond to exactly what I saw.
So I was thinking if I talk about it perfectly, I'm going to look like a liar
because they don't describe the same thing.
They all have their different description of what they've seen.
I can't remember.
I think it was one of them said it was like almost a minute.
And for me, it was only maybe 10, 15 seconds, if I remember.
So we all have a different experience from that moment.
So fast forward a few years.
I'm in Washington.
So I'm like, you know what?
I'm going to ask a big question.
So I told the lady in front of me, and as I'm talking to her,
the entire table stopped talking.
All the attention turned on me.
So I told her what I saw.
And I ask her, I say, you know, I just want to ask you, am I crazy?
Or did we all collectively became crazy for a few seconds
and saw something like an illusion?
Or is there something out there that are not us?
And she told me, you're not crazy.
There is something out there.
I was like, boom!
Like, oh my God.
And these are the people that knows.
Because that's what they do.
If someone would know, it's those guys.
What was the atmosphere after that?
Man, I'm not going to lie.
Since that weekend, I mean, now I sleep good.
But the next few days after that weekend, it got me thinking so much
I had a hard time sleeping at night.
Because these are the sort of questions that keep me up at night.
And I talked to a lot of these guys.
I asked them a lot of questions.
And man, this is insane.
It is so crazy that I would be very reluctant publicly.
And it's not me.
A lot of them, what they told me and a lot of stuff that I've read
are like seen as conspiracy theory.
But what they told me fit what I've read.
And I'm like, that can't be true.
But I would be very reluctant to go publicly
and talk about what I've read and what they told me.
Because it will attack my credibility.
People will roll their eyes.
Like, GSP just lost his mind.
He's brain damaged.
This is no way.
But I mean, it's just crazy.
And I know you dive deep into this stuff.
So you can understand a little bit.
This is pretty insane.
It is.
And it's one of those things that when you say it out loud,
you're like, God, that sounds just absolutely made up.
It sounds like science fiction.
But the truth I've found in my research
is often much stranger than fiction.
And that's something that the more I look into it,
the more that's becoming true.
And one of the things is, first of all,
the fact that you're even just talking about this
and being open about it, I think is really healthy.
Like, maybe 10 years ago, this would have been considered
a really touchy podcast to do.
But I think in today's landscape,
isn't that surprising to a lot of people.
They're kind of like, well, it's good.
It's good that more people are understanding.
Because I do believe that in 10 years' time,
maybe even less, that if you don't believe
that there's something going on,
you're the conspiracy theorist.
I think that more people are kind of coming around
to this idea that, OK, all right, we're being visited,
or they're already here or something.
Yeah.
And another thing that I think I consider
this very important is, you know,
because of what's going on in the world,
there's a lot of wars, there's a lot.
And I feel that if we found out that we're not alone,
it will kind of unite us.
We will stop fighting over some stupid differences.
You know what I mean?
We'll get together better.
And there's a lot of things that could change
the entire world, the energy thing.
You know, like if this thing is true,
this technology is true,
this can be used for the benefits of mankind.
You know what I mean?
And, man, it can change the world.
And for me, I think it would be important to have
maybe not a full disclosure on this thing,
but at least more disclosure on the matter,
because it will be beneficial to the world.
Yeah, great point.
You know, something you just said there, too,
is not full disclosure, and I agree with that.
I think most people who are familiar enough with the topic
also agree with that, that there needs to be...
We just need to get it out of the way that this is real.
Like, just that.
Let's just get past that barrier right now,
because we're so slowly approaching it,
and what's happening is that more things are coming out
faster than we're able to disclose it, right?
And so there needs to be like...
We need to just bridge that gap and say,
hey, these things are real.
This is happening. We are being visited.
We're not alone. Start there.
You know, Chris, most people,
like if you talk to most people,
are not even aware that, you know, you say UAPs,
there's things that flies, and not only flies,
that goes under the water,
that are picked up by a very sensitive military instrument,
and they don't know what it is.
I mean, it's been disclosed.
It's been declassified since, I think, 2017.
It was in an article in the New York Post,
but most people are not aware of that.
Most people still think it's not true.
Like, I mean, you can research it. It's true.
It's been out...
The cat is out of the box, so to speak.
But most people are not aware of it.
And I don't understand why the media don't talk more about it.
I mean, it's one of the...
I mean, are we alone? Are we...
Like, even if we don't have the evidence
to really know if we're alone or not,
but this is very important.
I mean, you have a certain object
that flies over a sensitive military installation
and are picked up by an instrument.
I mean, man, it's something to talk about,
and nobody talks about it.
I'm like, you have to dig in to find out about it.
Yeah, that's true.
It's crazy to me. It's important.
Very important. It's arguably...
The implication of it. It's huge.
Yeah, the most important thing.
And this is interesting because it also ties into
a lot of the other stuff that you're interested in
and ancient civilizations,
this sort of idea of maybe
this cyclical civilization thing happening, perhaps,
or our lost technology that we might have had,
because you've been traveling the world recently
doing side quests, which is pretty cool.
You did your homework. You know.
You did the main quest,
greatest pound-for-pound fighter, UFC champion.
You've done all these amazing things.
And I think it's kind of cool to see what you're doing now
because you're like, man, I did all this stuff.
Now what? What next?
And now you're looking deeper.
Now you're like, well, what's the meaning?
Where do we come from? What's happening?
And you're going to places like Baalbek, Egypt,
and all these amazing places.
So what kind of fuels that quest?
Knowledge.
And I know that a lot of these archeological sites,
it's still an enigma.
They have a rough idea of when it was built
and how it was built,
but there's a lot of mystery surrounding it.
And if someone says that they know everything,
that's not true.
And the weekend I had in Washington, too,
one thing they confirmed to me is that,
and I knew that before, but they just told me that
is that a lot of the ancient texts,
a lot of the religious texts that we read
and a lot of the ancient texts that talks about
angelic beings flying chariot and stuff like that
are probably account of...
UAPs, UFOs.
UAPs and things that they...
But they didn't say flying saucer or a spaceship
because it was outside of their vocabulary.
It was outside of their frame of reference.
So the way they describe it,
it was the way they use word that they knew to describe it.
Yeah, chariots of fire, shields, drums.
A lot of people said drums.
Angelic beings and things like that.
There was one actually that said earthenware
was the...
And earthenware is literally a plate.
So when you think of saucer,
their word was earthenware.
So like flying earthenware, you're like,
well, that's a flying saucer.
And Jacques Vallee, are you familiar with Jacques Vallee?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, he's just like the goat when it comes to
looking at that ancient stuff
because he looks in weird, obscure references
like fairies and goblins or whatever it is.
And he'll find stories where there's missing time,
where people have been taken, transported,
and they're describing, like you said,
a lot of the same things,
but they just didn't have the vocabulary.
Exactly.
It's fascinating to me
because a lot of it is subject to interpretation.
So it's hard to differentiate what is it.
You know what I mean?
In a lot of religious texts, for example,
it's subject to interpretation.
And that's one of the reasons why there is,
for example, in Christianity,
there are the Catholic, the Protestant, the Adventist,
because they have a different interpretation of what it is.
And you can make a case for a lot of these ancient texts
to be an account of something.
Close encounter.
Yeah, exactly, exactly.
That could be an interpretation as well.
I think so.
And I think that's a valid thing
and that we're discovering that more and more.
You know, you have like, what was it,
Charities of the Gods or whatever.
And Diana Pasolka as well puts out a lot of work.
She's a theologian or studies theology
and has found that UFO is kind of like the new religion
where we're following the same symptoms
as a new religious coming.
Like when Christianity was coming to be,
it was very rebellious.
The Romans were pushing against it.
You would get killed for following the word of Christ
until the revolution was so big that it became the thing.
And that revolution, when that happened,
there was a lot of sightings.
There was a lot of angels coming down with messages,
prophetic images, all of these things.
And if you look at now, that's kind of happening as well.
We have some characters out there
that are also getting these images
or that are getting these sightings on command.
And so yeah, if you were to take these texts
and bring them back 2,000 years,
they would almost be identical.
And so yeah, it does leave you questioning,
is UFO and ufology and is this the new religion?
Are aliens the new angels,
not just are aliens the old angels?
Are we going to worship aliens?
That's right, because before they used to believe
in spirit of the forest, whatever it is.
Now they became maybe religion, now it was gods,
and now not everyone,
but a lot of people don't believe so much in religion anymore.
So if they try to make sense of it,
they will say it's maybe coming from another planet.
We don't know what is the truth.
It's crazy, but there's certainly something going on.
There's certainly a phenomenon that it's hard to explain.
Yeah, and for anyone who hasn't had a sighting,
I've had some multiple sightings in my life
that I can't explain.
I can't tell you for sure if they were UFOs or extraterrestrials,
but I can tell you for me at the time,
it felt like it was, so that feeling I know,
I understand that feeling,
and when you experience something,
it kind of shakes your foundation.
That's the starting point where you're like,
okay, hold on, you didn't see what I saw,
you didn't feel what I felt, and that's very personal.
From what I saw, I'm easy to be discredited
because I'm not an astrophysicist,
and a lot of people will say,
oh yeah, you don't have the knowledge, the credibility,
the competency to say that what you saw
was an unidentified flying object
because maybe it was Venus, or I don't know,
a swam guest, or an asteroid that bounced back,
or a satellite that followed.
I mean, I've seen something that changed direction,
and if it's Venus or something that could be explained,
I will be very, very, very, very surprised,
and the fact that all of us saw it in a different way
was like, man, I don't know what to make of it.
Have you ever spoken to any of them afterwards about it?
Oh yeah, absolutely, all the time.
We've talked about it, and a lot of them,
I'm sure they're like me,
they're a little bit shy to talk about it,
but I think it's important.
I think it could attack our credibility a little bit,
but it is important because I'm sure there's a lot of people
that have seen stuff that are shy to talk about it
because they're going to be seen as crazy,
especially when you spend a lot of your life
in a full-contact sport.
A lot of people will say, oh, he's brain damaged,
but how do you explain that the five of us see something?
I mean, collectively, it's kind of crazy.
Yeah, absolutely,
and I don't think that that's the case so much anymore.
I think maybe, again, like 10 years ago, prior to 2017,
I think that that might have been the case where it's like,
oh, who are these guys? They're just crazy.
They're conspiracy theorists,
but I think now we're in a really new landscape
where talking about it isn't so...
Sure, there are some people,
but I really do think that most of the people that matter
in this subject and who are trying to push this forward,
I mean, we're all in agreement here that something's going on,
and what you described, too,
which is really interesting, the skipping part.
I want to talk about that for a second
because this is also something mentioned by Bob Lazar,
and you had an opportunity to meet Bob.
Yeah.
Did you bring this up to him?
I did.
I met Bob, and for people who are not aware,
Bob claims that he worked on a secret project in Area 51
in a place called S4, in a secret base,
and he worked on trying to back engineer an object
that is not from this world.
That's his claim, and I've talked to him.
I don't have any certainty,
but I believe that he believes that he tells me the truth.
That's what I believe.
Same as Louis Lisando.
You know, I'm not perfect.
I've been fooled before, but when I talk to them,
I trust them that what they're saying to me
is what they believe to be true.
You got a good read.
Yes, and Bob was explaining to me then,
and he used to describe these flying disks a long time ago,
like more than maybe almost 40 years.
It's been like when he came out.
30, 35.
Almost 40 years.
And the way he used to describe them, if I may,
let's say it's a disk, he was describing them
when they fly locally, they go like this,
but when they have to whatever, return from where they're from,
they point their belly, and the reason why they skip
is because of the distortion and space and time.
So that's from our perspective.
We've seen the object skipping,
but from maybe perhaps their perspective inside,
they don't skip, maybe they go.
So I don't know because I never experienced it
being inside these things, but that's how he explained it.
And I found it fascinating.
Then when I talked to him, he explained that to me,
and it made more sense.
And I've always been very curious about also consciousness.
What is consciousness?
Because we cannot even define what is consciousness.
Religious people will say, oh, it's your soul.
Scientists who are atheists will say,
oh, it's the chemistry of your brain, you know,
and the argument that will be like,
oh, you say you're a good or a bad person,
but let's say you get in a car crash, boom,
and you wake up from a coma,
maybe you won't be the same person anymore.
So that's their argument.
They say, oh, that because your brain,
the chemistry of your brain is affected,
so we're, you know, in a way we're all, there's no soul.
It's only matter. It's only material.
And that's one of the questions that keeps me up at night.
Are we, you know, do we have sort of a soul
or are we only material?
Are we more than our physical body?
And one guy that made me change my mind on it is,
a friend of mine is Lex Friedman.
He had a podcast.
And he works in AI, robotic.
And one day I asked him, I said,
because I used to believe about determinism.
I thought that there's no,
I used to think that there's no such thing as free will,
that everything is, you know, come from a cause, the causality.
We have the illusion of free will,
but everything is predetermined.
And by definition, if there's a cause,
there's no free will because a free will is something
you do spontaneously without cause.
So I asked Lex, because if someone knows it's him,
he works with robot.
And, you know, I asked him, I say,
do you believe in free will or determinism?
And he said something to me that changed my way of thinking
because he's so smart and educated.
You know, when you talk to guys like him or, you know,
even Elon Musk, I had a chance to talk to him.
I was like, these guys, they make me think for freaking months
and years after I've talked to them.
I have to process what they tell me.
And he says, George, we don't even know what is consciousness.
Therefore, we cannot know if there's free will
or determinism or both.
We don't know.
So even him, he doesn't, you know, he doesn't know.
That's the right answer.
You know what I mean?
When you don't know until you don't know,
you have to remain like this.
So I've always been fascinated about that.
And that's why during COVID, after I retired,
I decided to go on a journey.
I decided to do ayahuasca.
And I never talked about it because as an athlete,
I was always anti-drugs.
Because for me, in martial arts, one of the values is respect.
And, you know, if you're respectful, you're going to fight fear.
You're not going to use performance-enhancing drugs.
So I never wanted to use drugs.
I waited after I retired to do that experience,
but I always wanted to do it because I'm very curious about consciousness.
You know, we all have dreams sometimes that we can remember,
but what does it mean?
Because we're sleeping and we have dreams that seem so real.
So what it is?
Like, is it only imagination, material from our brain,
like circuitry, or there's really something?
So I decided to do an adventure, ayahuasca.
Ayahuasca is psychedelic, very strong psychedelic.
Extremely strong, yeah.
And I never take drugs.
I never snore cocaine or did anything else.
I've tried marijuana before, but it's not really my thing.
It makes me paranoid.
I've drank, but I never did that.
So I start from zero to a hundred kilometers per hour.
And I got in touch with this guy because for a reason,
I'm not allowed to say who it is and where it is.
But so one night I decided to do that.
And because of my name, I don't want to be, you know,
when I did it, I was kind of scared.
I decided to bring a friend of mine who was my bodyguard.
His name is Eddie.
He's a friend of mine.
And I decided to bring him with me alone just in case something happened
because people will laugh at it, but I'm afraid I've never done drugs before.
I told him if something happened, bring me to the hospital right away.
Best thing to do probably.
Yeah.
So I was alone when I did it.
I was with him and the shaman and one of his apprentice.
And I had a friend with me that I've done ayahuasca before that did it with me.
That's it.
Because normally when you do that, you have a room with maybe six, eight people.
But I didn't want to do because I wanted to be private.
So when I first started, I took it to a cup and it's made of,
I think it's made of a leaf and it's a mixture of natural ingredients
that come from the Amazon and it had been boiled.
So you take it and what I did is I took it and I lay down on a mat
and I'm in the basement of a house.
And I didn't do it in South America.
I did it here.
So when it started after a few minutes, I start leaving my body.
I start levitating and going towards the ceiling.
And when that happened, I felt like I sort of lost control.
So I kind of resisted and I came back into myself.
And for the next maybe 20, 30 minutes, nothing happened.
And then I started thinking, I was like, shit, I might have ruined my entire adventure.
And it made me sad a little bit.
Then the shaman came to see me.
He's like, are you okay, George?
I explained to him like, yeah, I resisted.
I left my body, but I kind of resisted because I didn't like the sensation of losing control.
And he looked at me, he's like, George, you have to let yourself go.
And for me, it's hard.
It's something I've never done.
I always like to be in control because my background in mixed martial art,
you have to be in control and control all the data in order to maximize your chance of winning in a fight.
But now I have to let go, to rely on something that I've never done and let it go.
So he says to me, he's like, let it go.
I'm like, okay, can I take some more?
He's like, you can take more as long as you feel good.
And I see that you're good.
I'm like, all right.
So I take another cup and I lay down again.
And then I left the...
I'm not leaving my body going up like this.
I'm leaving it going up like this, looking down.
You're seeing yourself?
Yeah.
I'm seeing myself, but I'm seeing myself and I'm still aware.
I'm still aware that I'm in the bed.
It's like I'm in two places in the same time and I'm not alone.
There's something that sort of lift me up.
And can I use...
I'm going to draw it to you so you can...
So this thing that I see appears to me under this shape.
It's called a keyhole shape, they call it.
Whoa.
No eyes, no mouth, like this shape.
What color?
Was it black?
Was it see-through?
It was no color.
It was just translucent.
It's not like I could see it with my eyes.
I was seeing it inside my head.
Right, you were perceiving it.
And it was communicating with me.
Not like I'm talking to...
Hi, how are you?
Like in my head.
Like a airdrop.
And everything it was thinking I was receiving
and everything I was...
He was thinking I was receiving.
So he was like a connection, you know?
And as I'm going up, I see myself.
I even see my friend.
He was texting someone.
And I told him, I'm like, I know you were...
After the adventure, I told him, I said, you were texting this person.
He said, how did you know?
I went over your shoulder and I saw it.
And I'm lifting, I'm lifting, I'm lifting.
And I go through the ceiling, I see the house and I'm like...
And to the opposite of what happened a few minutes before,
the first time when I didn't want to lose control,
now I feel very confident because this thing is carrying me
and I feel like the best feeling in the world.
Safe.
Safe, love, successful, confident.
Like I feel like I'm in the up top emotionally.
Like I feel like I'm like the best feeling in the world.
Not physically high, but mentally, man, feel like in perfect harmony.
And as I'm going up, I'm like, who are you?
You know, who are you?
And it says, I'm you and everybody at the same time.
I'm the air you breathe and the water you drink.
And it didn't say it through my mind.
And as I'm going up, I see the town where I am.
I see the planet.
Then it made me understand that it says to me like,
I know why you're here.
You're curious to know about what is consciousness.
And I'm going to show it to you.
I'm going to show you what is consciousness.
And then I see the map, the planet, the solar system.
It's like I'm going out.
Like I zoom out from where I was.
And I see the entire thing.
I see the galaxies, the universe, the different universe, the different dimension.
To the point that at one point I'm like, I can't explain it.
It's too much.
Okay, it's too much.
I can't take it anymore.
It's like, please, I don't want to know more.
I just can't take it.
And it was very weird.
I'm the one who sort of tell him.
And the whole time this thing is with me, sort of guiding me.
And I'm like, because I'm in a great, I'm in a feeling of harmony.
And I'm telling it, I'm like, is it only for this adventure?
Will you leave me after this?
Or he's like, no, I'm going to be always with you.
And when things doesn't go well, close your eyes and remember me.
I was always going to be there even after this adventure ends.
I'm always there with you.
And I'm like, okay.
And then it sort of says to me, it's like, now that you know what you came for,
I would like to share something with you.
There is a lot of time that you do things that you don't realize that you hurt people.
And I'm like, okay.
And it's like, I'm going to show you things.
But after you've seen it, it's up to you to make the effort to change.
Because I cannot make the effort for you.
You have to make the effort if you want to change and become better.
I'm like, okay.
And then it start going into some of my past.
Your memories.
On my memory.
But not like memory, like I was reliving certain memory that I push so deep inside of me,
like I didn't want to remember.
And stuff from my childhood, stuff that are so personal that even I cannot talk about.
But stuff also that I've done, certain things that I've done to people,
like stuff that have been done to me, but also stuff that I've said, I've done,
that I didn't realize at the time how much I hurt certain people.
And I didn't mean to hurt them, but it made me,
this thing made me sort of go through the perspective of the person that I was hurting
and live the emotion of that person live when I did that.
And I lived it and now I understand.
And I, shit, I really hurt that person when I did this.
And like a mirror, like if I would have done it to myself.
And I felt the emotion running through.
And now I realize, I'm like, shit, I feel bad.
I've done this and I didn't even realize that I hurt.
I hurt that person.
And you're so caught up with what you do.
You only focus on, for me when I was young, the most important thing was
to be the strongest man in the world.
And all my focus was on that.
Everything I did was about to be champion.
And that's what it was.
The other thing around, I was seeing it not only as a distraction,
because I had great, great times.
A lot of the people I've met, I really genuinely love those certain people
and I love them.
But because my focus was not on prioritizing them
and more prioritizing my goal, I hurt them in the process.
And I didn't not realize that.
And this adventure made me realize that.
And man, it was crazy.
And a lot of things, that's just one example, but a lot of things like this,
I relive through my mind.
It made me realize that sometimes I've said stuff in other situations
to other people and I hurt them.
It made me very sensitive about stuff that I've done.
And I was like, shit, I really did that.
I didn't realize at that time how much I hurt certain people.
And now I do.
And even after my adventure was done,
I call certain people and I apologize to them.
I say, sorry, I know I did this, I did that.
Hey, man, I did that.
You know, like certain people that I noticed that I hurt.
And I thought they would have found it weird that I called them.
But a lot of them, they were like, oh, they're like, oh, thank you very much.
I mean, you come a long way and I appreciate you.
You realize and it means a lot.
And I sort of made peace.
I made peace with it and it felt great.
And that was one part of the inventory.
And at the end, because it lasts about four hours, you know, it's a strong drug.
They call it medicine, but it's really a drug.
And towards the end, this thing again, I always point it out because I want people to see.
It says to me, it's like now, George, I know you hold a lot of grudge, a lot of anger.
You know, you grew up with a lot of anger and you didn't let it out.
It served you for what you did for your fighting.
But now you have to learn how to let it go.
And when I did this adventure, I was always contemplating an opportunity maybe to make a comeback or because I still had that thing inside of me.
So it says to me, it's like now you're going to have to do like a detox and it will manifest physically.
And I'm like, OK, you have to release all the negative emotion and it will manifest physically.
Are you ready? I'm like, yes, I'm ready.
And it says, like, if you need my help, I will always be there.
So I said, OK, and I'm ready.
And then I went to the bathroom and that day before you do ayahuasca, they advise you to not eat, to not eat anything.
You know, if you eat very light and I didn't eat that day, I fasted.
So I go on the bathroom because I start feeling a little bit sort of sick and I have a bucket.
And I told you early on in my adventure, I had the hot the hot top in terms of emotion.
I felt very good. But now, my friend, I dive down deep to the point that I have nothing to live for.
Like, and I'm a very happy person in life.
And but now, man, like nothing to live for.
Like, basically, I want to die.
And I start having very negative thoughts and it manifests physically.
It comes out. I'm on the bathroom in the liquid.
It comes out crying, like, like, like depressed, depressed, you know, like to the point like it's insane and throwing up.
So and I'm sweating like I'm in a sauna.
Like down, cry, sweat, like everything comes out.
And up to the point that I can no longer take it.
And now I'm thinking about this thing.
I'm like, please, I can't take it.
I can't take it. And it comes back to me.
Lift me up like a little bit like I'm drowning and I cannot breathe.
And they lift me up like, take a few in hell.
OK, OK, are you ready to dive back into it, George?
You have to you have to let it go. Let it go.
Like you have to clean it up.
I'm like, OK, I'm ready. I'm ready.
OK, go back in it. And then I cry.
And then when I can no longer take it up, it comes back.
It lift me back up.
OK, take it. Take a break.
Take a break. But we have to go back.
It's almost done. OK, OK, OK.
I'm doing it again. OK, go.
Like a few times.
It lasted for about 20 minutes.
And even my friend was outside.
He knocked in the bathroom.
And the whole time I was conscious that I was in two places at the same time.
I was on the toilet, but I was also somewhere else like doing like a purge.
And he knocked at the bathroom.
He said, George, you OK?
I'm all right, man. I'm all right. Thank you. Thank you.
Things go well. I just need to let it go.
He's like, OK, if something happened, let me know.
We would break the door and we come get you.
And I'm like, no, no, no, I'm OK. I'm OK.
So I was able to talk and drink that adventure to the point that when it was done.
I took a shower. I changed my clothes.
Man, I felt so light.
It was just like a relief.
It felt so good physically and mentally.
And I have no evidence to prove you that.
Yes, I really did lift my body.
I went somewhere outside that the experience that I live in my mind.
Maybe I really did it or maybe I was so freaking high that I think that I did it.
I think I went to people's head and I had like a mirror emotion experience.
I made it all up because I thought I can't tell you.
But I'm under after living the adventure that I lived.
I'm under the impression that a strong impression that there is something to consciousness
is not only measured by materialism.
Now, I used to be septic, like how do you say agnostic, agnostic, agnostic.
But now I lean more towards a believer.
No, no, no, I'm really I'm really convinced that there is something.
And a lot of my friends that are atheists that I told them that they say, oh, you were just so fucking high.
Yeah, maybe, maybe I was.
But it shaped me to my core so much that I think there is something, you know.
And it's and I think it's a beautiful experience.
I don't encourage people to take it because it's a it's a drug and I did it once.
And I don't have the desire to do it again because I love my brain and I don't want to damage it.
But I'm happy I've done it.
I'm very happy I've done it because it's an experience that changes my life.
Wow, George, thank you for sharing that.
No, it's something that I never talk publicly about it.
But it's something that really changes me.
And I'm very happy I've done it.
It's it's it's crazy.
It's it is crazy.
And if some people sometimes they wonder, should I do it or not, you have to to listen to yourself.
Don't force yourself.
If you force yourself, you it's not going to be good.
You need to do it because you if you're ready to do it, you want to let you have to let it go and you have to treat that with respect.
You know, it's a it's a I know it was used heavily by ancient culture in a way to perhaps communicating with something or to get deep inside your own consciousness.
But it's really something that you need to treat with respect.
And it's not a recreational drug.
It is absolutely not.
And it's a it's an experience I've done.
And I'm very happy I've done it.
And yeah, it changes me.
That is really, really profound.
That sounds like, you know, a lot of a lot of people we talk and we talked a little bit before this podcast about, you know, my experience.
And I had a lot of people say, you know, you should after my out of body experiences.
And I had like half a dozen of these where I'd leave my body through meditation.
And, you know, a lot of people were like, you should do ayahuasca or you should do DMT.
And so I did DMT, albeit my experience was nowhere near as like profound as yours.
There was the same element of phasing out of your body and kind of like lifting out.
And I felt a very familiar sense to that.
And so for me, it was very validating because like you, through my experiences, I was changed.
I was also I grew up Catholic.
I became atheist, moved towards agnosticism because I started being like, I don't care.
There's some I don't know. Maybe there's some maybe there isn't.
I don't know.
And then through these experiences of seeing my own self, I'm convinced that I'm more than my physical body.
Yeah.
And like you said, like there's no hard evidence anywhere.
But the hardest evidence, I like I don't need.
I just there's a knowing now that I can't ignore.
There's one thing that is very important to mention that is.
Because sometimes like you read Rene Descartes, he says like, let's say you put a straw in a glass of water, you see the straw bending.
So your senses can fool you.
If they can fool you once, they can fool you twice or forever.
So because of that, for me, it was very important that I was like, how do I know this experience is real after when I'm done?
So I asked this thing, I asked, I asked it, I say, how would I know?
And it says to me, I will give you a gift that only you will know.
And I didn't realize what it was, the gift.
But now I know I used to be scared of height, like crazy scared of height.
I've done stuff in my life that require me to step over my fear, to challenge my fear, like skydiving.
Or, you know, even when I was in Singapore, I did some climbing under a bridge.
I was terrified. I've always been terrified of height.
I know when I change the, you know, when the leaf in your, when in spring when you have to go on top of your house for the gutters, clean the leaf.
I'm terrified of doing it. I freaking hate it.
I'm like, I feel the feeling like I'm about to fall.
Like, even when I go up in a building, I look down, I feel like it shake me to my core.
But now I know since my experience, I don't have that feeling anymore.
Yeah, I swear, I swear it's true. If you, if you eat.
So that's like a personal. Yeah, it's crazy.
Like a personal confirmation that what I live is real.
So there is an argument to counter that that would say, oh, the drug you took maybe break your brain and break that that that part of your brain that gives you the fear.
Maybe it's the drug that done it might maybe or maybe it's really this this thing that gave me it.
I don't know. But I know for a fact that now when I go on, for example, in the height, I'm aware of the danger, but I'm not paralyzed and stiff.
I'm not like I used to be before. Right. I'm more comfortable.
But I'm aware it's dangerous, but I'm not. Yeah. You know what I mean?
We say in French, I'm frozen. You know, like I'm frozen. Yeah.
And it this is something that's sort of for me. Yeah. Confirm.
That was like a little a little wink. Yes.
Because for me, it's important that I have a confirmation that it's deeper, not only in my senses.
I've seen something. I hear something because this could fool you sometime.
You know, and it's almost like it knew that.
I want to give you something because I know it says it to me because I asked the question, I said, how would I know if it's real?
And it sort of made me understand like that's you will have a gift and I didn't realize what was the gift.
And now I know that's the gift. That's interesting.
Or maybe I'm completely insane. I made it all up in my mind. Who knows?
You know what I mean? Yeah, definitely.
You know, that's the counter argument. But I also counter argue that with, you know, why?
Why? Why do we associate the physical with the real? Right.
What if this isn't real? And what if everything else is? Because that seems to be the trend.
It seems to be like if we're looking at interdimensional beings or even the existence, the nonexistence of space time,
like the way these things operate behaves differently.
When we sleep, time behaves differently when our brain shuts down.
It's like it seems like this astral or this whatever this space is might be the real in like, you know, much like the simulation theory.
And I don't like that word because it makes makes us feel like a video game.
I don't think that's at all it. But this is some type of lower density 3D avatar that we're sort of learning lessons through.
So the way that I always see this is that that's the reality. OK, this other place is the reality.
And there you have instant manifestation. You can manifest anything. You can go anywhere.
Anything just happens instantly. It's so easy. But when you do that, you don't learn anything because it's everything's too easy.
You have it all. So we're put here into these, you know, 3D into this 3D reality and everything's hard and slow.
And we move like through molasses here. And if we want to manifest something, it takes years or months.
And we have to think of it and we have to really like and move things to make it happen.
So it's like a slow motion version of what's really going on.
But this is the only way that we can learn hardship and we can learn lessons that we take back to the reality. Right.
So when people say, you know, is it real? Is it not real?
I think what we're asking, like, is it physical or nonphysical? And I don't think nonphysical means it's not real.
I think there are different reels. Yeah.
What I get from my ayahuasca adventure also is the fact that I'm under the impression and that's only me.
That consciousness is something that linked everything together,
that we're all ones in the same time, that we're all different. Yeah.
You know, in a physical, in a materialistic world, we'll say like, let's say I die.
You bury me naked underneath the soil.
I will stop existing as an entity walking around, but I will not end.
I will be transformed. The worms will eat me.
Perhaps the grass on top of me, the herbs will grow faster because the organic material.
So I will move from that state of walking around to another state of different things.
And I'm under the impression that that's what consciousness is about.
And it made me, it gave me also the impression that, you know, when someone die, we're all very sad.
You know, when it's normal, we're sad.
But it gives me the impression that there's something that, you know, that person died that became part of something else
that one day will join, will join it as well to be part of that thing.
And we're all sort of together.
I don't know how to explain. It's a freaking profound experience.
And they say, you know, we saw certain clip online, like the Rick James.
He says, hey, cocaine is a hell of a drug, but ayahuasca is a hell of a drug too.
So I don't know what to make of it.
Yeah, they should definitely make that a meme instead.
They're going to make some meme now. Ayahuasca is a hell of a drug.
It's a Joe Rogan saying, Rick James.
Yeah, that's, I mean, that's, that seems to be on par with a lot of beliefs.
And that's the thing. It's like, this isn't the one thing that I keep understanding is that none of this is new.
Right. And that's the feeling that I got when I was sort of leaving my body as well.
I started vibrating before it happened. Right.
I started getting, and I thought, I documented this.
I thought there was a truck on the property.
And I was like, how rude that like there's this giant truck on the property when we're trying to meditate.
Turns out, no, that was me.
There was a vibration in me and it wasn't physical, but it felt physical.
And when that was happening, like it was just so strange.
And the feeling that I got, the overwhelming, like the only way that I can explain it is this is ancient.
That's it. Whatever's happening to me right now, I felt tied me, connected me to thousands of years of humans.
That this specific moment right now, you know, links me to them.
Not me researching something, not something I'm eating, not the air, not nothing, this feeling.
This is a very human feeling. Yeah.
And this is something that links me to all of that.
Like we all have differences over time and knowledge and intelligence experience, but this we have in common.
And that was a really powerful sensation to feel that because it felt true.
It felt like, hey, this is, this is true. This is real.
And I even told you before the interview, before the podcast that I would be very interested to go back into that state.
But I'm no longer interested to do it using drugs to get there.
I feel it's sort of a shortcut. Yep.
And sometimes with shortcut, I feel sometimes it's like giving a gun to a child, you know, or it doesn't have the wisdom to use it.
And maybe I did ayahuasca, but I didn't have the wisdom.
I didn't work together. I just took something and I get there.
I cheated. You know what I mean?
And I feel I did it once. It was OK.
But I'm very interested if it's if there is a way because I heard monk monks get there because your brain produced the empty.
If there is a way to get there naturally, I would really love to learn that.
And I know you're you're you're trying to you're going down that rabbit hole.
And I'm really interested to learn these.
When I was young, I when I was a kid, I used to have experience called sleep paralysis.
And that's how they call it. You know, I don't know what if it's what it is.
And that's one of the reason why I first started getting interested by UFO.
You know, even before I had the encounter with my four friend that I've seen something in the sky.
It started way earlier when I was a kid.
I used to, you know, I used to be in bed at night and I used to have nightmares of, you know, of things that came and get me.
And I used to tell my parents, I'm like, man, I was scared.
And for a long time, I was terrified.
I thought like something came to get me.
And I met, you know, when I met Joe Rogan and he talked to me about a phenomenon, a phenomenon called sleep paralysis.
He says, like, there's there's a phenomenon that you're in bed and you cannot move.
And your brain produced the empty and it start hallucinating things.
And that that could be it.
And I, man, it really, it really traumatized me when I was young to the point that even now I'm an adult sometimes.
And I mean, let's say I'm in bed and I'm alone and I start thinking about it.
It makes me remember the fear and it scared me even when I'm a grown man and I can't defend myself.
It traumatized me to that point.
And that's one of the reasons now I would be very interesting to learn of how I could perhaps get back into that mental state if there's ways to do it naturally.
I used to be very sceptic.
I used to learn to hear all those stories.
Oh, yeah, there's that.
They go, I'm like, yeah, right, right.
But now that I did ayahuasca, I know it's possible to do it on drugs.
I would love to know how to do it naturally just to perhaps increase my knowledge and maybe help me be a better person.
Yeah.
And that's probably the best intention to go into it with.
And that's probably the strongest intention as well.
Because when you rule out, this is just something in my experience as well.
And this has been echoed by a lot of people who study this.
But when you rule out the ego part of it, that's when things happen, right?
If it's not for monetary gain or it's not for any other purpose.
But once the ego is out of the equation, that's when you're more receptive.
That's when the intention's sort of pure.
And it kind of picks up on that, the phenomenon.
It's a very interesting thing that you just mentioned, ego.
And that's one of the things I had a hard time to let it go.
In the fighting world, it's a very egotistic industry.
Everything is about being the alpha, not being scared.
Very physical, lower density.
Yeah, 100%.
It's a lot of bullying and mental warfare.
And you never want to admit that you're scared, even though deep down inside you are.
Because it shows signs of weakness.
But it's not.
In a way, admitting that you're scared, it showcases that you're strong.
Because you're allowed to talk about your fear.
And if I'm talking, if I'm an open book and I talk about my fear, I'm not afraid of you.
You know what I mean?
Because I've shown my most vulnerable part.
Because I'm confident that I'm better than you.
True strength.
Yes, yes.
So yeah, but the ego, letting go of your ego.
The ego at the same time, it's your pride.
It is what makes you stand up and being strong towards adversity.
But at the same time, it's a double edged sword.
Because if you let it go, it can make you a better person.
Be more open to people, you know?
Yeah.
And that's something that you've actually talked about.
I remember hearing that too, like admitting you're nervous.
Or admitting that like, yeah, no, I am going into this fight.
You know, you're not like just everyone else where they were like, you know, this is it.
I'm going to, you know, there was a certain, but that helped you.
That like made you a more intelligent fighter as well.
You know what happened, Chris?
Early on in my career, I mean, the way I describe it is we're not all born with the same set of card, you know?
We all have different skills, you know?
If I would have been born with an anti-cap, I would never be able to be champion.
I'm a very athletic person.
I've always been good in sports.
And I developed a passion with martial art early on, watching movies.
You know, Jean-Claude Van Damme and all these guys, Chuck Norris.
They really inspire me.
Steven Seagal, Arnold Schwarzenegger, Steve Astor Stallone.
And I was bullied at school.
So I first started karate.
I started with Kyoko Shin Karate as a self-defense to defend myself in the schoolyard.
And then it transformed into a passion because things back then was not well.
Things were not going well at home.
My dad at the time was drinking and things were not going well at school because I was getting bullied.
Instead of focusing on what the teacher was saying, I had to try to think about how I'm going to reach out my locker,
pick up my book and get to the bus before the guys get to me and beat me up.
And that was something that was happening to me on a weekly basis.
So I was not happy.
I was not good anywhere.
I felt bad everywhere.
The only place I felt good was the dojo because I was doing well in karate.
I was starting to collect metal.
And that was the only place where I feel like, hey, man, I'm good here.
You know, I'm doing something well.
And then later on, my dad, he did something that really inspired me and brought back my family together when he stopped drinking.
And it really inspired me.
And it changes my life because I saw how hard it was to fight the thirst.
And not only that he stopped drinking, he started to mentor younger people that try to stop drinking.
I remember at night, sometimes the phone was ringing at 11 at night.
And it was my dad picking up the phone.
It was maybe a younger guy.
It was like, hey, man, I'm thirsty.
My dad was like, I'm coming. I'm coming to get you.
So he really inspired me because I saw how hard it was.
And I realized it only later when I was an adult, not really at the time.
It was like sort of a delay.
And it really inspired me.
But I remember even early on in my career, we talk about ego and pride.
When I was looking around, I never felt I never fit.
I felt I never fit where I was.
I loved the purity to be.
I wanted to be champion.
I did it for the right reason.
I didn't want to do it because I wanted to be popular with the money because they didn't have any money and popularity back then.
I just wanted to be champion.
I wanted to be the best.
I did it for the pure reason.
But when I was looking around and I was looking at my training partner in my environment, I didn't fit in because all the guys I was with, they were like, yeah, I can't wait for Saturday night.
I'm like, man, I'm scared.
I'm not happy to be here.
I'm happy to be in the gym to train and to have that lifestyle.
And I know if I want to continue to have that lifestyle, the sacrifice is that I need to fight Saturday night and win the fight in order to do it.
But I don't enjoy this process.
I'm not happy to do it.
I'm happy to get to have that lifestyle for free.
But I'm not happy to go fight.
I never like to fight.
So I decided to seek the help of sports psychologists because, man, I felt I never I didn't fit in.
And some sports psychologists tried to brainwash me.
They were like, George, stop saying you're afraid.
You're not afraid.
You're excited.
And one of them, it was like it was my English used to be very like it's still bad, but used to be way worse before.
And I was thinking I was like, is it the language barrier excited?
I don't think I'm excited.
I would be excited in different situation, but I'm not excited to go to know that I'm going to fight Saturday night, not knowing if I will be badly injured or humiliated.
I'm afraid.
And then I realized that, man, I need to make peace with it.
And there is no shame to admit that you're afraid because there is no courage without fear.
And when I made peace with that, it changes everything in my life because I made peace.
And I said it to even in my open is like, yeah, I'm scared of you.
But no matter what, I'm going to freaking walk the walk on Saturday night and there is nothing you can do.
And the way you counter fear, whether you're a fighter, an entrepreneur or whatever, it's with the preparation.
The more well you prepare, the more you will build up your confidence.
And if you have confidence, remember, confidence is not the absence of fear.
It's knowing that you have what you need in order to succeed.
And a good analogy is if I talk to young students at school, I'm telling them if you have an exam Friday and you study very hard.
Yes, you will still be afraid Friday, the day of the exam.
But you have the right to be confident, to walk in there with confidence, even though you're afraid.
But if you have not studied, you will be afraid.
But you don't have the right to be confident because you know you didn't do the work.
You didn't put in the work and confidence, whether you're a fighter, an entrepreneur, whatever you do,
even in any situation, even if you go ask a girl on a date, confidence, whatever you do, it's the most important thing.
One of the most important things. You need the skills, the preparation and the confidence.
Because if you don't have confidence, it's a little bit like a good analogy that my sensei was saying to me.
If you don't have confidence, it's like someone who has a lot of money in his bank account, but no way of accessing it.
You can never reach your full potential. And the way you build confidence is through preparation.
And when I made peace with it, I knew I was afraid. I made peace with it.
I remember when I was young, I thought the fear will go away over time, that I will get used to it.
I will no longer be afraid. But that's not true. It's the opposite.
It gets worse because every fight is bigger than the last one.
And it gets worse. But because I made peace with it, I was like, man, I know this is normal.
I need to be afraid because I know when I'm afraid, it high-end my reaction time, my reset time.
It makes me better. So I embrace fear. I know it's a normal thing.
And if my opponent is like, are you afraid of me? I'm like, yeah, man, I'm afraid of you.
But I'm going to fucking do it regardless. And I think from my perspective is way scarier than saying, no, I'm not afraid.
99% of the people in my field of work are like, no, I'm not afraid. I'm going to kick his ass.
Bullshit, man. You're scared. Or either you're scared or you're a psychopath or you're a liar.
That's the three possibilities. You're lying or you're a psychopath.
You know what I mean? Or you're dumb as hell.
Because if you're not afraid, that means you don't know the consequences of what can happen.
That's true. Yeah, wow, man.
Because you never control the entire data. When you go into a fight or you have to focus on things that you have the power to control.
You don't want to focus. And that's the hardest thing to do because there's so many distractions.
You don't want to focus on things you don't control. For example, what the people are going to say.
Am I going to win or lose? What my opponent is going to do?
This needs to be wiped out of your mind, only focusing on things that you do control, things that I do.
Me as an entity, I don't exist. Am I going to be sick the morning of the fight? Am I sleeping well or not?
I don't care. It's out of my mind. The only thing that matters is the objective.
And the objective is the only thing that matters because that's what's going to lead you to the path of victory.
And this needs to be done at all costs. That's the spirit. You need to go in.
It's hard to think about it, but that's the way it is. Like a soldier. It's objective, no subjective.
But that's such a big contrast between being there, preparing yourself physically, mentally for a physical and mental bout.
And on top of that, all the other obstacles that are being thrown your way, not only health-wise,
but also emotionally or personally the things that you're dealing with or the media and all this stuff.
It's a big battle going from that to what happened after this ayahuasca trip, which is completely almost like...
180 degree.
Yeah, the opposite. It's like, okay, you've done that. Now forget all that.
And you're like, how do I forget all that? That's your identity. That's everything.
And you had to come to terms with that too. So that must have been just like...
I mean, I can even hear you telling a story and I know that it's changed you.
Let's put this scenario. If you were to somehow have a time machine and go back into the ring,
but after having this experience, do you think that would make you a better or worse fighter?
That's a good question. I think it would make me worse.
I think there's a chronological way to do it.
I think you don't want to do this before you finish your career.
Right.
And what I'm saying is only from my expertise, my experience, but I know that there's some other professional combat athlete.
For example, Deontay Walder mentioned, I believe, that he did ayahuasca and he believed that's why his career went down.
He said it publicly. And I can understand why.
Because that ego thing that we talk about as a fighter is the most important thing.
That's your spine. That's what holds you up against all odds, against all the adversity.
It's your ego, your pride. But in society, it could be an obstacle.
Because sometimes an ego, you have to let your ego aside.
Putting it down, it makes you a better person, I believe.
And even the people that know me personally say that when I did ayahuasca, it really changed me.
It made me more empathetic, more in touch with other people.
I'm by no means perfect. I have a lot of issues and I need to work on myself a lot.
But I'm a little bit better than I used to be.
I can see that as being a problem too, going into the ring with empathy.
Feeling bad for hurting your opponent is not something you want to think about.
You want to be like an alpha bull. You're here to destroy and kill everyone.
That's how it is. That's how you need to be. But you can't stay like that all your life.
And I believe one of the reasons why a lot of athletes in combat sports have a hard time letting it go.
And you see a lot of athletes sometimes, they should have retired maybe a decade ago, but they're still out there fighting.
I mean, it's very sad. It's very, very sad. You see that happening all the time.
And they hurt themselves. Oh, CTE physically, they hurt also themselves business-wise.
Because when you finish on top, for example, for me, the best reason why I stopped is because it's my health.
I wanted to finish healthy, to have a future, to be healthy for the rest of my life.
But also the second reason is business-wise. When you finish on top, I compare, for example, entertainers or athletes like stock in the market.
If you finish on top, you're stuck worth a lot of money. So there's a lot of opportunity.
When you retire and you turn around, a lot of business opportunity opens to you.
Those opportunities will not be there if you retire on a four losing streak because your stock will go down.
And it's something to think about. So a lot of people, they told me, yeah, you must have, George, you should have keep on fighting.
You left a lot of money on the table. Maybe I left some money on the table, but I think I catch it up on the long run.
And on top of that, I didn't damage my health because it's not only the fight.
Think about it. When you get ready for a fight, you have to go into a training camp, get hit and all that.
It's even worse than the fight itself and all the stresses that you have.
And for me, the stress was the most damageable thing, the stress.
I've always been very open about it. I was stressed, I was scared, and it took a lot out of me.
A lot more than the physical damage. Oh yeah, 100%.
I developed a condition called ulcer colitis, I believe a big part because of that stress.
And in my last fight with Michael Bisping, I fought in the Madison Square Garden.
Prior to that fight, a few weeks, I had severe cramps. When I went to the bathroom, it was blood.
And I didn't know what it was. I was like, man, is it a cancer or anything?
And I told myself, whatever it is, I'm going to deal with it after the fight in a few weeks.
So after the fight, I did what they call a colonoscopy. They put something inside of you.
They give you some medication to empty yourself, you know, and something that you don't want to do before the fight.
But they put a camera and they went to see inside. I got diagnosed with ulcer colitis.
Ulcerative colitis, yeah.
So I was on medication. But I'm not a big fan of medication.
I mean, I always look for alternative ways of how I can get better.
And I met a doctor in Toronto that changed my life. His name is Jason Fung.
Jason Fung, you can research it. Jason Fung, F-U-N-G.
He wrote many books about fasting and he got me into a fasting program.
And believe it or not, a few months after, all my symptoms disappeared and I no longer use medication.
Do you think that that also had something to do with the fact that you weren't fighting anymore?
It could be.
Because of stress.
Because of stress, yeah. But both, like, I mean.
It could be. But I had other stresses in my life. It could be that.
But I believe that the fasting really helped me.
Yep. I believe in fasting too, by the way.
Because it gives time to your system to rejuvenate.
You know, if you eat all the time. And when I was fighting Michael Bisping,
I was on the diet that I was forcing myself to eat because I was trying to put on weight.
Which was, by the way, a big mistake of my part. I should have just stayed the same weight that I am.
But I was trying to put on weight because I was fighting in a weight class heavier than I normally compete at.
So I was trying to get bigger. But it didn't do me any good because I got sick and everything.
But the fact that I put a lot of stress, like mental stress and physical stress, I think that's what triggered that issue.
And after when I went to fasting, different fasting protocols, it helped me get rid of all my symptoms.
Yeah. I mean, people need to be aware of the fact that diet can fix 90% of the health issues that are out there right now.
Maybe even more.
I made some research and I found out that, you know, the reason why we eat three times a day,
and sometimes even some people eat more than that, like five times a day,
it's since the Industrial Revolution. Before that, this did not exist.
Since the Industrial Revolution, because of the work, the laws, they had to make time for eating for the employees.
So if you look, if you go back, this thing did not really existed. It was since the Industrial Revolution.
So it's really recent in our evolution that we are conditioned to eat at that time.
Think about it. Just logically think about it. Like our untargeter ancestor,
they did not wake up in the morning and have breakfast, you know, most of the time because you need to work to get your breakfast.
You need to hunt. You need, you know, you don't get your breakfast for free in a fridge.
Yeah, so exactly. So the fact that you wait in the morning, and that's what I do now, I don't get breakfast in the morning.
I eat my eggs and, you know, my coffee a little bit later during the day and after my first training.
And I just wish, Chris, I would have known that before.
It would have, it would perhaps not have caused all the harms that I did to my body.
Yeah. But then again, you know, you being on that path is what led you to this.
So you might not have, you know. That's true. It's like a feedback loop.
You have to, you have to go through the hardships to learn, to learn all this stuff.
But it, I mean, it's very, very interesting. My, myself, so I eat mainly a paleo diet.
I'm, I'm like, I'm borderline in ketosis most of the time because of like this paleo diet.
I don't eat sugar, no dairy, you know, no pasta. It's strict.
No processed food.
No processed food, none.
Oh, interesting.
Just meat, leafy greens and root veggies.
And do you think that helps you to get into that mental meditating state?
Because I've heard that, and correct me if I'm wrong, you're the expert on that.
Like apparently you have to be centered.
Like you cannot be hungry or sad or, you know what I mean?
Like horny or you have to be, right?
Yep. It does help. It does help. And there's been a lot of studies actually.
There's a guy, Graham Nichols, he did a lot of research on this too.
How actually not, his research was not eating meat, how it induces more psi ability.
So more sort of the psychic sort of ability during these out of body experiences and all that stuff
that there's been a correlation between like vegetarians and vegans having actually more experiences
and more accuracy during these testings.
I tend to think that it probably isn't the lack of meat.
My, I guess, hypothesis is it's the lack of processed food.
Chemicals.
Correct.
There's a lot of chemicals and veggies as well.
Yes. They're everywhere.
And so it's really, it's difficult to do a diet without processed nowadays
because processed is just so much cheaper and groceries are getting more expensive.
And so it's not easy for everyone to have like a good diet.
It's very strange, but like you look at like, okay, the poorest parts in the world,
yes, people are very skinny because they're malnourished and they're not eating.
And then you look at like just above that, people have a little money, are completely overweight.
And then, and you have a lot of money, you're back in shape again.
And so it's like, you know, like we really do have a system where we're offering a lot of really bad food at low cost,
you know, and that's, that's been part of the problem.
But to your point, there is a certain headspace that you have to be in,
but that headspace I don't think can come at the beginning.
I think it takes practice like everything else.
Like, I don't think you can go into meditating your first time ever,
be centered and have like an amazing experience.
I think it's just something you have to keep doing because it's different for everyone.
The feeling, the meditation itself, calming your mind is very,
it depends where you're at and what you've eaten really and all this.
So it's a journey that over time you start to discover what's good for you
and how you can actually see very clearly what's going on in your psyche when you get to that point.
So if I'm in a meditation and something keeps popping up, something keeps at the beginning, I'd be like,
oh, I try to shut that down. I have to shut this down.
I have to control and I have to like shut myself up.
And after a while, you're just like, okay, come on in.
And you look at it and you observe it.
And then when you're done with you, you're like, you good now?
Okay, you can leave.
And this becomes like through practice, you're able to do this much easier.
And it becomes like fun.
It becomes fun to embrace and sit with your problems and sit with those stresses or those,
like you said, like if you're horny or if you're angry.
And they even say that during the Monroe, the Gateway experience.
Even before that, they briefed me and they're like, you might get horny during these things.
And I'm like, what do you mean?
It's energy.
It's one of the most primal forms of energy.
It's creation energy, right?
And so how at first you're like, oh, I'm getting a random boner during my meditation.
What the hell is going on?
And then after a while you're like, oh, I can take that energy and sort of spread it through my body.
I can control it.
I can. So again, it's not about shutting down all of these things,
but it's about re-channeling that energy and much like martial arts.
You know, if somebody's coming at you, it's using their own energy against them
rather than forcing against that energy, which could be damaging for you both.
Yeah.
It's much easier to take that and roll with it.
How do you, why?
I mean, I have to be the devil advocate now.
Why nobody has ever come publicly in a way to prove that?
Like, you know what I mean?
Like that.
The out of body experience and stuff?
Yeah, not out of body, but like the, you know, the psionic power, because it's not proven.
Like remote viewing sort of thing.
Like why, if it's true, there is no strong evidence of, let's say like, okay,
like someone can do it, goes public.
Okay, I bring me anybody that I will be in the room next to that person
and know, I will, I will draw what they draw on the paper or whatever it is.
Like why you think, I mean, because I'm, I'm still septic.
Yeah.
And sometimes I think, you know, when you do these experience, apparently from the lore,
you have to take off your intellect and be more into intuition.
But how do you make the difference between intuition and deduction?
Because when I'm fighting, I don't know what to explain it.
If someone is about to throw a punch, I will see it coming.
Is it intuition or is it deduction?
Because I've seen that pattern so many times, so I can identify it before it comes.
Or is it both?
It's a great question.
What makes a good athlete an athlete?
Is it his intuition?
Because there's guys like, for example, John Jones.
Yeah.
Man, he's freaking fat.
He's a freak of nature.
You see him, like the way he moves is so beautiful.
Demetrius Johnson.
Is it his intuition or is it deduction that he can?
All the great guys in hockey, Wayne Gretzky, you don't even look, he passed the puck.
I'm like, man, Michael Jordan.
Yeah.
Is there something more than deduction?
Of course, some of the Atheists will say the logical ways of thinking.
I mean, in our world, we'll be like, oh, he practices so much that even...
He's in a flow stage.
Yes.
He had a flow, but flow is not really accepted.
It's like, oh, he practiced it so much that he knows where the guy is because of the practice.
Or is it something more like an intuition?
That's my question.
And that's one of the things that could be interesting.
You know what I mean?
Is there a way to prove it?
And why, if there is a way to prove it, why it's never been done before?
Or if it was done, is it secret?
Now we get into the CIA, like with all the program, like Stargate and all that.
So, I mean, there's a lot to unpack there because it's...
First of all, there is a lot of evidence showing that psi ability is real.
There's a lot of evidence showing that remote viewing is real.
If you know where to look, the thing is it isn't pushed on a mainstream level.
And most people won't accept it because of the shifting goal posts a lot of times.
For instance, the tests that are being done to prove...
I mean, there's Dean Radin, there's Rupert Sheldrake, and there's...
Joseph McMonacle, right?
Joe McMonacle, he's a remote viewer.
But the people that studied him, there's the doctor that studied him.
He's the chief research physicist, Dr. Edwin May.
He has 30 years of data spanning over six remote viewers, 30 years of data.
So he has a clear... And he's a research physicist.
So he has a clear line, and his line...
And normally if you see something over time like this, you see the line go down, right?
Because it's just like... His is a straight line.
Like Joe McMonacle, straight all the way through in terms of his testing.
What do you mean? The line is the success?
Yes, correct. It's a straight line.
How come it's not freaking public?
That's what... It's very frustrating because I want to believe, Chris,
and I really want to... But my freaking logical...
The logical part of my brain is like, if there's no evidence, it's not true.
So there is a lot of evidence. There is actually a ton of evidence.
There are a lot of books out there too, and I can point you towards those books,
of studies that are peer-reviewed even.
Dr. Daryl Bem did amazing studies on precognition.
That was proven. They did this test, I think, 93 times or something.
And thousands of people... This was a real test that was done.
On remote viewing, you talk.
This was on precognition.
I'm sorry.
Seeing the future.
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Foresee something that did not happen yet.
But on a minuscule level, right? On a scientific, like, how can we improve this?
And a lot of that has to do with what you were saying, with this instinct, right?
And so what they would do is they would flash these images on these...
They had them hooked up to EEG machines or whatever they were.
And they would flash images, some were positive and some were negative.
And they would measure the brainwave activity.
When the images were negative,
they would see a spike in their brainwave functions,
fractions of a second before the image was shown.
Wow.
Yes. And they did this over and over and over and over.
And is it peer review?
Yes, it is peer review.
Really?
Yes, absolutely. But it's so minute.
Rupert Sheldrake did a test, and this as well.
He wrote a whole book on this, very fascinating.
But it was the connection between dogs and their owners
and how some of them seem to have some type of psychic connection.
And so the way that they tested this, they had the dogs at home
and they gave the person a pager who was out of the home.
And at a random time, they would page them to go home, okay?
And they would go home in a different way, not normal way, like not with their car.
It would be somebody else's car or a bike or a bus or something.
And they would page them at a random time during the day.
Well, the second they page them, a lot of these dogs
would get up off the couch and run to the door.
As soon as the intention of the person was to go home,
the dogs would come to the door over and over again.
Really?
And not only that, halfway to their home,
they would page them again to turn back.
The dog would go back on the couch or whatever.
And so they did this over and over and they found that some of these dogs
do have this consciousness connection.
There's something more there.
It's not only humans.
No, it seems to be a field, some type of field.
So it's not a frequency, but some type of instantaneous field
where intention is really, really, really strong.
And to go back to like the instinctive thing,
Joe McMonigal talks a lot about that.
He thinks remote viewing or precognition was due to us having to survive.
And a lot of times, where's the water?
You'd go see the shaman and the shaman would tell you where the water is.
And the most important, the most powerful person in the tribes,
a lot of times, weren't the strongest.
They were the most psychic.
According to the lore, when you dive into that sort of rabbit hole,
the kids that have autism and problem to communicate verbally
seems to be more prone to develop those abilities.
Yeah, like in the telepathy tapes.
Yes. It makes sense.
From my perspective, I remember when I fight someone,
when they call it the zone.
And once again, it could be deduction or intuition,
but sometimes I used to sort of know what the guy is going to do.
Like I'm in his head and take downs and, you know, it's hard to explain.
Even though when I was fighting, I sort of do it,
but I don't know if it's by deduction because I've seen this pattern,
but everybody's body is different or it's intuition sort of.
And my question is, which ability is to foresee the future is one,
remote viewing is another one to go somewhere, right?
And is there, do they have telepathy, like communication,
or do they have telekinese,
or what is it exactly proven by pure review in that regard?
I mean, okay, so there is precognition that has been peer reviewed
that you can look at.
Precognition is the future.
Exactly.
But also remote viewing, there's been a lot of case studies,
especially with Dr. Edwin May.
He put out like volumes,
I think two million words he published on the actual tests,
giving you the actual tests, what he did, what the results were over time,
the wins, the losses, everything.
And you have it all there.
And sometimes it's just incredible when you look at the data itself.
You're like, wait a second.
It could be a coincidence. It cannot be a coincidence.
I mean, not, no, the p-value.
So statistically, an anomaly.
It's okay.
Yeah, statistically, it's in the millions.
It doesn't make sense.
And this is pure review.
It's undeniable.
Undeniable, yes.
Yes, and the work is available.
I did a whole deep dive onto this stuff.
It is available.
But the problem is that when you go towards certain people who are gatekeeping
a lot of the parapsychology,
what's happening is that the goalposts are shifting with these people.
So if you say to them, what do I need to do to prove to you that remote viewing is real?
Okay.
They say, okay, make sure the p-value, so the statistical value, is higher than this.
We also want these type of tests done.
You say, okay.
So they do those tests and then they present them.
And they're like, here you go.
And they go, ah, there must be something wrong.
There must be something wrong.
Do it again.
But here, let's make the p-value like this.
And then they do it.
And they keep shifting these.
And one of the reasons why, I mean, since I met you, it's not a long time ago.
It was like two, like a few weeks.
That's your fill of expertise.
You're in a way, you're a magician, like a wizard, because that's what you do.
You do the shows.
So if someone would know, it would be you.
I remember I watched, you know, James Randi.
He used to be, he used to debunk.
Yes.
And he used even himself saying like, hey, I'm a con man, but I will fool you.
And you will not know that I fool you because you will be fooled.
And in the same way, if you would be fake, you would know because that's what you do.
Because of your expertise.
Yes.
You're used to.
And there is a lot of fakery.
Of course.
Because that's the magic.
That's the beauty of a magic trick.
But that's perhaps one of the reasons why a lot of people are septic.
They're like, yeah, but I've seen this sort of magic trick.
But you, you've seen a lot more than an average person.
That's your fill of expertise.
You dive into this and you believe in it.
So it's kind of crazy for me to believe that you believe in it.
Because if someone would know, it would be you.
You know what I mean?
You work with David Copperfield and all these guys.
Like, man, you cannot, it doesn't get bigger than this.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
And it's not that I went into it believing.
That's the other thing.
Oh, you did not before.
No, of course not.
Really?
Yes.
Of course.
That's why I did the whole remote viewing thing.
I studied remote viewing for a year.
We documented the whole process and we were starting to get results that were really,
really accurate.
And we're like, man, there is something here.
Hold on.
And, and then visiting these people and talking to these physicists and, and going back to,
I met Joe McManigal.
I met Ed Dames.
Yuri Geller I spoke with even.
Yuri Geller.
He was debunked, I think, by James Randi.
But I would like to hear his side of the story because I only hear one side.
It's tough with him.
Yeah.
Because he's also a showman.
You know, and he does that for a living.
Yeah.
And you know, he's always played that blurry between the lines thing is like, he wouldn't
answer questions like, oh, we're going to use my spoons or like, it was always like
some, and magicians know him very well.
He's a, he's a known magician among magicians.
Right.
And so we know, I know how to bend spoons, you know, in a way that makes it look like
they're bending on their own through illusion.
Right.
Now the question becomes, you know, when you have somebody who can have those power or
not those power, sorry, someone who's practiced that ability to make it look like they're
bending spoons now tell you, but also there's real spoon bending.
You're like, then it kind of like makes it muddies up the water where you're like, I
don't know if I can believe what you're saying now, because you're also showing me tricks
and telling me the real, but now you're telling me there's real real.
And I'm like, that's something I have to try for myself now, because I don't know if I
can believe you.
I've seen, for example, James Randi, when he went to the church pop up, pop off, you
know, he was a miracle healer.
It was like miracle crusade.
And he was, he had a mic, you know, and a hair piece.
And he knew by reading the the prayer of all the faithful before the mess that, oh, I'm
sitting in this row.
I have a cancer.
And he used to be like, Marilyn, sitting in row six, number five, you have like a cancer.
And I will cure like this is insane to use to use that to.
I mean, I know placebo effect is a real thing, but you're not going to freaking cure cancer
with that.
But that makes it look very bad.
My question is, when is there a moment that you said you were very septic in the beginning?
Is there a moment that you were like, holy shit, this thing is real?
Like, like me in Washington, when they freaking confirm it to me, like, like, like there's
something going on and it's it's we cannot explain.
I don't know what it is, but we cannot explain.
Is there a moment that it hit you like crazy?
There were several moments.
It was a slow burn for me because I was very again, I was very like, OK, I can explain
that with coincidence or confirmation bias or like.
But then when I started doing it myself, I started getting really close results and they
were pretty consistent.
Can you explain for like for me or people that are not aware, like how those experience
are made, like in which which context that they're they're like remote viewing.
Right.
Yeah.
How do you perform this sort of thing?
If someone want to try it at home to see if he you know, if he can do it or.
Yeah.
You would.
So first of all, like there's different ways to do it.
The way that we did it was my friend would take an image, a random generated image from
the Internet.
He would fold it up, put it in an envelope, a sealed envelope and write like a six digit
random number on the envelope.
He would then give me the six digit number and I start there.
So you mean you see the digit?
Yeah, I see the numbers and the digit is linked to an image that you do not see.
Correct.
OK, OK.
Yeah.
And so that's all I have.
And so you're not trying to decipher what that number is.
It just gives you a point of reference non-locally to the image.
It could be anything.
Yeah.
And you have no clue of what it is.
No.
OK.
Yeah.
No, I don't know.
So it could be a bumblebee to a bicycle to the CN tower to somebody playing soccer.
Like it's really anything.
OK.
And you would then there's like a series.
And this was taught.
I learned the method that was like kind of taught in the CIA, which is like sort of this
controlled remote viewing where you have different stages.
So stage one, two, three, four, five, etc.
And stage one, you would scribble like this little ideogram.
It's like a little scribble.
Then you would describe that.
And then after that, you would go into descriptors.
And so now we're talking, what do you perceive?
So when you're in this calm state, you're just trying to perceive things.
So you're calming your mind and you're like, what do I smell?
What do I see?
What does it feel like?
What's the texture?
Is there a sound?
Is there a movement?
Is there an energy?
Is there a feeling?
What's the gestalt?
Like, what is this?
Does this feel like an open space?
Does this feel like a building or a life form?
And you would just kind of like perceive and just go on intuition and just kind of like
and just go and just not even think about it.
Just start drawing stuff.
We start writing all these things down first.
You're just describing windy steel metal taste of metal.
I feel this like fuzzy.
Also this warmth and like you don't write the you don't do the image.
You write words.
You're just writing.
You're writing descriptions of like what this feels like.
And you're going, going, going.
And after that, when you're like, OK, now you go into drawing.
Now you're like, OK.
And you're not trying to draw something specific.
You're just drawing what your perception is.
You're kind of like just going with it.
Because the last thing you want to do is we call this AOL, analytical overlay.
You don't want like if I have yellow, black, fuzzy, buzzing, now I want to think Bumblebee.
Right.
And that's a bad thing to do.
So you don't want to.
But automatically your brain will go to Bumblebee.
Yeah.
And that's an AOL.
By deduction.
Exactly.
You want that out of the way.
So you'll write Bumblebee as an AOL just to kind of like get it out of your mind and keep going.
And when you're drawing, it's hard to do.
But like what you can.
I'm sorry.
When you say Bumblebee, AOL, you put AOL next to it to know that is scratch.
Exactly.
OK.
Sorry.
Yes.
You would just sometimes just get it out of the way.
But other times it would keep coming back.
And you're like, OK, it's something there.
And it would turn out to be a Bumblebee.
You know, so it's like hard to really discern what was what.
And then you go into more descriptors after that.
And after you're done, you pretty much end your session.
You take out the photo and you look at the data and you try to compare and then you evaluate.
We give ourselves a score on zero to ten on how close we were.
I don't think I ever gave myself above seven because I'm very much confirmation biased.
And I'm like, you know, so we would look at it together and try it.
But sometimes you're like, man, like, oh, my God, oh, my God, oh, my God.
And there wasn't one thing I wrote down that wasn't part of the image.
You know, and then you're like, I could have said like this could have been anything.
Yeah.
So when that happens over and over.
And by the way, you're while you're doing it, you're like sometimes like this is like not while you're doing it.
But right after you're done, when you're about to open the envelope, you go so silly.
Yeah.
This is going to be all wrong.
I'm going to look like such an idiot when this is opened.
And then you open it.
You go, oh, my God.
And it really shocks you.
It's like a magic trick that you did yourself.
Wow.
And this whole thing, how long it takes, for example, if you want to do the experiment at home with 20 minutes, maybe.
OK, so everybody can make an exit.
And how do you differ, for example, like I don't know the exact term in English.
You know, when you look at a cloud, it's paradox.
You make you make something out of the cloud that looks like how do you differ from the word you wrote down or sort of.
But it could have been anything.
How do you defer that like to.
So that's that's where the confirmation bias comes in.
OK, that's where you have to like sort of like look at things really objectively and be like, is like, OK, that could have been that I could have been that.
But sometimes it's very specific.
Perhaps you need to give it to someone that is outside of the experiment and see if he makes that connection.
Right.
Normally, that's what they did at SRI during the Stargate project.
What would happen?
And this is really interesting, too, is a whole study on this as well, because they don't know whether you're actually perceiving the target or you're perceiving the image of the target.
So the image of the target.
Yeah. So so what they're what they're thinking is that because time behaves very differently, too.
And so a lot of these like Stargate people, 90 percent of their remote viewing things that they did for these like 17 out of the 19 agencies.
Star Stargate is the the program, the program by the CIA that was in the 70s.
Right. Yep. OK.
70s and 80s and 17 of the 19 intelligence agencies of the United States used the Stargate program at one point.
All right. Some of them came back over 100 times.
There was five hundred and five individual missions done over the 17 out of the 19 agencies with Stargate in 20 years.
So we know and Joint Task Force was one of the big ones, FBI.
And so there's a lot of like people using this stuff.
The thing is, the the people doing this, the remote viewers, they would never be getting the target.
They would never know because it creates a feedback loop.
So they don't know if they did well.
No way.
Yeah. Because first of all, it's a top secret.
So you can't you can't be briefed on it.
No freaking way.
And so they would do it.
And the only way that they knew that it was successful is that this agency came back for a different mission.
No freaking way.
And again and again and again.
Yeah. Because they they know that if even if you see the target 30 years later.
Right. Yeah.
And finally, you get to see that remote viewing session you did back in the 70s.
Now you've changed it.
Now you've created a feedback loop to where were you remote viewing the moment you looked at the target in the future?
Or were you remote viewing the event?
Right.
So it's a very strange.
Are you kidding me?
It's very strange because there have been times with Angela Ford, one time they asked her like, hey, OK, here's the target.
Whatever.
She starts drawing like this big drum, sort of like the circle and this and that, like all these.
And she's like, it's a water purification plant.
And she's like, here's the diameter and she's meters of diameter of things and everything is like perfectly laid out.
And then she goes, yeah, water.
And they're like, sorry.
No, it's a water park.
They're like, close.
You got close to water park.
And then she's like, something doesn't sit well with me.
They started doing research.
Well, 50 years before that water park was there, it was a water purification plant.
They pulled up a picture.
The picture of the water purification plant matched her remote viewing almost one for one in size and everything.
You could almost lay it over.
That's how close it was.
So now they're thinking, OK, did you go back in time and remote view or did you go forward in time and see the picture that we that we pulled up?
Oh, my God.
Very strange.
Yes.
That's crazy.
I mean, so it becomes that's a lot of times like.
Wow.
Remote viewers like Joe McManigal did not want to see the target ever, ever, ever.
Yeah, it will affect.
Yeah. Yes.
He always said that always.
He was very stern.
Never show me.
Never tell me anything.
They know some of them were very successful, like Ego Swan.
Joe McManigal is one.
I think is he the only one alive now that is from that Stargate, right?
From the original.
Yeah.
And the reason like, I mean, correct me if I'm wrong, but the reason why they started this program in the first place is because during the Cold War, they found out the Russians were doing it.
The Russians because the Russian learned something from the German, perhaps that they were doing before the during the Second World War before the Second World War.
So they want to get that knowledge and the American like, hey, they start doing it.
We got to do it, too.
Right.
Yep. Yep.
Pretty much exactly.
The Russians leaked purposely.
It was thought information about experiments they did with rats to where they would they tattooed all these rats and then they tried to predict which rat would die first.
They put them up in mountains and whatever.
And it was it was very, very accurate.
But turns out and Joe McManigal talks about this that it was the guy who tattooed the rats that was actually psychic because it was the order that he tattooed them in.
Very bizarre test, but they that's what initially got leaked.
But yeah, those psionic type programs existed before Stargate.
You know, there was Center Lane, Grill Flame, Sunstreak.
These were all psychic programs.
It's you think it continues till this day.
Yes, yes.
That's what I've been told.
And wow, do you think I mean, one of the reason it's not public, it's because they don't want everybody to know about it because it could be used as a weapon if it's in the wrong hand.
If someone becomes very good at it, I mean, it could be like the implication of this is pretty freaking crazy.
I mean, imagine imagine if it turns out to someone can enhance that power and be very good at it.
Like, I mean, what's that?
What what can you do with it?
Yeah. And you can know where the secret base are.
I mean, I know. I mean, according to the law, certain certain peoples have been used to locate certain bases and people like other people as well for for extraction.
I mean, and those people that have done that work, they never knew, for example, for the American, they never knew if their result were good or not.
Not so sometimes because they would have to like for certain exceptions.
But normally, no, normally like 95 percent.
And the main reason isn't because of the feedback loop is also a reason.
But the main reason was because the they were classified projects.
So like the CIA or let's say, I don't know, Joint Task Force, they would, you know, be trying to intercept the drug cartel coming in through the coast.
And the Joint Task Force came back, I think, one hundred and forty one times with new missions.
Wow. Because apparently they were intercepting a lot of drug boats, really using remote viewers.
Yeah, but that is crazy.
I mean, man, I want to believe Chris, I really want to.
And it's just like there's a thing in my brain that bullshit bullshit.
But man, I it's hard to to have an argument when you have these results, you know, like when they come back and they ask.
I mean, there's a reason why.
But until someone does not like use like a Star Wars, the force, you know what I mean?
But even that I remain a little bit septic.
And even if you would do that to me, I would be like, man, this freaking guy is a wizard.
He's got a trick and like there's like a rope connected or it's hard.
And then the same time, I believe.
I mean, according to the to the law, if you dive into that rabbit hole, I think there's a lot of disinformation campaign surrounding U.A.P.'s psionic stuff.
Right. I think there is because the the the organization that they use these things that works on on it, they don't want everybody to have access to it.
Right. So they perhaps use this information campaign to discrete state.
Oh, yeah. The validity of the one that are real.
Right. Correct. One hundred percent. You don't want to put that past them.
It's they are the smartest intelligence agencies.
You know, it's they have all the money.
The military has all the money.
And they're going right to, you know, out of university, grabbing mental level geniuses and grabbing like, you know, the best Ivy League intelligence people at a school and recruiting them into these three letter agencies.
Of course, you know, they got the smartest people working on this.
And their whole job is to figure out every variable.
Right. So like every scenario possible.
Like they I guarantee you they've got probably a dozen doomsday scenarios of what if zombies, you know, like they have everything.
Right. So for sure, anything we speculate, they've probably thought of.
We're not faster than them. Yeah.
I mean, talking to to Lazar, Lou Elizondo and all the guys I've met during my my my trip in Washington.
One thing they a lot of them told me is that everything is very comfort, comfort mentalized.
Yes. So nobody really know the old the entire picture.
I mean, there must be someone.
I mean, one thing I've I've I've been told is like the last president to have been brief on on this matter is George Bush, senior.
Yeah. Because he was the head of CIA.
But after that, because a president in the United States, for example, is the most powerful man on a hurt.
People say he's really but he come in and goes every four years.
So if they tell him everything, maybe he's going to spill the bean.
Like it's also for a security reason.
You know, like you never know if he you know, mental illness, you become crazy.
You just say out loud the secret that that protect North America or, you know, the United States or also a plausible deniability.
Yeah. So there's a reason they don't tell the president because if something comes out and the president during a press conference, they go, hey, what about UAPs?
He has to lie now in front of people.
Right. So it's better to not tell him because he has plausible deniability.
He can say, I didn't know if anything goes wrong.
God, man, I want to believe.
But, man, it's hard.
It's hard until you don't have the perfect evidence.
But I want to believe, man.
I really that's a problem.
I want to believe.
But that does not make it true.
You know, sometimes when you want something to happen, you see it from your your perceptions linked everything towards that.
But that doesn't mean it's really what is happening.
God, I really want to believe.
And one guy I would I mean, because of the war, I might be point point out by the finger saying this, but fuck it.
I'm going to say one guy I would like to ask the question.
And I think one person that would know the most most of this answer is maybe Vladimir Putin.
Oh, yeah. Is the is in the KGB.
Yes. I think you would know if there's someone that knows a lot about this.
So that would be him. Yes.
One hundred percent. And I can promise you, if I ever meet him, I will ask him the question.
I will even if I look like an idiot and, you know, I would freaking do it.
And I don't know if I will be able to say what he told me.
You know, if I have a chance, man, that would be like if I meet someone like like like him, I would freaking ask him like like I would say, can I can I talk to you for a second one on one?
I will. Maybe he's not going to say it to me with the truth or maybe he will thinking that, oh, I'm going to say it to him.
Because even if he comes out public, it's like maybe like the guys in Washington, maybe that's the way they were thinking.
Explaining to me the whole thing is like, oh, if he come out public and say everything that we told him, he's going to hurt his credibility.
So he's not going to say it regardless.
You know, unless he's a fool, you know. Yeah.
Or maybe it softens the blow. Maybe it's like, oh, let him say it first.
Yeah, but man, I'm not the one who's going to say it now.
Now the people are going to think I'm brain damaged big time if I you know what I mean.
But that's fascinating.
Putin definitely knows, by the way.
And so does and so does senior president of China as well.
And these guys have been in power for too long.
The president of China, you think? Oh, absolutely.
So Putin, the president of China, is George George Bush senior still alive?
Right. I don't think so.
Is he? I'm sorry for my. I don't even know.
That's a good question. I'm not sure if he would.
He would maybe know. Is George Bush senior still alive?
We're both Canadian, so we can be forgiven on.
No, he had 2018. Yeah.
You know, Paul Elyar, the former minister of Canada.
Yeah, he came out publicly saying crazy claims.
I mean, this is this is a fact. He says that we're not alone.
There's even like 60 freaking insane.
Like did he lost his mind or is he does he has strong evidence or he says that he what?
Man, it's hard to know now.
But, man, there's a lot of credible people that came out publicly.
One of the Israeli.
I'm a shed. I'm a shed.
Yeah. Like, what is his position?
He was the Israeli space in charge of the Israeli Israeli space program.
He was the he's the father of the Israeli space programs.
He put up 13 satellites into space and he was awarded the highest awards by military and and civilian awards for some of his things.
And the awards that he got in the military side are classified.
We don't know why he got those awards, but he got the awards.
We don't know what the awards are for. So he's a credible source.
And what did he say exactly? He says that there's a Galactic Federation.
Yeah. It's like Star Wars.
Paul Hellyer said the same thing.
And now, you know, who knows?
Because the other thing is that we have to understand is that there are people who are fascinated with this topic that work in the government, too.
Right. So they're human.
These people, you know, there are some people who want to believe that are in government.
These people are perfect.
So, you know, when I think of like even Stargate, there was General I'm forgetting his name.
He was a stubble bind and he loved the remote viewing stuff.
He was like, you know, but he loved it too much to where they were like, all right, we're going to make you retire now because it's like you're going in too deep.
You want to believe too much. And now there's this bias.
It affects your judgment.
So I am a shed is friends with Yuri Geller, very close friends.
Right. So in my head, I instantly that's a bit of a red flag for me, even though Yuri Geller, some of the claims he has, I believe could be true.
I still think that there's this sensationalist ideology that might exist here that might skew a little bit of the information that they're that they're given.
And because they're in a position where we would trust them, they can say anything.
And now we kind of take it as the word. Right.
And I think we need to be careful with that, too, because I think in our government, especially especially in the Republican side of the government, there's a lot of faith based culture.
Yes. And so dangerous. Yeah.
And so, you know, when you're talking about NHI and all of this, you know, it gets to a place where some of them want to believe more than others.
Yeah. And we just have to be aware of that, too.
So it's like, yes, on one hand, it's very hard to get clean information. Yeah.
Which is why I think the best thing that we can do, you and I and the people watching is try these things for ourselves.
Try remote viewing. Try out a body experiences.
Go into a field and try to see E5, a UFO or, you know, do these experiences yourself, because no matter what I tell you, no matter how much data I show you or what type of trick I can do for you.
It's not going to convince you unless you see it yourself.
One of the arguments that a lot of scientists will say to counter the existence of NHI non-human intelligence, that would be like, oh, where are the evidence?
The cell phone? I'm like, there's freaking tons of it, bro.
There's tons of video that people film the orbs, but all those videos, they're not clear.
Like, they're not like, if I would film you like this, like they're sort of blurry.
Or if you look at the UFO, most of the time you see the edges sort of blurry and the explanation, according to ufologists, they would say, oh, it's because the distortion of space and time in which these vehicles are, you know,
are functioning with, I'm like, shit, I want it to be true, man.
I will continue my quest in the pursuit of truth.
But frick, man, it's hard to know. It's hard to...
It's fun.
Oh, it's fun. It's a lot of fun.
But talking to a lot of the people in that field through all these years, I mean, apparently there's two schools of thought.
There's a group of people that really want full disclosure on that matter because they're concerned.
They have kids. They're concerned about the future.
And a lot of the guy in Washington have thought they want full disclosure.
And there is another group, apparently, too, that do not want disclosure because a lot of people, they harm a lot of people and they will be accounted for a lot of the pain, a lot of the things they've done.
And I hope it's not the case, but maybe we will have to wait until those people that are accounted for the harm they've done passed out before we move to a full disclosure.
I don't know, but...
Yeah, like there's the cover-up is covering up the crimes.
Yes, like a little bit like the JFK file that soon will be probably public.
They say one of the arguments, I think, is Trump's was saying is he needs to wait that all the people passed out because a lot of harm has been done.
But you don't want to tarnish the reputation of a living person.
You want to wait that it's finished until you... I mean, is it true or not?
You also have the families of those people, like the Bush family is still around.
I don't know if it's Trump who said it or if it's someone that said it, that he said it.
Like, that's the consensus on it.
But is it the same thing with disclosure?
Because if you dive into this thing and from what I've learned, a lot of people got hurt, man.
They did a lot of bad stuff to acquire knowledge and control.
And if the whole thing is real, it's freaking dark, man.
Yeah, dark, scary.
I mean, the one thing I always come back to that always kind of glitches in my head is the people who want to know want everyone to know.
And then the people who know want no one to know.
So if I take that information, I look at it, and I'm like, what is so bad about the information that once you understand what it is, you don't want anyone else to know about it?
And that's a scary thought experiment to be like, damn, what could that be?
And you know what I keep thinking back to and more and more as this goes on is like, do you see Three Body Problem?
No.
So Three Body Problem is a book that they did, which eventually turned into a Netflix thing.
And it's the idea that this civilization that is far away receives a signal.
And it's kind of like the alone in the forest theory where like, you don't want to make noise in the forest.
Because if a predator sees you, he's going to come towards you.
And that's kind of what happened.
And now they send us a message saying like, all right, you got 40 years and we'll be there in 40 years.
We're on our way.
Yeah.
And now we've got 40 years to figure this problem out before they get here and advance our tech and like, you know, I mean, it's all science fiction, but who knows?
Look, man, there's something attached to this that a lot of the people that study that phenomenon believe that since the invention and the detonation of the atomic bomb,
a lot of the sensitive military installation and even a lot of the guys confirmed it.
They think that a lot of the sensitive military installation that contain nuclear weapons are monitored by these things.
And apparently, according to a report, like a real report, they have the capability, these UAP, to shut it off or shut it, put it on as they wish to control remotely on and off switch.
Like these freaking installation.
That is fucking crazy, man, if it turns out to be true.
I mean, the report are there.
It's supposed to be in Russia and America.
And that's the thing in a court of law.
This would be enough to be an evidence for it to be true.
But because that subject is so stigmatized, man, it's so crazy.
There's even an agreement between Russia and America.
Pull this up with Lou.
We looked at it.
There's an agreement.
There's all sorts of agreements.
Like if they start their nuclear thing, like they have to let us know.
There's like this whole thing.
And on one of the stipulations, it says they have to call each other if ever an unidentified object is picked up on radar because they don't want to mistake it for an attack.
So if it says for any unidentified objects, like they have to like pick up the phone and be like, was that you?
And they're like, no, that was not.
So like, OK, it was a UFO, kind of like scratch that off.
So like, it's been a problem for them, apparently.
I would just put it out there.
I mean, if there's a disclosure coming up publicly, as a public figure, I'm ready to say what I know.
You know what I mean?
Because I don't have, you know, I'm just a freaking former retired athlete.
You know, I'm not an astrophysicist, but to make the subject more volatile for people to bring eyeballs on the subject, I'm ready to, you know what I mean?
To help disclosure, because I think it's important.
I think it could change the world for the best.
But I'm not ready to go by myself in the front line because, man, if you do that, your credibility, everything will be attacked like freaking crazy.
And I still don't know for a fact, what I've heard and learned, did they mess up with me?
Is it a freaking joke?
Because people make jokes sometimes or whatever.
You know, like, it's a very interesting thing, man.
But I really love to dive into it.
And it's, man, I really hope, and according to a lot of people I've talked, and I'm sure you did in our living, there will be, we will have undiable proof that there's something.
And I just can't wait this to happen.
Maybe even sooner than later.
I think so.
George, I have one last thing we're going to do here.
Well, two last things.
I would love for you to sign these books in a second.
Of course.
And we're going to do some giveaways.
One of them is for me and then two of them is for the audience here.
But before we get into that, we have Patreon members or members.
Of course.
We call them interns.
Yes.
And we let them ask, so I choose three questions.
Oh, sure, for sure.
And we're going to pull it up here.
Give me a second.
I have to turn this camera on back here.
All right.
Thank you.
So the first question we have here is a picture.
A secret tunnel is his handle.
And it's going to come up behind me.
In your research in archaeology, have you found anything resembling giant humanoids?
Well, there's a lot of text that talks about it like the Anunnaki, the Nephilim, even in
Christianity.
Is it true or not?
I want it to be true, but just because I want it doesn't make it true.
It's all about an interpretation.
If you look at the Sumerian text, there's different interpretation.
There's one interpretation made by Zechariah Sitchin that talks about the Anunnaki that
he believes that there was a race of aliens that were giant that engineered us.
And it's in a nutshell.
That's what he believes.
But he was attacked by a lot of people.
And a lot of people tried to debunk him.
And some of the things he said turns out to be...
Some of the things he says, it's hard to dismiss.
Now in the future, it turns out to be real.
Like the asteroid belt and the formation of the Tiamat, Marduk.
So it's hard to defer what is real, what is not.
What is an interpretation?
I wanted to believe, but yeah, it's a trend among certain ancient texts.
The interpretation of certain ancient texts that maybe once upon a time it was like a giant.
But I think we need to have our strong evidence.
I know there's a lot of things online that says they found bones of giant.
But man, why is it hidden?
Yeah, where is that?
Yeah, man, why don't you put it out?
And there's a conspiracy like, oh, they hide it.
I mean, I don't know.
Well, there's the Afghan giant.
Remember that story?
They're the soldier.
Yeah, they all have red hair.
They shot down this 13-foot tall, apparently killed one with a spear.
And then they just mowed him down and helicoptered him out.
What was interesting about that is that, first of all, it happened in a modern era.
And there were a lot of people that came out on Coast to Coast AM talking about that they've seen it,
which is like military people, which is interesting.
But again, like you said, give us a picture, give us something.
Give us something, man.
Why there's no freaking strong evidence?
You know what I mean?
I don't know what to make of it.
I don't want to be the first to go publicly saying, oh, I believe in it or not, because I don't.
I think I'm very septic.
I entertain the idea of it.
It would be cool, but I don't fully believe in it.
I mean, it's interesting.
I read a lot about it.
It's not something that when I see an article about it, it's not something that I'm like, oh, it's bullshit.
I like to read it just to amuse me.
And then I'm like, it's interesting.
I keep it in the back of my head, but I don't fully believe it.
And I don't reject it either.
I just put it on the side.
You know what I mean?
That's the healthiest way, I think, to approach a lot of this thing.
I think a lot of people could learn from that because being extreme one way or the other is no good.
Staying in a relatively realistic ideology, I think that's probably...
I agree.
All right.
We have next here Maverick Star.
We talked about this.
So this is an interesting question.
You actually had mentioned this.
So I guess we've already answered this.
But have you ever felt as if you knew what was going to happen in a fight before it did?
Yes.
Sometimes in fights when you're in the zone and being in the zone is not too much.
It's not too much being too much focus.
Because if you're too focused, you lose how much time there is on the clock.
You lose what your coach are saying to you because they have a different perspective.
And it's important to hear.
You lose also because I speak English.
I speak a little bit of Portuguese and Spanish.
I can understand sometimes like the basic.
Yes.
So it's an advantage for me because they don't understand me, but I understand them.
So I know when they say, for example, for example, I'm on the ground.
Cotovel is an elbow or a shaft of brass, like an armbar.
I know when they're calling something, they're going to try something.
I know before it comes.
So is it because it's deduction?
When you're in the states of flow, you don't want to be, like I said, too focused because you miss those cues.
And you don't want to be too distracted because you can get caught with something you don't see coming.
You want to be in the flow zone.
I don't know if it's because of it.
Do you feel it though?
I feel it, but I have no evidence to prove you.
It's an intuition more than a deduction.
You know, it's interesting because I felt when I'm in that state, the best of that state, it's when my fighters flight,
when I'm the most afraid because it triggers something very basic to my core.
Maybe it links to the reason why the psionic team, apparently they try to recruit kids that are autism,
that don't have the ability to speak and that are in a very poor and dangerous environment.
Maybe after a disaster, that's why they recruit those.
Maybe that's the case because I know that when I'm scared and it triggers something survival, I get into that state better.
So that's why when I say I'm not afraid to admit that I'm afraid, it's because I know that my fear will enhance me and I embrace it.
Some people, the fear, it paralyzes them.
Me, I'm like, I fucking love it.
I don't love it, but I know I need it to be at my best, so I embrace it.
That's so sick.
That's all you need to think when you go into a fight because you need to learn how to control it.
That's really interesting.
I could talk about this for forever.
During remote viewing stuff and even psionic stuff, Jake Barber talked about a way to shortcut the psionic is to add trauma.
So to put you in a state of fear.
So he mentioned that.
Really?
Yes, absolutely.
That could be interesting.
His interview with Jesse Michaels.
Oh yeah, he said the fighter's flight thing.
They would induce fear.
They would induce, actively give them drugs to be more afraid and then calm them and then play this line.
Because maybe the reptilian part of your brain kicks in.
And has access to the survival.
And sometimes in order to survive, you have to know what's going to happen a second in the future.
And so that's kind of where they're trying to tap into.
From remote viewing, all of the most successful remote viewings happened when it was human life at stake.
Or when there was like a large amount of entropy, big change.
So that's why they would have a really easy time finding nukes with this stuff.
So it's almost like the universe wants you to survive.
And you are the universe.
So you're tapping into that to help you survive, help you evolve, help you see forward a little bit.
And they give you that edge of probability on that quantum scale to help you get to that next level that you want to get to.
So it's very, very small.
But I mean, I think nonetheless.
That's a very interesting theory.
I mean, if you believe in that stuff, it makes sense.
I mean, I wanted to believe and I wanted to be true.
And maybe that's one of the reasons I was doing so well in my career.
You tapped into this.
I tapped into this.
Or maybe it's because by pure hard work and training, I've seen devil's pattern and I was by deduction.
Like an AI type of...
But maybe it's something else.
I don't have the answer.
I've done it, but I don't have the answer.
And I wish I could.
And I want to learn more about it too.
You know, like I told you, like to tap into this thing if it is the case, if there is something to it.
Yeah.
And that's the best thing to do too is check it out for yourself.
Last question here.
And I think this is by...
I think I forget K.
I forget your name.
But I don't think there was enough room on the split flap.
It says, is information or alternative theories being suppressed in the mainstream archeology community?
I think so.
And the reason is...
Let's talk about Gobekli Tepe.
Okay.
It's...
Now they know it's at least like almost...
It's 11, 600 or 12...
I mean, around 12,000 years ago.
Before that, before it was discovered, it was to the mind of archeologists,
it was impossible that Antargetter could build these sort of things.
Because in their mind, they needed to have agriculture to settle themselves,
to have abundance of food before they can do certain things like this.
Like Gobekli Tepe, it's an incredible site.
It's pillars with carvings of animals.
It's an alignment, an astronomical alignment.
That is unbelievable.
I think a big part of it is still not uncovered yet.
So we don't know what it is, what the full thing, the full site look like.
But from what they have discovered, it changes everything that we knew about our ancestor.
So in the mainstream, if all your life you spend time to follow one narrative,
and now out of sudden, boom, the whole thing changes.
If you attach certain emotion to what you read,
it could be bad because you're attached to that truth, and now that truth is no longer real.
And I think a lot of, not all, but I think certain maybe archeologists could have an issue
detaching emotionally from an ideology that they've been fed all their career.
And you have to accept the fact that, shit, there's something new, now we need to change.
I know that a good archeologist do that.
The one, they do it, they go only with facts, fact check.
They attach no emotion because it's only an idea.
If you've been taught something and you teach it and you found out it's wrong,
it takes a lot of ego.
You have to work on your ego telling, hey, finally what I taught you is wrong.
We learned recently that this is what happened.
I mean, there's a lot of emotion and money linked into that story.
So when something changed the old paradigm, it shaped up a lot of people.
Same thing with Clovis first.
In archeology, before, they thought that humans, it was a false point.
At the point of the spear, they thought human came in only a few thousand years in America.
Then they found out, oh, you got pushed back by the Clovis.
Now they know that Clovis first, it was sort of a doctrine.
It was like nobody, yeah, it's impossible.
You're never going to find any older remain of humans before Clovis because there were no Clovis.
It was like a doctrine.
Like Grandma and Cuck talk about it.
And they freaking found some that are even older than Clovis.
Now they know that there were humans in America before Clovis.
And they might find in the future even older, older, older.
So they keep pushing back the date.
And it shook the entire theory of how humans arrive in North America by the Bering Strait.
And at the time, they arrived because now what we thought it was turns out to be wrong.
It's much older than what we thought.
And the more we dig in, the more we find stuff.
And I think it's excited.
But for some people, it's frustrating.
And I don't think you should attach any emotion to this.
It's just knowledge.
Just information.
Yeah.
And what you know sometimes can be turned out to be wrong.
Same thing in training.
Like stuff that I used to do back then, I thought was good.
Now I know is wrong.
And I change it.
I don't attach any emotion.
I'm not stubborn and say, oh, I'm continue to do this because I want to improve.
And then I have to accept like, shit, what I was doing was wrong.
So, OK, I stopped doing it and I improve.
You know, in sport, that's why people ask me very often, oh, is the fighter todays are better than the one in your time?
And I think, yes.
The reason is not because the guys are better.
It's because the knowledge and the technology improve.
Humans were the same.
We're the same human.
But our knowledge and technology improve.
And therefore, guys got better.
They got better performance.
And in a sport like combat sport, you cannot measure the result.
But in, for example, in the races or lifting, you have data.
You know that, for example, Usain Bolt beat Jesse Owen.
But did he beat him because he's better or did he beat him because he had the shoes?
He was running on the different surface.
The right training.
He also had the departure block that Jesse Owen did not have.
He had the, you know, now, you know, like they use a lot of technology and knowledge that they didn't have back then.
Yeah.
So if you give that to Jesse Owen, maybe he would have been better than Usain Bolt.
Who knows? Maybe not.
Maybe yes.
So same thing in combat sport.
I believe the performance got better.
The future generation will be better.
Not because they're really better, just because they have more access to better technology and knowledge.
You think there's a peak to that?
It's a good question.
Can we become like the peak performance athlete?
I'm a pure risk.
I'm against the idea of equipment.
I know it's a freaking business, but I think it's wrong.
So you can measure it better?
I think guys should be fighting maybe in shorts, bare hands, like he used to be.
I think sprinters should sprint barefoot.
No freaking departure block on the same surface they always run, because it affects the data.
If you give a better surface, a surface that is harder, that has more respawn when you run,
therefore it messed up the result because the one that didn't run on that surface has a disadvantage.
The shoes change everything.
The grip of the shoes, the departure block, it gives you the kick in the beginning.
I just take race as an example because more people know about racing than anything else.
But fighting is the same thing.
You use performance enhancing drug or you use different equipment.
Excuse the data.
It's fucked up.
But we live in a world that we want to see the record being broken.
And it's our nature.
We want to go further and better and better and better.
I understand it.
And it's a lot of money attached to it, to the equipment.
It's a business.
But as a pure risk, I don't like to see it.
But I have to make up with it because that's the reality I live in.
Wow. Great answer.
I never actually gave that some thought.
I've thought about that too.
Is Sidney Crosby better than Wayne Gretzky?
Is Wayne Gretzky better than Gordie Howe?
But it really comes down to the improvement of equipment, the improvement of how you train,
what you're training, and little minute things over time that are shifted a little bit.
But yeah, they're not on an even playing field, so hard to measure.
I went to the Raptors because I give speeches to the teams, sometimes to professional teams.
And man, they have certain technology.
The Raptors, for example, they know where they're more likely to score when they take a shot than other place on the field.
Like they have some freaking data that is just unbelievable.
So they know that if they pass the ball in that sort of area and they have a guy that shoots in,
they're more likely to because everything is measured.
It's freaking crazy.
And it's knowledge. Knowledge is a weapon.
Technology and knowledge is a weapon.
That's how Alexander the Great, Genghis Khan, the Romans, the Second World War was won because of knowledge and technology.
And the same thing in my fights. I had knowledge.
I was a very good athlete, but I didn't became champion because I was the best athlete.
There were guys that were better athlete than me.
There's a guy that I work hard, but I'm sure there's a guy that worked just as hard and maybe harder than me.
I work smart, but there's guys that work smart.
But I was very lucky to have the influence and certain contact that gave me the knowledge that I have.
And that's, I think, one of the main reasons why I was successful.
And in warfare and in life, even as an entrepreneur, I think it's a key.
When you get knowledge and you know how to use it, you can be successful.
I mean, that and I will say your humility is also something that yourself you won't go and talk about
because it's hard to talk about oneself as being humble.
But you're a very humble person and in victory in all the successes.
And I think that as well makes you stand out, not only as an athlete, but as a human being.
So I think that that's really commendable as well.
Thank you, man. Thank you, Chris.
I'm happy we crossed paths and I got to know you, man.
And it's fun, man. It's fun.
And I'm looking forward to these experiments that I'm willing to try to psionic stuff.
I'm curious and I want to know if there is something to be done because you convinced me of the possibility.
I wouldn't say the truth because I don't know if it's true, but the possibility because my mind was a little bit closed before.
But the possibility that that could be enhanced.
And if that's the case, man, man, I want to be part of it.
I want to want to know.
Georges Saint-Pierre, thank you very much for talking to me today.
Thank you to you. Thank you for having received me and also for introducing me to Lou Elizondo.
For me, it was very important.
It's a great pleasure and to all the Quebec fans who are listening to us right now.
It's probably a shock to hear me speak French, but I think it's mandatory too.
I didn't know you speak French before I met you.
And you speak like like perfect. I was like shit. I'm like, I don't know.
Maybe one day we'll do another podcast in French just for the Quebecers.
Of course, but the audience is bigger in English. It's normal. Absolutely.
Thank you, Georges. Guys, if you want to pick up, if you want to get one of these signed copies,
we're going to be giving two away, one to the patrons.
So if you want to increase your chances, five bucks a month, you get some extra content.
Check out the memberships or the Patreon or we're going to also give one away to the general comments.
So simply leave a comment below and let us know what your favorite part of the interview was.
Maybe something you learned about, Georges, you didn't before.
And I'll pick one of you guys to win these. Thanks so much.
Alright, Georges. So this is for me and this is for the other people here.
Ah, yes.
Thank you.