When discussing UFO legacy programs, I aim to expose any clandestine, black-budget U.S.
government military intelligence operation, partnering with defense contractors, federally
funded research and development centers, and university-affiliated research centers engaging
with non-human technology. These programs seem to take many forms, including crash recovery of
non-human vehicles, material exploitation of technologies of unknown origin, reverse engineering
of anomalous craft, and construction of copycat vehicles famously known as alien reproduction
vehicles, ARVs. On this channel, we have discussed myriad major range and test facility bases and
defense laboratories and centers where such programs are likely located. We have also
discussed at length contractors, FFRDCs, and UARCs that are alleged to operate alongside the
CIA and NSA across Army, Navy, and Air Force UFO programs. When such clandestine and secretive
operations to master non-human technology have led to, in David Grush's words, a multi-decade
secret Cold War, where might these programs be located? The logistics of maintaining secrecy and
strict need-to-know access for unacknowledged special access programs focused on anomalous
research, development, test, and evaluation of non-human technologies and storage of non-human
craft and possibly biologics are likely tremendous. For this reason, we must look underground and
evaluate the decades of rumors and testimonies of UFOs and deep underground military bases or DUMs.
DUMs have served as a continuous focus of this channel with recent discussion
and direct investigation into Dugway Proving Ground. The United States premier chemical
and biological testing range and its alleged 1,300 square mile subterranean facility and
remote entrance in the desert. For this investigation, we will be continuously referencing
the work of Dr. Richard Sautter and his three masterpieces titled, Underground Bases and Tunnels,
What is the Government Trying to Hide, Hidden in Plain Sight Beyond the X-Files,
and Underground and Underwater Bases. These three dense pieces give us keen context into
subterranean bases in the form of stringent fact-based analysis through publicly available
records, FOIA documents, declassified documents, and the occasional witness testimony.
Deep underground military bases do indeed exist. This is fact and we will explore this fact today,
but do these sites engage with UFO legacy programs? And if so, which DOD sites and
what do they do? And could the decades of rumors regarding underground tunnels connecting these
clandestine sites through an internal rail system possibly be true? Hey guys, it's UAP Gurb and thank
you so very much for joining me today as we embark into the world of the subterranean to investigate
Dumbs and UFOs. The subject of UFO legacy sites embedded into mountains with hidden hangars,
sequestered a mile beneath the earth's surface, or hidden anywhere out of the public and satellite
view has long been a talking point of this channel in my investigations. Today, we finally look below
the earth's surface to evaluate the existence, feasibility, and operations of UFO legacy programs
and deep underground military bases.
To borrow from the title of the first chapter of Dr. Richard Sauter's underground bases and tunnels,
deep underground military bases are indeed real. Throughout this project, I will be interchangeably
using the terms DUMB and subterranean facility or STIF, the name said to me by multiple veterans
who have traveled to such underground locations. And speaking of, I should mention, I have spoken
to nearly half a dozen former military personnel who have traveled to STIFs across the country.
I try to shy away from inserting first-hand source testimony and anecdotes into my videos and let
evidence and research speak for itself, so I will interject with these first-hand testimonies when
and if necessary. In a 1989 speech titled, Underground Facilities for Defense, Experience
and Lessons, Deputy Director of Engineering and Construction for the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
Lloyd A. Dusha said, quote, After World War II, political and economic factors changed the
underground construction picture and caused a renewed interest to think underground. As a
result of this interest, the Corps of Engineers became involved in the design and construction
of some very complex and interesting military projects, end quote. In the same talk, Dusha
would then go on to exclaim, quote, Although the conference program indicates the topic to be
underground facilities for defense, experience and lessons, I must deviate a little because several
of the most interesting facilities that have been designed and constructed by the Corps are still
classified, end quote. Acknowledged military subterranean facilities do indeed exist.
Publicly known sites include the NORAD Cheyenne Mountain Complex buried deep under Colorado
Springs. This enormous installation, built to monitor North American missile threats,
sits 2,000 feet underground and spans 5.1 acres, featuring six three-story high and 40-foot wide
tunnels and 15 three-story buildings made of steel plates. And these are just the acknowledged
portions of the base. Additionally, the Raven Rock Complex, aka Site R, serves as a secure
underground command center or backup pentagon and is shrouded in mystery. This site under Fort
Detrick, Maryland, includes accommodations for 3,000 people, has an in-built medical and dental
clinic, fire department, post office and five acknowledged three-story buildings. The secrets
Raven Rock must hold are endless. But existing acknowledged dumps are not the focus of today's
investigation. Instead, we plan to pursue dumps that operate as UFO legacy program locations and
explore the feasibility of decades of rumors of hundreds, if not thousands of miles of underground
tunnels and railroads connecting deep underground UFO legacy operations. To once again quote U.S.
Army Corps of Engineers Deputy Director for Engineering and Construction Lloyd A. Dusha
when speaking about the Corps' involvement in the 1960s construction of the Cheyenne site, quote,
As stated earlier, there are other projects of similar scope, which I cannot identify,
but which include multiple chambers up to 50 feet wide and 100 feet high,
using the same excavation procedure mentioned for the NORAD facility, end quote. After all,
according to a 1985 U.S. Army Corps of Engineers report titled Literature Survey of Underground
Construction Methods for Application to Hardened Facilities, STIFs can be built anywhere with the
right amount of money and in myriad types of structures utilizing deep shaft structures and
facilities tunneled into mountainsides. The report even states, quote,
Since adequate technology is available to construct hardened underground facilities
under virtually any ground conditions, the main constraint in construction projects remains
economic viability rather than technical feasibility, end quote. As we know from David
Grush and multiple other sources and testimonies, UFO legacy programs operate on the U.S. Black
Untraceable, deep-sixed money and contracts buried within special access, controlled access,
and unacknowledged special access programs. From the excellent work of Catherine Austin Fitz I
mention often, we also know that as much as $21 trillion in unauthorized spending has occurred
between 1998 and 2015, and this is just within the DOD and Department of Housing and Urban
Development, much of which Fitz believed was designated for clandestine military R&D.
Publicly denied UFO research development test and evaluation underground locations would
absolutely classify as such. Dums for clandestine and unacknowledged use is also a practice very
much currently in play. One such example is Warrington U.S. Army Training Center located
in the Northern Virginia town of Warrington. The book, The Secret Team, the CIA and its allies
in control of the world by Fletcher Prouty, identified a highly secretive underground
installation that serves as a federal relocation center by an unknown agency. This was confirmed
in an Inquiry Magazine article titled Going Underground by Robert Walters, which plainly
states the U.S. Army Warrington Training Center is a CIA covert facility. Additionally, there is the
highly secretive U.S. Navy underground facility in the mountains of West Virginia near Sugar Grove.
This location is an underground site run by the Navy for the National Security Agency,
so the NSA and CIA already have a traceable interest in using U.S. military bases underground
facilities as a cover for unknown usage and operations. So before discussing much of the
testimony of UFOs and Dums, let's quickly touch on the reality and history of these impressive,
often unacknowledged sites.
The inception of Dums in the United States can actually be traced back to the Nazis,
an Operation Paperclip, the famous program to recruit Nazi scientists,
engineers and technicians into U.S. government employment. Near the end of World War II,
the Nazis had begun utilization of what we might call Dums. In the book Lucky Forward,
The History of Patton's Third Army, Colonel Robert S. Allen detailed allied discoveries of
Nazi underground bases.
Some Nazi installations were over 50 feet underground, comprised of several miles of
two- to three-story facilities. The sites were arranged like wheels with spokes designed with
reinforced concrete. The Nazis designed such locations as Ordov to house Nazi high command
after the bombing of Berlin but never got the chance to populate the facility. We additionally
have the Regenwurm Lager or Earthworm Camp in Poland. This Nazi sprawling underground complex
beneath West Poland's full extent is still unknown today. The site featured miles of
underground tunnels and electrical train lines connecting bunkers, fortifications and other
critical military facilities. This sounds familiar, no? Two declassified documents can be discovered
dating back to 1947 regarding the aforementioned Operation Paperclip. Featured in the documents are
requests by Air Material Command for a quote-unquote requirement of four German technicians to consult
on a planned underground plant program. One man named was Xavier Dorsch, director of the
TOT organization in the closing of World War II. This was the Nazis' equivalent of the U.S. Navy
Seabees or U.S. Army Corps of Engineers but not part of formal German military structure.
The founder of this organization, Fritz TOT, designed the famous German Autobahn Highway system.
Towards the tail end of World War II, Dorsch had helped with developing a series of massive
underground industrial manufacturing facilities to hide from allied bombing raids. It is indeed
quite possible he also aided on the Regenwurm Lager and Ordov. Documents and research show Dorsch
once briefed the Americans after he was captured in 1945 and again in 1949. We do not know the
full extent to which he aided in these programs. These massive Nazi underground industrial
manufacturing facilities possibly give us our first look into UFO legacy programs and dumbs.
I have covered on this channel the 1933 Magenta Italy UFO crash retrieval, a case whose validity
is strongly supported by David Grush. You say it's a 90-year cover-up. Just about, yeah. 90 years.
1933 was the first recovery in Europe in Magenta Italy. They recovered a partially intact vehicle.
In this case, the Nazis purportedly took control of a crashed lenticular disk from the Italians
in 1943 before being recovered by the Americans post-war. Hans Komler was a Nazi engineer behind
construction of numerous concentration camps including Auschwitz and led myriad Nazi secret
weapons projects. Komler would have indeed been one of chief scientists and engineers to study
a recovered lenticular craft due to his unrivaled command over Nazi secret weapons programs.
Komler went missing near the tail end of World War II. However, documents prove rather convincingly
this evil engineer was taken alive into U.S. custody. Albert Speer, Nazi and Reich minister
of armaments and war production, claimed in April 1945, Komler informed him he had business
to offer the Americans. OSS agent Donald W. Richardson seemingly confirmed this by stating
70 years after, he still couldn't fully speak on interrogating Komler. But the Nazis had brought
treasure to the U.S. that, quote, served the development of armament platforms for the Cold
War and for the future, end quote. Under Komler's command, numerous underground tunnels and bases
existed employing German companies to develop and build parts for advanced aircraft and secret
weapons programs. Komler is even said to have stashed treasures and documents regarding his
think tank's top secret documents in a facility underground in the woods of Czechoslovakia.
According to Hidden Nazi by Dan Ruder, 44 years after Operation Hidden Documents to retrieve these
stashed top secret documents, an American team from Lawrence Livermore Labs and Los Alamos Labs,
two FFRDCs, went to a new underground cavern that had not been emptied at the end of World War II
called Mednic Hill. What was found here was, quote, the key to what was hidden at the previous site,
end quote. It goes without saying it stands to reason Komler conducted early iterations of UFO
legacy programs underneath Mednic Hill, as well as his numerous underground locations and tunnels,
and that Xavier Dorsch was a key engineer in constructing these facilities. With Dorsch being
requested by Air Material Command and Komler being more than likely secretly smuggled by the
Americans, these two men could very well be the key architects of modern-day U.S.,
UFO, and dumb legacy programs. I am no expert in history, so to learn more about Komler,
I strongly recommend watching the documentary The Two Lives of Hans Komler. Later in this project,
we will see even more ties between Nazi Germany, Dums, and Paperclip, then in the form of Maglev
train systems. On numerous occasions in the 1950s, the United States proposed massive
underground facilities that seemingly disappeared from public light. It is unknown if many of these
facilities were built or not. One example can be traced to 1957 to Green Mountain outside Huntsville,
Alabama. Huntsville is deeply enshrouded in U.S. antigravity research, but we are looking elsewhere.
Two articles in 1957 reported the U.S. Army was planning to build a rocket factory
inside of Green Mountain. The plan was proposed by the American Machine and Foundry Company,
Redstone Arsenal, and the Army Ballistic Missile Agency. This location was slated to have a sort
of subterranean junior pentagon where elaborate headquarters would be installed to direct the
defense of the southern U.S. from enemy attack. Again, it is unknown if this location was ever
built. However, such discussion of a junior pentagon illustrated early private military
cooperation, a theme we will touch on much more, much later. Analysis of U.S. military
and underground studies additionally allows us valuable insights into Dums. Take the Rand
Corporation, for example. An FFRDC I have spoken about ad nauseam is a primary semi-government
institution up to its eyeballs in UFO legacy programs. Rand Corporation was established in
1948 and grew out of Army Air Force Project Rand in 1946. Project Rand sought to carry out
long-range research projects of interest to the Air Force. In the 1950s, Yousaf and Rand began
working on the question of underground-based construction and organized various symposiums.
Let's analyze a resulting 1959 publication, Deep Underground Construction. The purpose of such a
symposium, according to the chairman, was to discuss, quote, the problems of protecting
military installations located deep underground or under mountains, end quote, in the event of nuclear
war. The chairman also stated since 1957 the Rand Corp had been, quote, actively investigating the
need for a small number of super hard deep underground centers, end quote. Additionally,
in 1960, Rand published a study under Yousaf's contract dealing 12 locations for underground
sites. All sites were assumed to be more than 1,000 feet deep. Of specific interest here is
Site 3 in Santa Barbara, California. Santa Barbara is located just over 100 miles from the Antelope
Valley, California, we will discuss later. Research suggests a major network of UFO-focused
stiff facilities exists interconnected under the Antelope. Site 3 is also located less than 100
miles away from Los Angeles, where a tremendous amount of DoD research development test and
evaluation laboratories lie. We have already mentioned the U.S. Army Corps of Engineer giving
in 1989 a quite frank admission of classified underground facilities. And outside of the 1987
U.S. Army Corps of Engineer report detailing construction of dumps boils down to cost. In 1959
to 1961, the Army Corps of Engineer published a five-part training manual titled Design of
Underground Installations in Rock. This startling series assumes the pre-existence of underground
facilities. The report states, quote, vital government installations have been placed
underground as exemplified by the Ritchie Project, end quote. Many of these facilities were designed
as command and control centers and survival bunkers for nuclear attacks. These are known
as continuity of government sites. Raven Rock qualifies as one such continuity of government
or COG dump. Design of underground installations in Rock additionally make some statements of
extreme relevance to the testimonies of dumps and UFOs. Some installations listed by the Army were
to be shallow, while quote, more important equipment and facilities essential to defense
may be installed in deeper workings that are likely to be long and tunnel-like, occupying one
or several stories, end quote. The report detailed enormous underground facilities featuring 50 by 50
feet tunnels and chambers as much as 100 feet high, even stating, quote, truck or rail traffic
might be important, end quote. The Army even cautioned, quote, landscape scars, roads,
and portal structures, aka entrances, should be as inconspicuous as possible.
Camouflage should be considered, end quote. This is of extreme consequence when discussing
testimonies such as MS, who detailed the entrance to the Dugway Stiff as a small building in the
middle of nowhere. In 1963, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers published a manual titled Utilization
of Nuclear Power Plants in Underground Installations. This manual discussed self-contained
nuclear-powered underground facilities with button-up diesel secondary systems.
Critically, in 1964, the Army Corps of Engineers or COE proposed 12 massive structures to be built
up to 4,000 feet underground. There are two sites here of massive importance to our investigation,
one facility below Yuma County, Arizona, to be accessed via a vertical or inclined shaft.
Such entry points are common amongst claims of UFO dumps such as the Dugway Dump whose entrance
is purported to be a vertical elevator shaft. In Stephen Greer's DPI Archive, who fans of this
channel will know I have extracted a tremendous amount of information and worthwhile investigation
from, witness 10773's statement reads, quote, nose of massive research and storage facility,
material of unknown origin at Yuma Proving Ground, end quote. Fascinating connection here.
Yuma Test Center is also home to Yuma Proving Ground, a U.S. Army major range and test facility
base. Similar to Dugway Proving Ground's Army MRTFB, the West Desert Test Center, Yuma Proving
Ground is also run by Army Test and Evaluation Command. Indeed, it is no stretch to assume if
a STIF exists under one of these Army MRTFBs, an equally impressive facility likely exists below
the other. Second here is Site 3 in Inyo County, California to be accessed via inclined shaft.
Inyo County resides on the inside boundary of China Lake Naval Weapons Testing Facility.
China Lake is one of the Navy's premier major range and test facility base and a location spoken
of on myriad occasions as an underground legacy program location. China Lake really needs no
introduction, but stay tuned as we will discuss China Lake in much more detail along with
Antelope Valley. But quickly to mention, Dr. Richard Sodder received testimony from a Navy
contact who served at China Lake. The witness confirmed an impressively large and deep installation,
claiming the facility extends one mile deep and contains, quote, weapons more powerful than
nuclear weapons, end quote. Alongside the U.S. Army COE, the U.S. Navy is also deeply entwined
with underground and possibly undersea bases, but that's another story for another day.
In 1972, Naval Facilities Engineering Command issued a report titled Subsurface Deployment of
Naval Facilities, discussing several Navy installations to be placed underground. These
include administration, medical, aircraft maintenance, ammo storage, and miscellaneous
storage facilities. The U.S. Navy CBs additionally maintain underground installations between the
Presidential Camp David and CIA Facility Camp Peary, which we will discuss later on.
In 1947, U.S. Air Materiel Command requested Nazi technicians for construction of underground
facilities. In 1989, Loi Dusha admitted numerous underground installations existed and were
classified. This means Stiffs of Interest were built from 1947 to 1949, a 42-year period. We
can also assume some facilities were built before 1961 where the five-part Army COE document
assumes the existence of such facilities. One such example here may be Groom Lake Area 51 that was
built in the 50s on the site of a former Boron mine. After all, a 1991 DARPA report details
secret cavities may be found in conjunction with underground mines. However, due to the existence
of literature on described future plans for massive bases post-1961 that really hold our
interest, we can assume from 1961 to 1989, the majority of our Stiffs of Interest were constructed.
Dums are not a new subject to the study of UFOs or my channel. I myself have talked a tremendous
amount of the alleged DARS, Defense Advanced Research Center, a 10-story underground location
built under Area 51 relayed by USAAF Master Sergeant Edgar Fouchet that dealt with alien
reproduction vehicles, including the TR-3B. I have also spoken on the enigmatic Northrop-Tahan,
Lockheed-Hellandale, and McDonnell-Douglas RCS facilities that have since at least 1987
been accused by excellent researchers such as Bill Hamilton as housing UFO legacy programs,
and don't worry, we will touch on these facilities in much more detail later.
Quite recently, I've discussed the Dugway Dumb as relayed by witness MS and even provided images
and details of the exact alleged entrance to the facility, which exists as an elevator shaft
concealed by a tiny building in the middle of nowhere Dugway near German Village. As strange
as that might seem, a 1991 paper issued by DARPA, the Defense Advanced Research Project
Agency, and US Army Missile Command titled Development of Inspection and Detection Techniques
for Hidden Cavities. This document served to train field nuclear weapons inspectors to identify
underground clandestine test complexes in developing nuclear nations. The report plainly
states buildings of various size can provide cover for shafts or other openings to a secret
underground cavity. Sounds similar to MS, no? And lastly, I've relayed the testimony of Randy
Anderson in the underground facility under the Naval Surface Warfare Center crane housing the
alleged Off-World Technologies Division. The subject of underground UFO legacy programs
rose to prominence in 1989 with the claims of Bob Lazar and Reverse Engineering under Site 4,
as well as the Dulcey Base fiasco where starting in 1979, Paul Benowitz was fed disinformation of
a joint human extraterrestrial base under Dulcey, New Mexico. Both S4 and Dulcey are worthy of
further investigation. In fact, I believe S4 to be a very real location, but due to the controversy
around these accounts, discussions of these sites will be largely omitted from today's discussions.
The first true mention of Dums and UFOs I can find is from Look Magazine in an article titled
Is This the Real Flying Saucer? dated 1955. The article discussed a Canadian company constructing
a flying saucer while also depicting a facility built underneath a hill with a vertical shaft
to the surface allowing the departure of flying saucers. Further rumors of UFOs and Dums wouldn't
really arise until the 1970s, so this article is indeed intriguing. Leonard Stringfield's UFO
crash retrieval status reports 1 through 7 is a body of work I often praise extensively. After all,
Stringfield is in my opinion one of the greatest UFO investigators of all time. His work on UFO
retrieval incidents and operations spanned from 1978 to 1994 and relay some of the earliest
mentions I can find of deep underground legacy operations. Let's briefly explore a few.
One such intriguing report is an anonymous letter Stringfield received 12 February 1974.
The letter highlighted secret research on UFOs taking place at a secret underground complex
below Grey Army Airfield in Fort Hood, Texas. According to the witness, the complex is shared
with ICBM silos built into a small mountain. This is fascinating as later in the project,
we will discuss how numerous Dums were constructed primarily as ICBM sites.
The witness described a section of the mountain would open up onto a jet interceptor runway,
which was once accidentally observed by a private pilot making a forced landing over
this restricted air corridor. This underground facility, according to the witness, was tied with
NORAD in Cheyenne Mountain, Colorado, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio, Tinker Air
Force Base, Oklahoma, Carswell Air Force Base, Texas, and others. And this is where the anonymous
account gets very interesting. The witness stated the complex employed a squadron of unmarked
helicopters dispatched, quote, when the need arises, end quote, codenamed the Blue Boys.
This sounds incredibly similar to UFO recovery rapid reaction units I have spoken about in
numerous crash retrieval cases, such as the Blue Berets in the 1965 Kexburg, Pennsylvania case.
The choppers additionally carried a new type of missile the source had been informed had been
used on UFOs, but a new system had been in development, which would be far more efficient.
This was an electronic warfare system designed to disable UFOs under quote unquote controlled
conditions. This letter would arrive to Stringfield's desk in 1974, but now in 2025,
we have heard the whistleblower testimony of Jake Barber, where he discussed EMP type weapons
designed to bring down UFOs over the enigmatic range. In your time in deployment, you met
certain people from an aerospace company, didn't you? Yes, I did. Now it's also part of the
constraints you operate under that you can't name that aerospace company. Correct. There's no good
reason to name them even if I wasn't constrained. What were they doing there? Well, they were
supporting us with some new weapons technology that could be used to
disable vehicles and aircraft. I can disclose this. My understanding is that they were essentially
using it was actually I think it's a meta republic record that microwave weapons,
pulse microwave weapons were being used at that time. Correct. There were some early prototypes
that were being used at that time. And I met individuals that were there representing the
companies that were providing that service to the government, made some friends, and those
relationships led to opportunities later in the California desert, where I began my journey.
Leonard would actually see a volume of reports regarding underground complexes at Fort Hood,
including a USAAF Lieutenant Colonel who relayed to him in 1975 of an underground project that
took place at Fort Hood. In 1976, Stringfield met an individual from McGregor, Texas who claimed
his father had worked beneath Fort Hood on the UFO program. This secondhand witness relayed a
quote from his father stating quote, the technology that is being applied in this underground complex
would remind someone of a science fiction thriller. It is unbelievable what they know
and what they can do from this area. Spanning the late 70s into the 80s, Stringfield received
myriad reports of an underground facility beneath Wright-Patterson Air Force Base housing preserved
non-human biologics. One such account was relayed from witness J.K. who worked at a Nike missile
site in Wilmington, Ohio. J.K. claimed to have seen nine alien bodies under Wright-Patt in 1966
encased in glass frozen to preserve. J.K. also claimed recovered craft were housed at McDill
Air Force Base, Langley Air Force Base, and Seymour Johnson Navy Training Center outside of
Norfolk, Virginia. These locations purportedly all housed craft and sometimes biologics in
underground hangars to conceal material from military and politicians. Stringfield heard
similar accounts of biologics under Wright-Patt relayed secondhand from one T.S. who allegedly
witnessed bodies in the early 1950s. T.S. were amongst a handful that relayed such stories.
Leonard Stringfield would also once receive an anonymous, undated letter from a U.S. airman who
was stationed at Kirtland Air Force Base, New Mexico. The source relayed rumors and stories of
UFOs being stored in the Manzano storage area in remote Kirtland. Remember if you will, Kirtland
is home to Sandia National Labs FFRDC, which ranging from the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit
report to accusations of reverse engineering a propulsion device for the TR-3B by Edgar Fouchet
has stood as a high probability candidate in UFO RDT&E programs. Manzano Mountain Underground
Facility is no myth either. While researching for his 2001 book Underwater and Underground Bases,
Soder received FOIA documents of two underground facilities below Manzano. While these documents
of course say nothing about UFO storage, it is fascinating to see Soder confirm the rumors of
an underground installation beneath Kirtland. Lastly, I want to reference an anonymous letter
to Leonard Stringfield I have covered before. This is dated March 14, 1975, which claims to
recount the testimony of one Lieutenant Colonel Simms, a pseudonym. I previously discussed this
letter in reference to the project on ED, an Edwards Air Force Base 412th Test Group Electronic
Warfare Test Director who claimed to the existence of a joint UFO reverse engineering program
operating between Edwards Air Force Base and the Nevada Test and Training Range. Viewers of this
channel will know I consider ED to be one of the most critical UFO legacy witnesses of all time,
and as a quick side note, ED also referenced attending the S4 site. This letter was referenced
due to the mention of Hanscom Air Force Base in the Massachusetts Institute of Technology,
an air base and university where ED worked from 2002 to 2005 on foreign military assets.
Amongst the intriguing mentions of contractors, FFRDCs, UARCs, and air bases involved in UFO
research and investigation, the source relayed Lieutenant Colonel Simms speaking of several
computer banks hidden within underground installations scattered across the U.S.,
housing sophisticated computer equipment, electronic instrumentation, and mobile radar units.
According to Simms, these underground installations employ, quote,
squadrons of unmarked helicopters which have sophisticated instrumentation on board that are
dispatched to areas of UFO activity to monitor these craft or airlift them out of the area if
one has malfunctioned, end quote. This sounds quite similar to the Blue Boys rapid reaction
unit relayed to Stringfield, does it not? But perhaps we have other confirming evidence,
so let's also reference the book Trinity's Children Living Along America's Nuclear Highways.
The authors of this book state, quote,
There are more Cray supercomputers in New Mexico, an Air Force computer expert once said,
than anywhere else. They're here at the weapon center, referring to Kirtland. They're across
the street at Sandia. They're at Los Alamos up the highway, and they're at the, quote,
underground places nobody knows about. Intriguing, as we already know Kirtland
and by extension Sandia employ at least two underground facilities in the Manzano Mountains.
Los Alamos National Labs additionally employs a deep underground installation.
Dr. Soder had quite an interesting engagement with Los Alamos. He repeatedly attempted to
FOIA the Department of Energy for information on underground facilities and tunnels beneath
Los Alamos. The DOE continuously responded there were none. Eventually though, the DOE
provided Soder a badly blurred phototastic copy of an article by Earl Zimmerman titled,
LASL's unusual underground lab, which described an underground facility built in the late 1940s.
This article was undated and of uncertain origin, however Zimmerman can be found labeled as a press
bureau member from 1963 to 1965 in a 2020 Los Alamos organizational chart. Dr. Soder additionally
met with a businessman who relayed his experience in visiting Los Alamos in the company of a highly
cleared associate. The businessman was privy to wherever his esteemed colleague went without
question. The individual claimed 75 percent of Los Alamos' facilities are underground and extend as
far as one mile underground.
In relation to TUOs and UFOs, so far we have covered very real stiffs under Kirtland slash
Sandia in Los Alamos while also discussing the possible existence of facilities
existing under Wright-Patterson, Fort Hood slash Grey Army Airfield, Yuma County,
China Lake, as well as the Nevada Test Site under the Nevada Test and Training Range.
Now onto one of the most critical areas of my research, the Antelope Valley, California.
For this section, we will reference the work of both Dr. Soder as well as the late Bill Hamilton,
a tremendous UFO researcher. Hamilton served as a true pioneer of the field, serving as the first
researcher to ever produce the term and a public image of ARV and even handed incredible witnesses
such as Mark McCandlish and Bill Uhouse to Stephen Greer. Hamilton's excellent book,
Cosmic Top Secret, an ultra-rare early 1990s lecture recorded for VHS titled
UFOs and Underground Bases, offers us keen insights into Hamilton's research on dumbs and specific
area of interest, the Antelope Valley. In fact, Hamilton produced a map relayed to him by sources
of connected underground UFO facilities in the American Southwest. We will compare this map to
existing DoD laboratories and RDT&E locations later on in this video. China Lake Naval Air Station
is also quite close to Antelope Valley, so we will discuss that enigmatic facility here as well.
Since the late 1980s, Hamilton's work focused on Antelope Valley, California. Many will know
this region as one of the chief centers of aerospace technology, housing the infamous
USAF Plant 42, Lockheed Skunk Works, the former Norton Air Force Base, the legendary Edwards Air
Force Base, major installations for Northrop Grumman, Rockwell, and McDonnell Douglas,
as well as numerous intriguing radar cross-section facilities in the form of Northrop Tehan, Lockheed
Hellendale, and McDonnell Douglas. I have spoken on all of the aforementioned facilities in prior
work. Palmdale, California within the Antelope has served as an unrivaled US military-slash-private
contractor classified aircraft production and maintenance location. The region has produced
many of the United States' most famous advanced aerospace platforms such as the RQ-4 Global Hawk,
B-2 Spirit Bomber, B-21 Raider, F-117 Nighthawk, and F-35 Lightning. The Antelope Valley in the
city of Palmdale have also served as a critical pillar of my research. Whether this be Norton
Air Force Base serving as the location where primary witness Brad S observed the Fluxliner
alien reproduction vehicle, witness Ed disclosing his work for the 412th test group serving as test
director for reverse engineered vehicles out of Edwards, Edgar Fouchet who stated pilots of the
TR-3B reverse engineered Triangle ARV were plucked from the Edwards 412th test pilot school, or the
alleged Project Red Light out of Edwards which served to act alongside Area 51 to test reverse
engineered vehicles, very similar to the claims of Ed. Antelope Valley is the most consequential
location that has ever come up in all of my research. The late Hamilton was obsessed with
the radar cross-section facilities mentioned above, specifically the Northrop Tejon installation,
sometimes referred to as the Tehachapi facility or Ant Hill, due to the rumors of incredible
amounts of underground tunnels beneath the installation. In my video on Northrop,
I investigated this RCS facility in great detail. Thanks to the research of Dr. Sautter,
we know the Northrop Tejon RCS does indeed have an underground facility, just as does
Hellendale and McDonnell Douglas. The question is how big, how deep, and what do they do?
Some rumors persist of up to 42 levels with underground tunnels connecting the facility
to Edwards and other installations. The concept of a corporate dump should come as no surprise
to anyone. In 1981, the American Telephone and Telegraph Company, yes, AT&T, revealed several
underground emergency centers. Believe it or not, AT&T itself has been historically implicated in
non-human technology transfer, but that is not our topic for today. These underground centers
exist 40 feet below ground and feature three story centers with data banks, dorms, and kitchens.
One such location is reported to exist in Catrone County, 180 miles near Sandia National Labs.
This is not surprising, seen from 1949 to 1993, AT&T and its subsidiary, Western Electric,
ran Sandia National Labs at Kirtland at the order of President Harry S. Truman for the
Department of Energy. Indeed, as recently as 1970, the Standard Oil Company of New Jersey
operated an emergency center 300 feet underground near Hudson, New York. This location that more
recently held corporate reports featured dining halls and 50 sleeping rooms for key company
officials. But back to Tehan and quickly, for those who don't know, what exactly is a radar
cross-section facility? To summarize, these facilities utilize high-frequency radio waves
to test aircraft's radar signatures. This military testing aids in the development of stealth
technologies by reducing radar cross-section. The site features large runways and pylons raised
from underground on concrete diamonds as mounting pads to blast aircraft and materials with radar.
Many RCS facilities, including the Three in Antelope Valley, saw construction during the
Cold War. This led the majority of the installation being built underground to hide RCS pylons,
equipment, models, and technology away from Soviet spy satellites. Numerous researchers
over the years have accused the Northrop Lockheed and McDonnell Douglas RCS sites as integral legacy
program locations focused on the downing, retrieval, and storage of non-human craft.
The contentious Dr. Stephen Greer even claimed to have both knowledge of the entrance for the
Ant Hill Dome, as well as personally been flown over these sites and observed the electromagnetic
pulse weapon systems that are used to down craft. Now interestingly, the Senate Intelligence and
Armed Services Committee and other senior officials had no idea of this. The top people
in the special forces who are outside this illegal black project system didn't know about it.
I had known about it since the 90s, but I'd never of course flown directly over it because it's
classified airspace and very sensitive. So you can see what looks like a trough and a runway.
It's just where the man-made UFOs that we've been building since the 1954-55
come out. They go up and they hover. They're silent. They're electro-gravitic, anti-grav.
The diamond on the left, you see that looks like a runway with a diamond. It's not a runway because
they don't need to run and get there's non-aerodynamic. They just go boom up, but they're
placed over different diamonds. I have a whole series of video and pictures of these I won't
have time to go through, and that's where they're put at various elevations and then struck with an
electromagnetic weapon to see if it's hardened enough to withstand conflict, right?
When discussing the RCS facilities, and in particular, Hamilton's obsession with Tejon,
some may remember the XF-131 Super Sentinel. This incredible triangular ARV was drawn by
forensic artist Bill MacDonald and later featured in Season 1 of The X-Files. According to MacDonald,
the craft design was relayed to him from two Northrop Tejon and two Lockheed-Hellandale
engineers who were jaded from the intense secrecy from which they operated. I personally have spoken
to MacDonald on numerous occasions regarding this triangular ARV out of the Antelope Valley and put
much credence into this testimony. For years, Hamilton compiled first-hand witness testimony
regarding Antelope Valley and specifically the Northrop Tehachapi site. Let's briefly investigate
a few of these testimonies. A local man with property on 170th Street west of Tejon reported
to Hamilton of the ground opening like a missile silo where a flying saucer took off. Edward's Air
Force Office of Special Investigation silenced this witness. UFO researcher Dr. Richard Boylan,
alongside the first-hand source of Bill MacDonald, have additionally accused Tejon
as a manufacturing site for reverse-engineered vehicles including the XF-131 Super Sentinel,
an anti-gravity disc dubbed by Boylan the Great Pumpkin. A contractor named Chuck
relayed his experience digging the underground tunnels beneath the anthill to Hamilton.
This source claimed tunnels in the dump had round doorways with few doors and red and green lights
for ID and entry. An intriguing source of Hamilton claimed to have worked on project Star Talk at
Tejon. This project involved lasers in a big building underground for the purpose of constructing
systems to quote-unquote bring in UFOs. The source mentioned scalar technology,
a concept Stephen Greer would later on discuss for decades as a weapon source to down UFOs.
The Star Talk informer also claimed to work at McDonald Douglas Stiff where he observed a
UFO held in an underground hangar. This name was very hard to make out by a 144p documentary,
but one Hamilton informer went by the name Goburn who claimed to work at Tejon,
Hellendale and the Nevada Test and Training Range. This source relayed to Hamilton he
worked with alien technology that deeply frightened him. According to the source,
on-site personnel would rotate every 14 to 16 days living and working on-site,
and there existed a command center under Haystack Butte which connected to the anthill.
Hamilton had numerous other informers who would discuss experimental discs being flown out of
Edwards Airfield, extraterrestrial discs being held under Edwards, and underground UFO work
below a hangar on Edwards North Base. Many of these informants would discuss ground vehicles
like electric cars within the dumps and maglev train systems connecting the base to others.
We will of course discuss this much later on. From his data and sources, Hamilton learned of a
supposed massive complex of underground facilities in the Antelope Valley engaged with UFO testing,
storage and material exploitation, all connected via tunnels and transport systems. These
facilities included Tehachapi, McDonnell Douglas, Hellendale, George Air Force Base, Edwards,
the NASA rocket test site and China Lake. A network of joint USG and corporate facilities
all connected in the Antelope Valley dedicated to the storage and exploitation of UFOs has proven
to be quite a common theory since the late 80s and early 1990s work of Hamilton. I'd once again like
to reference Stephen Greer witness A.H. I have discussed in multiple projects A.H., a Boeing
insider with numerous connections to UFO legacy programs, has historically and likely to this day
served as a primary source of information for Greer. In his 2000 tape testimony, A.H. delivered
to Greer much of the information Greer still discusses to this day, including reference to
a massive facility existing below Dugway. A.H. additionally discussed a complex of underground
facilities near Anzo, California, just south of Antelope Valley, while also addressing a critical
Northrop underground facility named, of course, Tejon. Did he share with you any other information
on other facilities that dealt with this issue in the US or abroad? Yes, he mentioned there's a base
here in California near Anzo, California, and there's another base in the deserts of, I believe
he said Tejon, I believe that's the word that he used. There's a base near Lancaster and Palmdale
area and near, this is very funny, it's near Northrop. There's an underground area out there
too that he was aware of, but he particularly mentioned and stayed focused on Anzo, California.
There's some underground areas up there too that they're researching some of this technology and
at March Air Force Base through Project Red Light. Of this network of proposed facilities,
one possible dumb stands out from the rest, Edwards Air Force Base. As mentioned in nearly
every project, Edwards serves as home to the 412th Test Group, a major range and test facility base.
Witness Ed, a vetted and accomplished USAAF veteran, claimed Edwards and the Nevada Test
and Training Range, specifically Nellis Air Force Base in Area 51 slash Groom Lake,
which is actually run by an Edwards 412th Detachment, runs a joint UFO reverse engineering
program. Outside of the claims of Hamilton's informants regarding Edwards and craft stored
in underground installations, there are many fascinating testimonies and avenues of research
we might pursue. Remember how one source of Hamilton claimed to have worked on the
Ant Hill installation under Tejon in Antelope Valley? The source claimed the installation's
command center existed under Edwards Haystack Butte. This sentiment is shared by the controversial
and enigmatic whistleblower Dr. Michael Wolfe, who claimed as a UAP consultant to the National
Security Council he heard live extraterrestrials were kept under Haystack Butte Edwards.
Test facilities are built into and on Haystack Butte, east of Edwards. Indeed, these facilities
are run alongside a primary field lab at the remote northeast corner of Edwards by the Air
Force Research Lab's Aerospace Systems Directorate. AFRL, Edwards 412th Test Wing, and NASA Flight
Research Facility work together at Edwards to plan, conduct, analyze, and report on all flight and
ground testing of aircraft, weapons systems, software, and components, as well as modeling
and simulation for the USAAF. Since facilities are built into the Butte, it is no stretch to assume
locations are built under the Haystack Butte. And remember, this USAAF AFRL Rocket Propulsion
Division and their rocket test labs on Lumen Ridge were named by Hamilton and his informants as
featuring a stiff location connected to the wider Edwards underground complex. This lab features a
number of underground missile silos, but the extent to which the Air Force Propulsion Laboratory
sprawls underground is unknown. However, and very interesting, numerous studies out of the Air Force
Rocket Propulsion Lab have shown a heavy interest in anti-gravity propulsion. Is this location
definitely UFO legacy related? Unknown. But a strong argument can be made from witness testimony.
And lastly, a bit north to Antelope is China Lake Naval Air Weapons Station. As we showed in a 1964
Army Corps of Engineers study titled, A Feasibility of Constructing Large Underground
Cavities in Yo County, which shares territory with China Lake, was considered for underground
purposes. The underground cavity of interest was 4,000 feet deep, and it is unknown if this
facility was built. However, numerous witness testimony may give us some idea. As we also
discussed above, Dr. Sautter had been given testimony by Navy veterans stationed at China
Lake who not only claimed the facility goes one mile deep, but weapons work is conducted on
weapons more powerful than nuclear weapons. Hamilton himself also had a source who allegedly
served as an aerospace engineer consultant to NASA and Colonel. This unnamed Colonel claimed he
worked at an underground installation at China Lake, Edwards Air Force Base, and the Nevada test
site. These locations were, according to the source, connected via a maglev train system from
which he would often enter through a dump beneath White Sands Missile Range. I put stock in this
testimony due to speaking myself to a witness who claimed to travel via underground train
system from a fort in Texas to White Sands. This source, an Army officer in the 2010s,
claimed the train's speed and acceleration were so great it reminded him of his fear of flying.
We also have Ed in the mention of Edwards and the NTTR. China Lake is not mentioned in his
testimony, however it stands to reason the very near China Lake, which serves as the Navy's largest
single land holding representing 85% of the Navy's weapons and armaments RD, T&E programs, could
likely see crossover T.U.O. programs with the USAF. If these programs exchange non-human craft,
materials, and research, it stands to reason such transactions would be conducted underground to
maintain secrecy. I would in the future like to do an entire video on China Lake, so hang tight.
Corporate and military installations do indeed exist below Antelope Valley. Again,
the question is do these sites deal with technologies of unknown origin and exploitation
programs? Antelope and Palmdale are home to aerospace juggernauts and myriad DOD, RD, T&E,
and MRTFBs and have for decades featured numerous testimonies of ARV, underground installations,
and claims of UFO legacy programs. Due to these factors plus witnesses who have told me they have
traveled below the Antelope Valley, I am inclined to conclude such an anthill, if so to speak,
does in fact exist, to work on UFO legacy programs.
The vast majority of our focus today is the American Southwest and endless claims of
underground UFO research in RD, T&E, but quickly I do want to look East. We have already discussed
STIFs used by the CIA and NSA under cover of the Army and Navy respectively, but what about
UFO STIFs? For this reason, I would like to look to the United States Capitol and address the Deep
Underground Command Center. The D.U.C.C. was a STIF below the Pentagon that was never built,
however, I am not sure just how true that statement is. Now, an acknowledged STIF under
the Pentagon does indeed exist, the National Military Command Center responsible for generating
emergency action messages to missile control launch centers, nuclear subs, and battlefield
commanders. This NMCC was set to serve as an interim facility for the never built D.U.C.C.
The Deep Underground Command Center was first proposed in 1963, three weeks before the
assassination of JFK. Declassified top secret documents dated 7 November 63 detail former
Secretary of Defense Robert McNamara proposing meetings to discuss the National Underground
Command Center. These plans for the National or Deep Underground Command Center detailed a complex
command center built 3,500 feet below Washington D.C. This location would be built to withstand
direct hits of 200 to 300 megaton warheads that penetrate 70 to 100 feet below the surface before
detonation. Two separate facilities were proposed, an austere facility with 10,000 total square feet
and 5,000 operating square feet accommodating 40 people at a depth of 3,500 feet. This would cost
over 110 million dollars or 1.1 billion today. The second was a moderate sized facility with 100,000
total square feet and 50,000 operating square feet accommodating 300 people at a depth of 3,500 feet.
This would cost 310 million or over 3.2 billion dollars today. The Joint Chiefs interestingly
proposed the austere facility to be too small. The operation capsule of the center would be near
the Pentagon and an access elevator would descend 3,500 feet underground from the Pentagon to the
installation. This may seem like a massive undertaking, however, the memorandum stated,
quote, there is little argument that the construction of a D.U.C.C. is technically
feasible, end quote. To quote the memo again, quote, the nature of the D.U.C.C., regardless of
the initial size selected, lends itself to later expansion, end quote. Once Lyndon B. Johnson took
office, a second memorandum was issued 16 January 1964 from Wal Rostow to McGeorge Bundy stating the
D.U.C.C. concept should proceed. Rostow served as a senior advisor to both Kennedy and Johnson.
An additional memo followed the same day from McGeorge Bundy to Carl Kasin showing planning
for the D.U.C.C. had been going forward since the early days of the Johnson admin.
Kasin was deputy special assistant for national security affairs to Kennedy and possibly stayed
on to advise on the D.U.C.C. program. The memo additionally stated, Kasin having spoken to Harold
Brown read the D.U.C.C. Brown served as director of defense research and engineering from 1961 to 1965.
A last top secret memo dealing with the D.U.C.C. was issued by the Bureau of the Budget estimated
between 1963 to 1964. 40 plus percent of this document is redacted. Was the D.U.C.C. ever built?
Conventional sources would say no, however I would argue indeed it was. This confidence of mine is
from sources who have described to me first-hand encounters within an enormous cavernous facility
below the Pentagon. But how does such a proposed facility deal with the subject of UFOs? If the
D.U.C.C. was indeed built, it is a publicly denied site. Therefore, we can feasibly reckon if the
site does exist, it deals with subjects critical to U.S. national security. Since the 1954 atomic
energy agreement, materials pertaining to UFOs have been misclassified as trans-classified foreign
nuclear materials. As relayed by physicist Robert Sarbacher in 1950, UFO programs exist and their
classification resides even higher than that of the H-bomb. On this channel, I have spoken in depth
that UFO legacy program operations are the ultimate secret, deep-sixed, clandestine set of
programs deeply embedded within special access programs. The Pentagon resides near Crystal City.
Crystal City features 8 of 10 of the U.S.'s top defense contractors, and the small neighborhood
is where two-thirds of federal contracts are awarded by value. This location holds primary
offices held by Northrop Grumman, Lockheed Martin, Boeing, Raytheon, General Dynamics, L3,
Aerojet, Rocketdyne, and more, all contractors I highly suspect engage with UFO programs. The
neighborhood also holds or is in close proximity to numerous FFRDCs I believe are up to their
eyeballs in UFO programs. These include the Center for Naval Analyses, Institute for Defense Analysis,
Aerospace Corporation, and Rand Homeland Security Operations Analysis Center. Additionally,
Crystal City is home to myriad DoD research agencies including DARPA, Office of Naval Research,
and Air Force Office of Scientific Research. I do believe similar to the Antelope Valley,
Crystal City's amalgamation of DoD entities, FFRDCs, and contractors is a major center of
operations for UFO legacy programs. Perhaps due to limited airspace and usage of MRTFBs,
unlike the American Desert and Southwest, Crystal City is where the majority of UFO-related
USAPs are created, maintained, and kept secure. This is a thesis I will continue to explore in
depth in the future, if Crystal City does indeed majorly engage with clandestine UFO unacknowledged
special access programs. It stands to reason such a classified effort involving DoD,
private, and semi-private entities would require a massive underground facility.
The idea of a major network of underground tunnels connecting DUMs nationwide is often scoffed at.
I have no idea if the entire nation's STIFs are connected via tunnel system, but a strong argument
can be made complex systems of interconnecting STIFs exist in the American Southwest and East
Coast. After all, in a document obtained via FOIA by Dr. Richard Sauter, we even have hard
numbers from the military-industrial complex of the estimated number of total personnel needed
to build and operate a deeply buried hundreds of mile long tunnel system. And this is the order of
7,800 to 8,700 people, and we also have a hard estimate for the total expenses associated with
constructing, operating, and maintaining such a system, the neighborhood of $17 billion over
a 10-year period. Many such acknowledged tunnel systems exist, like the Department of Energy's
sprawling tunnel network below the Nevada Test and Training Range, but let's continue to explore
the feasibility of massive tunnel systems connecting bases dozens or hundreds of miles apart.
The technology for such undertakings does indeed exist. The most likely candidates are nuclear
subterranes and tunnel boring machines. Tunnel boring machines are huge cylindrical mechanical
boring machines that tunnel through rock and soil, chewing out circular tunnels that may range in
diameter of up to 35 or more feet. These Goliaths are powered by electrical motors that have a
cutting head equipped with various metal attachments made of super hard alloys that
cut through rock as the head rotates. The head rotates and the cutting tools dig into the rock,
ripping and gouging it away. The excavated rock or muck is then passed by a conveyor assembly to
the rear of the machine where it can be hauled away by truck or train. According to the Pacific
Gas and Electric Company, utilizing a Robbins Company TBM to bore a 22,000-foot long 24-foot
diameter tunnel, it took a rate of five to six miles per year. However, in better conditions,
some TBMs could bore at a rate of 10 miles per year or greater, roughly double the rate of the
Pacific Gas and Electric Company. This would mean dumps below China Lake and Edwards could
be connected in as little as five and a half years. Nuclear subterranes were originally
designed by Los Alamos National Lab. Sound familiar? The patents for such machines were
filed, technical documents were written, but the project seemingly faded into obscurity.
These fascinating machines work by melting through rock and soil, leaving neat, solidly glass-lined
tunnels by vitrifying materials. Heat is supplied to the system via compact nuclear reactors that
circulate liquid lithium from the reactor core to the tunnel face, melting rock in front of the
machine. Cooled liquid lithium then circulates to the back of the machine alongside the exterior of
the machine to cool surrounding rock as the machine is forced forward. Patents were first
proposed by the Atomic Energy Commission and US Energy R&D in 1972 and 1975. Further nuclear
subterrene patents in 1975 detailed tunnel systems of 12 meters or more in diameter.
All but one of the inventors listed in the three patents above were from Los Alamos. Additionally,
a 1973 Los Alamos study titled, Systems and Cost Analysis for a Nuclear Subterrene Tunnel Machine
a preliminary study concluded nuclear subterranes to be a cost-efficient solution to satisfy US
transportation tunnel demands. Similar to how we deduced numerous dumps were built around 1961 to
1989, we can make similar deductions regarding connective tunnel systems. If such an enormous
tunnel system exists, it likely saw construction beginning around the early 1970s, 1974 to be exact.
The Bechtel Corporation is an American engineering, procurement and construction
management company founded in the US. Bechtel has often been targeted as one of the US corporations
responsible for dumb tunnel systems. In 1974, Bechtel released a report titled, Research Program
Plan for Meeting Tomorrow's Needs in Tunneling and Excavation Final Report. This report states,
quote, the demand for tunneling and underground excavation for national defense needs is believed
to be large. Some examples of underground defense facilities include hard rock silos,
command posts, communication systems, personnel shelters, storage and power generation facilities,
end quote. Interestingly enough, the same report shows a massive list of novel ground disintegration
techniques in R&D stages. In 1972, the governing board of the National Research Council formed the
US National Committee on Tunneling Technology. This committee functioned as the, quote, United
States focal agency in the field of tunneling technology to assess and stimulate improvements
in tunneling technology applications and to coordinate US tunneling technology activities
with those of other nations, end quote. By 1977, this USNTT had six major subcommittees,
including the Deep Cavity and Tunnel Support Systems committees. USNCTT partnered with
numerous corporations, agencies and academics of particular interest to this channel. These include
both Sandia National Labs and Bechtel Memorial Institute. I have accused Bechtel of engaging
deeply with UAP legacy programs, including operations at the Dugway Alleged Dome. In 1981
and 1982, the USNCTT sponsored a project called Workshop on Technology for the Design and Construction
of Deep Underground Defense Facilities. This was done at the behest of the Nuclear Defense Agency
and co-sponsors included the Bureau of Reclamation, Army, USAAF, Navy, DOE and National
Science Foundation, including others. The 1982 report of the workshop detailed the need for 400
miles of tunnels ranging from 2,500 to 3,500 feet for various purposes, including housing nuclear
missiles. These tunnels were to be up to 16 feet in diameter with, quote, interconnecting passageways
and adits, horizontal passageways for storage, living quarters and other needs, end quote.
The location of such a network of tunnels, according to the New York Times, would be,
quote, probably in the desert of the western United States. Such tunnels and installations
were to be powered via fuel cells or nuclear reactors, and as we saw in 1963, the US Army
Corps of Engineers was very serious about nuclear reactors powering self-contained underground
installations. Fuel cells may also be of special interest here, seen as in 1984 Boeing published
the results of a study that set forth plans for power generation in deep ICBM bases using
iron-chlorine fuel cells to generate power. The USNCTT called for mobilization of this plan
in the late 80s and early 90s. The committee called for tunnel boring machines to be utilized
starting in 1985 for carving tunnel systems. By 1988, USNCTT was publishing reports titled
Tunneling and Underground Space Technology Discussing Underground Missile Systems Ranging
Between 3000 to 8000 feet underground. During this period in the 80s, numerous contractors
I have directly accused of being involved in UFO legacy programs would aid in the construction
of deep underground missile bases and tunnel systems. Of course, we must assume some if not
many underground nuclear missile bases may have served as clandestine RDT&E facilities. This
should not come as a shock, as we have already discussed US intelligence agencies utilizing
underground military sites for secret operations. Such corporations include BDM who was awarded in
1985 a contract to conduct quote, intercontinental ballistic missile deep basing communication study
end quote, as well as TRW who had since 1968 been involved in studies into high speed ground
transportation tunnel design and cost analysis. Both corporations were later on bought by Northrop
The 1985 BDM study is of particular interest here. Remember if you will, earlier that same year,
20-25 May 1985 to be exact, BDM McLean also held the Advanced Theoretical Physics Conference.
The meetings of this exclusive group were classified utilizing DOE controls. Notes of
this conference were released by attendee Oke Shannon who formerly served as manager
for special projects at Los Alamos National Labs. This McLean Virginia secure facility
group discussed myriad aspects of UFOs including legacy programs and a major engineering project
under Bobby Ray Inman. Viewers of my channel will absolutely recall Inman mentioned often as a senior
UFO legacy operations member. At this time, the vice president of BDM was former major general
and founder of US Army INSCOM Albert Stubblebine. Stubblebine will be mentioned again in this
project including how he was accused of engaging in UFO craft storage and material exploitation
while head of army intelligence at Fort Hachuca, Arizona. Interestingly, the Advanced Theoretical
Working Group was spearheaded by US Army Colonel John B. Alexander who from 1982 to 1983 reported
directly to Stubblebine. Additionally, recall how Philip J. Corso claimed a UFO working group was
established in the mid-80s. According to Corso, this group saw ample funding from US Army INSCOM
General Stubblebine. It is interesting to think of possible ties between this ICBM deep basing
communication study and Albert Stubblebine and the Advanced Theoretical Physics Conference and a
possible UFO working group accused by Philip J. Corso. Throughout the 1980s, US industry and
government additionally demonstrated a keen interest in life support systems for massive
tunnel systems, underground ICBM installations, as well as deep and I mean deep underground bases.
This can be demonstrated in a November 1985 contract to Unitech Technologies Hamilton
Standard Division for life support and chemical biological agent mitigation system on small
ICBM deep basing programs. US Army Corps of Engineers as well as USNCTT have even discussed
provable technologies, times, and prices to construct such massive tunnel systems.
Yet no data exists on any large-scale tunneling project. This may force us to look deeper like
at the low-profile records of the Bureau of Reclamation who during the 20th century excavated
hundreds of miles of tunnels up to 28.5 feet in diameter at depths of hundreds to thousands of
feet. Quite often the Bureau would utilize classic tunnel boring machines. Numerous
inside sources to Dr. Richard Sautter have informed him that some of the Bureau of Reclamation's
tunnels have doubled as cover for other clandestine underground tunnels. To quote underground and
underwater bases, quote,
and striking out secretly to make a clandestine tunnel. It takes about 10 men to operate a TBM
and in good rock you can count on as much as 15 miles of tunnel per year, end quote.
For decades, rumors of underground railroad systems, specifically maglev trains, have been
inseparable from testimony regarding dumps and UFOs. As we discussed earlier in the Antelope
Valley section, such a concept was relayed to UFO researcher Bill Hamilton by some of his many
informants. But just how true are these rumors of a high-speed electromagnetic railroad system
often described as a pneumatic system, aka a train system operating in a partial vacuum tube?
To begin, what is maglev? Maglev trains are a type of rail system levitated by
electromagnetics rather than employing wheels. Maglevs feature numerous benefits to conventional
railroad systems, including higher speeds, superior acceleration and deceleration, lower
maintenance costs, improved gradient handling, and lower noise. But are much more expensive
compared to traditional systems. Maglevs have even reached top speeds of 375 miles per hour.
And pneumatic tube trains are an early form of transportation or air vacuum to move containers
or vehicles through tubes while minimizing friction. New York's first subway system was
an underground pneumatic tube transport line created by Alfred Eli Beach. Earlier in this
project, we spoke of Nazi scientists being sequestered by Air Material Command in the US
to work on underground complexes. I would also like to draw attention to Herman Kemper. Kemper
was a Third Reich engineer who created a concept for the Rohrbahn. The Rohrbahn was a system of
magnetic levitation trains designed to speed through underground vacuum tunnels at hundreds
or even thousands of miles per hour. Suspended passenger cars on magnetic fields would be
propelled through tunnels negating any friction of wheels, rails, and air. Kemper's research
began in 1934. By 1938, he envisioned Berlin connected to other European cities with cars
traveling at 600 to 1000 miles per hour. It is unknown how far the Nazis pursued this concept,
nor is it known if Kemper was recruited by Operation Paperclip. A feasible hypothesis
here is Kemper was contracted by the US to help build early iterations of maglev pneumatic systems.
Maglev, UFOs, and Dums are often lumped together as conspiracy, however maglevs are not a niche
concept. Since the 1960s, maglev technology has seen numerous patents and by the year 2000,
even Lockheed Martin entered into agreements with Trans Rapid International USA to develop
maglev technology in the US. In fact, by the early 1990s, an acknowledged multi-agency
National Maglev Institute was formed. This joint effort by the DOE and US Army Corps of Engineers
sought to, quote, define the role maglev could play in US transportation system, to assess the
potential for maglev in the domestic market, to recommend a strategy for the introduction of
maglev technology, and to identify the most appropriate federal role, end quote. This NMI
published a report in the early 90s titled Compendium of Executive Summaries from the
Maglev System Concept Definition Final Reports. This series of reports sought to determine
nationwide maglev system availability by the year 2000. Some interesting players appear in this
document. This includes a joint project with Bechtel, Hughes Aircraft, and MIT, which employs
a UARC for the Army. A second report saw work by Boeing Aerospace and General Dynamics to study
superconducting levitation. To top this off, a third study saw joint efforts into
superconducting magnets performed by Grumman Corporation pre-Northrop, Bechtel Memorial Labs,
and Honeywell. All contractors mentioned above in above board maglev technology research I highly
expect have for decades attempted the reverse engineering and material exploitation of non-human
craft. However, rumors of clandestine maglev systems far precede the 1990s and 2000s.
Dr. Richard Sauter as well as Bill Hamilton first heard whispers of such systems in the 1980s.
Sauter himself referenced reading reports of underground rail systems to Area 51 from Mercury,
Nevada and the Naval Surface Warfare Center Corona Division. Discussion of these rail systems would
even pop up in online UFO forums around 1997. Look at the name on the top of these testimony reports,
A.J. Cradock. In discussed in the Dugway project, Cradock is an oil tycoon operating in Libya that
helped Stephen Greer in the 1990s with Seaseti. Cradock brought Greer, in my opinion, incredibly
valuable and relevant information regarding Area 51 moving many UFO operations to Dugway.
So if maglev systems existed far before UFO legacy program defense contractors engaged with
the acknowledged National Maglev Institute, where and when might these systems have been developed
and of what technology? The mid-1960s saw established engineering professors from the
Office of Naval Research, Army Research Office and Booz Allen Hamilton establish the International
Society for Terrain Vehicle Systems, or ISTV. Real quick, in the mid to late 20th century,
I believe Booz Allen Hamilton was as involved in UFO legacy operations as Northrop Grumman is today,
but that's another project for another day. The ISTVS working group coordinated research around
high-speed underground tube train systems. At the same time of the ISTVS, the U.S. Department
of Commerce established a multi-agency panel focused on high-speed underground tube train
systems. The panel produced a 1967 report titled R&D for High-Speed Ground Transportation, which
states, quote, Regardless of the system adopted, it can be assumed that extensive tunneling will
be involved. It is recommended that the department cooperate closely with other agencies in planning
and funding research into this area to provide an extra stimulus for rapid development, end quote.
Of massive consequence to this investigation, in 1972, Robert Salter of the R&D Corporation
published a study titled The Very High-Speed Transit System. In this study, R&D set out a
continental deep underground concept that was described as, quote, electromagnetically
levitated and propelled cars in an evacuated tunnel, end quote. The study makes some truly
shocking statements, including, quote, In an example case of a direct link between Los Angeles
and New York requiring only 21 minutes of transit time, I believe Salter additionally makes a critical
statement that lends strongly towards the subject of UFO legacy dumps. Salter states, quote,
These intermediate staging points are apparent when throughout this video I have made and will
continue to make in the Hamilton map segment the argument that UFO dump networks feature central
hubs. These hubs, if so to speak, are connected to one another and branch to local smaller dump
facilities. Think of a railway central station connecting to other major stations while also
featuring alternative lines to small local stops. Much of this technology was based on work conducted
by Robert Goddard, father of modern rocketry's 1945 vacuum tube transport system, as well as
Michael Minovich, the physicist behind introducing gravity-assisted propulsion around planetary bodies
1961 work deep underground tube shuttle. Salter and Rand strongly recommended placing the VHST
underground to remove interference with environmental factors such as grade crossings,
weather and infrastructure and also observed that it was not appreciable harder to tunnel at great
lengths underground than at shallow depths. Within this study is a map of the proposed VHST
that corresponds strongly to build Hamilton's alleged western state dump network, but more
on this later. Around a similar timeframe to this Rand study is the high-speed ground transportation
initiative. This group became operational in the 1960s, performing most of their work in the 1970s
before slipping out of public view in the 1980s. For a period of 10 to 15 years, the United States
saw enormous efforts into R&D and feasibility and desirability of high-speed underground tube
shuttle train systems. Entities involved in this program are countless, including TRW, General
Dynamics, MIT, Southwest Research Institute behind Project Stargate, General Electric, NASA,
Army, Navy, and Battelle Memorial Institute. I have mentioned some of the work published under
this initiative before, including TRW's 1967 study titled Abstracts of Concepts of High-Speed Ground
Transportation Systems. Remember, TRW was purchased by Northrop Grumman and long considered as the
contractor behind the majestic 12-like entity Project Zodiac. For the high-speed ground
transportation initiative, TRW additionally prepared a study titled State of the Art Tube
Vehicle System in 1970. This study discussed tube systems in tunnels as deep as 3,000 feet underground
using trains that would travel at speeds of 450 miles per hour. Similar to the dumb tunnel concept,
no admission of maglevs connecting stiffs is publicly available. However, there is an
overwhelming body of historical evidence that U.S. and defense contractors have had a keen
interest in high-speed underground transit systems traveling at least as fast as a commercial airliner.
To close off our investigation, I would like to return to 1992's Cosmic Top Secret by Bill
Hamilton. In this masterpiece of a book, Hamilton provides a map of underground facilities and
tunnels provided to him by one TAL in 1990. Some data here is from Thomas C., aka Thomas Castillo,
which is an extremely controversial source with the Dulcey, New Mexico story, so instead,
let's go ahead and analyze the map. This network spans the American West and Southwest with major
installations listed in Southern California, New Mexico, and Colorado. As expected earlier,
we find Edwards Air Force Base connected to myriad locations including numerous small marks labeled
R&D. We also see a supposed underground base marked Cat. This is of course Catalina Island,
fascinating how in 2023 and 2024, discussion began to swirl of an underground extraterrestrial
or human base off of Catalina Island. We also see Area 51 as a major reference with connections to
Tonopah, an installation infamous in UFO lore as well. We also find interesting solo marked
dumps not connected in this alleged system including Fort Hachuca, Arizona, a location
I estimate is involved heavily in UFO programs. Remember if you will, Fort Hachuca holds a defense
agency major range and test facility base, a critical core facility called the Joint Interoperability
Center. Army intelligence at Fort Hachuca was previously run by U.S. Army INSCOM founder,
Major General Albert Stubblebine. Stubblebine and INSCOM have been accused by myself in numerous
projects amongst others as engaging in UFO crash retrieval, storage, and material exploitation.
Therefore, it is really no surprise to see Hamilton's map designate Fort Hachuca as a
dumb location. On the map are many locations in New Mexico including the controversial Dulce,
Los Alamos, and Sandia slash Kirtland. The latter two we know have underground facilities,
indeed the same extents to Cheyenne in Colorado. Intriguing to note here is an installation in
Chihuahua, Mexico. This subject wouldn't be touched on again until Jake Barber's
Romana Clay called Sentinels of Ether. This project describes a 2004 blue on blue UFO
retrieval team fire operation in which the clandestine team flew into a disguised base
hidden in the mountains of Chihuahua. What happens when we start to compare this map to others?
See now a comparison between Hamilton's dumb network and Rand's VHST. See the interesting
direct route shared across the two maps through the northern area of Arizona and New Mexico.
Additionally, observe how Southern California sees routes split to both Southern California
near San Diego and Northern California near Sacramento before continuing north to Portland
and Washington. Also notice connections to Denver on both locations. Outside of Cheyenne Mountain
Complex, Denver, Colorado is home to an enormous underground FEMA complex. This is likely a
continuity of government or COG complex. My true interest lies in comparing the Hamilton
piece to defense laboratories and centers across the United States. Here we will not find Groom
Lake amongst other select facilities, but I believe this comparison is of critical importance.
If you will, please forgive the maps not lining up. The 1990 map is scaled differently than the
2019 DOD map, so the two are not merged to scale perfectly. Aligning the two maps brings extreme
interest to both dumb locations as well as markings on the Hamilton piece that are labeled
R&D. Since this map pertains to connected underground UFO installations, we can assume
by the map's legend these locations do not employ dumbs but are still focused on UFO legacy R&D.
As expected, Southern California brings a massive amount of locations of interest.
Even outside of the Antelope Valley to the southwest in Los Angeles lies a tremendous
amount of DOD RDT&E labs, FFRDCs like RAND and Aerospace Corporations, and UARCs like the USC
Institute for Creative Technologies. Numerous other locations outside of the Antelope line up
between the two maps we have discussed throughout this investigation, including Fort Hachuca,
Cheyenne Mountain, Colorado, Dugway and its two MRTFBs, Los Alamos, White Sands Missile Range,
Sandia, and Kirtland Air Force Base. From referencing DOD labs, we can also learn Kirtland
and its proven underground facilities stand out even more. Kirtland additionally holds the Air
Force Research Lab's Space Vehicles Directorate and Directed Energy Directorate. Of note shared
on these maps, albeit slightly shifted, is the 4th Defense Estate Microelectronics Activity in
Northern California. In DOD terms, 4th Estate describes non-military parts of the DOD. These
include the Defense Contract Audit Agency, Defense Contract Management Agency, and the Defense
Finance and Accounting Service. 4th Estate agencies and field activities all watching this video
might recognize are DARPA and the Defense Missile Agency. Prior to this investigation, I had never
come across mention of a dump below the DMEA, so this is a terrific point of research moving
forward. Let's also reference more of the non-connected R&D locations on Hamilton's
map that exist as acknowledged DOD RDT&E facilities. In Nebraska, on both maps,
we find identification of the US STRATCOM, University Affiliated Research Center,
the University of Nebraska National Strategic Research Institute. Viewers of my work know UARCs
and FFRDCs are cornerstones of UAP legacy programs, so it is interesting to see Hamilton identify a
as a UFO R&D location all the way back in 1992 that would not be founded until 2012.
In Oklahoma, we observe Fort Sill as UFO R&D and the Naval Surface Warfare Center Indian Head
Special Weapons Division McAllister Detachment as UFO storage. I have come across both of these
locations in my research, however, it is interesting to see an NSWC location labeled as storage,
especially after the testimony of Randy Anderson and the Off-World Technologies Division at the
Naval Surface Warfare Center crane. In northern Kansas, we observe overlap of a UFO research
facility. This facility is the US Army Leavenworth Research Unit. In Texas, we find Fort Hood Army
Research Unit as a UFO research location, however, it is interesting to see this facility is not
marked as a STIF, especially after numerous testimony relayed by and research done by
Leonard Stringfield. The Hamilton map deserves an entire investigation of its own and possibly,
I will do so with Dr. Soder, because after all, this map does accuse dumbs of existing at all
locations we have previously discussed as well as many that warrant further investigation including
Fort Stockton, Fort Irwin, Vandenberg AFB, Chocolate Mountains Aerial Gunnery Range, 29 Palms,
Hutchinson Air Force Station, and Peterson Air Force Base as well as the cities of Kingsley,
Nebraska, Tulsa, Oklahoma, and Riverton, Wyoming. I have spoken to Dr. Soder and he has spoken
directly with Bill Hamilton regarding this map so just maybe he can aid in further dissecting
of these locations. Hey guys, it's Gurb and if you're still with me, thank you so much for joining
me in this. At this point, hour twenty, hour and a half investigation into dumbs. As many of you
know and as many people have been looking forward to this project, dumbs are a passion project of
mine. I speak about installations under Dugway, under the Antelope Valley, under the Northrop
Tejon and Hellendale facilities in numerous videos. I think probably my last four videos straight I
have mentioned one if not multiple of these locations. As we made it to the end of this video,
I'd like to thank again Dr. Richard Soder for all of his excellent research. Now this video is going
to be doing things a little bit differently. Of course, in every single one of my videos,
I include my show notes in the video description or a link. Please bear with me a couple days here as
I have not only compiled my research links for this video, but also every single document that
I can find that Dr. Richard Soder has included in his three books. So every single defense
technical document, every single Army Corps of Engineer document, every single document I could
find which there's hundreds. So please allow me a couple days to compile all that and deliver that
because I think it's excellent to read through all of those and please read through Dr. Richard
Soder's books. They're excellent. As we know from today, the subject of dumbs is very vast. It's
almost impossible to know where and when to start. There's a tremendous amount of literature on deep
underground facilities for continuity of government use, for ICBM silos, for just general
underground installations accessible by vertical or inclined shaft. There's also a tremendous
amount of information specifically starting post 1974 with Bechtel on large-scale tunneling systems
and conventional and unconventional blasting methods. This would be a tunnel boring machine
or a nuclear subterrene as a conventional method or explosives or possibly nuclear detonation as
unconventional and also a lot of literature on maglev technology. I know these three subjects
of interconnected dumb bases are often scoffed at without a lot of research but this is a very
serious subject and at least I would say focused in the southwest and the American desert and the
east there are probably large networks of dumbs. This would include New Mexico, Arizona, Southern
California, possibly up to connecting to Dugway and Colorado and then a network out east including
the Warrenton Army Training Facility, Camp Peary, Camp David, the D.U.C.C. which I wager highly exists
and so forth. Now of course let's treat this video as a part one. A part two will be a project with
Dr. Richard Soder. I spoke to him the other week for about two to three hours and he graciously agreed
to come on the show and talk more about dumbs. I think what's really interesting here is there
are numerous informants just like Bill Hamilton had that have told him about installations and
facilities and perhaps he can tell those on our project together and relay them because he said
some to me in our conversations that he hasn't repeated publicly that are indeed quite interesting.
Also when Bill Hamilton was still alive Dr. Richard Soder talked to him at length about his
network of dumbs maps so possibly for an hour, hour and a half we will dive into that so please
look forward to a Dr. Richard Soder project coming in the future and please also look forward to the
show notes. You know another thing I'm doing is I'm planning to build a website no sign up needed
it's not the DPI archive but I'm planning to put up a website where I have videos, transcripts of
the videos and all research links so I'd like to put those there. The only reason I plan to do this
is to make it easier to access all the materials I put forth with my research but I want to know
what everybody thinks about dumbs, specifically networks of dumbs. Dumbs are not a controversial
thing, dumbs do indeed exist and from numerous testimony whether that be Leonard Stringfield,
whether that be testimony to Soder, to Hamilton, to myself, there is a incredible argument that
many of these facilities, dumb facilities, engage in UAP legacy programs. I like to think back to
the testimony of MS for example which led to a tremendously fruitful venture into the dumb under
Dugway and of course we even have a specific entrance to that facility. Other research from
other informants can be done on this. Another thing I did differently in this project of course
is I hardly interject when witnesses have spoken to me about testimony or given me testimony.
I thought it prudent in this investigation just when speaking about various dumb facilities and
to summarize these include I've spoken to individuals who have been in networks under
the Antelope Valley in a location under Texas that connected via underground train that went
so fast it reminded this army veteran of his fear of flying to white sands missile range as well as
the what we might call the deep underground command center out east. This is a location
deep under the pentagon how deep I don't know however I have good insight this is a facility
or at least there are facilities here that are run by the CIA directorate of science and technology.
If that sounds familiar to you that was the CIA office that blocked the material transfer in 2008
from Lockheed Martin to the OSAP program and that was the 1953 Kingman crash. But the networks of
dumbs are what are so interesting to me for example harkening back to the story of Ed and the Nevada
Test and Training Range and Edwards Air Force Base there's other testimony about connections
in bases in southern California to to Area 51 Tonopah the Nevada Test and Training Range.
If I could ever get Ed to sit down in a room and believe me I've tried to speak to him the first
thing I would ask him if there's connective tunneling systems and what type of vehicles
if there are that connect these two places. Now absent in this video of course I talked about
the beginning other stories of Bob Lazar the stories of Dulcey Bace and Thomas Castillo
and the story of Phil Schneider. I believe that these in that these witnesses these subjects are
very controversial so I didn't include them because of their controversy but because
when I have such controversial claims I think it prudent to investigate those and vet those
and try to determine any sort of objective information from those when we can. So you know
S4 for example I do believe S4 is a facility that does indeed exist does it have extraterrestrial
or non-human technology I don't know an individual I've spoken to that went to S4 talked about
colored lines where to walk but he didn't see anything that would say non-human technology
but then again he was not privy to the entire base but because of that I would like to focus
on subjects like S4 maybe Dulcey Bace and maybe other locations as well and I will do those in
a separate project. With this project I wanted to take as objective of an approach as I could I
wanted to combine the facts we know about Dums about tunnel systems about maglev systems and
relay those to stories of the Antelope Valley stories of locations out east I mean there is
a tremendous amount of facilities I didn't get to cover here that I would like to revisit so
again as I spoke about in the project with Dr. Richard Sauter this is just kind of a taste
into Dums I do think this is one of the most consequential subjects of UFO legacy programs
you know like I said and I'll say it again most underground facilities as we see from the US
Army Corps of Engineers and other documents were first proposed as a continuity of government a
COG or a ICBM silo facility and we know that is partially true in the large FEMA underground
center near Denver Colorado which everybody knows I'm from Colorado so that's near where I am so
the clandestine operation when did these start as we talked about the Dums there's a good argument
that in post 1961 when the US Army Corps of Engineers really started to look into underground
facilities massive ones ranging up to up to in some documents 8 000 feet underground
into the late 90s I think this is when the vast majority of underground installations were built
when were the connective tunnels built if these do exist which I believe many locations do feature
connective tunnels this of course as we saw in the Bechtel report with conventional and unconventional
tunneling methods probably started around 1974 between 1972 and 1974 a whole host of tunneling
committees and institutes were set up to investigate massive tunneling systems and of course
following in the 80s into the 90s we see the same thing with maglev technology so I think the order
of operations here is likely the dumbest built maybe a decade later connective tunnels are built
and maybe a decade after that the full train systems are implemented I mean in the 90s we
see the National Maglev Institute and we see corporations like Grumman like General Dynamics
like Battelle doing aboveboard maglev research so this could likely imply they have been doing
clandestine research into similar projects into electromagnetics long before then so it's a it's
an incredibly fascinating subject especially when you start to look at the Bureau of Reclamation
and what Dr. Sautter has relayed from his informants about the Bureau of Reclamation
this was possibly an aboveboard tunneling system in the American Southwest that featured
clandestine secondary tunnels to bore out whatever was needed and as we saw in the list I scrolled
through there are hundreds of tunnels from the BOR that in the mid to late 20th century and some
of these are hundreds of miles long some of these are thousands and they range in depths from
just underground to up to near a thousand feet so when Dr. Sautter's informant relayed to him
that 10 men can operate a TBM and a good TBM in good conditions can chew through up to 10 miles per
year I do think this is a likely candidate you know this harkens back to other UFO legacy program
funding operations how we what we can make educated guesses via IRAD, sole source contracts,
IDIQ and utilizing legitimate contracts to skim off funds for UFO legacy programs.
Now again I want to know what everybody thinks if there are people here who have been to underground
facilities massive deep underground facilities please reach out to me I would love to hear about
your experience I will respect your anonymity but if you have a location a facility to describe
or an experience in such a facility please reach out to me I would love to talk to you but
again guys let me know in the comments what you think this has been a long spiel almost 11 minutes
I think I've rambled quite a bit please remember to like and subscribe on the video and remember
guys I do have a Patreon I don't gatekeep my content in my opinion this might be stubborn
or this might be a bit narcissistic I think the content is important to view so I'm not going to
gatekeep anything because I would like all of my research all of my projects and all my research
materials to be publicly available to anybody so the Patreon is there to support what you think
the channel is worth not to lock off any content so with that guys I have a couple projects coming
up I'm really really really darn excited about I'm trying to think about how I'm going to juggle
these but about three projects on the immediate mind I'm already working on including and that
includes the project with Dr. Richard Sautter so I will catch everybody soon and thank you so very
much for joining me bye now