Officially designated as the Dugway Proving Ground, this military facility covers an astounding
1,250 square miles of the Great Salt Lake Desert.
Dugway's official mission is to test top-secret weapons and aerospace systems, but UFO researchers
believe the true purpose of Area 52 is even more sinister.
When you imagine UFO legacy program operations focused on the retrieval and exploitation
of technologies of unknown origin, what kind of facilities come to mind?
Is it Area 51 and its alleged legendary auxiliary site S-4?
Maybe you think of the Naval Surface Warfare Center crane and its possible off-world technologies
division.
Or perhaps you reference China Lake Weapon Center, Edwards Air Force Base, Wright-Patterson
or any number of U.S. Department of Defense installations that are steeped in UFO lore.
Maybe, just maybe, when imagining UFO legacy program locations, you picture Dugway Proving
Ground, an enormous 1,300 square mile U.S. Army installation nestled between three mountain
ranges in remote Utah that specializes in the testing of biological and chemical weapons.
Being referred to as Area 52, Dugway Proving Ground rose to prominence in the late 90s
as the successor to Area 51's UFO programs due to heavy public exposure on the once-denied
Nevada site.
Ever since, the Utah site and accompanying two premier MRTFBs have been the focus for
Deep Six's clandestine UAP operations.
But this spotlight doesn't solely focus on the enormous facilities sprawling across
the Utah desert.
Dugway has additionally been accused as the location of a DUM, a Deep Underground Military
Base.
Today, we shed light on Dugway and discussion of its technologies of unknown origin, exploitation
programs and subterranean presence, through analysis of the facility's intriguing Army
and Air Force MRTFBs, study of defense contractors present on site, and careful evaluation of
the witness testimony of one MS, who I have covered on this channel before, who stumbled
upon a craft of likely non-human origin at the infamous Dugway range.
Hey guys, it's UAPGurb and I am thrilled for you to join me as we venture into the
world of legacy UFO programs to analyze Dugway Proving Ground.
How deep does the rabbit hole go between the United States' premier biological and chemical
weapons testing facility and non-human technology?
What individuals, military units and corporations possibly engage with Dugway and UFO reversals
force engineering and material exploitation programs?
And does Dugway operate such UFO programs above and below the Earth's surface?
Join me today as we find out.
Dugway Proving Ground is located 85 miles southwest of Salt Lake City in Tewila County,
Utah.
It encompasses over 1,250 square miles and it is larger than the US state of Rhode Island.
The site itself is ideal for seclusion and privacy free from urban encroachment, light
pollution and excess acoustic and electronic noise.
Dugway is surrounded by mountains, salt flats and desert terrain.
These geological features combined with a defense retainer that will apprehend approaching
civilians with armed personnel and black-op helicopters.
Make the Utah Proving Ground perfect for clandestine and classified military test and evaluation.
Dugway was founded in 1942 with the mission to test US and allied chemical and biological
defense systems and perform nuclear, biological and chemical survivability testing and training
of defense material using chemical and biological agents and stimulants.
The Utah Proving Ground uses its state-of-the-art laboratories and chambers to conduct testing
and training under environmentally controlled conditions.
Dugway's inception arose from the 1941 Pearl Harbor attacks which quickly saw the United
States military increase military capabilities in numerous areas including chemical and biological
warfare.
The infamous site has participated in the never-ending global war on terrorism, employing
special forces mission rehearsals, classified testing and biochem urgent need equipment testing.
Dugway has a laundry list of significant accomplishments including unmanned aerial systems test support
but we will skip over exploring this entire list of accomplishments.
According to a 2021 US Army Dugway Proving Ground Mission and Capabilities Overview public
Dugway is a massive contributor to Utah's economy, employing a total of 2,120 employees
and residents, 784 of which are primarily Army and Air Force contractors, 622 of which
consist of primary mission and installation contracting command, think on-site security
personnel, and 486 of these military or defense agency civilians.
Dugway or DPG as we'll refer to it throughout this project partners with myriad US military,
government and intelligence agencies including many that harbor our interests throughout
this investigation, US Army Airborne, Navy, SOCOM aka Special Operations Command, the
388th Range Squadron out of Hill Air Force Base, Departments of Justice, Homeland Security
and Interior, NASA and three universities.
Out of these three universities I would like to draw specific mention to Utah State University.
USU employs a university affiliated research center, UARC, for the Missile Defense Agency
known as the Space Dynamics Laboratory.
In numerous projects I have spoken on UARC's and their similar counterparts federally funded
research and development centers, FFRDCs.
FFRDCs and UARCs are semi-private DOD driven research and development institutions I have
spoken ad nauseam are key contributors to UAP legacy programs.
While not the topic of today, UARCs and FFRDCs likely exist as a sort of project manager
serving as subject matter experts and research and development leaders for joint corporate
and US government UAP programs.
In fact, I believe these two types of institutions to be exponentially more knowledgeable on
and crucial to UFO exploitation programs than most defense contractors through their
sole source contracts.
Another topic for another day, however, FFRDC will come up again throughout this presentation.
For this investigation we will primarily be focusing on two locations on Dugway known
as MRTFBs, Major Range Test and Facility Bases.
MRTFBs are known as the quote, core set of DOD test and evaluation infrastructure and
associated workforce that must be preserved as a national asset to provide T&E capabilities
to support the DOD acquisition system, end quote.
The quote, unquote, critical core of test bases comprise over 10 million acres of land
in the United States, employ over 25,000 people annually and receive over $4 billion in acknowledged
funding annually.
There exists a total of 23 acknowledged MRTFBs, 8 Army including Yuma Test Center Arizona
and White Sands Missile Range, 6 Navy installations including Naval Air Warfare Center Pax River
and China Lake Naval Warfare Center and 7 Air Force bases including Edwards 412 Test
Wing, Nevada Test and Training Range and the 30th Space Wing at Vandenberg and 2 Defense
Agency Bases.
Army here will associate all listed locations with mentions of UFO legacy programs.
I myself have extensively published on Witness Ed, who spoke of a joint UFO reverse engineering
operation between the Nevada Test and Training Range and Edwards 412 Test Wing in California.
I strongly recommend viewing this project if you have not already.
Dugway Proving Ground possesses one such MRTFB, the US Army's West Desert Test Center and
also shares the South Range of the Air Force's MRTFB, Utah Test and Training Range with nearby
Hill Air Force Base.
Pay close attention to these two major bases as when we analyze the testimony of MS, we
will be exploring a thesis of a joint Army and Air Force legacy program comprised of
the WDTC West Desert Test Center and the UTTR Utah Test and Training Range that extend deep
below the Earth's surface.
And while on the subject of MRTFBs, we will dive into much more detail later on, including
discussing the Avery Technical Center and shared Michael Army Airfield which I believe is the
operational above-ground testing location of this joint UFO project.
But before we venture into Dugway's history with UFO, let's touch on one more thing while
the West Desert Test Center is fresh in your mind.
The questions at WDTC are spearheaded by Army Test and Evaluation Command.
As we begin to implicate Dugway and thus ATEC as engaging in UFO legacy programs, I find
the Army Test and Evaluation Organization structure well worth referencing.
Analyzing the reporting structure of ATEC, far up the food chain we can observe the Secretary
of the Army as well as the Chief of Staff and Vice Chief of Staff of the Army answering
directly to the US Secretary of Defense.
Numerous subsets pertain to these four positions including Director of Operational Test and
Evaluation.
But what is interesting here is oversight and T&E policy as well as USA Tech Command
is independent from conventional Army Research and Development Test and Evaluation structure.
This independence is mandated by the Office of Management and Budget as well as the Office
of the Secretary of Defense.
This separation exists apparently to ensure warfighter safety through unbiased evaluation
as well as credibility with decision makers.
But I can't help but to think here, such a structure could quickly lead to a lack of
oversight on ATEC programs and thus a lack of oversight on West Desert Test Center programs
at Dugway Proving Ground.
Let us pause and reflect on historical mentions of Dugway and analyze how and why this site
has often been referred to as Area 52.
Serving as the United States premier biological and chemical weapons facility, it is no surprise
the secrets of Dugway and its decades of classified operations are held close to the chest of
US military and intelligence.
I would like to briefly discuss a fascinating alleged 1953 UFO crash retrieval case that
occurred less than one month after and solely 200 miles north of the infamous 1953 Kingman,
Arizona crash.
The Garrison, Utah, UFO crash retrieval was investigated at length by UFO researcher Steve
Jones and relayed as a moderate confidence case in Ryan S. Wood's masterpiece, Magic
Eyes Only.
Steve Jones was first introduced to the case by a group called the Phoenix Project in 1993.
A group member, Al, discussed the case with 10-15 large aerial photos dated June of 1953.
These images apparently depicted a large valley with a triangular-shaped area on the ground.
A remote station resides alongside the feature called the Desert Range Experimental Station
or D-RES, which is located on the southwest of Dugway's West Desert Test Center extending
from Tooele to Millard County.
D-RES is managed by the U.S. Forest Service, an arm of the Department of Agriculture.
The Phoenix Project group presented to Jones a D-RES logbook dated 1979-1980 that featured
peculiar entries such as USAF at Army personnel from Fort Carson, Colorado, USAF Command Center
and representatives from a defense contractor.
Phoenix Project believed the D-RES to be a front for a secret research facility that
studied a crashed UFO that was buried, resulting in the surrounding geology.
During his many visits to the site, Steve Jones was indeed able to track down witnesses
who claimed to see such a crashed object.
Local resident Bart Wright claimed as a child living eight miles outside of Garrison he
saw a strange blue light streak across the sky and crash near the side of the valley
containing D-RES.
According to Wright, the impact caused the ground to shake and sky to light up.
Steve Jones hired a geologist in 1999 named Lamont Sorenson to conduct magnimeter and
seismic tests on the triangular formation where the craft allegedly crashed.
The geologist found no evidence of underground anomalies but did claim he did not think the
formation was made by nature.
He thought that some kind of artificial digging process did in fact take place.
Whenever a buried UFO is mentioned, this leads to an interesting case but ultimately the
Garrison, Utah crash is a dead end.
I would also like to reference the story of the flux liner alien reproduction vehicle
many viewers of this channel will be quite familiar with.
During his decades of investigating into the copy vehicles observed by primary witness
Brad Sorenson at the 1988 Norton Air Force Base Air Show, the late Mark McCandlish would
encounter multiple witnesses who had encountered and seen crafts similar to the instantly identifiable
flux liner.
Of note were two photographs McCandlish obtained possession of from USAAF Captain Harvey Williams.
Williams photographed this disc in 1967 while flying a C-47 at 12,000 feet over Provo, Utah.
The object bears striking resemblance to the flux liner and possibly details an intriguing
evolution in imaging technology from 1967 to Brad's observation in 1988.
Let me explain.
Brad and McCandlish claimed the ARV flew via a synthetic vision system, overlapping cameras
that allowed for a pilot inside the craft to access full 3D view when operating the
craft.
The cameras were housed in protective acrylic bubbles, almost appearing as off-the-shelf
components.
Due to cameras being much larger in 1967, if the USAAF Captain did indeed photograph
an early model of the flux liner, this would feature a larger synthetic vision system to
accommodate larger camera technology.
But I am equally if not more interested in the location of this sighting at a low altitude
of 12,000 feet.
Provo, Utah is only 100 miles from Dugway and less than 75 miles from Hill Air Force
Base.
Remember what we discussed earlier.
Dugway and Hill Air Force Base share runways such as the Dugway-Michael Army Airfield and
operate together in the Utah Test and Training Range southern area.
Also recall the numerous mentions of MRTFBs and how two such critical cores reside on
Dugway.
I would once again like to reference Witness Ed and the Joint Reverse Engineering Program
between the Edwards 412th Test Wing and the Nevada Test and Training Range.
Both the 412th and NTTR are Air Force MRTFBs, just as the UTTR is.
The testimony of Ed explores two MRTFBs working in conjunction to test reverse engineered
vehicles.
USAAF Master Sergeant Edgar Fouchet stated the TR-3B reverse engineered triangle saw
operations at Area 51, which is part of the NTTR, and pilots inside the triangle were
pooled from Edwards Air Force Test Pilot School, part of the 412th.
The Fluxliner alien reproduction vehicles were allegedly shown at Norton Air Force Base
in 1988, which is within extreme proximity to the fabled USAAF Plant 42 and Edwards Air
Force Base.
If Harvey Williams did indeed image early iterations of the Fluxliner, this would imply
a UFO reverse engineering and ARV testing program between two MRTFBs.
Utah Test and Training Range and Edwards 412th Test Wing.
This is incredibly similar to the claims of Ed and Fouchet.
Further in this exploration, we will investigate a possible UFO legacy program operating across
both Army and Air Force MRTFBs at Dugway, but we will save this for later.
In June of 1997, Popular Mechanics Magazine published a stunning monthly issue.
The titular article titled The New Area 51 discussed the Air Force abandoning its once
most secretive site for top-secret testing and moved to a new, more private location.
Let's of course dive into this intriguing article to discover the quote-unquote New
Area 51 and its secret airbase operations.
Right off the jump, the images in this piece are fascinating.
We see a sticky note that says Call Admiral Inman at Science Applications International.
Now I know this isn't the subject of the video, but for an article that mocks the idea
of UFO reverse engineering programs by claiming those who believe the X-Files and existence
of a dress collection by former FBI Director Edgar Hoover are the type of people to believe
in UFO crash retrievals, why is Bobby Ray Inman mentioned?
Members of this channel may recall recent mention of Inman in the Northrop Grumman Project.
Admiral Bobby Ray Inman, former NSA Director, CIA Deputy Director, and Science Applications
International Corporation SAIC board member, once discussed UFO recovered vehicles to NASA
mission specialist Bob Eschler.
Inman also referred Eschler to retired Rear Admiral and BDM board member Sumner Shapiro,
who informed Eschler UAP retrievals would see teams take apart craft, pack them up,
and ship them around the country to different laboratories.
Inman is an integral figure in the discussion of UFO crash retrievals in the 1980s.
And I do not need to go into SAIC and their likely involvement in an off-world technologies
division at NSWC Crane.
This tiny sticky note in a rather deprecating article is incredibly interesting.
The Popular Mechanics piece states due to overexposure as America's worst kept secret,
Area 51 shut down.
This is of course objectively false, however, later individuals we will discuss in this
project reference a percentage of up to 40% of Area 51's clandestine operations moving
to Dugway.
One primary reason for the move out of Area 51 according to the Popular Mechanics author
Jim Wilson was the need for a different type of proving ground for ultra-high performance
military aircraft.
After some impressive sleuthing including referencing Air Force Base Command General
Howell Estes and NASA Administrator Daniel Goldin's 1997 agreement to share quote-unquote
redundant assets, as well as a 1996 NASA announcement stating Michael Army Airfield would share
as a runway for several X-33 missions, Popular Mechanics narrowed in on Utah.
In a quick side note, the X-33 aircraft capable of Mach 15 was a Lockheed Martin Skunk Works
production formed out of the Palmdale facility.
Both Michael Army Airfield, which sits nestled on Dugway's West Desert Test Center within
the Avery Technical Center and don't worry much more on this later, as well as Green
River Utah Launch Complex part of White Sands Missile Range were ideal installations for
the new Area 51.
Michael Army Airfield possessed an equally, if not more, deterring surrounding area than
Area 51.
Not only is the Airfield situated on 1,300 square miles of Dugway ranges, but it is also
bordered by numerous mountain ranges and salt flats.
The Airfield did, however, lack adequate landing runways according to Popular Mechanics, which
is why Utah Launch Complex, situated only 200 miles away, served as the ideal dance
partner for the Michael Army Airfield.
The magazine attempted flyovers of the Airfield to snap images of the surrounding area, but
were warned of being shot down.
Additionally, the magazine attempted to purchase satellite imagery of the Utah Launch Complex
but was denied due to security reasons.
The claims of a new Area 51 are not isolated to mainstream publishers like Popular Mechanics.
Let's revisit the testimony of Edgar Fouchet in the TR-3B.
Like I said in the Northrop Project, many are critical of Fouchet due to his claims
of a reverse-engineered triangular alien reproduction vehicle with little in the way of physical
proof.
However, his disclosures have led to incredibly actionable intelligence and worthwhile investigation.
In his 1998 IUFO-C International UFO Congress presentation, Fouchet presented comprehensive
disclosures of TR-3B, Area 51, NSA's Men in Black Treat, EG&G, and Project Red Light,
as well as the DARSS Defense Advanced Research Center, which I have talked about numerous
times on this channel.
In the presentation, Fouchet made mention to a source informing him beginning in 1992
the Air Force conducted a contingency plan due to massive public contention on Area 51.
This would see the majority of exotic Air Force platforms relocated to Utah, Colorado,
Alaska, Greenland, Diego Garcia, and south of Area 51 to S4.
And there is evidence to show a heavy focus on Area 51 and UFO programs in the early 1990s,
which may in fact have seen projects moved out of Area 51 Groom Lake.
In 1990, Jane's defense writer James Goodall revealed a thesis of at least eight black
programs flying out of Area 51 Groom Lake, including a silent triangle utilizing unconventional
technologies.
An unnamed source Goodall knew for 12 years stationed at Groom Lake later explained that
UAP positively existed at the base while another source stated quote,
We have things out there that are literally out of this world, better than Star Trek or
anything you can see in the movies, end quote.
Claims of Area 51 moving clandestine operations to Dugway were additionally made by
One A.H.
A.H. claimed to be a former Boeing employee who leveraged significant knowledge on UFO
legacy programs from friends at the NSA, CIA, NASA, JPL, ONI, NRO, Area 51, the Air Force,
Northrop Grumman, Boeing, and others.
A.H. appeared as a primary witness on Stephen Greer's 2001 excellent disclosure briefing
document and had his testimony taped in the year 2000.
Now it's worth noting as I discussed in the Northrop Project, A.H. is likely a primary
source of information for Dr. Stephen Greer, similar to UFO researcher William Hamilton.
As A.H. has been in contact with Greer for decades, and Greer repeats much of what A.H.
has stated in the past.
Greer talks often of Dugway as a primary UFO legacy program site, discussing a Utah underground
complex south of Salt Lake City accessible only by air in the 2001 disclosure briefing
document and again in a 2016 presentation.
In this 2016 presentation, Greer discussed black program locations and code names which
relate to the testimony of Ed.
In this discussion, Greer tags Dugway as quote, the most critical one, end quote, when discussing
black program facilities.
And in Utah, one of the most critical, and this is the most critical one that's new,
is the Dugway proving grounds outside of Provo.
And this is classified airspace above and no access by ground.
Above ground, you don't see much and everything is underground.
Richard Foesch, this Naval Research Labs official, was out there with some Generation Five or
Six or whatever night scopes doing an operation.
And he looked out and he saw these objects coming out from underground that then zipped
over and that were these massive disk in triangular shape, anti-gravity objects that
were ours.
And some were just sitting out there watching him.
And that's outside of Provo out in the desert.
It is not inconceivable many of Greer's early ideas on Dugway were disclosed to him
by witness A.H.
After all, in 2000, A.H. did in fact reference an underground Utah installation southwest
of Salt Lake City accessible only by air that tests and maintains extra-terrestrial
technology.
We're incorporating this technology from these crafts at Area 51.
And I also found out that they are moving a lot of the personnel and some of the equipment
and some of the extra-terrestrial technology equipment and the craft to base up in Utah.
However, we can find some extremely interesting pre-2000s discussion of Dugway by Greer.
See on screen now a March 1998 email exchange with Greer and UFO investigator Steve Jones.
Yes, the same investigator we discussed above with the alleged 1953 Garrison, Utah UFO crash.
In these initial exchanges, Jones details his field notes while near the Desert Range
experimental station studying the retrieval case.
Jones mentioned he had learned that work from Area 51 Groom Lake had indeed been moved to
Dugway in an area called Dog, west of the main gate.
Jones himself had collected data since the 1980s on tarped trucks left in the middle
of nowhere in Utah.
These truckloads were left between Hill Air Force Base north of Salt Lake and Wendover,
Utah bordering Nevada.
This between Area is of course Dugway and the Utah Test and Training Range.
Recall also that Dugway and Hill Air Force Base share airstrips in the UTTR, Hill itself
and its 388th Range Squadron operate on the Dugway-Michael Army Airfield.
What is more intriguing to me is an even earlier 1996 exchange of emails between Greer and
one A.J. Cradock with the subject line, quote,
Area 51, insiders say area southwest of Tuwila, Utah deserve a look, end quote.
A.J. aka Tony Cradock once did work with Greer, serving as webmaster for Seaseti.org.
Cradock is also the founder and CEO of Cradock, an oil and gas service provider in Libya.
Why did a CEO with 40 years' experience in the international petroleum industry engage
in UFO research with Greer in the 90s?
Anyways, in this email addressed to Greer, Cradock links a discussion with an insider
source.
The sender or insider had their credentials withheld but claimed to work on several sites
checking badges and running ground surveillance equipment, tremor sensors, ground surveillance
radar, etc.
The source additionally discussed EMP weaponry that could fry vehicle computers or electronics.
We live in a world where EMP devices are often discussed as legacy program weapons to shoot
down non-human craft, so this inclusion is interesting.
The source claims Cradock and others, implying Greer, were looking in two obvious directions
for UAP programs.
Although Area 51 did indeed have legacy programs, the source advised Cradock to look in the
state of Utah to the southwest of Tuwila County and west of Salt Lake City.
In this described area existed nine exclusion zones, four of which featured underground
locations, and this area, of course, is Dugway Proving Ground.
The Cradock-Greer connection here is fascinating and well worth exploring more.
However, remember this discussion of Dugway, Area 51, and mysterious programs took place
before the 1997 Popular Mechanics article on the new Area 51, Fouché's disclosures,
and A.H.'s film testimony.
Very pertinent, this insider source claimed to have knowledge of Dugway Proving Ground
and UFO legacy programs before any public exposure.
In June of 2023, the contentious Stephen Greer held his first whistleblower symposium at
the National Press Club since his 2001 panel that featured the legendary Mark McCandlish
amongst other first-hand witnesses.
Viewers may remember this panel as featuring the first public disclosures of Michael Herrera,
and we now know UFO whistleblower Jake Barber was in attendance.
One witness featured was not present at the event and had his story told by Greer.
This was a witness known by the pseudonym M.S.
So there's another gentleman, I'm going to run through these very quickly, we'd be here
for 30 hours if I didn't, I'm just giving you a tip of the iceberg, right?
This is a guy who was at the Dugway Proving Grounds for a key facility, M.S. we call him.
He was a work for C. Martin Corporation contractor, and he was in a facility that had an extraterrestrial
vehicle that was being studied by scientists, he knows the chief scientist involved, he
has named that individual to us, and they can all be subpoenaed now.
So this object was there in 2009, he didn't know the date of acquisition, but he thought
it was fairly recent.
Next.
He also was read into and had the chief scientist show him the location which we now have of
a dumb deep underground military base that is in the Dugway sector, so called Avery Sector
A-V-E-R-Y, and it has huge capacity for parking, you go in and there's a vast underground complex
in that location.
That location has been handed off to investigators with the U.S. government.
Next.
This gives an illustration of the size of this, you could put easily on the platform
that goes down the Air Force One, it's a very large elevator that goes down underground.
Upon release of the DPI archive, I investigated all files relating to this fascinating case.
Files on M.S. can be found under witness ID 10655.
Due to lapses in site security and data presented in the documents, I was able to track down
witness M.S. and hear his incredible encounter at Dugway first-hand.
Viewers of my channel may recall an interview with M.S. in UFO Witnesses' redacted list.
This project was deleted to respect the privacy of other witnesses covered in the project,
however, I would now like to revisit the testimony of M.S. with exponentially greater focus on
his claims.
The purpose of this investigation will be to identify specific buildings and military
units operating UFO legacy programs at Dugway Proving Ground as well as explore any and
all evidence to the enormous facility likely beneath the ground of the Utah site.
And before we get started, I would like to add, M.S. was approached by elements of the
Senate Select Committee on Intelligence to testify regarding his claims, and I can confirm
this as he shared with me the screenshots of their outreach.
M.S. turned down the requests as he is a current railroad employee and was unable to break
away from work for a week plus even when SSCI offered to pay for his travel.
I have a tremendous amount of respect for M.S. and find great value in researching his
testimony.
Witness M.S. served in the U.S. Navy and was even stationed in the Auxiliary Division of
the USS Teddy Roosevelt from 1990 to 2000.
During his service, M.S. entered into government contracting work.
From 2009 to 2013, he worked as a maintenance painter and sign technician for the C. Martin
Company.
C. Martin is a DoD contractor whose mission is to, quote, provide a fine-tuned approach
to managing people, time, and resources to provide quality services while creating value
for our customers, end quote.
C. Martin operates as a prime subcontractor with DoD in myriad capacities, specializing
in facility operations and maintenance, logistics, construction, range operation and maintenance,
etc.
And C. Martin does indeed have a location on Dugway located near the Administration
Center.
C. Martin's range and facility operations and maintenance contracting pertains greatly
to areas of interest for this investigation, specifically for Avery Technical Center, which
resides on Michael Army Airfield shared with Hill Air Force Base in the 388th Range Squadron
as well as locations a stone throw away called Ditto Technical Center.
Ditto contains the heart of the West Desert Test Center, which alongside ATEC tests chemicals
and biological weapons across the Utah Range.
In fact, the Army Test and Evaluation Command Major Range and Facility Base West Desert
Test Center is majorly funded by the Joint Services Chemical and Biological Defense Program
CBDP.
A lot of acronyms I know, but remember the term CBDP as we will discuss it again both
in relation to a specific contractor of interest at Dugway and for MS's story.
Now MS's experience begins in 2009, four months into his work for C. Martin at Dugway.
MS held a level 5 proximity badge, which allowed him access to myriad facilities across Dugway
to perform DoD contractor work.
And crucial to note, MS did not have a security clearance even though he occasionally states
level 5 clearance instead of badge.
MS would often ride into Dugway Proving Ground from Kaysville, Utah in a van where all other
travelers held top-secret clearance.
One normal day on the job, MS was tasked with electrical meter reading to allow the US government
to bill various contractors working on site.
There was a kid that was underneath me as my apprentice, because I was one of the maintenance
painters.
We took care of every facility out there.
And so he called in sick one day, I had to go read meters for him because that's what
they do.
So the government is in control of about 48% of that, and then 52% of it is private contractor.
And that's why they don't have to disclose anything.
So I had to go out and read his meter that day to get everything turned in to the government.
And I can't remember how many facilities there were.
There's probably a good 15, but those 15 took me to places where I've never really been
out there and opened my eyes up to a lot of different things.
This led MS to the Avery Technical Center where he entered into the quote-unquote Ghost
Building, a building nicknamed for having no numbers and no insignia.
Initially, I believed these facilities may be the material test facility or defensive
test chamber just south of Avery across the road from Ditto Technical Center.
After all, MS will soon describe the incident location as a clean room of sorts, and these
are high-profile CBDP test areas on site at the West Desert Test Center.
However, these installations are well-known and indeed named and numbered.
On the other hand, Avery Technical Center yields very few search results and quite often does
not appear in numerous U.S. Army and A-Tech documents.
In fact, Avery is curiously missing from DPG visitor guides while other areas of interest
such as Ditto are clearly mentioned.
Last time I covered MS's testimony, I had very little to work off regarding Avery, bar
a September 2017 DTTF facility description document and image from Facebook.
Before we investigate Avery, I must clearly state I am not revealing any classified information.
All locations and installations to be discussed can be referenced in public domain materials.
Let's reference a July 2012 unclassified report titled Environmental Assessment of
the Continued Exclusive Use of Department of the Army Land Located at U.S. Army Dugway
Proving Ground by members of the U.S. Air Force that offers incredible insights and
exploration into Avery Technical Center.
As mentioned numerous times so far, Avery Borders, Michael Army, Airfield and both the
Airfield and 40-acre Avery area are the focus of the 388th Range Squadron out of nearby
Hill Air Force Base.
Avery partly serves as air testing slash training for the 388th.
Historically, Avery had conducted numerous radiological studies and investigations into
the handling of radioactive material, including utilizing their radiobiological warfare laboratories
for the Atomic Energy Commission.
Avery employs an internal rail system for the transportation of radioactive materials.
This mention of an internal rail system is truly massive as we further on investigate
Dugway's alleged deep underground military base.
Aerial views of Avery yield no building descriptions unlike the nearby Ditto area where facilities
like the Diner, Contractor Jacobs, etc. are mentioned.
However, this environmental assessment document offers us a gorgeous detailed overview of
Avery locations, see on screen now.
Locations of interest include the 10-02 Avery Tunnel Entrance, 10-12 Photo Operations and
Maintenance, 10-38 General Storage and 10-16 Classified Storage.
Now other buildings outside of this map not marked Developed slash Unclassified exist,
however, I am willing to bet this experience took place at building 10-10, Test Operations.
With enough investigation, let's hear from MS as he entered this ghost building.
I walked into one that they called the ghost building because it just kind of came out
of nowhere.
No numbers on it, no nothing.
And opened up the door and basically had a M16 stuck in my chest and I had my level five
badge on.
I think that was the only thing that saved my tail that day.
There were what I call white coats, you know, they're kind of like doctors type set up
inside the building, kind of like a little clean room area and, you know, I'm sure,
I don't know if you've ever been in a car accident or not, but when you have your light
kind of flash before your eyes, everything starts to slow down and you start really taking
in a lot of information very quickly.
And so that's what I, you know, what happened to me is with the gun and everything else,
it just kind of, everything just started to fall into place.
That thing was on its own power, when I hover in, there's kind of a, I don't know if you've
seen the rendering or not.
Yes.
Well, the door, there was no door, it was just kind of open on the bottom, but everything
it just kind of just fall in there on its own power.
No noise, no, no anything.
But the white coats walk around it, analyze it, do all their stuff, I don't know.
There's, you know, a few gift arm guards in there at the time.
And I, like I said, I don't know if they were getting ready to move or, you know, what have
you.
Before we discuss this incredible craft, who were these armed guards that held MS at gunpoint?
Will numerous US facilities actually contract security personnel instead of enlisted men?
This is done through sole source contracts, a contract method Dr. Eric Davis has stated
is used for UAP legacy programs.
These contracts were given to private security companies post 9-11 to bolster US Army and
other military installation security.
I have found a 2006 General Accounting Office report titled, quote, Army's Guard Program
Requires Greater Oversight and Reassessment of Acquisition Approach, end quote.
This document discusses all contracted security personnel issued by the Army.
Dugway Proving Ground utilized Chenega Integrated Systems.
In future projects, I will be interested in exploring both Chenega and their subcontractor
Vance Federal Security Services.
Wackenhut Services, which Admiral Bobby Ray Inman was formerly a board member of, is a
private security corporation I highly suspect was involved in UAP legacy program security.
Wackenhut, like Vance Federal Security Systems, were used as subcontractors to Army installation,
not primary contractors.
Now unless contractor security personnel were highly cleared security specialists, I highly
doubt these private security companies could do more than scan vehicles and check badges
for access to legacy program sites.
Therefore, while I do reckon security services like Wackenhut and possibly Chenega have historically
performed installation and access security for UAP legacy program locations, I must conclude
the armed guards within proximity to the saucer were known as industrial security Indusec
personnel.
Now why that conclusion?
Industrial security, quote, conducts risk management activities with respect to the
U.S. government's defense industrial base, including critical technologies and the defense
supply chain through oversight of the National Industrial Security Program, issuance of facility
security clearances, foreign ownership, control, and influence mitigation measures, information
system cybersecurity oversight, and other activities related to protecting classified
and controlled unclassified national security information and related technology, end quote.
See on screen now an ATAC security specialist role for Dugway detailing an Indusec position.
Numerous responsibilities are listed for this role, including one such task, which is to
provide backup as the alternate special security officer for sensitive compartmented information
SEI programs.
Moving forward, investigating industrial security alongside UAP legacy program installations
will be paramount to my research.
Anyways, MS observed a saucer, roughly 10 feet tall and 20 feet in circumference.
The craft was hovering 10 to 12 inches off the ground.
The disc had no seams or fasteners and appeared to be made out of one piece and featured a
brushed metal appearance.
Around the craft were six lab technicians, I believe these to be ATAC and Battelle Memorial
Institute scientists, and more on this later.
MS believed this craft was in the process of being dismantled due to a bottom section
of the saucer being removed featuring a conical structure.
This conical section appeared to be floating and was almost independent of the craft.
One cannot help but draw parallels to Bob Lazar's drawn extraterrestrial reactor model
that he claims served as the propulsion mechanism for the sports model flying saucer.
Appearing by the craft was a flat screen television type of electronic, displaying a mapping
system.
More on this shortly.
That component area, that triangle, it's like it's floating.
Like it's generating a power.
I don't know, like a lot of, everything happened very, very quickly and just trying to take
in everything as fast as I could.
That section is basically doing its own thing.
When I stand in, you know, like, I don't know if you're fairly with something or just,
that's what I said, is it in transition to where it's like, you guys have it out in this
building out in the middle of nowhere, but then, you know, you have military vehicles
around, you have regular civilian vehicles around, but if this thing's on its own power
doing its own thing, what are you guys going to be doing with it?
Are you guys going to move it underground, more stuff going on, or have you taken what
you've wanted?
MS was taken by the guards to the nearby Ditto Technical Center to the garrison building
where two men in civilian clothing immediately began interrogating him.
The men were clad in black suits, and MS guessed these individuals to be FBI or CIA.
Quite possibly, these men could also be the infamous alleged NSA men in black treat.
For six hours, MS was harassed and interrogated.
The entire duration, MS maintained he had no idea what he saw and he was just doing
his job.
Eventually, he was let go.
I didn't say a word to these guys when they sat me down.
So I don't know if they knew that I saw something.
I don't know how they, you know what I mean?
But we, I still worked out there, so I still had a confidential agreement with them.
I still had all that, but I don't know where it would stand nowadays.
In the months and years following the incident, MS would discuss his encounter with family
and friends and ask around to find more.
MS reached out to various individuals affiliated with Dugway, including one such person.
MS stated, quote, I reached out to him and got him to talk about my situation by accident,
end quote.
This individual, pseudonym GP, worked in legacy operations at Dugway and possibly still does
today.
GP was a senior chemist involved in Dugway's UAP legacy programs both above ground and
in the subterranean facility where he claimed a light rail system connected the Dugway dumb
to numerous others around the country.
GP commented little about himself.
He primarily discussed with MS what he went through at Avery.
What we do know about GP, according to MS, is he is a DOD chemist by degree and was moved
to DPG after being promoted to work in UAP legacy programs.
MS lost connection with GP when he left C. Martin in 2014, but we are attempting to get
in contact with him today.
Often when discussing legacy program operations, we discuss research and development.
Engineers, physicists, military brass, the discussion of a chemist is indeed intriguing.
However, high level DOD chemists involved with technologies of unknown origin would
most certainly be stationed at Dugway, the nation's premier chemical and biological
testing facility.
What exactly did GP do at Dugway?
This is unknown, but speculating possibly his position could have seen him operating
with chemistry concepts surrounding the craft's propulsion system.
Analyzing biologics, studying metallurgy, the list is truly endless, but GP did have
enough knowledge to inform MS of the mapping system he saw near the craft.
And you'd have, you'd almost have like coordinates on there, is what I can describe.
So the way that, the way that that's set up to me is what it looked like in the mapping
system.
When I talked to the gentleman that was over top of a lot of that stuff out there, he said
they're basically able to put on that system two points of, you know, references or whatever
that they're going to do on reference points and basically generate a wormhole and drop
through.
And so that's where he says that interstellar travel is how they get from point A to point
B so quickly.
In short, GP stated the craft was extraterrestrial and operated via gravity displacement but
wouldn't comment further.
Now, MS received confirmation from both GP and a current railroad co-worker of a massive
underground facility beneath Dugway.
The co-worker even claimed to have assisted in digging out the tunneling system beneath
DPG.
MS and myself are currently setting up time to meet with this individual as well.
Deep underground military bases, DUMs, aka subterranean facilities or STFs, are a keen
interest of mine especially in relation to UAP legacy programs.
DUMs do indeed exist.
Quite often planned as underground ICBM facilities, underground command bunkers, corporate facilities
or COG continuity of government installations.
Indeed, even deep underground tunnel systems have been planned to connect these facilities
like in studies conducted by TRW.
Massive machines called tunnel boring machines and nuclear subterranes have historically
been associated with such intriguing underground work.
In fact, the United States National Research Council has historically published special
projects on the creation of DUMs.
Such as this 1981 and 1982 workshop on technology for the design and construction of deep underground
defense facilities.
DUMs are not our focus today besides under Dugway, but again I have discussed such underground
facilities before and plan to tackle the subject fully in the future.
For now I'll leave you with numerous underground tunnel systems in western states detailed
by the US Bureau of Reclamation.
Many tunnel systems listed in this report feature tunnel distances of tens of thousands
of feet of length, tens of feet of diameter covered by hundreds or thousands of feet
of earth.
Now many such tunnels serve as waterways and aqueducts, however it is fascinating to see
such a volume of massive underground tunnels.
It is critical to mention the Bureau of Reclamation was one of the key members on the 1981 and
1982 joint project discussing deep underground defense facilities we mentioned above.
GP would state this underground facility at an undisclosed depth spanned 1300 square miles
which is the size of Dugway Proving Ground itself.
The tunnels connecting Dugway to other underground installations were wide enough to transport
enormous aircraft such as a 747.
These rail systems operated off of magnetics, popularly referred to as maglev trains.
It's 1300 square miles underneath and then there's a light rail system is what he said.
He goes that light rail system is connected to every base in the nation and can transport
the president's plane basically anywhere they need to without putting it in the air.
Maglev trains are a type of rail system levitated by electromagnetics rather than employing wheels.
Maglevs feature numerous benefits to conventional railroad systems including higher speeds,
superior acceleration and deceleration, lower maintenance costs, improved gradient handling
and lower noise.
But are much more expensive compared to traditional systems.
Maglevs have even reached top speeds of 375 miles per hour.
Now the implementation of maglev train systems connecting dumps is often seen as conspiracy however.
This is an incorrect assumption.
In 1986, FFRDC Los Alamos National Labs published a study titled,
The intriguing study discussed the creation of subsurface lunar tunnels connecting manned
installations that would feature maglev or other high-speed train transportation systems.
And while discussing specifics of the dump, I must once again state I am not releasing
any classified information.
Everything discussed from here on out is all public domain.
The entrance to the subterranean facility is accessible from a tiny building in the
middle of the West Desert Test Center near German Village Dugway.
According to GP, the entrance is solely an elevator to take personnel to the installation.
This entrance does not supply the Dugway dump with materials, food, supplies, logistics,
etc.
Instead, the dump is internally supplied from tunnels connecting the base to other subterranean
facilities.
When I last discussed MS and UFO witnesses' redacted list, I did not cover the supposed
entrance to the Dugway subterranean facility.
Since covering MS's story, Stephen Greer has taken it upon himself to leak this supposed
entrance himself.
See on screen now the critical update displaying the Dugway dump entrance on the DPI archive.
As mentioned above, this remote entrance is indeed on Dugway's West Desert Test Center
and is quite close to the Avery Technical Center and Michael Army Airfield, while lying
between properties considered as Air Force lease rentals on Dugway Proving Ground.
Analyzing Google Earth historical imagery, it appears this entrance was constructed sometime
between 1993 and 2006.
It could however be much older, as satellite resolution does not allow us to see clearly
at these older dates.
According to GP, much of the Dugway dump operations reside under nearby Granite Peak, which sits
just west of the alleged entrance in Avery and Ditto areas.
What is quite interesting to me is the fact the 388th Range Squadron out of Hill and Michael
Army Airfield runs multiple sites on and just north of the mountain.
I'd like to focus specifically on the mini-mute stations 10 and 2.
Mini-mutes are threat emitter systems commonly utilized to train pilots to recognize and
respond to various enemy radar threats.
One must wonder if the Granite Peak South Station has entrances to or interactions with
a supposed facility under the mountain.
MS's disclosures are truly astonishing, and I must preface I am speculating here, but
from MS's testimony, a strong thesis can be extracted.
MS stumbled upon a Joint Army and USAAF MRTFB UFO legacy operation operating between Atec
and the 388th Range Squadron with the aid of white coat contractors such as Battelle
Memorial Institute and Jacobs Solutions, more on them later.
This program operates above and beneath Dugway Proving Ground.
The clandestine program utilizes the Avery Technical Center's internal rail system to
transport non-human craft and materials onto unmarked secretive Avery buildings such as
the test operations and classified storage buildings.
Program scientists and the 388th Range Squadron utilize the southern part of the Utah Test
and Training Range to test extraterrestrial vehicles or alien reproduction vehicles.
This would operate similarly to what Witness Ed described with the Joint UFO Reverse Engineering
Program between the Edwards 412th Test Wing and Nevada Test and Training Range.
The program also utilizes top chemistry and biology subject matter experts from Atec
and DPG's Chemical and Biological Defense Program to either study biologics or engage
with any relevant aspects of non-human craft.
The Dugway DUM communicates and operates alongside other DUM locations across the continental
United States, likely hidden within and below major military installations and MRTFBs.
A truly incredible thesis, but one that can be reasonably constructed based upon the
testimony of MS and study of Dugway Proving Ground.
Lastly, I just want to briefly touch on some contractor operations at Dugway.
Remember, MS claimed over half of Dugway's operations related to contracting work.
In fiscal year 2013, according to the GAO, Dugway's West Desert Test Range saw about
77% of acknowledged work conducted for the CBDP, Chemical Biological Defense Program
Enterprise.
Now, what contractor might come to mind that deals in-depth with chemical and biological
concepts?
That's right, Battelle Memorial Institute.
I have covered Battelle at length before, including their project STORK, which was tasked
by USG to study UAP, parallel but independent to Project Blue Book.
I have also investigated Battelle and their curious links to nickel-titanium alloys which
may just have been the shape memory alloy recovered from the 1947 Roswell, New Mexico
crash.
I highly recommend viewing that project.
Battelle runs a host of biochem facilities, including the Battelle National Biodefense
Institute at Fort Detrick, Maryland.
This location has recently become entwined with UFO lore as a possible location where
non-human biologics are stored.
There is additionally now the alleged infamous exobiospheric organism molecular biologist
Reddit whistleblower testimony focused on this Battelle location.
But these claims are absent from this investigation as they require much more research.
To add further intrigue, at Fort Detrick, Battelle manages the National Biodefense Analysis
and Countermeasures Center FFRDC for the Department of Homeland Security, specifically
the DHS Undersecretary for Science and Technology.
I would once again like to draw attention to a primary thesis of this channel that FFRDC
and UARC often act as project managers, serving as subject matter experts performing R&D work
in joint USG and contractor UAP legacy programs.
And remember how we previously discussed the CBDP programs at Dugway?
While analyzing this joint multinational and interagency CBDP test and evaluation partners
chart we can see Dugway and Battelle are both listed as select few program locations.
In fact, the West Desert Test Center and Fort Detrick's National Interagency Biodefense
Campus at which Battelle operates are additionally quite intimate, serving as two of four of
CBDP's primary research and development and test and evaluation facilities.
Now I know that's a lot, but Battelle has historically also worked closely with Dugway,
including operating the Chemical and Biological Defense Information Analysis Center, CBIAC,
that operates at Dugway.
According to excellent UFO researcher Anthony Bregalia, Battelle additionally has a design
slash build division with capabilities for creating laboratories and other specialized
facilities.
In one article, Bregalia referenced multiple open source documents that discussed Battelle's
facility design and construction management work at Dugway.
According to these documents, Battelle has engineered enclosed testing facilities and
sealed structures at DPG that according to one technical report, quote, meet stringent
containment standards providing a degree of protection that has never been achieved before,
end quote.
Battelle's facility design services also include specialized locations such as clean
rooms.
Battelle also referenced back to the testimony of MS and the clean room that held the UFO.
Perhaps a full investigation into Battelle's construction work at DPG is warranted.
DPG and Fort Detrick's connections with each other and Battelle are quite interesting,
but this is where things get downright strange.
The director of Dugway's West Desert Test Center is one Mr. Ryan W. Harris.
Harris is, quote, responsible for the overall planning, directing, and evaluating all aspects
of work for the chemical, biological, and other acquisition test and training programs
executed by the test center, end quote.
Harris received a bachelor's in chemical engineering and served in the army as a chemical
officer.
In the year 2000, Harris would accept a project manager position working with Battelle at
Dugway.
This Battelle work saw Harris overseeing several testing and training programs and in 2004,
Harris would accept a project manager position with Dugway and work his way all the way up
the ranks until 2012, where he achieved the position as WTC test director, where he now
evaluates all aspects of the work for the chemical, biological, and other acquisition
test and training programs executed by the test center.
Interesting how a Battelle project manager becomes director of an MRTFB where witnesses
have claimed a UAP legacy program employing DOD chemists takes place.
But we don't stop there.
U.S. Army Chemical Engineering Corps member Greg Frank.
Frank served as a chemist for the Chemical Laboratory Division at Dugway Proving Ground
from 1984 to 1985, quote.
He directed and performed chemical studies and developed procedures for chemical testing
and analysis utilizing modern analytical instrumentation, end quote.
While serving as test officer, Frank would branch out into numerous vehicle and chemical
munition programs, developing material test plans and test operational plans.
When he left service in 1985, Frank joined Battelle as a project manager and principal
investigator where he, quote.
As of 2008, Frank operated as executive vice president for Battelle Science and Technology
and is responsible for over 5,000 scientists, engineers, and supporting staff.
But believe it or not, these are not the only connections we can make with WDTC leadership
and Battelle.
We can also take a keen look at Anders Weyborg, former director of Special Programs Division
at the West Desert Test Center.
Now working for the DOE, Weyborg once served at Dugway, ensuring execution of daily operations
within the test center.
Before working at Dugway, Weyborg worked at Battelle, serving as a test director responsible
for T&E of chemical and biological defense equipment.
Battelle and Dugway share intimate connections, likely Mirian more than we have just scratched
today.
Other contractors at Dugway are of extreme interest as well and will likely serve as
suspects of future investigations, such as Jacob Solutions who performs range testing
and lab services at WDTC.
This contractor operates a premium facility at Dugway Ditto and sees strong ties to its
board of directors and the Carlyle Group.
However, due to the intense focus of Dugway on biochem weapons programs, Battelle will
remain our primary suspect in UAP legacy programs at Dugway Proving Ground.
Hey guys, it's Gerb and I'd like to thank you all so much for joining me today as we
took this extended look into Dugway Proving Ground.
Why did we partake in this investigation?
Well, for one, something I've noticed and I'm sure many others have, is discussion
of Dugway around UFOs and legacy programs are quite intertwined.
However, there is barely any other discussion or research or claims or testimony involving
Dugway.
I think the perfect example of this is the beginning Quest TV video featuring Nick Pope
talking about Area 51 to Area 52.
This entire 10-15 minute video on YouTube, of course the link will be in the description,
discusses Area 51 and Dugway and talks about it being the new Area 51.
This video even features words from Richard Dolan, however, zero evidence or testimony
or anything is presented here.
So after having the testimony of MS, after having some of the words of Stephen Greer,
AJ Craddock and others, I thought it very pertinent to actually dive into Dugway.
Now I have reason to believe that Dugway is indeed a premier legacy reverse engineering
material exploitation program.
So I wanted to sift through all of this information and present an argument, especially as we
started to look into Dugway structure and how Dugway is comprised of two major range
test facility bases, a huge piece of this investigation.
As we know with the testimony of Ed, his claims of a reverse engineering program covered
two Air Force MRTFBs, the Edwards 412 test wing and the Nevada test and training range.
Dugway gives us an interesting look because due to the testimony of MS, we can conclude
of a joint reverse engineering program versus two branches of the military MRTFBs, the Army's
West Desert Test Center and the Air Force's Utah test and training range.
This of course, that involves Army ATEC and their Joint Chemical Biological Defense Program
and the 388th range squadron out of nearby Hill Air Force Base.
I tried to do many connections between the 388th rands range squadron as it's listed
and the Edwards 412 test wing.
Unfortunately there is very little to chew on there.
I do think the argument presented here is strong enough and there's enough valuable
data and listed data here for any policymaker or any individual with influence to conduct
a comprehensive analysis of MS and others claims.
Now, of course, twice in this video around the stiff sub training facility location,
I list the disclaimer that I was using only publicly available information.
Now, I do this because all the way back when discussing NSWC Crane in the testimony of
RA or we now know Randy Anderson, I caught a little bit of flack and a little bit of
fright for mentioning Crane and the possibility that this could be a catastrophic disclosure
and could be a breach of national security due to this being an underground location.
Therefore, when discussing the dumb locations, I needed to preface by saying this information
was all public domain and I thank you Stephen Greer for leaking that on the DPI archive
because that finally gave me a chance to talk about these locations.
Seen as the last time I covered MS, I was privy to these locations but did not think
it appropriate to list them but Greer took it upon himself to list Granite Peak in the
alleged dumb location by German Village himself so thank you for that and I must state once
again as I did in the last project, do not under any circumstances go looking for that location.
Dugway Proving Ground is protected land and protected airspace. These are military assets.
Do not go to the location, okay? If that is a location to a deep underground military base,
which I highly wager it is, do not go there, okay? I'll just make that very clear. Just
do not for your own safety, please. Don't. So there's other data to discuss surrounding
Dugway. As we saw with the Dugway history, there's not much linking Dugway to UAP legacy programs
unlike something like Edwards or Norton or even China Lake or White Sands Missile Range.
One of the biggest features of this project was of course the Garrison crash and then some of
the claims of Area 51 being moved to Area 52. Conversely for a place like Edwards we have the
story of Kent Sellen and the ARV and you know numerous craft and operations being cited at
Dugway. There is more in this video I wasn't able to include. One such story is the testimony of
Air Force Colonel Weinbrenner. Now Weinbrenner has a very interesting story as if anybody can
remember back to the Jesse Michaels interview with James Fox, filmmaker James Fox, Fox discusses a
film of the Holloman Air Force Base landing and how his friend Alan Sandler viewed this film
and told Fox about it. Well back in the 70s Alan Sandler and his co-video producer Robert Emanager
were attempting to make a documentary on UAP. This is when they were sequestered by two enlisted
Air Force personnel and shown the Holloman film and were licensed to utilize the film but that
licensing was pulled soon thereafter. One of these individuals was Colonel Weinbrenner.
Now on Colonel Weinbrenner's deathbed to close friends and families he allegedly said that Utah
is where the alien bodies are stored. Now that's a very interesting disclosure. Where the alien
bodies are stored this would be a very interesting place for this to be Dugway. You know of course
quite often Fort Detrick is talked about. I do believe Lou mentioned this and imminent as well
but as a place for biologics to be stored and this is where much chemical and biological defense
systems are ran and there's extreme ties to Dugway with Fort Detrick. So there's also interesting
data to explore of Dugway being not just a craft exploitation program on the UTTR but also a
biologic study area. Could this be where biologics autopsies take place? Where biological tissue is
studied quite possibly but this would be kept under wraps as any chemical and biological
data and information and study is incredibly secretive and incredibly classified as we've
seen with Dugway. You know Dugway's projects are not spoken of often and 77 percent of Dugway's
programs according to the GAO are conducted for the chemical and biological defense program.
I would like to know what everybody else here thought and while you're leaving your comments
let's also tuck into the testimony of MS. Of course I had talked to MS all the way back in
June of 2024 and those are the clips I have used for the conversation in this video exploration.
I do plan to interview MS again hopefully in person if that can be arranged. Hopefully
that can also be done with GP and the individual who claimed he helped build the railroad system
under Dugway. Such an investigation and interview with these three individuals would truly be
consequential. You know I find a lot of value in MS's testimony not because of him being reached
out to by the Senate select committee on intelligence which he indeed was. I said in the
project that he had received I have seen the outreach from these individuals wishing for him
to go to the hill to testify but also because his testimony at Ditto and Avery leads to such
fruitful research. As we've seen with Avery it has numerous fascinating buildings that could be
used for such operations classified storage test operations photo O&M internal rail system to the
Dugway deep underground facility. Just a very fascinating testimony to cover and I must add
with the Dugway dumb being just some small type of concrete facility out in the desert
just serving as an elevator to a dumb where it's this entrance point doesn't serve to transport
vehicles or armor or logistics or weaponry or food or anything but personnel traveling down
I must be quite plain here in my videos I don't generally like to say well a source told me this
a source told me this a source told me this but I do have a friend that has formerly served in
the United States Army. This was in the early 2010s that has talked to me about traveling in
Stiff's subterranean facilities. I cannot reveal these locations but he said he traveled across
state lines between Stiff's in an underground rail system that went so fast it reminded him
of flying in a plane of which he has great fear. So the fear of a plane's acceleration is what he
felt in the train. What was interesting to me is the location to which he traveled the entrance way
to that location was a small what you could call janitorial building or kind of potable water
treatment building in the middle of nowhere just a small building nestled in a location that
accessing these buildings took you to an elevator to a deep underground facility. This is not the
only individual I've talked to who has accessed a stiff or a dumb maybe we'll call them stiffs
because it carries a little more weight. I've talked to numerous people who have this is why
this topic carries such great interest to me especially because dumbs or stiffs are indeed
real. As I said oftentimes for corporate facilities such as AT&T who at least in the 90s and 2000s
housed many underground server banks and ICBM storage locations underground and possibly
underwater under ocean surface as well as continuity of government COG installation. COG continuity of
government reminds me a lot of when Colonel John B. Alexander who isn't the most trustworthy in my
opinion talked about Majestic 12 being real and serving as a continuity of government type
institution. This also reminds me of what also reminds me of continuity of government
is the description of the dugway done by GP which can talk about transporting the president's plane
to anywhere in the country. So I hope everybody enjoyed this dive into Dugway. I'd like to know
what everybody thinks this was a very important project to me because you know just as in every
single video I discuss SDI the strategic defense initiative FFRDCs or UARCs I can now incorporate
such testimony of major range test facility bases and T&E test and evaluation research and
development test and evaluation RDT&E into my projects. Remember guys when he left service
witness Ed served on the Pentagon for Air Force RDT&E and this is where he claims that
34 and 40 billion dollars went missing to non-authorized transfer of authority funds
in fiscal year I think 2013 and 2014 so Doge if you're watching go look at Air Force and possibly
Army RDT&E. Anyways what else can we discuss guys more interesting projects coming down the way
as I say in every project I do in fact have a Patreon if you want to support the channel
I don't gatekeep any content only support what you think the channel is worth and please remember
to like and subscribe guys these investigations are my heart and soul they do take a long time
so any comments about your thoughts on the investigation is much appreciated. If you've
noticed some oddness with the old eye here I'm dealing with some problems because that is what
happens when you grapple with individuals who do not wash their training equipment enough
do not wash the rash guard so thank you to that person who decided to wrestle with a very
disgusting rash guard I really appreciate that but I'm also quite elated guys because anybody
who watches the channel and has interacted with me knows I am an Alexander Volkanovsky superfan
and our glorious king has just been booked to fight Diego Lopez blockhead Diego Lopez at UFC 314
in Miami come April so I am elated about that that the dangerous power puncher Toporio is moving
up to lightweight and vacating the belt this is sweet Christmas to me so let me know what you guys
think about the investigation guys please remember to like and subscribe and I will see everybody on
the next show thank you