Your Army's research and development program is a continuing effort to help ensure the
survival of this nation.
Army industry teamwork is essential to the accomplishment of the Army research and development
mission.
To maintain superiority in our military arsenal, new ideas are essential.
New weapons must be developed and perfected to meet new requirements.
In these days of explosive advances in science and technology, Army research and development
plays a major role in maintaining America's military supremacy.
You are saying to the human race, for the first time, an official intelligence representative
at a high level from the US government is saying publicly, we are not alone.
We're definitely not alone.
Absolutely the data points empirically that we're not alone, yeah.
You've said that we have, the United States has spacecraft, intact craft.
We do.
Do we have bodies?
Do we have species?
Well naturally, when you recover something that's either landed or crashed, sometimes
you encounter dead pilots.
Well the book is really my experience as I lived them in research and development of
the Army under General Trudeau, Arthur Trudeau, and he drew me back in and put me in charge
of that and established the foreign technology division for me.
And these were the artifacts on the crash flying saucer, which we used the word applied
engineering.
Dr. Tello is still alive and knows he helped him.
And we fed these things.
He gave me the job of finding industry or scientists that were close to these items
and feed us to two of them in normal R&D projects.
And you're saying these items came from somewhere else?
They came from a flying saucer.
How do you know that?
Because they were marked in the files as coming from New Mexico.
Roswell.
Yeah, Roswell.
Well, I think some came, there might be another crash, but these were came from New Mexico
and Roswell especially.
And General Trudeau gave me the job of working out a program, put these things out, feed
them to industry, but there was provisions for you.
They could have the patents, but they had to feed them out back to us as a competitive
and to the American people and the world as necessary.
Before the 2023 congressional hearings on UAP, before the Schumer legislation and before
Grush, the 20th century saw a decorated Lieutenant Colonel of the U.S. Army speak and sign affidavits
on the existence of non-human intelligence, crashed UAP, and exploitation of technologies
of unknown origin.
The legendary Philip J. Corso and his infamous book, The Day After Roswell, and lesser known
but far more impactful manuscript, Dawn of a New Age, have cemented Corso as one of the
most controversial yet credible UFO whistleblowers of all time.
Lieutenant Colonel Corso's central claims revolve around his time in the U.S. Army serving
as the chief of the Foreign Technology Division, where he claims he not only came in contact
with autopsy reports of extraterrestrial beings, but also craft and artifacts from UAP crashes,
and discussed how under his command, technologies found in UAP were seeded into U.S. industry
to give the Army a competitive edge.
But are Corso's grand and epic claims indeed true?
And what can we learn from these claims?
What valuable research can be extracted from the names, locations, agencies, incidents,
and technologies mentioned by the late Corso?
Hey guys, it's UAPGurb and I am thrilled for you to join me as we fully analyze and deconstruct
the testimony of Philip J. Corso and his claims of UAP crash retrieval, NHI biologics, and
reverse engineering of exotic technologies.
Let's conduct a comprehensive deep dive into Corso ranging from carefully analyzing statements
made in his manuscript to digging through his military record and grand claims.
And some quick bookkeeping before we get started today.
We are taking the global bestseller The Day After Roswell, co-written by Corso, and throwing
it out the window.
We will instead be focusing solely on Dawn of a New Age, the original notes and manuscript
of Corso released in Italy in 2003 and the U.S. in 2011, after Corso's death in 1998
at the age of 83.
We will do this so we can directly study Corso's pure claims without the creative liberties
taken in The Day After Roswell, possibly inserted by the other co-writer Bill Burns.
According to Corso's son Philip Jr., he originally had no plans to release his father's manuscript,
but did due to his father's distaste for the bestseller.
As relayed by Jr., Corso went through The Day After Roswell and highlighted everything
he did not say or did not like.
He got solely halfway through before giving up due to frustration with the book.
Several individuals were privy to the manuscript before Corso's death, such as Colonel John
B. Alexander, who remarked on sensational details featured in the book missing in the
manuscript.
Due to the existence of the manuscript and Corso's son's firm remarks of releasing
the piece to correct the mistakes in the book that made his father furious during his lifetime,
we must give Corso the benefit of the doubt and study solely his unfiltered words.
For example, The Day After Roswell is 130 pages longer than Dawn of a New Age, whilst
the two cover roughly the same concepts.
Day After Roswell adds in details like recounting the time when Corso intimidated the CIA director
of covert operations into self-deleting.
The manuscript features no such tale.
Another example is the book originally shipped with a forward written by U.S. Senator Strom
Thurmond, who angrily recounted his statements once learning the book centered on UAP, leading
to an early copy reprint.
While the manuscript makes mention of Corso's relationship to Thurmond, no such advocation
by the Senator was ever mentioned.
A final example I'll discuss is the missing first chapter from the book, The Roswell Desert,
which describes the Roswell, New Mexico, UFO crash in painstaking detail and passes it
off as an accurate description even though Corso was not present at this event.
So feel free to visit the video description and download both the book and the manuscript
and follow along as we dive into the claims of Corso.
Philip Corso has as ironclad a background in the U.S. armed forces and military intelligence
as does David Grush.
Few other witnesses, even with proven accolades in the U.S. military such as Roswell witness
Walter Haught of the 509th Bomb Group, come close to matching Corso's rank, stations,
and history.
Lieutenant Colonel Corso served in the U.S. Army from February 23, 1942 to March 1, 1963.
The young man initially served in military intelligence during Europe in World War II
before becoming chief of the U.S. Counterintelligence Corps, CIC, in Rome.
At the end of the Second World War, Corso arranged safe passage for numerous Jewish
refugees out of Rome and served as personal emissary to Giovanni Battista Montini, who
would become Pope Paul VI.
Corso also served diligently in the early 1950s throughout the Korean War, performing
intelligence directly under General Douglas MacArthur as chief of the Special Projects
Branch of the Intelligence Division Far East Command.
His work here would focus mainly on prisoners of war, POWs, and missing in action MIA soldiers
during the war, tasked with investigating North Korean POW camps and investigating the
number of U.S. and UN POWs held at each camp.
Corso would even testify in 1992 before the Senate Select Committee on POW-MIA Affairs
on hundreds of American soldiers being abandoned at these camps.
Corso served on the staff of President Eisenhower's National Security Council for four years
from 1953 to 1957.
Skeptics and detractors of Corso claimed he was never a member of this NSC under Eisenhower.
However, the 1992 Senate Select Committee hearing report would say otherwise, where
the retired Lieutenant Colonel was clearly listed as NSC staff under the Eisenhower
administration.
We can also analyze Corso's own FOIA military documents, which show him as a member of the
Operations Coordinating Board, a U.S. secret covert operations committee established in
1952 by Eisenhower under Executive Order 10483, which reported directly to the National
Security Council.
In 1960, Corso joined and shortly became commander of the Army's Pentagon-based research and
development program, the illustrious Foreign Technology Division, under Lieutenant General
Arthur Trudeau.
This Foreign Technology Division is not the Air Force's infamous Foreign Technology
Division born out of the Air Force Technical Intelligence Center at Wright-Patterson Air
Force Base.
This program stems from the Office of the Chief of Army R&D and has almost zero trace
or record outside of Corso's own military documents, and we'll discuss this much further
later on.
I do briefly want to mention some interesting context to lend to the credibility of Corso
as we dive into his claims.
Viewers of my channel will know of my recent interview with Dr. Eric Davis of the Wilson
Davis Memo, where Davis intimately discussed President and former CIA Director George
H.W.
Bush's involvement with UAP legacy programs.
Well, let's reference Jacques Vallee's book, Forbidden Science Pacific Heights, which speaks
on Eric Davis and former President Bush Sr.'s professional relationship.
After a candid call initiated by Bush giving Davis advice on his future career, the two
spoke again and saw Davis ask Bush about his interest in Corso's disclosures.
Quote, could it be that Corso was mistaken in dealing with the material he was handling?
Could that have been Nazi hardware?
End quote.
Talkingly, to the statement on Corso, Bush replied, quote, impossible.
The two topics were clearly separated.
By that time, all German secrets had been processed and filed away.
They were not used as cover for anything else.
End quote.
Bush expanded on the 1954 alleged landing of non-human intelligence at Holloman Air
Force Base, where allegedly Eisenhower and NHI brokered a deal.
According to Bush, this event really did happen, resulting in a secret project with obscene
When the two spoke again, Bush told Davis he was briefed on legacy programs by Trudeau
at the time of the 1968 Mandel Rivers Congressional hearings.
The book says Colonel Trudeau, however, I do think this is a typo referencing General
Arthur Trudeau.
Bush Sr. claimed Trudeau told him his man Corso had been asked to testify before Congress
and was able to reveal rumblings of alien hardware that had been distributed to industrial
labs.
The Corso testimony was squashed as a result of this conversation.
And lastly, why did Corso wait until the 1990s to disclose his experiences with UAP technology?
Well, this is because he made a promise to Trudeau he would wait to speak until his death.
And General said, when I die, I feel you're released from your oath.
He died three years ago and I started to write it.
Number two is I couldn't talk about people who were with us that I had no right to talk
about.
In intelligence, like a newspaper man, you don't, your source is not named unless he
gives you permission to name him.
I had no right to do that.
And so my own family, Corso, my son says 35 years, you didn't talk, you didn't even
tell us.
So that's right.
Why did I tell anybody?
I had an oath with an honorable man, a great man.
And I wasn't about to betray that oath.
And not only that, I had never any intention of writing a book or putting it on paper.
That never entered my mind on nights in the military.
I never thought I'd write a book or even do a movie on it.
That never entered my head.
Shortly before his death in July of 1998, CAUS, Citizens Against UFO Secrecy, published
an affidavit released by Colonel Corso.
This affidavit was signed for attorney Peter A. Gersten of CAUS in order to file a lawsuit
against the Department of Army.
This affidavit reads,
And while stationed at Fort Riley, Kansas, I personally observed a four-foot non-human
creature with bizarre-looking four-fingered hands, thin legs and feet, and an oversized
incandescent lightbulb-shaped head.
The eye sockets were oversized and almond-shaped and pointed down to its tiny nose.
The creature's skull was overgrown to the point where all its facial features were arranged
frontally, occupying only a small circle on the lower part of the head.
There were no eyebrows or any indications of facial hair.
The creature had only a tiny flat slit for a mouth and it was completely closed, resembling
more of a crease or indentation between the nose and bottom of the chinless skull than
a fully functioning orifice.
That in 1961, I came into possession of what I refer to as the Roswell File.
This file contained field reports, medical autopsy reports, and technical debris from
the crash of an extraterrestrial vehicle in Roswell, New Mexico in 1947.
That I have personally read the medical autopsy reports, which refer to the autopsy of the
previously described creature that I saw in 1947 at Fort Riley, Kansas.
That the autopsy reports indicated the autopsy was performed at Walter Reed Hospital, which
was under the authority of the defendant at the time of the autopsy.
That the autopsy report referred to the creature as an extraterrestrial biological entity.
Right off the bat here, it sounds extreme Corso claimed to have observed a mangled body
he would later learn was a deceased being from the 1947 Roswell, New Mexico crash.
If you are not well versed with the July 1947 Roswell UAP crash retrieval, I do recommend
doing some homework before continuing with this project.
I'd recommend the Roswell cover up 75 years later, as well as my project UFO Whistleblowers
Volume 1 to hear from some credible whistleblowers on the incident.
For this video, we will be utilizing an array of interesting depictions of the crashed Roswell
saucer.
Based on reports and eyewitness testimony, Corso solely labeled the craft as the Roswell
crashed saucer in Dawn of a New Age.
We will explore all of these craft design in a future project solely focused on Roswell.
One night, I was a post duty officer.
Post duty officer means that I was in control.
For that night, I was the one that checked all the guards, checked all security areas,
fact checked the whole post.
I was the duty officer that night.
And I went to the veterinarian section and the one, a sergeant I knew very well, was
sergeant of the guard that night.
I told him, Sarge, how's everything around here?
And he said, fine sir.
I told him, you know, they told me to be careful to watch this area because you have a sense
of something sensitive here.
He said, you want to see it, sir?
I told him, yes, let's go look.
And I knew this sergeant very well, he was a master sergeant.
I went back and there was five crates there, like five or six, I think it was five.
I listed one up and here's this body there and floating and fluid.
And I looked at it, about 10, 15 seconds, not much more than that.
So I put it back down and I said, Sarge, come on, get out of here now.
I want to get you in trouble because I'm the duty officer.
I can go around, walk around here, but you might get in trouble for coming back.
Just come on, let's go, come out with me.
So we went out and I told him, where did it come from, Sarge?
He said, well, five trucks came through, coming through here from an airfield in New Mexico
and they're heading for Wright-Pattison Air Force.
Now, in those days, they wanted all these big roads now, in those days, Route 40 was
about the only cross-country route.
And the route that they took was Route 40, going through Fort Riley, Kansas and then
up to Wright-Pattison Air Force.
And I said, well, stay away from her, Sarge, I don't want you to get in any trouble.
I told him, I can walk around and see them.
So then I started to figure, what was that?
First I thought it was a child, because it was small.
Then I looked at this head and all, and this was only happened a matter of seconds.
Then I put the head back down and the head was different, the arms were spindly, the
body was gray.
So right at that moment, I figured, I don't know what this thing is.
Corso's official records do indeed place him at Fort Riley at this date, and he would
claim he was told the convoy of trucks hauling the bodies were headed for Wright-Patt and
came from Route 40.
This is very interesting, as quite often Roswell reports state wreckage was flown to Wright-Patterson
Air Force Base, were deceased by logics transported separately, and if so, why?
Myriad UFO crash retrieval stories feature flatbed Air Force and Army trucks hauling
wreckage away, such as the 1953 Kingman and 1965 Kecksburg crash retrievals.
Also an interesting line I'm sure many picked up, the body was referred to as an EBE, Extraterrestrial
Biological Entity, the same phrase used in the Majestic 12 Special Operations Manual.
This manual describes two sets of EBE, EBE-1 and EBE-2, EBE-1 closely matches the description
of Corso's observed body.
This affidavit provides little more information than Corso gaining first-hand knowledge of
the Roswell crash, but fortunately we have his entire manuscript to study.
Just to revisit, the bulk of Corso's testimony revolves around the U.S. Army's Foreign Technology
Division serving to exploit technology of unknown origin, TUO, from crashed UAP and
seeded into U.S. industry to primarily bolster the U.S. Army war machine and, as a second
directive, benefit the U.S. economy.
Through this program, we started feeding it out to industry, but this was not known,
not on paper.
They went out as normal research and development proposals, not to name something.
Yeah, you didn't put out a report that said there's some alien stuff figured out.
We put out a regular research and development proposal that came from somebody's brain,
and also this was known among a select few, mostly combat officers head-to-head.
We kept this among ourselves, because otherwise we were certain that they would have destroyed
our organization, and we had a good organization, General Trudeau pulled it together just a
couple years before.
They were a destroyed organization labeled us as kooks and taking our budget away.
So it had to be.
We didn't cover because we gave it to industry with the provisions, and I'll repeat this,
the provisions were to come back to us with what you approved, a competitive edge of the
economy, give it to the people and to the world if necessary, and take the patents.
This claim dating to 1962 parallels extremely closely the modern day disclosures that branches
of U.S. military work closely with contractors under unacknowledged, waived, special access
program in order to exploit technologies of unknown origin to primarily benefit the U.S.
military.
Let's monitor this evolution closely as we explore Corso.
It is endlessly fascinating to compare the secrecy and centralization of technology exploitation
programs under the Foreign Technology Division as outlined by Corso, all the way to how these
UAP legacy programs may operate today, stove-piped and protected from Congressional oversight
nestled within various intelligence agencies and military institutions in league with defense
contractors, UARCs and FFRDCs.
Anyways to the memo, after a brief forward and acknowledgement with the awesome statement
If one passage in these memoirs helps you survive in a troubled world, then all this
work is not in vain.
Corso begins an introduction for the reader.
Philip begins by giving the reader valuable insight into the creation of army research
and development projects exploiting technologies of unknown origin.
And guys moving forward, research and development will now be shortened to R&D and technologies
of unknown origin will be shortened to TUOs.
This sort of inception of a legacy UAP program gives us a framework to understand the construction
and evolution of such programs.
Corso also quotes the father of German rocketry, flying saucer researcher and mentor of Werner
von Braun, Hermann Oberth, who once stated quote,
We cannot take the credit for our record advancements in certain scientific fields alone.
We have been helped by people of other worlds, end quote.
1947 to 1958 saw the disorganized dark ages of army research and development.
NASA was founded in 1958, killing the army and DoD project Horizon, which served to build
a moon base.
Atomic energy was stripped from the army and handed over to the Atomic Energy Commission.
ARPA, the Advanced Project Research Agency, was also founded, clashing often with Army
R&D.
It wasn't until 1958, all army R&D was pooled under one single department, the Office of
the Chief of Army R&D.
This was Lieutenant General Arthur Trudeau, who handled all personnel, tech services,
laboratory and installations as well as budget.
Trudeau would then create the Foreign Technology Division and designate young Corso as its
chief.
Corso would take quote, all reports on foreign technology which included foreign beings and
events, those not of this world, end quote.
We will discuss this station and division in much greater detail later in the project,
but for now we are focusing solely on the manuscript's introduction.
This led, according to Corso, to the golden age of army R&D from 58 to 63.
However, in this time, the army still faced many challenges impeding their work, civilian
control of space efforts, DoD opposers, adverse policy guidance and the animosity of CIA Department
of State.
This would all lead to the hyper secrecy of all R&D data pertaining to areas out of this
world.
All of these materials were compartmentalized and trusted amongst a select few, quote.
Great efforts were made to bring large industry and select laboratories into the army R&D
fold, end quote.
Corso also states quote, the partners we sought and gathered were US industry, a strong laboratory
support and many leading universities, end quote.
I do believe this small line is one of the most crucial aspects of Corso's testimony
believe it or not.
Quite often on this channel, we talk not only about contractors involved in UAP legacy
programs but also university affiliated research centers, as well as federally funded research
and development centers, semi-private institutions.
One such organization created during this golden age of army R&D is an FFRDC I believe
is up to their eyeballs in UAP legacy programs, MITRE.
Officially established in 1958, MITRE was created by MIT Lincoln Labs employees creating
SAGE, the Semi-Automatic Ground Environment Program to coordinate radars to produce imageries
of airspace for the military.
A thesis I'd like to keep in mind during this exploration was the MITRE FFRDC created
in part to fulfill the need of army UFO R&D to see technology into US industry.
Of course the foreign technology division was created a year later in 1960, however
Corso does state before his station at the new office, material exploitation efforts
by the army had been ongoing since Roswell.
At an undisclosed date but presumably around the time or just before the creation of the
foreign technology division in 1960, Corso states the top 25 industries on the Fortune
500 list were contacted and meetings were arranged with their board of directors, top
personnel, with the chiefs of army R&D.
Laboratories were strengthened and organized, gathering funds to attract the best and brightest
including foreign scientists such as those brought from Operation Paperclip.
With contractors such as Bell Labs, who is credited with the development of the transistor
Two technologies Corso said were leveraged from UAP alongside universities and army laboratories.
This conglomeration, a powerful team, was tasked with exploiting TUOs.
The guiding principle of this army project had but two goals, national security of the
United States and protection of the American way of life.
In a rare Art Bell coast-to-coast interview with Corso and Colonel John B. Alexander,
Corso would state the foreign technology division began to operate with a budget of $2 billion.
The first item that would be built from a research contract, we funded the building
to the first one.
Then after that other people and other agencies funded it.
So we would fund these until it was actually developed.
We had our own laboratories, our comic labs, and the Nigerian labs where our labs at Fort
Belvoir.
Colonel, what aspect of this were you overseeing?
In other words, once you gave somebody a piece of this technology and a budget, what did
you then do?
Well, I was supposed to keep track of it while I was coming along.
This R, D, T and E funding would equal over $10.5 billion today, quite the starting budget.
The mention of R&D, test and evaluation contracts reminds me closely of witness Ed, who made
claims of a joint UAP reverse engineering group operating between Nellis slash Area
51 and Edwards Air Force bases.
After his service in the Edwards 412th group, Ed would work for USAAF at the Pentagon, serving
on acquisition integration and R, D, T and E panel.
It was here, Ed would claim $34 and $40 billion were siphoned off in respective years to non-Air
Force TOA transfer of authority funds.
Here in the introduction, Corso breaks down some of the breakthroughs leveraged from the
Foreign Technology Division and Golden Age of R&D from studying reports and wreckage
from Roswell and possibly other UAP recoveries.
Let's go ahead and break these down.
The first technology are image intensifiers, aka passive night vision devices.
Corso stated the night vision laboratory at Fort Belvoir, Virginia created these first
generation devices with aid from 48 US industries.
All with varying knowledge of the project.
Allegedly, information gathered from the 1947 Roswell crash led to this breakthrough.
Passive systems were indeed constructed by the US Army in the early 1960s.
However, many individuals such as Colonel John B. Alexander challenge this statement.
One of the most contentious technologies discussed by Corso is fiber optics.
This point of Corso's testimony has been highly contentious, like much of the materials.
Allegedly at Roswell, the recovery team discovered what they thought to be a broken wiring harness
with each loose strand end emitting a different color.
These wires were fiber optics.
Bell Labs allegedly utilized this technology to spearhead the greatest advancements in
communication history.
Now this point is contentious because French scientists were indeed working on early developments
of fiber optic principles in the early 1840s.
Bell Labs was involved in the development of fiber optics in the 1970s, where they improved
the technology and minimized loss on mass scale production.
Now let's keep in mind, Corso does say some of the non-human technologies leveraged were
used to bolster human technology, so perhaps this drastic Bell Labs improvement is one
of these instances.
And speaking of Bell Labs, let's remember back to the testimony of Edgar Fouchet, who
who stated that FFRDC's Livermore Labs and Sandia National Labs reverse engineered the
propulsion system for the TR3B alien reproduction vehicle.
According to the Majestic 12 documents and the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit reports,
Sandia has also served as a prime site for UAP crash retrieval and reverse engineering
operations.
In fact, I have spoken so much about Sandia, I highly recommend committing them and FFRDC's
in general to memory.
The telephone company AT&T was given managerial responsibilities of Sandia National Labs by
President Harry Truman in 1949.
As of 1925, Bell Labs and their engineering R&D department was placed under shared ownership
of Western Electric and AT&T, very interesting connections here.
Another alleged leveraged technology were super tenacity fibers from one single strand
of fiber that could not be damaged.
The Army at that time, according to Corso, had a tremendous need for fibers for flak
jackets, parachutes, and other military items.
Important to note, Dawn of a New Age states these fibers were utilized to construct composites
for stealth technology in civilian aircraft, while Day After Roswell states these fibers
were used to construct Kevlar, the material in bulletproof vests and made by DuPont in
1965.
Strange molecular alignment techniques were additionally studied from the Roswell crash.
The craft showed molecules down to individual atoms, had been aligned in various patterns
resulting in incredible hardness and resistance to scratches, stress, strain, and shear in
metals while all repelling cosmic particles and radiation.
The chief of R&D of the Army thought this to be a truly consequential discovery and
thus special teams were organized to investigate this chemistry.
Corso stated this atomic rearrangement could lead to incredibly strong yet light spacecraft,
but in 1963, and possibly through 1993, the Army had not solved this issue.
I personally have heard some similar claims that non-human craft employ materials with
interesting, atomic arrangements.
Corso also believed fluid amplification was leveraged from UFO propulsion and guidance
systems.
Fluidic principles led to the creation of the heart pump.
Even though fluidic principles are quite old, they were not utilized commercially until
about 1960 for the demand for reliable controls in space research.
Two of the greatest technologies exploited by Army R&D according to Corso were the transistor
and integrated circuit.
As we mentioned above, Bell Labs first introduced a point-contact transistor in 1947.
Jack Kirby of Texas Instruments introduced the first hybrid integrated circuit between
1958 and 1959.
Corso's testimony illustrates a strange transistor with hair-like wires and leads
and a chip in a stack of thin, uniformly-shaped wafer-like components found in a crash retrieval.
These formed complete electrical circuits and developed into the micro-module concept.
CRD said it would take 50 years to develop the transistor and 200 years to develop the
chip.
It came in a short span of five years.
Corso does state this development occurred before the golden age of Army R&D, 1958-1963,
with advancements as early as 1947.
As he states, improvements were made to the existing technologies in 1959 with the introduction
of miniaturization of circuits.
In fact, when Corso began his service as special assistant to Trudeau in 1960, Trudeau would
allegedly show in both transistors and integrated circuits and engage in some philosophical
on the implications of harnessing off-world technologies for human use.
Perhaps this does indeed adhere to conventional history, which states physicist Julius Edgar
Lillianfield proposed the concept of a field effect transistor, an FET, in 1926.
But it was not possible to construct a working device at that time.
It was not until 1947 we saw application of transistors.
The lieutenant colonel also stated the laser, who many program members suggested was the
EBE's method of communication over vast distances of space, was derived from the Roswell crash.
As we know, the laser, which stands for Light Amplification by Stimulated Emission of Radiation,
was created in 1960 under Bell Labs.
And again, what was the purpose of all of this R&D?
In Corso's own words, quote,
We never quibbled over who discovered or invented a development.
The feeling was if a discovery was adapted to a concrete development, we would all be
ahead in the game and the nation would benefit, end quote.
This reminds me almost identically of the claims made by David Grush regarding secrecy
of legacy program operations.
So the reason for the secrecy exactly is what?
Feudalistic dominance, who can have both asymmetric technology for, it seems like, just fueling
the war machine.
Grush says that through the 50s and 60s, encounters with the NHI continued, as did the cover-up.
Key to mention here, it is stated in the manuscript Extraterrestrials never gave humans a thing.
Not one scientific experiment has ever shown that.
Not one scientific advantage came voluntarily.
Everything was garnered by accident or perhaps force in some cases.
This raises a very interesting point.
Numerous individuals, such as David Grush, have flirted with the subject of agreements
with humans and non-human intelligence.
If these agreements do not involve technology, what do they involve?
And it's quite clear that you're talking about agreements between America and non-human
intelligences.
Have we made agreements with non-human intelligences?
That's the kind of information I really hope national leadership is able to get to the bottom of.
I need to pin you down on this.
Are there agreements between non-human intelligences and the American government?
I think that's a question that I would like to know all the details of as well.
Or is it possible R&D programs were kept separate from other compartmentalized
programs that inherited technology, a separation of programs I believe is active today?
I think something a lot of people don't ask that has kind of captured my attention.
During your time investigating legacy programs, did you see much collaboration
or compartmentalization between programs that may exist in Navy, Air Force, Army?
It's too snow-piped or compartmentalized.
You can't open it up to another one unless there is a need to do that.
That need to get access is defined on a government form called the DD-254.
And the DD-254 documents who has access and why and what gets accessed.
And if you're going to have to get access to another compartmentalized program,
then that has to be justified in the DD-254.
And usually that's not justified because programs don't really overlap.
However, Corso's claims NHI technology was taken, not inherited, mirrors closely the claims of
flux liner alien reproduction vehicle witness Brad Sorensen, who was told at the 1988 Norton
Air Show the basis for the ARV, the Roswell wreckage, was taken without the consent of
its operators. Another interesting parallel to today is a contractor Corso makes numerous
mentions to, the Sperry Rand Corporation. Not to be confused with the Rand FFRDC,
Sperry Rand was a major 20th century electronics corporation and military contractor.
Sperry Rand was additionally named in General Trudeau's memoirs as a frequent spot for meetings.
He would often meet with their CEO and directors to discuss army R&D projects.
One such director was the legendary General Douglas MacArthur.
Sperry Rand went defunct in 1986 and many of its divisions became part of Honeywell,
Lockheed Martin, Raytheon and Northrop Grumman.
Corso then goes on to mention a long list of other benefits garnered from UFO technology
exploration. One I want to mention is anti-missile missiles for the Star Wars program.
Long have I stated the Star Wars program, formerly known as the Strategic Defense Initiative,
had a secondary function to fund UAP programs and act offensively against UAP. There is indeed
interesting research to suggest although the program was set in place by Reagan in 1983,
Eisenhower established the program for UAP offensive action during his presidency.
The Colonel discussed the need for protection against the EBEs themselves.
The Lieutenant Colonel stated EBEs have performed acts of war with superior
advanced equipment and superior techniques. The threat internally was treated similar
to the Soviets as a fig leaf policy where the Soviets and non-humans threatened
existence but were not considered enemies. These acts included the controversial abduction
phenomena and mutilation as well as quote spying on our atomic installations,
hindering missile and space equipment testing, hampering our military deterrent and nuclear
deterrent, halting and interfering with exploration of moon and mars, causing crashes of aircraft and
casualties among military personnel and tampering with human and animal genome and quote. I would
like to explore some of these more controversial claims in a future project so let's hold on to
this. This passage is key to reflect on as in the revelations of David Grush we have heard people
have been hurt and killed by UAP but cannot attribute malicious intent to these intelligences.
To conclude with the introduction Corso placed much admiration for the individuals behind exotic
R&D. These veterans of World War II in Korea were entrusted with the United States government's
highest level deepest secrets. Now that we have spent over half an hour investigating the
introduction of the manuscript we can start to dive in and explore more of Corso's claims in depth.
Throughout the introduction of this document we heard Corso recount for the reader much of his
early military career but quickly let's recap some of his highlights right before he met General
Trudeau in his own words. Well your career to the to the point that uh you met the general was a very
honorable uh and fairly normal uh military career. It was in conflict just now we were fighting the
war in North Africa in Italy and then I joined the general I went to Korea I participated in the
Korean War and I joined McArthur staff over there and I came back and when I came back to the States
I joined Stephen Eisenhower as one of the military engineers at the city council at the White House
and there my career sort of changed. I was in the White House for four years and from there I took
command of uh of the little Mr. Client the army's Mr. Client range of white fans
then I took the combat Mr. Client and I had the promised warheads even for Germany's
and I became I stayed in command 18 months and then I became Richard General of the Army
and from there I came back to the United States and General Trudeau had reorganized research and
development of the army and he sent for me and I joined him as a special citizen
and he's the point of my division. Corso claimed his military career saw him earn nine clearance
levels above top secret up to the coveted eyes only material for the White House NSC matters.
Achieving these clearances is when the lieutenant colonel would claim he became aware of UFO
information though nothing pertaining to legacy programs or reverse engineering. Since his NSC
position occurred from 1953 to 1957 we can wager any interesting UFO information was presented to
him as intelligence staff O for the operations coordinating board attached to the National
Security Council. Corso claimed his superior and the president's special assistant C.D. Jackson
along with President Eisenhower himself were the only individuals aware of Corso's clearances.
C.D. Jackson here is Charles Douglas Jackson special assistant to Eisenhower and government
psychological warfare advisor. Jackson served as liaison between the freshly minted CIA and the
Pentagon. Jackson was also a member of the committee on international information activities. Corso did
discuss how in officer school he began specializing in air defense and ballistic missiles twice during
his command of missile units unidentified objects were picked up over New Mexico and Germany
traveling at over 3000 miles per hour. Corso was ordered to destroy any records and tapes following
service as commander of the 71st missile battalion in Germany and inspector general of the 7th army
Corso was led to become special assistant to the chief of army R&D lieutenant general Arthur G.
Trudeau quote if Edwin Teller could be called the father of the H bomb general Trudeau could be called
the father of the ballistic missile end quote and now we can get into some of the very juicy details
in 1960 Corso entered into his position as chief of the foreign technology division having seen a
small strange body while also being read into some unknown UFO information due to his clearance
levels and had been told of some exotic technologies leveraged from off-world technologies by his mentor
and boss Arthur Trudeau but I do find it strange Corso does not write about the 1947 non-human
intelligence body encounter in dawn of a new age as we observed in his signed affidavit this is
especially strange because this encounter of biologics was relayed in the book day after
Roswell so I guess let's go back and hear this story recounted in Corso's own words
and I was instructor at the intelligence school and we had an aggressor force we that I was
so one night I was post duty officer post duty officer means that I was in control
for that night I was the one that checked all the guards checked all security areas
fact-checked the whole post I was the duty officer that night
and I went to the veterinarian section and one of a sergeant I knew very well was
sergeant of the guard that night I told him Sarge how's everything around here and he said fine sir
I told him you know they told me to be careful to watch this area because you have a sense of
something sensitive here he said you want to see it sir tell me let's go look and I knew the
sergeant very well master sergeant on back and there was five crates there like five or six I
think it was five I listed one up and here's this body there and floating and fluid and
I looked at it about 10-15 seconds not much more than that so I put it back down I said Sarge come
on get out of here now I want to get you in trouble because I'm the duty officer I could go
walk around here but you might get in trouble for coming back just come on let's go come out with me
so we went out and I told him where did come from Sarge he said there were five trucks coming
through here from an airfield in New Mexico and they're heading for Wright-Pattison Air Force
now in those days young they want all these big roads now in those days route 40 was about the
only cross-country route and the route that they took was route 40 going through Fort Riley Kansas
and then up to Wright-Pattison Air Force and I said well stay away from her Sarge I don't want
you to get in any trouble I told him I can walk around and see them so and I started to figure
what was that first I thought it was a child because it was small then I looked at this head
and all right and this was only happened a matter of seconds then I put the end back down
and the head was different the arms were spindly the body it was gray so right at that moment I
figured I don't know what this thing is so like an intelligence business I just better put it in
back my head here and wait to maybe in the future I get collaboration so I can evaluate what it is
as chief of the foreign technology division the young lieutenant colonel would receive quote
all reports on foreign technology which included foreign beans and events those not of this world
end quote he would spearhead a team of nazi scientists brought over from operation paperclip
as well as us scientists and technicians some of these pieces of technology were known to be from
crashed ufos while others were educated guesses corso did recognize his position arose almost
exclusively from his close relationship with the infamous trudeau in fact trudeau personally gave
corso what is now famously known as the roswell file a box of materials and files pertaining to
the infamous crash caught me in one day said uh what make you achieve important most division
and they're going to have a three drawer file now once you go through this file and look what's
there and you give me a program and tell me what you think they are so I take this file
in my office downstairs from your office the second floor in the pentagon I open it up and
I start finding the material which he called later of course it was junk well and there was a bunch
of wires which I didn't know what they were which were in meeting colors I didn't even know if they
were wires I had this chip disintegrated circuit a laser instrument they could do like some of the
fine cuttings they say the manual medulations and I had also fiber optics something that I had those
and we called them we started that because one of my tonight reports on autopsy
that performed along the reed on our lab which refinanced the water
and when I read that it matched with what I saw for rally 14 years before
the whole topsy was similar what I'd seen so then I start putting two and two together
and gradually these items will start from then the general called me and I said work out a program
find scientists who are working on these things and shove them in there
I thought but general I have to study these things because really I told him not that
right I don't know what they said all of these things are but they're important he said well
Phil they are important give me a program what they are anyways after Corso was designated as
the chief of the foreign technology division by Trudeau in 1960 Corso was given four subjects to
keep track of one foreign development of this world two foreign intelligence and developments
not of this world three act as interim project officer on select r&d projects and four
all other duties assigned as special assistant to the CRD for the US army national security
measures meant points one three and four fell into normal categories but point two was a whole
different matter many experts in the know felt the army was helpless in the face of NHI technology
let's briefly touch on some more technologies and items featured in the Roswell report given to
Corso by Trudeau we have yet to discuss amongst the physical technologies and reports on artifacts
such as a paper thin high strength metal found at the Roswell crash Corso discovered autopsy
reports discussing beings almost identical to what he observed in 1947 accompanying images
show decomposed bodies roughly four feet tall and medical reports detailed heavy variations
to human anatomy and organs as well as skin and bone composition these biologics heart and lungs
were very large with a remarkably different muscular structure the beings appear to have
skin and bone structure built to protect vital organs from cosmic action cosmic radiation or
gravitational pull and it is interesting according to the manuscript a transparent film over the
eyeball of the deceased ebes led to Trudeau mandating the pursuit of passive night vision
technology analyzing every single file he had on the Roswell crash saucer Corso did notice some
odd discrepancies between the beans and their craft the files had no mention of food or
nourishment for the beans in the craft nor mention of water or drinking water or water
for cleansing the body the files made no mention to refrigeration equipment no mention of medical
equipment besides what the recovery crew guessed was a first aid kit and there was no toilet or
waste disposal facilities or no rest and no recreation facilities Corso and the OCRD believed
these beans to be clones or at the very least expendable creatures sent by some sort of
intelligence the chief even believed the Roswell craft to be a reconnaissance craft that would
return to a mothership for necessities the lieutenant colonel also reasoned possibly this
species had solved gravitational time dimensional travel and could instantaneously return to their
base throughout the manuscript Corso would often hint at multiple UAP or crashed flying saucers
analyzed it is frustrating we don't get a total count besides confirmation of the Roswell crash
as well as the 1947 July San Agustin New Mexico crash in which allegedly a flying saucer crashed
with no seams joint lines rivets or weld joints this is a ubiquitous description in almost all
UFO crash retrieval reports so when I start putting all this on the extraterrestrial together
I finally gave it a name I told him it looks like you know these are clones
and so the name came out extra extraterrestrial biological entity that's what we figured they were
better describe it we never used the letters et there was no such thing
you said that they looked like clones how they were clone not look like they were clones
we figured that they were created by some some other intellect and we also came to the decision
that they were made specifically to travel in space because we knew even in those days
that man could not travel in space some bones are affected his muscles are affected his brain is
affected man cannot travel in space so we came to inclusion of these creatures whatever they are
are made to travel in space and gradually through work we did we found out that disintegrated with
the flying saucer and with you because most of the failures make the flying saucers work
or the guidance system that this creature was also the guidance system was part of the engine
of the flying saucer it is also fascinating to see how the team was inspired and attempted to
study harnessing brain waves to control aircraft and anti-missile missiles this inspiration came
from apparent discoveries that these extraterrestrial biological entities were part of the craft's
guidance systems this may seem like science fiction however we do live in an age where
consciousness connection is indeed discussed with ufo craft piloting and we came to a conclusion
even in those days that these are the reason most flying saucers have failed is because our
conclusion was that this being is part of the guidance system he's part of that saucer i've
just had one of the most senior scientists in the u.s defense department's former admit to me that
he was read into a ufo crash retrieval program i've spoken to well over 20 people now what i
was told consistently was the technology is mind-blowing and they are not in a position
to be able to engineer it yet because it's just light years beyond what we have it's it's a
completely new type of physics is what one person said to me and you might be interested in this j
because of the sort of direction that your interests have taken without expanding on it
one of the people i spoke to told me that it had a lot to do with a mind interface connection with
the engineering that it was driven by some kind of consciousness or some kind of
intelligent connection with machinery that was beyond our understanding shockingly we can add
even more context these claims by analyzing the files of the legendary lennard stringfield
and take a look at a report of a possible recovered vehicle or alien reproduction vehicle
that utilized headband transceivers to operate quote lenn spoke to a mr hinds who had a source
from bell labs the informant stated that he was on the flight line at a california air force
base in the early 1950s and saw a ufo retrieval brought in he allegedly saw a cutaway of the
recovered craft plus the headband transceivers worn by the aliens anyone involved with the
retrieval was subject to intense scrutiny and search apparently one man must have kept a part
of the craft and he mysteriously disappeared he was never seen again the source feels that the
man was eliminated end quote chief corso somehow stumbled upon information that the soviets were
running their own parallel tuo exploitation program this may have stemmed from soviet
spies in new mexico tipping off stalin to the roswell crash where stalin allegedly gathered
the ussr's brightest to discuss the captured saucer quote some of the items found and analyzed by the
russians possess a similarity of items gathered in the united states others closely resemble
material collected by the u.s army soon after the crash end quote impactful statement as
recently dr eric davis confirmed the soviets did indeed observe and collect at least one crash
retrieval in their own territory it is unknown how exactly corso came across this intelligence
regarding the soviets but it is no surprise after the words of david grush grush says the united
states is not the only country that's encountered nhi and their technology he says our geopolitical
rivals have their own crash retrieval programs which they are also secretly exploiting for
military purposes we're in a competition with their adversaries to understand this
and it's a it's a multi-decade cold war that has been under our nose for so long and
you know there is no good way to level the playing field and hold other nation states accountable if
they're doing unethical or illicit activity as it relates to this subject however far down the line
in 1993 corso would ask old acquaintances to acquire about recovered materials from a kgb
general while much of the information was still held as top secret by kgb and gru corso was given
a list of materials you can see on screen now let's temper our expectations as this list could
easily have been disinformation given to corso however one piece that stands out to me was a
silvery tube found in the u.s in 1975 i wonder if this possibly relates to the august 1974 chihuahua
mexico crash i covered in which a u.s rapid recovery team relieved a deceased mexican army
squadron of a recovered craft possibly the soviets traced this recovery and found materials missed
by the convoy the foreign technology division was working with lasers anti-missile missiles
and directed energy weapons near the tail end of corso's career lieutenant general trudeau
retired in 1962 and the lieutenant colonel followed him shortly in 1963
now what more can we learn about the foreign technology division and general arthur trudeau
trudeau is a member of the military intelligence hall of fame the general served in world war two
in the korean war trudeau served as chief of army intelligence but was relieved by alan dolez director
of the cia possibly for his extremely rigorous anti-communist stance the general was shortly
reinstated and eventually in 1958 the golden age of army r&d began according to corso trudeau would
then return to washington as director of army research and development the general was so
influential to the army he was one of eight former generals included in the army's 1970s oral history
project funny enough when trudeau was interviewed for this project corso was found to be spending
time with his friend trudeau in his kitchen this speaks to the close relationship of the two and
their friendship during and after their service and outside of corso we have only one interesting
piece to link the general to uap let's remember all the way back to forbidden science where dr
eric davis claimed bush senior stated he was indeed briefed by trudeau at the 1968 mendel rivers
congressional hearings now i'm sure many are familiar with the united states air force's
foreign technology division that operated out of right patterson from 1961 to 1991 to reiterate
the office created by trudeau and chiefed by corso was not this infamous division the air
force program evolved from air technical intelligence center in 1961 and was assigned
under air force systems command the division reportedly operated on recovered russian mig
jets however due to the stove piping of ufo legacy programs it would not be shocking to
think perhaps this program also engaged with technologies of unknown origins parallel to
its army department let's reference us army colonel john b alexander's book ufos myths
conspiracies and realities i know i've had my problems with alexander before and his discussion
of the som 101 majestic 12 special operations manual however this quote is important quote
corso stated that he had been transferred back to the pentagon under trudeau and a division had been
created for him called the foreign technology division this is not to be confused with the
large foreign technology division of the u.s air force at right patterson ohio it was learned that
the army foreign technology division was formed as corso stated and then disappeared shortly after
his retirement end quote this is a fascinating point as after general trudeau four star general
dwight e beach took over command of army rnd and from there on out we find nothing of foreign
technology division why is this army rnd office proven to exist yet zero foya documents newspapers
or online articles exist about the correct program numerous references can be found to
the air force's foreign technology division but not the army's i find this very similar to the
army's interplanetary phenomenon unit which was discovered through foya to exist only throughout
institutional memory in the army i do believe this inability to track down the army's foreign
technology division to be of extreme consequence if corso's testimony is indeed true there is much
value we can extract here regarding uap legacy program operations this would mean the office of
the chief of army rnd created a very real program hidden and shadowed from the public eye by the
publicity of its big air force brother at right patterson throughout the manuscript corso would
even comment passively on this difference stating project moon dust and blue fly reported materials
and intelligence directly to the air force's foreign technology division out of right pat
and we can do some really interesting research by reading a primer on research and development
in the u.s army we can see in 1958 under trudeau the army established the army research office
under the ocrd due to pressure from civilian scientists which served as a single contact
in the army to maximize army rnd efficiency remember corso stated army rnd truly began
to flourish in 1958 when army began doing rnd away from civilian and institutions with prying eyes
one can then reason the foreign technology division may have run parallel to the aro
army research office out of civilian and congressional oversight this reasoning can
be further supported when the document states the army chief of rnd would have a parallel
line of authority to handle technical services on matters in his area this would in turn give the
chief of rnd trudeau authority on assignment of key personnel and allocation of rnd funds to
technical services this rnd primer document also reveals some startling revelations the army's
initial needs for managing rnd efforts led to the creation of university research initiatives
uri's independent laboratory in-house research ilir and independent research and development
programs irads some of you may remember irads as a funding mechanism for legacy programs mentioned
by david grush furthermore these uri and ilir programs would eventually lead to uarc and ffrdc
two types of military and federally controlled semi-private groups that likely operate heavily
with ufo legacy programs what a fascinating document there is absolutely more to explore
here such as the thesis of how legacy program architecture was born out of army rnd
i do want to spend some time visiting some of the smaller aspects to corso's disclosures we glossed
over discussing the manuscript corso additionally made some extremely interesting claims regarding
some information he gathered long after his service corso allegedly learned that in february
of 1987 colonel herald e phillips of the defense intelligence agency chaired a pentagon group
called the ufo working group this group apparently still in existence at the time of the manuscripts
writing in 1993 originally consisted of 17 men one army and three air force generals dia scientists
an army colonel three nsa officials a supervisor from the cia's domestic collection division
as well as a technical team from the cia science and technology directorate well for one where is
the navy here as the navy is likely up to its eyeballs in ufo legacy programs such as the
off-world technologies division housed at the naval surface warfare center in crane indiana
it seems strange that between 1987 and 1993 corso and his ufo working group intelligence
source would not know or not make mention to the navy's dealings in uap legacy programs
but let's go back to the mention of the cia science and technology directorate and how it
is of extreme importance here by numerous accounts the cia ds and t is where the quote
unquote ufo portfolio is held according to eric davis as well as chris sharp and many others the
director of this position glenn gaffney was the individual who stopped lockheed martin from
divesting uap material to osap in 2008 additionally former cia ds and t deputy director doug wolf
helped create the cia office of global access in 2003 which was accused by excellent journalist
chris sharp as serving as a logistics coordinator agency alongside jsoc joint special operations
command for uap crash retrieval corso was way ahead of his time to make mention to this
this ufo working group according to corso also received funding from us army inscom intelligence
and security command founder major general albert stubblebine in the last few projects
i have done i have talked at length about stubblebine and his likely work in uap legacy
programs including fort hachuka in the 1960s stubblebine was also allegedly the man who tried
to pay off steven greer in the 1990s and the alleged founder of the nsa's men in black
treat tactical reconnaissance engineering assessment team we'll skip over this for now as
we cover this in depth with edgar fusch and the flying triangle arvs but for now how about this
inscom special forces unit the illustrious intelligence support activity isa was handed
over to jsoc in 2003 the same year wolf constructed the cia office of global access which allegedly
used jsoc for uap retrievals isa is often known as the most secretive and clandestine of jsoc units
even outside of the ufo working group just how intimate is us army inscom with legacy programs
and does this working group not sound very similar to a majestic 12 like structure
let's take this time to briefly point out another distinction between the book and the manuscript
in day after roswell claims are made of working adjacent to roscoe hillencoder and the infamous
majestic 12 personnel list under eisenhower and truman dawn of a new age sees corso recognizing
the eisenhower briefing document report but how he never saw the report at the nsc and white house
the vast majority of criticism against corso comes from analysis of the day after roswell and his
claims of technology seeding the lieutenant colonel's military accolades are beyond question
we have already addressed the stark differences between the manuscript and the book the book
clearly added myriad details to spice up the story of corso the manuscript is well it's tough reading
but it gives us an unbridled look into corso's experiences the manuscript was also completed
prior to the release of the day after roswell colonel alexander and others were shown the
completed manuscript around the time of the book's release while alexander joc valet and others are
still very critical of corso's they all maintain the lieutenant colonel story never wavered details
were never altered added or subtracted corso sounded like a tape recorder you could rewind
or fast forward to parts of his disclosures and always hear the same details never any wavering
allegedly corso had but 24 hours to edit the day after roswell book which led to no oversight on
all the creative liberties in the piece one must ask why the subject of this non-fiction book
was stripped of all creative control of the project in his book john b alexander details a
letter he wrote to corso about all the issues related to the day after roswell mind you these
criticisms are all leveraged towards the book still interesting to keep in mind and i highly
recommend looking at this nonetheless link in the description many discrepancies regarding
technology seeding has been thrown at corso some of which we have already addressed jock
valet for example well versed in computer science stated corso's assertions regarding
integrated circuitry were not documented facts colonel alexander himself had specific issues
with the passive night vision system mentioned by corso alexander stated the genealogy of infrared
and nvg technology can all be accounted for alexander detailed how he spoke to the director
of night vision laboratory at fort belvoir virginia dr lou cameron who flatly denied how an
eye lens of nhi aided in passive night vision breakthroughs legendary researcher stanton
friedman was also extremely critical of corso associating him with bob lazar which in my opinion
regardless of skepticism against corso is very inappropriate friedman criticized corso for his
grand story absent of evidence this is a viewpoint i can absolutely empathize with but what does
stanton have to say now entirely differently in terms of background lieutenant colonel philip
j corso came out with the book on the 50th anniversary of roswell first published right in
roswell called the day after roswell in which he claims that when he was at the foreign technology
desk of the army research and development command at the pentagon under general trudeau
he surreptitiously slipped a filing cabinet full of advanced technology wreckage from roswell
into the hands of american industry and he saved the world that's how we got kevlar and
micro integrated circuits and a whole long list of things and uh it was a great story
and the forward of the book was by senator strom thurman the oldest serving member of
the senate who said nice things about corso but in his intro his forward says nothing about roswell
in his manuscript and book corso was indeed what you could describe egotistical but in his memoirs
he never once claimed to have been some sort of world savior he was very patriotic and simply
aimed to strengthen the army this is obviously not friedman's fault as the book was his only
available analysis on corso at the time well to make a very long story short when you start
checking on colonel corso lieutenant colonel corso things just don't check out he provides no
validation for any other claims there's no index in the book either they say new documents finally
released there's nothing new in there and many people have gone through i know one phd who was
a colonel in the military who sent me a list of 92 false claims made in the book
92 i mean just technically wrong all over the place well you can blame that on the co-author maybe
but uh some of the discoveries of physicists just won a nobel prize for example for work done
three years before corso was connected with the army research and development group he's a nice
gentleman i met him while he was alive uh but his claims senator thurman withdrew his forward
wasn't in the next edition of the book because it was written for an entirely different book
about corso's activities corso talked about the fbi his good buddy hoover when his fbi file was
released uh hoover had nothing but bad things to say about corso now it muddied the waters
and got a lot of attention why would such a distinguished military man well the real
military people will tell you he only made lieutenant colonel after 22 years in a lot
of lieutenant colonels not nearly as many full colonels so it's another example of taking
advantage opportunism if you will uh he also claimed that he was a member of the national
security council and a sworn statement for a lawyer was going to go after the government to
spill out all colonel corso's files well i checked with the eisenhower library he not only was never
a member of the national security council which is very prestigious indeed he never attended a
meeting of the national security council he was a liaison between the security council and some
other groups but it doesn't help ufology to have this kind of thing going on people accept a great
deal and his book sold well but i'm sorry it isn't what it claims to be
it's not a real expose of the truth about roswell and flying saucers and
government's new technology cut now in july of 2024 john greenwald and the black vault published
documents released by the fbi on corso and no no documents discussing ufos a portion of these
documents pertain to in 1964 to 65 fbi background check on corso for his perspective position on
the immigration and national security subcommittee of the house of representatives corso had allegedly
provided some unfounded claims in the past according to these documents delivering a list
of fabian socialists to his good friend arthur trudeau the fbi was unable to validate these
claims corso was also investigated for spreading claims garnered from cia sources that lee harvey
oswald assassin of jfk was an fbi informant now oswald being either an fbi or cia informant
probably does not seem too unlikely to everybody regarding a soviet defector michael golanowski
the fbi documents state quote another government agency has characterized corso as a parasite who
has never produced any intelligence through his own efforts but has profited from information
developed by dedicated government agents and investigators end quote all of these critical
files on corso were cross references and not main files meaning the fbi never officially
investigated corso from these files it does appear corso like to quote unquote waste the
fbi's time making accusations no content here actually discusses his duties with the foreign
technology division let alone the army and of course it is odd the selection of documents
released when they were released why are there no documents on corso's army position and why are
there no documents on the foreign technology division my greatest issue with corso arises
from a massive firsthand experience relegated to the very end of his manuscript remember corso
claimed to have witnessed an extraterrestrial body in 1947 observed ufos on radar at ballistic missile
sites in 1958 and 1959 and eventually studied materials recovered from uap crashes for the
foreign technology division corso's affidavit says as much without reference to the nike missile
site encounters however at the end of this manuscript corso recounts an incident while
in command of a missile silo at white sands missile range corso claimed while driving alone
in an isolated area he sought shelter from the heat in an abandoned mine within the mine he
claimed to have encountered face to face a bean of non-human intelligence the bean was drawn in
corso's manuscript and communicated to him telepathically we can also see him relay drawings
of this bean in a long lost interview featured on weaponized with george napp the bean wished to
leave the surrounding area however active radar interference from nearby installations were
preventing its craft's departure a common theory by corso and some roswell researchers is radar
systems interfered with craft navigation leading to crashes i am still very skeptical on this point
corso asked the bean what he would get in return for lowering the radar coverage the bean responded
quote a new world if you can take it and quote corso would then grant the beans wish when he
returned to his installation this experience was so profound to him he would often contemplate the
meaning of the statement during life corso would even relay this story to john b alexander george
napp and possibly others including a film to his grandchildren somehow danny sheehan saw i found to
be extraordinarily important the the little eight millimeter home movie that uh that colonel corso
actually produced to be shown to his grandchildren after he died this this is this i found to be
extraordinarily persuasive that he and i got to see the film uh but it wasn't supposed to be shown
till after he died and uh and i was shown the film uh and it shows him talking to his grandchildren
saying that even though i'm gone now i wanted to make sure you understood this and what he did he
talked about the fact that back in 1945 in july uh when before we had even dropped the bombs on
hiroshima in nagasaki while they were experimenting with the nuclear bomb uh out in the desert at uh
alamogordo and white flats uh that in uh new mexico he he in fact was one of the the security
officers there uh and he said that they were seeing ufos he told his grandchildren uh from
from the grave basically on the bit and little eight millimeter home movie that he had been there
and that saw the ufos and that he took a lunch break to go leave and went off into the hill
somewhere to go to lunch and he saw one of the craft that had landed uh it had been somehow
disabled by the radar that was up all around the proving grounds uh and he had a direct contact
with the ufo occupants of the vehicle and they they communicated to him telepathically to please
take down the radar just temporarily to allow them to flee uh and he actually did that he told
his grandchildren he went back and as a range officer ordered them to shut down the the radar
for just a short time to do some kind of recalibration of it and at that point the ufo craft fled
uh shot off into the sky now that's that's corso talking to his grandchildren
in a in a private never intended to be made public uh eight millimeter film and so i found
that quite convincing about corso uh so when corso reports that he was actually put into possession
of some of the technology that had been recovered from the roswell crash i tend to give it a
considerable amount of credibility and the fact that the the various uh aero uh aerospace uh
corporations try to set forth some sort of a long explanation about how they really developed the
silicon chip they really developed the fiber optics they really developed uh the other uh
technology that corso attributes to the roswell crash that's exactly what they would do there's
any doubt about it that they would obfuscate and they would try to construct some sort of an
alternative explanation for how they develop themselves this technology and so i'm just saying
that i find the corso uh testimony more credible than many people do i must be very clear here how
shehan is indeed incorrect about the 1945 date corso claimed this event occurred when commander
of the ballistic missile firing range at red canyon part of white sands this station was in
1957 to 1958 my issue here is this is a truly consequential encounter if true initially i
believed this passage to be a dream or metaphor until i read more about how many others corso
would tell this story to unfortunately this is an issue that plagues much of the ufo realm
witnesses stating disclosures then adding well and then this happened and then that happened far
after their initial disclosures one would imagine such an intimate encounter with a non-human
intelligence biologic would be featured in most of corso's disclosures make of this passage what
you will however it does leave somewhat of a sour taste in my mouth that such a dramatic
encounter is relegated to the very back part of his manuscript hey guys it's uap gerb thank you
so much for joining me as we took this 90 plus around 90 minute deep dive into the claims of
lieutenant colonel philip j corso now before we get started and kind of uh give this conclusion
a lot of the time you'll see corso mentioned as colonel philip j corso i have never once been
able to verify that corso was indeed a full bird colonel so thus i try to stay true to what i know
as fact and what i've seen on his military records and call him lieutenant colonel philip j corso
so the reason i took on this project quite often i'll see people either pro corso or anti-corso and
much of their arguments crux on the day after roswell book a lot of the people who disregard
corso or put away his claims have a unsavory taste in their mouth from the day after roswell
whether that be to some of the unsubstantiated and wild claims such as um corso forcing a cia
guy to self-delete or some of the egotistical megalomania of course so in the day after roswell
book about him being a world savior and just some of the uh perfect synchronicities of you know
perfect descriptions of the roswell crash and roscoe hillencoder and the majestic 12 so i wanted
to take a step back and read the pure manuscript dawn of a new age of course so this is 176 page
manuscript if you ever watch this video again if you're interested i do recommend reading the
full thing however it is a very dreadful read most things are talked about eight or nine times
throughout the manuscript so it can just be a trudge to get through now i do notice that there
are still some differences between corso's affidavit and the dawn of a new age manuscript
and this being the description of the encounter at white sands in 57 and 58 which we just touched on
in the end of the video of encountering a non-human intelligence with almost a different
physiognomy to the bean he claimed to have seen at fort riley in 1947 so that that description
still leaves a bit of a strange taste in my mouth due to reading it after about 120 140 pages into
the manuscript at first like i mentioned i did think it was a metaphor a new world if you could
take it something to teach his grandchildren to learn from but corso is alleging that this is a
true incident he not only wrote this in a film in his manuscript in a film to his grandkids that
somehow she handsaw but also told john b alexander joc valet and george napp about this experience
so let's kind of dive into some of the things i found very interesting because i do think
there's a lot of very credible statements made in the manuscript now i cannot speak to the
veracity of the technology seating claims i'm not an expert in integrated circuitry i'm not an expert
in computer science i'm not even an expert in metallurgy that was one of my worst classes
material science in the university so i cannot speak to that that is why i tried to put a balanced
take of course those claims and some traditional history but what we can speak on is some of the
factual accuracies of u.s army r and d at the time you know i know we analyzed that primer quite a
bit so it was fascinating to see kind of the army's need for a centralized r and d project under
trudeau spearheaded in 1958 just like corso said that's when the golden age of army r and d began
it was also very interesting to see back in the late 50s and early 60s the u.s army was trying
to kind of get with semi-private institutions and universities in order to um flourish under army
r and d this is something that we talked about quite often ffr dcs and uarcs and
reverse engineering programs and legacy programs utilizing these sorts of institutions for
probably material study and so forth and also the foreign technology division this is something i
think is one of the most crucial aspects of this video that i've seen almost nobody else talk about
the foreign technology division under which corso worked was u.s army not air force this is not the
infamous foreign technology division out of right pat now we can ask ourselves why is there no
information about this foreign technology division why can we see nothing about it except in the
actual military documents under corso i myself have some foya documents out to try to investigate
this further but as we've known with the interplanetary phenomenon unit with the u.s army
there are some weird institutions that somehow exist through institutional memory
i'll be interested in to see if i can pry anything free from foya regarding the army's foreign
technology division however my hopes aren't necessarily high that being that if this was
indeed one of the first structured u.s legacy programs i'm sure we'll get no information and
i do want to touch on that because if corso's claims are indeed true and i look favorably upon
the claims of corso we'll just say that there's some claims that still bewilder me like the
nhi encounter and so forth but this program started in 1960 would likely be one of the
first structured u.s legacy programs utilizing corporations you know bell labs and some of the
fortune 500 companies as well as universities and semi-private institutions so if these
disclosures and testimonies are indeed fact we can extract a lot of interesting data and
worthwhile investigation here seeing how legacy programs were structured and and framework and
that is something that could extend to today which i find highly likely seen as i do believe
in modern day or at least the early 2000s the army's role in legacy programs has often been rnd
to try and equip the modern warfighter with reverse engineered technologies of unknown origin there
will be a lot more to discuss on that in the future and hopefully as we move on over time we
can try and crack into some of these legacy programs and and talking exactly what about the
army air force navy does and what contractors work under them and so forth speaking of contractors
spary rand wasn't that an interesting details the memoirs of true dough and discussed by corso one
of the one of the companies they met with often was spary rand and when spary rand went defunct
i'm doing this off the top of my head which i believe was 86 much of their information and
engineering divisions were bought up by raytheon northrup honeywell and i believe raytheon as well
as bell labs i think one of the most interesting connections here is bell labs being owned by
at&t who in turn owned say own had ownership of sandia national labs under mandate by truman
sandia is a usual suspect mentioned in the majestic documents mentioned by edgar fuchet
mentioned in the interplanetary phenomenon unit documents that are still disputed to this day so
there's a lot of interesting data here to kind of analyze a hypothetical or very much real us army
reverse engineering program and speaking of that i'm also so fascinated by corso's discussion of
the ufo working group wasn't that interesting mentioning the cia directorate of science and
technology having a major position on this group of about 17 18 people on the board as we know with
the work of chris sharp thank you chris sharp if you ever watch one of my videos i'm honored you're
you're an inspiration but that in 2003 cia oga served as a logistics coordinator for ufo crash
retrieval with the help of jsoc as we have just analyzed the cia directorate of science technology
spawned the oga and then us army inscom founder major albert major general albert stubblebind who
corso said funded the ufo working group under inscom in 2003 the isa the intelligence support
activity known sometimes as the activity the most clandestine of jsoc units was given over to jsoc
and this was all in 2003 around the time of the oga's creation which is allegedly the time the
oga served as a logistics coordinator for crash retrieval if you don't know much about the isa i
highly recommend watching some videos on them they are some uh true bad people in terms of just their
training and so forth they're really interesting i'm always interested in learning more about jsoc
but i do want to know what everybody thought about the video and corso after analyzing his
claims in a vacuum purely analyzing his claims without any of the nonsense and extracurriculars
from day after roswell what does everybody think let's get a discussion going if you do not know
i have a discord come join that i'll have the link in the description we'll probably have some
conversations going on about corso and so forth because i would really like to talk about that
if anybody has any experience or other information on the foreign technology division
let's get talking because i think that if you take one single thing away from this video i i would
like it to be that the army had an rnd program in the 1960s called the foreign technology division
that there are no documents and no data for all we know is that true doe followed upon his
retirement in 62 by dwight e beach four star general um we're in command of u.s army rnd the
office of the chief of army research and development so there are some kind of clues there for us to
work on further but i hope everybody enjoyed this project we're coming up on a year anniversary of
the channel i got something a little fun to to revisit for that but thank you all for tuning in
again i'd like to know what everybody thought i got a patreon in the in the channel description
i don't keep any content everything i do is for the world to see so if you want to support the
channel only support what you think the channel is worth with that being said guys we will get
working right on the next project and i shall see everybody soon please remember to like and
subscribe and thank you so much for tuning in bye everybody