For decades, debate has raged on in ufology about the existence of a committee of elite
military leaders, government officials, and scientists tasked with the investigation,
study, and collection of UFOs and their occupants.
This now infamous group was revealed through hundreds of allegedly leaked documents over
the course of 1984 to 1999 to be titled the Majestic 12 or MJ-12.
Any viewer of my work will know I often reference the Majestic documents in MJ-12, such as my
Del Rio case where I bring up the Majestic document called the Eisenhower Briefing document,
in which I reference a December 1950 UFO crash retrieval stated to have occurred near the
Mexican-Texas border between El Indio and Guerrero.
A crash retrieval Lou Elizondo has now stated to have occurred in his 2024 book, Imminent.
So with the contentious nature surrounding the Majestic documents in ufology, the debunking
work done by professional skeptic Philip K. Glass and others, alongside the FBI's
to haphazardly write bogus across one set of documents to label all documents as false,
why cover the Majestic documents?
To me, the analysis of MJ-12 and the Majestic documents must consist of studying the documents
themselves, their origins, content, provenance, and connective tissue to not only other Majestic
documents but also acknowledged and declassified files, like the work done by the legendary
Stanton Friedman and world-class Ryan S. Wood.
This is why today I have partnered with fantastic UFO researcher Ryan S. Wood to explore the
Majestic documents.
Ryan and his father, Dr. Robert Wood, a former McDonnell Douglas rocket scientist, have spent
decades painstakingly scrutinizing the entire catalog of Majestic documents to unravel the
mystery that is the Majestic-12.
Hey guys, it's UAPGurb and thank you so very much for joining me, author of Magic
Eyes Only, and myself as we discuss the authenticity, origin, and context of the Majestic documents.
With the revelations of David Grush in the 21st century, the reality of UFO crash retrieval
and reverse engineering has made its way into the public zeitgeist.
This is why we must take a closer inspection of the highly debated group allegedly first
tasked with UFO crash retrievals, the Majestic-12.
Before we get into the interview, I want to take a brief moment to introduce the Majestic-12
for any newcomer to the subject.
I highly recommend reading Top Secret Magic by Stanton Friedman, studying Majestic Documents.com
written by Ryan and Dr. Bob, my all-time favorite book Magic Eyes Only by Ryan S. Wood, or reading
the incredible Medium articles by Blocked Epistemology.
The Majestic-12 is a group known from a series of controversial leaked documents to have been
tasked with UFO study, collection, and analysis.
The group seemingly rose to power around the time of the 1947 Roswell, New Mexico crash,
but with origins extending even earlier, around 1941 or 1942.
According to Stanton Friedman, the group allegedly consisted of 12 members, MJ 1-12, consisting
of six civilian and six military personnel.
Of the military people, two representatives each from the Army, Navy, and Air Force served
in the MJ-12.
The private sector saw seasoned research and development organizers and very strong intelligence
community leaders participate in the group.
Viewers of my Robert Saarbacher video will remember Dr. Vannevar Bush, head of the Office
of Scientific Research and Development, who was labeled a crucial founding member of the
Majestic-12.
Other original members named in the Majestic documents include General Nathan Twining,
the leader of Project Sine, aka Project Saucer, in 1948.
James Forrestal, Secretary of the Navy and first U.S. Secretary of Defense, who conveniently
threw himself out of a hospital window in 1949.
Donald H. Menzel, astronomer at Harvard and high-security consultant to the NSA and CIA.
Roscoe H. Hillencoder, Admiral, Navy Intelligence, and first Director of the CIA.
Walter B. Smith, General in the U.S. Army, Ambassador to the USSR, second Director to
the CIA, and Forrestal's replacement.
And Hoyt S. Vandenberg, USAF General, second Director of the Central Intelligence Group,
Air Force Chief of Staff.
And this is just a slice of the total members.
I highly recommend analyzing the MJ-12 master list created by Ryan Wood.
Many over the years have hypothesized what the magic in MJ-12 stands for.
User blockedepistemology hypothesizes this name is derived from the 1945 May Johnson
Atomic Energy Bill.
Excellent Reddit researcher, user HarryIsWhiteHot, believed magic was some sort of continuation
of a very high classification standard titled MAGIC, used during World War II.
I find myself believing MAGIC is an abbreviation for a Joint Intelligence Committee, possibly
something along the lines of Majority Joint Intelligence Committee 12.
But without further ado, let's talk to Ryan S. Wood and begin to dive into the origins
of the documents.
Yeah, well, the broad brush is that there's some 3,500 pages over 19 years from seven
different sources.
The first event was in 1984, when Jamie Chanderay, which was an LA TV producer, I believe, received
the Eisenhower briefing document, which Stan Friedman ultimately got in, outlines the
original 12 MJ-12 members in that document.
And that's the one that was taken around to the FBI, and several people submitted it to
the FBI, because the FBI is responsible for leaks of classified documents.
And the FBI took it to a variety of three-letter agencies and said, did you lose this?
And they said, well, no, we didn't lose this, we don't know anything about it.
And so after their process, they declared it bogus.
And despite the efforts of Stan Friedman to authenticate a whole variety of people that
were MJ-12 members, and then the other two different sources for that same document that
came into the field years after that, some with different marginalia, some with slightly
different three-hole punching.
And so, I mean, they aren't stunningly authentic in original paper or something like that.
But there are some other sources of that same document that have surfaced over time.
But it was a briefing for Eisenhower, and that was the first one.
And that sort of kicked things off and got Stan Friedman really pushing along.
Returning viewers of my channel will know the first ever Majestic document quite well,
the top secret Magic Eyes only Eisenhower briefing document.
This document stating to contain compartmentalized information essential to U.S. national security
was organized to brief president incumbent Dwight D. Eisenhower on the Majestic 12 group
on November 18, 1952.
The document labels Operation Majestic 12 as a top secret R&D slash intelligence operation
reporting solely to the President of the United States, set up by a classified executive
order of President Harry Truman by recommendation of Dr. Vannevar Bush and Secretary Forrestal
on the 24th of September, 1947.
Funny enough, in the daily appointment history of Harry Truman, we can find a meeting with
SecDef James Forrestal and Dr. Vannevar Bush arranged at the suggestion of Forrestal.
The briefing document includes a list of all 12 sitting MJ-12 members, including General
Walter B. Smith, who replaced the deceased Secretary Forrestal on August 1, 1950.
And again, we can find an actual appointment held off-record with Truman and Walter B.
Smith on this exact date.
The briefing document discusses the hysteria caused by saucer sightings of Kenneth Arnold
in the summer of 1947 and subsequent failures to pursue these discs in flight.
July 7, 1947 oversaw the beginning of the MJ-12 with the Roswell crash.
Northwest of Roswell Army Airfield experienced the now most famous UFO crash in history,
which according to the Eisenhower briefing document, saw craft and body collection efforts
by General Nathan Twining and Dr. Vannevar Bush.
A soon-to-be sitting MJ-12 member, Dr. Detlev Brank, performed autopsies on the bodies and
coined the term EBE, or Extraterrestrial Biological Entity.
The Roswell team and Dr. Donald Menzel concluded the craft was of non-human origin and likely
originated from a solar system far removed from our own.
The report discusses forms of writing on the Roswell craft, something primary witness Jesse
Marcel Sr. and Jr. would claim to witness on a small piece of metallic debris.
The Roswell report led directly to the creation of projects Sign, Grudge, and Blue Book with
very limited interaction between these official programs and the MJ-12.
And I'll draw your attention back to a whistleblower I covered, Brigadier General Steven
Lovekin, who claimed to have observed pieces of Roswell debris in a classified portion of
Project Blue Book far removed from the official reports.
The document then discusses the 1950 El Indio crash, touched on in 2024 by Lou Elizondo,
and makes specific mention of the Atomic Energy Commission and Sandia National Labs.
Curiously, near the end of the document is listed a contingency plan, MJ-1949-04 P-7-8.
And just remember that contingency plan.
Tireless work was done by Stanton Friedman,
authenticating the Eisenhower briefing document in his book Top Secret Slash Magic.
But there are two specific investigations I want to mention.
In 1989, Friedman physically traveled to the National Archives and reviewed
files of the Office for the Secretary of Defense.
Within these documents were numerous November 18, 1952 briefing documents
for President-elect Eisenhower.
None of these briefings mentioned MJ-12,
but it is fact the Truman administration was indeed briefing Eisenhower on this date.
Investigation 2 circles around the labeled briefing officer, Admiral Roscoe H. Hillencoder.
Debunkers of the majestic documents claim Hillencoder was sent to Korea in 1950 for six years.
However, Friedman was able to determine Hillencoder was indeed present in Brooklyn,
New York in late 1952 when he was made head of the 3rd Naval District in New York.
So Hillencoder could have indeed been present at the Washington briefings on November 1952.
And many MJ-12 files with Hillencoder as a key individual exist,
though they do require further research.
Such as this February 11, 1948 Hillencoder to Truman Majestic Black Book Summaries document,
which makes direct mention to MAGIC.
Or this September 19, 1963 CIA Director Hillencoder to Donald Menzel Memo,
which sees the director congratulating his fellow alleged MJ-12 member on his book
regarding what we can assume was successful obfuscation of the UFO reality.
And lastly, we have some key clues on a September 19, 1947 memo from Hillencoder
to Joint Intelligence Committee.
This majestic document memo, allegedly dated just before Bush and Forrestal's request to create MJ-12,
is titled quote,
Memorandum for the Military Assessment of the Joint Intelligence Committee, end quote,
aka MAGIC.
The memo requests a classified intelligence project, quote,
We recovered one craft, captured one, end quote.
This memo states no clear coordinated scientific examination was possible until,
quote, unquote, we got a clear directive from the president.
The memo also states Wright Field had a new biological laboratory.
The Joint Research and Development Board and the FBI, MI5 and MI6 were helping with the effort.
And finally, guys, back to Mr. Wood.
The other one that's really big is the Special Operations Manual,
Extraterrestrial Entities Technology Recovery and Disposal.
And that was leaked in 1994 to Don Berliner,
who was an Aviation Week and Space reporter in Washington, D.C.
And it was an undeveloped film.
It came in a little green box and they went and my father and I and,
well, not me, but my father and Don went to the dark room and developed it
and got all the original images.
I'll just pull a couple sheets out just for fun to show you.
This is, you know, it came in an Echo binder along the edge over here.
And also it came with the change control page, which is difficult to see,
but it says Kirkland Air Force Base Unit KB88, Building 21, Kirkland Air Force Base N.M.X.
We found that there was a Building 21.
I think it's now called Building 40 back then.
And the fact that the abbreviation for the stamp, Kirkland Air Force Base N.M.X,
is the correct postal abbreviation for 1954 for New Mexico.
If it said N.M., that would have been a hallmark of bakery or an anachronism
that would be worthy of lots of investigation.
Mr. Wood and myself will speak on the special operations manual throughout this video,
so we will only go into brief detail here.
The manual, according to Ryan Wood, Dr. Robert Wood, and Stanton Friedman,
is equally, if not more authentic than the Eisenhower briefing document.
Friedman has even stated,
quote, the Majestic 12 document's problem is complex and extensive.
On balance, it appears that the EBD, TFM, and CTM are almost certainly genuine.
The SOM 101 memo is very likely genuine, end quote.
Debate has raged on for decades now if the document is a hoax,
real, or possibly Soviet disinformation.
Later in the interview, we will do an entire analysis into the special operations manual,
or the SOM 101 as I'll refer to it.
But for now, understand this manual, allegedly written in 1954
and initially housed in Kirkland Air Force Base,
serves as a comprehensive summary of majestic operations
for quote, unquote, Majestic 12 units, and quote, unquote, authorized personnel.
The manual contains everything from MJ-12 full operational capacity
and MODIS operandi, NHI craft and body descriptions,
to MJ-12 recovery and disinformation protocols.
Similar to his masterpiece, Magic Eyes Only,
Ryan Wood has attributed a weighted authenticity rating to every document
based on factors such as direct firsthand witnesses,
forensic analysis if possible, document source, etc.
The special operations manual and Eisenhower briefing document
are two of the few pieces Wood has rated with the highest level of authenticity.
But are there others with such high confidence?
But I would also add the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit document,
because the government's acknowledged the existence of the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit,
part of the Stephen J. Chamberlain Assistant Chief of Staff for Intelligence,
Technical and Scientific Directorate, Counter Intelligence Group,
IPU, Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit, all these hierarchies down in the 40s time frame.
Well, this was 47, where the IPU document.
But what's interesting about the IPU document, which is on majesticdocuments.com,
people can read it.
And in my book, Magic Eyes Only, is details about the Roswell crash.
When it crashed at 2332 Mountain Standard Time, it dropped off radar.
And it had discussions of body parts inside the craft in handwritten notes.
And it had discussions of autopsies of the aliens done by Dietlef Bronk and Charles Ethan Ray,
which when I started to look around, I said, who's Charles Ethan Ray?
And he was a medical corps expert with Leslie Groves, the head of the Manhattan Project.
And I called up his daughter in Seattle and said,
do you think your father could have autopsied an alien?
And she didn't hesitate at all and said, yes.
Not that she knew that he did it, but it's clear in her mind that,
oh, absolutely, this is the sort of stuff he would have been tapped to do.
So I mean, there's just more and more detailed stories about the IPU in that document.
And so those three, I mean, each one has its own basket of interesting facts and authenticity.
Viewers of this channel will know recently I have been discussing the Interplanetary
Phenomenon Unit, the U.S. Army's in-house unofficial department in the 50s, for an
assistant chief of staff for intelligence to study UFOs. The IPU, initially discovered through
FOIA requests after initial DOD denial, exists only through quote unquote institutional memory.
I highly recommend reading Anthony Bregaglia's piece on the IPU. The existence of this division
was first revealed on September 6, 1980, in a FOIA request by Richard Hall and later confirmed
in a 1984 FOIA request by UFO researcher William Steinman. It took until the 1990s for the USG to
state all records were destroyed. Even though Hall's 1980 request oversaw the Army Director of
Counterintelligence state all IPU records were surrendered to Blue Book. Anyways, as Ryan stated,
on MajesticDocuments.com we can find two IPU documents within the MJ-12 documents.
IPU Field Order and IPU Report. The Interplanetary Phenomenon Field Order lists a July 4, 1947
correspondence of a situation occurring the day before the memo requesting personnel including
an aeronautical engineer and medical doctor cleared for quote, need to know, end quote.
And this date should ring a bell as occurring right before the Roswell crash. The IPU report
first made its way into the public on July 16, 1995 and lists astonishing information authorized
by Lieutenant General John A. Samford and approved by CIA Director Alan Dulles. Some of you may
remember Samford giving the famous press conference alongside Roswell General Roger Ramey post the 1952
UFOs over Washington DC incident. This document explores in great detail the events of the Roswell
UFO crash including initial tracking and assessment of the two sites of the crashed disc.
A very key clue in this document is the mention that some Roswell Army airfield investigators
at LZ-1, the debris field seen by Brazel and Marcel, thought the wreckage may have been a
Project Mogul balloon until Los Alamos personnel determined the wreckage was something quote,
unquote, out of this world. If you know anything about the Roswell crash you'll know it's often
explained away as a Project Mogul balloon. And this was revealed after the initial
weather balloon cover story in the U.S. Air Force's 1994 report, The Roswell Report.
The Roswell Report states the Mogul flight that was misidentified as a large metallic flying saucer
with bodies was Mogul flight number four, which allegedly launched on June 4, 1947.
However, in 2024, Project Mogul's field operations director, Dr. Alan Crary,
revealed with evidence, flight number four never took place on this day and was indeed cancelled
due to weather. Anyways, the IPU report states a radiobiological team and security detail from
Sandia National Labs were summoned by Colonel S.B. Housebrook. Chosen scientists consisted of AEC
personnel including J. Robert Oppenheimer, Werner von Braun, and others. And before you say this
sounds too fantastical, remember von Braun's mentor, Herman Osberth, performed serious analysis
on UFO flight characteristics. Twining, Vandenberg, and others are named within this
report as aiding in the recovery effort and overall operation. And an interesting line here,
quote, it has become known to CIC that some of the recovery operation was shared with representative
John F. Kennedy, end quote. I'm not going to spend too much more time on the IPU report,
but as Wood stated, Detlev Brank is named as assisting in the autopsy. The report then
discusses the NHI bodies, body parts seemingly dissected similar to a frog scattered at the
primary crash site, and the death of multiple Sandia lab techs due to a form of contamination.
And I recently discussed this contamination in my 1974 Koyama, Mexico crash retrieval case.
Based on the documents Ryan Wood has the most confidence are in fact legitimate,
I asked him to describe robustly what exactly compromises the Majestic 12,
how various named members fit into the group, and the impact such an organization had on
ufology at the time of the initial MJ-12 documents being leaked. Well, it's a top secret research
and development intelligence gathering organization that was formed by executive order of the
in September 24th, 1947. 1947 was when the Atomic Energy Act was created, when the CIA was created
and sort of the OSS was transitioned, Office of Strategic Services, which was the CIA at the time
into the CIA, and they formed this top secret research and development intelligence gathering
organization. And it was, you know, headed by Vannevar Bush, part of the
Office of Research and Development, OSRD, and this is where
Eric Walker, Dr. Eric Walker lived working for Vannevar Bush and ultimately took over
the organization and was widely understood to be familiar with MJ-12, well leading it
in that group. So the names of the people caught a lot of attention and Stan did a lot of work and
has written his book Top Secret Magic, I think, which highlights a lot of the research around
the various people. He dug into Carl Sagan, which was a person that shouldn't have been
on the list, sort of, you know, he was a big debunker. But when Stan finally went to the
various archives and dug around, he found lots of correspondence between other MJ-12 members and
so that was, you know, interesting and powerful for the authenticity of the document. But it was,
again, it was a photocopy, well actually was film, it was undeveloped film, just like the
special operations manual that arrived. It might have been from the same source, but it certainly
wasn't mailed the same way.
Eric A. Walker. In my video on physicist Robert Sarbacher, I discussed how Dr. Sarbacher directly
named Vannevar Bush as a key figure studying UFOs within the U.S. government. During conversations
with Stanton Friedman, Dr. Sarbacher, who was a member of Bush's Research and Development Board,
mentioned Dr. Eric A. Walker as a key figure connected to UFO crash retrievals. Walker was
contacted by researcher William Steinman and not only confirmed the existence of the MJ-12,
but actually admitted his own presence at the 1965 Kexburg, Pennsylvania, crash retrieval.
I highly recommend revisiting my video here.
So, I mean, going to the special operations manual that you mentioned with the Ray Z, there's so
many hallmarks of authenticity in that particular document. I can start with the fact that we took
it to a retired government printing officer, General, not General, but McCarter in Washington,
D.C. He retired from the U.S. government printing office maybe like six months before we visited
him. And we, you know, went to his house and set it up on a card table and slid the document across.
And he looked at it and said, well, you know, by the title, Extraterrestrial Entities Technology
Recovery and Disposal, I would think it's fake. But then he flipped through the documents and saw
that the Zs were raised and said, oh, this is an artifact of hot lead printing press. Besides the
fact that he checked it for everything. I mean, he said the fonts are right. The indentations are
correct. The use of M dashes in MJ-12 long dash clearance is correct. The capitalization of
first aid was correct for the period. So he went through a bunch of subtleties that we didn't
understand or perceive at the time to highlight the fact that it was real in his mind and
ultimately concluded that, yeah, the CIA probably printed it in a cage down on 10th Street.
That was his opinion at the time. With Mr. Wood passionately discussing his authentication
methods of the MJ-12 Special Operations Manual, now is the perfect time to discuss the contents
of this absolutely mind boggling document. SOM-1 was sent anonymously to Don Berliner in 1994 and
consisted of undeveloped 35 millimeter triax film authenticated to 1954. Labeled top secret magic
eyes only, the manual details the full operational capacity and mission of the majestic 12. As
mentioned by Mr. Wood, we see the document control is regressed to a singular stamp of Kirtland Air
Force Base, New Mexico. The document control page shows us MJ-12 members, MJ-01 and MJ-04,
who altered the document from 1954 to 1958. Initials listed here are EWL and JRT, two names
Ryan has actually tracked and we will discuss shortly. And now we get into the meat of this
document, quote, this manual has been prepared especially for majestic 12 units, end quote.
Its purpose is to present all aspects of MJ-12 so authorized personnel will have a better understanding
of the goals of the group, be able to more expertly deal with UFOs,
ET tech and entities and increase the efficiency of future operations.
Section 1 project goals and purposes of this document make some startling revelations.
1. MJ-12 considers unidentified flying objects UFOBs to be a matter of the very highest order
of national security. 2. There would be a negative impact on the public with general
knowledge of the UFO situation. 3. Danger present if advanced tech falls into the hands of adversaries.
And 4. MJ-12 was established on the 24th of September 1947 under recommendation by
Vannevar Bush and Forrestal. The goals of MJ-12 are clearly outlined here as well.
1. Recovery for scientific study of all materials and devices of foreign or ET manufacture.
Recovery by any and all means by group. This immediately reminds me of the 1974
Koyama case with the American retrieval team finding the craft in Mexico at all costs.
2. Recovery for study of all entities and remains of entities of non-terrestrial origin through
independent action by those entities or by misfortune or military action.
3. Establishment and administration of special teams to accomplish the above operations,
which reminds me for the third video in a row of Christopher Sharpe's article on the CIA, OGA,
and JSOC being behind crash retrieval operations. 4. Establishment and admin of special secure
facilities located at secret locations within USA for providing receiving, processing,
analysis, and study of any and all materials and entities classified as extraterrestrial.
5. Covert operations carried in collusion with the CIA both home and abroad.
And 6. Establishment and absolute secrecy of all operations. As of the time of the alleged creation
of this document in 1954, MJ-12 does not consider NHI to be a threat, consisting of a benign presence
but with technology far beyond human science. The group had in possession several recovered
dead biologics. Section 1 General begins to define the scope of the Majestic-12, determination,
documentation, collection, and disposition of debris, devices, craft, and occupants.
This section defines ET technology as aircraft not manufactured by human power,
objects that appear as one of several shapes and configurations and exhibit
extraordinary flight characteristics, consisting of materials exhibiting characteristics beyond
science. And this section even describes EBEs, creatures, humanoid or otherwise,
whose evolutionary process differs demonstrably from that of Homo sapiens.
And now we get to my favorite part of this entire document, the description of the craft.
Elliptical or disc-shaped craft appear to be metallic and dull in color, whose appearance
consists of two pie pans or shallow dishes pressed together. SOM 101 even lists some dimensions of
these craft. They are 50 to 300 feet in diameter, with their thickness near 15% of the total
diameter. A dome extends above the disc, about 30% of the disc diameter, and extends 4 to 6 feet
above the main body. This dome may or may not include windows or ports. Lights on the craft
exist on the top, bottom, and rim that only function during operation. There's no antenna
or projections, but there are three extendable sets of landing gear. Cigar shape or tic tacs
are considered very rare. They can be 2,000 feet long and 95 feet thick. They do not operate in
lower atmosphere and travel at excess of 7,000 miles per hour. They do not engage in the rapid,
erratic or instantaneous maneuvers the smaller craft do. The ovoid circular or teardrop shapes
look almost like an ice cream cone, round at the large end and tapering to a near point at the
other. They are 30 to 40 feet long and have a diameter 20% of the length. The craft have
a bright light at the end point and the craft travels pointing down. And lastly, we have the
airfoil or triangular shape. These were considered new tech due to rarity of recent observations.
The craft appeared to be an isosceles triangle, with their longest side being near 300 feet
length. Little was known about the performance capabilities, but they operated appearingly
similar to the disc or ovoid shape. SOM101 then begins to go into description of extraterrestrial
biological entities, listing a Type 1 and Type 2, and thank you to Bill McDonald for the art here.
EBE1s look humanoid. They are 5 to 5 feet 4 inches tall, weighing 80 to 100 pounds.
They have larger, more rounded craniums with chalky yellow, thick, slightly pebbled pale skin.
They have small eyes wide set that are almost almond shape, with brownish black irises and
very large pupils and grey whites. Their mouths are wide, nearly lipless. They have fine hair,
not confined to underarm and groin. Their body is thin, with no fat and good muscles.
EBE1 has small hands, four long digits, no thumb, but webbing.
The description of the Type 2 EBE will remind you as much more of a classic grey.
They are humanoid, but 3 feet 5 inches to 4 feet 2 inches tall, weighing 25 to 50 pounds.
Their large, elongated head is larger proportionally to that of a human or EBE1.
Their eyes are large, slanted, and nearly wrap around their head, showing only pure black.
The nose appears to be two small slits above a slit-like mouth with no external ears.
Their skin is pale blue, greyish, fine-celled, and smooth.
They have no hair, leading MJ-12 to believe these creatures are not mammalian.
Their hands have three long fingers plus a long thumb.
They have four toes, jointed with a membrane.
The document then gives astounding descriptions of extraterrestrial technology recovered from
crash sites from 1947 to 1953. This date range includes Roswell to Kingman.
Metallurgical analyses show the materials were not known to terrestrial science at the time.
The material showed incredible strength and extreme resistance in proportion to weight
and size appearing similar to aluminum foil or aluminum magnesium sheeting.
Identical to the claims of primary Roswell witness Jesse Marcel Senior down to the
inclusion of inscriptions on material. In the press blackout section,
we find information extremely pertinent to today's age.
Media denial, discrediting witnesses, deceptive statements.
There are countless examples I can discuss here, but I recommend watching my UFO Stigma video
and paying key attention to the Robertson Panel and Condon Committee,
and also look at the reprisals against David Grush.
Secure the area, removal and transport, and cleaning the area all detail systems and
protocol for crash retrieval. What is of extreme interest here is the specific mention that any
specific craft or device that appears to be functional is designated to Red Team.
I can't help but think back to R.A. and how one piece of technology he observed at the
off-world technologies division was designated a weapon during recovery due to an energetic
discharge. But I asked Mr. Wood if he had ever come across this Red Team before.
I'd have to look, but I mean, I recall Blue Fly and Blue Teams as well. I mean, I think the term
Red Team and Blue Team are the same teams, so to speak, in crash retrievals. But, you know,
right in the front description of the Special Operations Manual, they have,
they mention these MJ-12 recovery teams. And I think in the,
well, you know, at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, they call it the Blue Lab.
Now on to Section 16. Special or unusual conditions has a very interesting note here.
Should the need for public disclosure become necessary, the majestic team was to issue
Contingency Plan MJ-1949-04P-78. Remember this from the Eisenhower briefing document?
We don't have the contingency plan. It's interesting that in the back of the Special
Operations Manual, there's a series of references in the back, and they weren't supplied.
That's the missing appendix too, right?
Yeah, that's the missing appendix for references. I mean, it's in the back here, but
for example, the photographic references were all correct, and you can go find them. So they're
correctly referenced in the back. And then there's also another sort of authenticity point is the
the UFOB, Unidentified Flying Object Identification Guide, that is listed in the manual,
but was not supplied as photocopies, original photocopies. But other FOIA documents provided
a typed version of it, not typeset, but just typed. But when my father retyped it all,
following the format of the manual, it perfectly matched the page numbers in the table of contents
and fit like a glove right in there. Section 17 Extraterrestrial Classification Table is truly
consequential for analyzing this document. Intact craft, damaged devices, identified and
unidentified fragments, and weapons were all to go to Area 51-S4. If you say Area 51 wasn't built in
1954, we'll discuss this shortly. Media, electronic recordings, maps, charts, etc. were to go to
Kirtland Air Force Base Building 21. Supplies and provisions, as well as deceased entities,
were to be sent to Wright-Patterson Air Force Blue Room. If Blue Room rings a bell besides Mr. Wood
just commenting on it, remember in my UFO whistleblowers video, Senator Harry Goldwater
was denied access to the contents of the Wright-Patterson Blue Room by General Curtis LeMay.
I think the government does know. I can't back that up, but I think that at Wright-Patterson Field,
if you could get into certain places, you'd find out what the Air Force and the government
knows about UFOs. Reportedly, a spaceship landed. It was all hushed up, quieted, and nobody ever
have never heard about much of it. I called Curtis LeMay and I said, General,
I know we have a room at Wright-Patterson where you put all this secret stuff.
Could I go in there? I've never heard him get mad, but he got madder than hell at me,
cussed me out, said, don't ever ask me that question again.
And speaking of General Curtis LeMay.
We have accommodation from Curtis LeMay to Harry B. Cooper, which is the father of Tim Cooper,
where many of these majestic documents came, and for his outstanding work at the USAF
program. I can supply you that document. You can put it up on the screen.
So that's another example of why in the world would Curtis LeMay sign accommodation
for somebody for their USAF program. It just makes no sense if it's not totally real. I'm just trying
to find a copy of it quickly. Yeah, I mean, it's hard to read here, but this is their seal and
accommodation. And it's to Harry B. Cooper, master sergeant, distinguished himself by
meritorious service as a non-commissioned officer in charge of printing management
branch and non-commissioned officer in charge of camera section, publishing division,
command directorate of administration of services headquarters, air defense command,
Int Air Force Base Colorado from 30 September 57 to 1 June 63. So he was at Int Air Force Base
between 57 and 63, looking at photographs of UFOs and printing all sorts of classified documents.
And, you know, I think it's Harry's relationship to this UFO topic and the friends that he made
during that time that allowed those friends to decide that I want to give stuff to Harry's son,
Tim Cooper, and several of the mailbox drops that had a lot of these documents from
ostensibly the interplanetary phenomenon unit officer or moon dust officer came from.
Back to section 17, living entities were to be directed solely to OPNAC BBS 01. Of course,
OPNAV, not OPNAC, stands for the Office of the Chief of Naval Operations. There are some who
guess this acronym stands for the Oceanic Platform for the North Atlantic and Caribbean, and that
BBS stands for the Bermuda Biological Station now called BIOS, the Bermuda Institute of Oceanic
Sciences, but there's really no proof here. SOM 101 continues with packaging and shipping protocols
for EBE life and states, quote, loss of EBE life is acceptable, and also details in figure
four, the extraterrestrial craft referenced earlier in the document. Here we observe classic
saucer and triangle shapes, but also the conical shape, which closely resembles the 1976 Tehran
Iran UFO case and the Cash Landrum case. You know, in 54, now they have the triangle shape,
they have the ice cream cone shape, they got the cigar shape, the typical saucer shape.
But I draw your attention to the triangles and the ice cream cone, which is, you know,
famous for the Cash Landrum case, and triangles are, this is some of the earliest mentions of
flying triangles. But anyways, let's circle back to the document control page and analyze the
initials EWL and JRT. Inside the control page, which is typical of every highly classified
document, this was apparently two points above top secret, according to the document,
classifications are different now, and it's pretty much, I believe, an Air Force document.
So I went to the Albuquerque phone book, pulled it up for 1954, 55, 56. I mean,
the entries in the change control page span from 54 to 57, I believe. And they have the initials.
And so I looked in the phone book and found all the initials, and there were two people, Jess R.
Totten and Captain Lewis, I think. They both lived on Perimeter Road, like four or five houses
from each other, inside Kirkland Air Force Base at the right time. And that's in the authenticity
discussions on the specialoperationsmanual.com website. It's in my book. And I'm working on
a new updated pamphlet that will have the whole manual and all the authenticity discussion that
people can read just easily. So I found them, and then I hired a private investigator
to go find them. And well, I actually found one guy, one JRT, but he said he's not the right guy,
despite being there at the right time. And he was the one who lived on the street near
kind of what you found from the phone book at the time near Kirkland, correct?
Well, I didn't go to... So the process is really to go to the adjutant general's
listing in government document libraries to find their name and serial number. And when you get the
serial number, you can get their national personnel record center files. And then you can start digging
around and try to find these people. And I found one JRT, which I thought was the right person,
and went to his house. He took the meeting. I was surprised and pulled out a FedEx envelope with
this thing. I'm sure he probably thought I was from the CIA or something. And opened it up,
handed it to him and said, is this you? And he looked at it for a while and looked at the
initials and said, no. Well, I asked him, well, what did you do at Kirkland Air Force Base
on that time? Well, I was sort of a psychological counselor or officer. I mean, he basically sort
of hemmed and hawed about what he did. But nevertheless, the other private investigator
found the kids of EWL, I have to look at my notes, but wife or daughter. I think it was the wife.
And apparently he had passed away, was buried. I think he was buried in Florida.
We have a grave marker. And we got platitudes. But once you hire private investigators there,
they can do things that I just find very uncomfortable. They'll just lie to your
face all the time. They'll lead you on. They'll squeeze information on all these methods that
you know, I just don't have the skills to do. And so I found that very interesting process.
So we did our best to find that. But I would say the smoking gun there is that,
yay, there's two initials are correct. And they were on the base perimeter road addresses.
And that was just like, whoo, boy, that's a really good hallmark for authenticity
that it was real. And, you know, I know you mentioned John Alexander and his comments.
Maybe you want to set that up and I'll respond. Some of you may be familiar with Colonel John
B. Alexander, a former US Army colonel whose name has been deeply entwined with ufology and
government psionic programs like remote viewing. Not only has Alexander made some outward comments
on the MJ-12. Okay, we haven't got time to cover all that. MJ-12 was real, had absolutely nothing
to do with UFOs. And if you understand what it was designed for, it was the right kind of people.
You don't have to make explanations as how certain people got in. But the people who did know, I mean,
I just, in fact, what the thing was, at one time I had got rumors of the program. And it was one
time that I went to Subalpine and said, what about this thing? And he says, we're not going to discuss
that. And it was super, super secret and parts of it still are and need to stay that way.
In his book, UFOs, Myths, Conspiracies, and Reality, Alexander claimed Dr. Bob Wood told
Alexander he believed the Psalm 101 manual to have been created in 1954 with the expressed
intention to be leaked to Soviet spies as part of a disinformation campaign. The intent would be to
get the Soviets to commit resources to UAP crash recoveries. Well, what does Ryan have to say?
Yeah, I mean, I wish I knew what he's up to. I guess I've known John for many, many years
and so has my father. And he's always wanted to push the envelope and try to squeeze information
out of people or trade information. So he has, I mean, he was in Vietnam. He was a
special forces colonel operating in Cambodia illegally, you know, maybe on orders, maybe not.
So he's had a long history of trying to skirt the edge of legitimacy, in my opinion.
And, you know, why did he say this, that it's Russian Soviet, you know, spycraft? I think it
was to curry favor with somebody else because it just makes no sense. I mean, there's why would
you expose the fact that you've got alien technology that is going to write Patterson
Air Force Base and Area 51 S4, and you've got bodies and parts and the whole retrieval program.
And why do so much and then leak it? Why wouldn't you just, you know, you could
put it with one of your assets in the Soviet Union and leak it in a much more
more responsible, less visible way? And so from a psychological warfare point of view, or
or PsyOP, it just, it doesn't work. It's like you're exposing too much information. There's
no need to create such a fancy document with such high credibility to
to try to scare the Soviets. They have their own crashes. No ET's are real. I mean, or China,
they penetrated the Manhattan Project, you know, within a year
to get the atomic bomb. And I'm sure that they were right on top of the whole, you know, UFO,
crash UFO thing. So it doesn't really make much sense in my mind. And the same thing is true
with the entire swath of majestic documents, is that why in the world would you try to do
something over 19 years with so many documents of so many different different quality aspects?
Some are really just photocopies, other original documents. So it just,
if you're trying to scare the living daylights out of some, you know, foreign intelligence agency,
it's probably better to do something else. With all this talk of the SOM 101, let's spend some
time authenticating the document and spend some time analyzing arguments against the document.
Now, there is a witness, Navy Yeoman Dale Bailey, who alleges he saw the SOM 101 manual when he was
assisting in the destruction of classified UFO material for an admiral in 1976. Mr. Wood is
currently in the process of locating files on this witness from his father's archive, so I may have
some testimony from this individual soon. Within the words of the document, the Woods have noticed
many minute details that speak to the manual's authenticity. These include the mention of craft
tape when discussing packaging NHI materials, not duct tape, which is accurate to 1954 shipping
methods, as well as some spelling mechanisms, such as screwdriver being two words, which was customary
in 1954. The capitalization of first aid, which was changed to lowercase in the late 50s. The
abbreviation of New Mexico as N.MEX, not N.M, which was altered for zip codes, as well as the solo
typo in the document in the word desiccant. And there is, of course, the point we touched
on earlier, the raising of the letter Z, which indicated the usage of a hot lead press. Many
detractors to the document like to point to the cover page and usage of variable fonts and drop
shadow font, but we can find other Army field manuals from this time period using the same
styling. Odd fonts had also been used in various documents, like this October 24, 1952 memo
initiating the NSA under the Truman administration. Blocked epistemology has theorized the usage of
fonts was actually experiments done by Dr. Vannevar Bush, who actually experimented with fonts,
such as pictured here in a popular mechanics magazine, where we can see Bush operating a novel
phototype setting machine out of EG&G in 1950. Bush even led the design of the cryptographic
machinery used by the NSA's predecessor, OP20-G. Skeptics of the memo additionally like to point
out a restricted classification on the memo's cover page and how the memo cannot be both top
secret and restricted, since restricted classification falls below confidential and top secret.
This is a misunderstood point. According to the 1947 Atomic Energy Act, information on atomic
energy is born classified even if not created by USG elements. In situations such as these,
restricted data is not a level of classification. A document containing restricted data can also be
classified as secret or top secret. The SOM-1 was also written during the time that the restricted
classification level was phased out of USG to confidential, so we can find articles during this
time about an extended changeover period due to some issues. Additionally, skeptics point out the
fact that Area 51-S4, as highlighted in the classification table, did not exist in 1954,
and this is a very important point to address. Yeah, well, and we found a newspaper article in
51, basically contractors are pissed off that there was this huge government contract awarded
to a competitor for hundreds of millions of dollars for concrete out in Area 51,
and they're fighting back and forth in the newspaper in 51.
And the other thing is it was Groom Lake. There was a mine, the Groom Lake mine,
which was a borax mine there already that could have been exploited to be enhanced
for an underground facility as well. That could still be researched further to find out from
the mining department and the historical records of, well, how big was this underground borax mine?
How many millions of square feet is it or was it? Where precisely is it? So you could dig further to
provide further evidence there, but yeah, clearly it was started in 51, and I'm sure started small.
I strongly recommend reading Jan Aldrich's 1996 criticism of the special operations manual.
Aldrich's primary criticisms of the manual revolve around what it doesn't include,
such as instructions to tell recovery teams to set up a grid, photograph the scene, and tag each
item for future reference. Aldrich also criticizes the use of downed satellites,
which in 1954 was before the time of Sputnik. The use of the word satellite has been utilized
commonly during this time period in literature to discuss space debris. I find much of his
criticisms to be fluff, such as problems with interchanging the phrases MJ-12, Magic-12,
and Majestic-12 throughout the document, and can't help but to feel that Aldrich cherry-picked
his arguments surrounding what is not instructed of the recovery teams. However,
I do think his criticisms are important to understand when reading the document.
If you want to read more, Ryan and Dr. Bob have a massive section on their website,
specialoperationsmanual.com, authenticating the Psalm 101. I highly recommend reading this for
more of a deep dive into authenticating the manual. The article explores more into the
provenance of the document, including analyzing the anonymous store in Wisconsin where the film
was mailed. With all of this discussion around the Psalm 101, I found it important to touch on
the legitimacy of other majestic documents, especially those that have been found in avenues
such as the National Archives. Ryan had many more to reference. There was the Cutler Twining memo.
This is Bob Cutler, Robert Cutler to the National Security Council, and it says NSC MJ-12 Special
Studies Group in 1954. It doesn't say Majestic, but it says MJ-12 Special Studies Group. It's
original onion skin. It's in the Library of Congress Manuscript Division in downtown Washington.
There's other documents too. There's one at College Park in Maryland from the Joint
Intelligence Objectives Agency, which is part of paperclip that says CIA MJ-12 on the bottom
of a memo for Project Paperclip, Project 63, I think. Anyway, there's a couple of examples,
and then there's acknowledgement, as I mentioned earlier, that the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit
exists as well. It's not like there's no evidence from the National Archives, let alone
all the other stuff, all the other UFOs, Project Sign, Project Grudge, and all that research.
Of course, with Ross Coldheart's new reality check program, interest in JFK and the majestic
documents is at an all-time high, and I was super keen to explore this avenue.
I think it's in the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit, one where they say that Kennedy was given
some information or believed to have gotten information from somebody in Congress
while he was, before he was elected president. So Kennedy was aware of it according to the
documents of this topic and its importance. There's also National Security Action Memorandums
like a week before he's assassinated, where he says to James Webb, the head of NASA,
I want you to share with the Russians the knowns and the unknowns. And by implication,
that means open the kimono and tell the Soviets all about UFOs, and lots of reasons why Kennedy
would be assassinated. But here's another one reason, is that you might have told the truth or
pushed harder on cooperation with the Soviets. I mean, particularly after his Bay of Pigs
showdown, he didn't want that to happen again. The connection with JFK and MJ-12 does not stop
here. Within the majestic documents lies a retyped NSA intercept of JFK's hotline,
talking to the premier about the UFO situation and national security implications.
JFK is also mentioned within another set of documents Wood considers to have the highest
authenticity rating, the burned memo. In June of 1999, UFO researcher Tim Cooper received an
anonymous letter from a source claiming to be a CIA counterintelligence officer, with documents
that would connect MJ-12 to JFK's murder. The source commended Cooper on his decision to have
worked with Dr. Bob on the majestic files. The files included by the source claim to have been
some of the last surviving paper MJ-12 documents, after a special classified executive order from
Nixon ordered all MJ-12 documents to be destroyed and moved onto computers. The burned memo was
allegedly snatched from a fire before being destroyed and is unlike most documents' original
paper. This memo is from MJ-1, aka the Director of Central Intelligence. The memo is directed to
MJ's 2-7, in reference to Project Majestic in Jehovah, Averro, Parasite, and Parheleon.
As you must know, Lancer, codeword for JFK, has made some inquiries regarding our activities which
we cannot allow. We can also find a 1961 document allegedly sent by JFK to the Director of the CIA
requesting an update on the psychological warfare plans related to the Majestic-12.
And here is a very interesting additional point. In 2023, President Biden ordered some documents
from the JFK investigation be released. One name of note within these documents was CIA agent Ruben
Efron, who was intercepting Lee Harvey Oswald's mail in the months before his assassination.
I do find it a bit strange. The October 15, 1955 Central Intelligence bulletin listed operative
Ruben Efron, as well as three other USG or US military personnel, as witnessing disc-like UFOs
when traveling via train in the Caspian Sea. There are hundreds of Majestic documents,
and the Woods have implemented a really quality scale to gauge the authenticity of these documents.
So of course, with so many documents from so many sources over so many years,
I was encouraged to ask Mr. Wood if there were any documents he suspects are forgeries.
At this point, I don't have any information that any document that's listed on the website
is fake. I have no credible evidence that it's genuinely faked. I mean, so to fake something,
you have to have really, what's the specific, why did you fake it? Did you launch it against
a specific target in intelligence? Are you trying to mess with the UFO community? Why bother?
The general attitude of the intelligence community of the people that control this secret
is to ignore everything and provide no additional confirmation or evidence. They just try to manage
leaks and discredit people. So that's the methodology for managing leaks. So I would
say at this time, I have no evidence that anything has been faked. Now I've got lots of documents
where you can't do anything more. Like the Aquarius document that came out in the Carter,
was allegedly signed by Carter. Yeah, I wanted to bring that up. That was brought forth by UFO
researcher Lee Graham, the Aquarius document package. Can you talk about that and describe
it a little bit along with kind of your feelings on it? Yeah, I mean, it's sort of
fluff in my mind. I mean, it's informed fluff, but there's nothing to check. There's not enough
specifics to validate or check anything. And it just seems odd that a document like this would be
devoid of specifics. Maybe they wanted to ensure that there weren't any specifics that were
checkable. But that's the part that's troubling. And you can't check it, so you don't know what to
do with it. So that's why it's in, as Stan Friedman calls the gray basket, or I call the
neutral basket, where I need more evidence to push it down or up. As we know, the majestic
documents were leaked during the 1984 to 1999 era. This time was post Robertson panel and
Condon committee where public interest in UFOs were at a relative low. Only behind the scenes
in the 70s were researchers like Leonard Stringfield doing serious research on crash
retrievals. With the majority of the documents dating back to the 40s and 50s, I asked Mr. Wood
why he thought the leaks occurred when they did. But it was really about
Vannevar Bush writing to Eisenhower saying, you know, we have all these celestial gifts
from crashed UFOs, and, and we really ought to do something about it. And he said,
be quiet, go win the war, and come back to me later. And when Roswell happened, they actually
pushed at it and started this organization. So who leaked it and why? Well, again, there's
multiple sources, and we don't really know, but we know that there was two film drops in
84 and 94. Those may have been the same people, but maybe not two different people.
The certain method of delivery in an undeveloped film was the same. And then there was several
mailings from Sacramento, California. There was several mailbox drops,
some physically put in Tim Cooper's mailbox without postage. It's like somebody went into the mail
room where I was a member of the post office and put it in his mailbox, or cracked his code at the
top and stuck it in. And then there was some mailings, for example, from the post office,
some mailings, for example, from the Freedom of Information Act office at Fort Meade, Maryland,
that came physically mailed the Encyclopedia of Flying Saucers, which is original onion skin.
And then there was a couple of different documents that were, they had this dash one and dash two in
the upper corner on every page. And ultimately, Thomas Cantwheel wrote a letter at the time of
his death or near the time of his death to Tim Cooper. It basically said,
Dear Tim, by the time you get this letter reaches you, I will left this world. So he's dying of
cancer. And he goes on to describe his relationship with Stringfield and Friedman
and intelligence contacts at Fort Meade, Maryland, Roswell, and then has a sketch of a craft
that, you know, he sort of drew as the Roswell craft. And then we also had another
letter from Salina, which is allegedly the daughter of
Thomas Cantwell or Cantwheel, which is a pseudonym, you know, it's not his real name.
Right. So, but he worked allegedly at the Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit and probably
was an OSS officer in that timeframe. And, you know, you don't know what he died of other than
cancer. But so that's sort of the broad brush of the sources of materials.
And there's so many names. I mean, on the majesticdocuments.com website, there's a,
you dig around, there's a personnel- The master list, right?
Master personnel data list. And I'd urge everybody to file off your Freedom of
Information Act requests to the CIA and the NSA and the Air Force and Air Force Office of Special
Investigations and try to dig up more information and more FBI files on those people and individuals
or go to the National Archives. So there's loads of research to be done. It's just,
you got to pay people to do it. This is the limited bandwidth. Everybody in ufology sort of
has this, you know, peak of enthusiasm and then it wanes and then you sort of have the trough
disillusionment. And then if you keep going, you keep learning more, it's a complicated world.
The mention of Cantwheel, sometimes mistaken as Cantwell here, gives us a great opportunity
to analyze what we know about the majestic document leaks and their sources. There are
three major sources of document leaks. One, Cantwheel, who supplied much of the material
we've covered today to Tim Cooper, such as the IPU Report and Field Order, Hillencoder Magic Memo,
First Annual Report, and the JFK to Director of the CIA Documents. Selena, the alleged daughter
of Cantwheel, supplied Cooper with 10 short memos alongside documents like the twining
White Hot Report, Eisenhower to Oppenheimer Memo, and Directive from Twining to Truman.
And lastly, we have Source One, who supplied the burn memo we spoke about earlier. In his letter
to Cooper, Thomas Cantwheel took ownership for many of the mailbox majestic document drops
starting in 1992. Timothy Cooper investigated Mr. Cantwheel and legally bound his findings in a
five-page affidavit distributed to Stanton Friedman and Dr. Bob Wood that can be found
on MajesticDocuments.com. Information obtained by Cooper and shared with Stanton and Bob include
claims of Cantwheel's background. Cantwheel himself stated to be part of the, quote,
Counter Intelligence Corps, CIC, Scientific and Technical Branch Interplanetary Phenomenon Unit
from 1942 to 1958. According to Cantwell, he served in the CIC until 1980 and worked for CIA
covert operations in the 60s and had contacts with the FBI, KGB, and GRU. He claimed to have
retired as Lieutenant Colonel and been involved with the Majestic Community, MAJCOM, and the
super-secret 5412 Group, end quote. Well-respected Reddit user HarryIsWhiteHot has spearheaded an
investigation into identifying this mysterious Cantwheel, so credit for his amazing work.
Harry has proposed the idea for why CIA operative Boris Dmitry Tarasov is the man behind the
enigmatic Thomas Cantwheel. Tarasov's CIA career spanned between 1956 and 1968 after
immigrating to the U.S. from Russia, where his Russian language abilities proved invaluable to
U.S. intelligence agencies. His U.S. Army records from the Counter Intelligence Corps ranged from
1942 to 1945, where Tarasov then left the CIC to work for the Red Cross in Cleveland, Ohio.
Harry wisely points out, this Red Cross work likely is a cover story for work on the
IPU, stationed out of Wright Field, which is located in northern Ohio near Cleveland.
Wright Field also housed the Army Air Materiel Command, where General Nathan Twining,
alleged Majestic 12 member, was stationed. It's worth mentioning during his time at the American
National Red Cross, Tarasov was employed for building maintenance engineering under a social
agency. One must ask why a counterintelligence operator tasked with, quote, detailed composition
of the foreign armies and their intelligence services approach and interrogation of the enemy
military personnel and civilian detection and prevention of the acts of sabotage, end quote,
would leave for a social agency four years into their career before rejoining the CIA.
Interesting connection here as well. In Cooper's description of Cantwheel,
he states while Cantwheel was part of the CIA and CIC, he interrogated agents in West Germany.
We can see on Tarasov's official record in 1945, the agent attended the advanced CIC school
in Oberurself, Germany, where he was tasked with, quote, extracting the necessary information from
the enemy population, military, and members of the Nazi party, end quote. In his analysis
of Cantwheel, Cooper also states Cantwheel served as U.S. Army intelligence in Washington,
D.C. from 42 to 45. What we can find, Tarasov attended the Military Intelligence Training Center
and performed CIC work at Camp Richey, Maryland, a mere 70 miles from D.C. in the year of 1945.
At the time of Cooper sharing his investigation with Friedman and Wood, he believed Cantwheel
to be living in California and to be in his 90s. We can find no obituary for Tarasov,
but at the time of this personal history statement titled CIA Historical Review Program
Released as Sanitized, released in 1998, just two years removed from Cooper's investigation,
Tarasov was indeed living in San Leandro, California. Born in 1908, this would have
made Tarasov 88 at the time of Cooper's investigation if he was still alive when
Cooper received his letter. This rabbit hole goes much deeper, with Tarasov being stationed in 1963
as a translator operations officer in Mexico City, transcribing and translating some agency
surveillance traffic from communist-aligned embassies and other specific targets. Tasarov's
work was used as evidence to prove that Lee Harvey Oswald visited Soviet compounds,
so of course Tasarov's work dovetails into the JFK assassination. I personally have my own theory
on the concentration of these documents, as we see the majority of information collected on the
Majestic 12 as a snapshot in time in the 40s and 50s. I draw your attention to the 1954 Atomic
Energy Agreement as mentioned in the 2024 and 2025 Schumer legislation, which states NHI craft,
materials, and bodies, as well as UAP and legacy program information, were hushed away as trans
classified foreign nuclear materials. I find it interesting after the SOM 101, which was released
in 1954, most majestic documents dated after 54 contain nowhere near the detail on program operations,
scope, and purpose. Perhaps the 54 AEC agreement oversaw a drastic shift in MJ-12 records.
I relayed this theory to Mr. Wood, and he shared the same sentiment.
That's absolutely true. I think that's when it sort of happened. And that's maybe why we got the
special operations manual, is that the Air Force officers that were responsible for this basically
got the rug pulled out of them, said, no, no, you guys don't get to do this anymore. It's going
someplace else. And people were pissed. And this guy took it and decided at some point he was going
to leak it. Mr. Wood and myself circled back to the personnel list I touched on earlier in the video
with some of the original members named in the MJ-12. I asked Mr. Wood about names associated
with the majestic 12 that have been overlooked or forgotten about. Yeah, I mean, it's in the
White Hot Report, it's mentioned that it was really Forrestal and Bush that came together and
said we need to form this top secret research and development intelligence gathering organization.
And I think it's also mentioned right there on the front couple pages of the special operations
manual, the history of the group, where it talks about special classified presidential order,
and James V. Forrestal and Vannevar Bush formed the group or recommended to the president to do
that. Now, Forrestal, you know, he had a little bit of a drinking problem and he was very much
of the attitude that we need to be more open and potentially discuss this with more people.
I don't know if he was all the way to go public, but he was thrown out the 75th, well, thrown out
the top floor of Bethesda Mays Naval Hospital or fell out the floor or something.
Defenestrated, as they say, although I don't think it was windows, it was
bars. But anyway, he lost his life over that. And actually, in one of the majestic documents,
it says it's even necessary and regrettable that Forrestal had to lose his life.
And in my book, Magic Eyes Only, there's a dedication to those that have lost their lives
for the sake of UFO secrecy. And Forrestal is clearly one person that he lost his life for that
sake of secrecy. So outside of Bush and Forrestal, are there any kind of names that you think as you
were talking about how the majestic documents in the master list needs further investigation?
Are there any names that you think are absolutely crucial to study and have kind of been looked
over and forgotten about? Yeah, I think so. There's the White Hot Report,
which is, you know, it's basically this is the group that went to Roswell and did a bunch of
analysis and worked all over the summer to create this report in September. So it happened in July
and everybody went crazy and investigated and wrote up this report and presented it to the
president and others. And there's the members of the mission. You know, there's people like
Captain Charles Buchanan. Who the hell is he? I still haven't found him. And what's his military
personnel record file like? Or Robert Ginsburg, Colonel Robert Ginsburg or Captain Richard Glass
or, I mean, Carl Hummelsine is a big, well-known person. Major General Stephen Chamberlain,
Assistant Chief of Staff for Intelligence. He was certainly a known, you know, Major George
McDonald. That was his Chamberlain's boss. He was, you know, he was like the Chief of Staff of the
Air Force. Admiral Paul Lee, he's very well known. Leslie Groves, head of the Manhattan Project. He
had all his team members there. James Lay Jr. Thomas Lynch, which is the finance guy in the
Treasury Department. So they had, you know, they got Navy and Air Force and finance people and
as well as, you know, Von Karman and Oppenheimer and Doolittle, James Doolittle and Professor
Einstein. So there's loads and that's just one document where you could dig into the next level.
You could write a whole book on just that one document and all the interconnections and the
validations of every single sentence and every single linkage between people and their
correspondence. It's a huge amount of work. I mean, I'd love to give somebody, here's 50 grand.
I want you to go write a whole book on this one topic and go spend a year researching.
And as I mentioned before, we really do observe the Majestic 12 as a snapshot in time. Myself
and I'm sure every viewer of this video wonders about the evolution of the alleged group,
how they operate today, and if in 2024 there is still a group known as the Majestic 12.
So the documents sort of in the history point of view are stop in the mid 50s or so with the
fifth annual report on Majestic. And I suspect that it's probably still has the same name.
It's such a rare club, you know, to lose that history and change the name seems silly,
but they could do it. And there's probably certainly a lot of subclassifications
and different groups that are focused on hardware or bodies. Those are obvious
bifurcations of classification. But then probably within each of those, there's probably additional
classifications to compartmentalize it and get into buckets where they could potentially work
with private corporations or other organizations. But in my mind, it's the Aerospace Corporation
and the Carlisle Group and EG&G and some of the historical ones. I mean, Rand, for example,
up to their eyeballs in this stuff. And there's probably a lot of them that have done research
historically. We have heard so much from Ryan about his involvement with the Majestic 12,
but another key player is his father, Dr. Robert Wood. Why did Dr. Bob, a rocket scientist,
get involved with UFOs in the Majestic documents? It was maybe 1967 or so, 1967, where he started
reading a bunch of UFO books and convinced his management that, are we going to figure out how
the UFOs work before or after Lockheed does? And they said, well, how much money you want to try
to work on that bomb? And so he spent internal R&D Douglas Aircraft Company money and then
the merger happened to McDonnell Douglas. But so for a couple of years, they spent the equivalent
of four and a half million dollars working on gravity experiments, theory, being interviewed
abductees. I mean, I remember as a little boy, 13, 14, going out to the Mojave Desert.
One of his engineers was out there with a magnetometer and strip chart recorders and
they had anomalous events and sleeping on this couch in this high heat in the desert. And
it was fun for a kid at the time. So that was his work. They didn't have any access to classified
information, but that was the start of his deep interest in UFOs. And actually he hired
Stan Friedman to work for him and look at the nuclear physics aspect of UFO propulsion.
Viewers of my channel will remember Project Moondust, an official group proposed in 1961
by the U.S. Air Force alongside projects Blue Fly and UFO. Moondust was tasked to
locate, recover, and deliver descended foreign space vehicles. Moondust's counterpart,
Blue Fly, served to facilitate expeditious delivery to foreign technology division of
Moondust or other items of great technological intelligence interest."
In my video on Moondust, we covered a variety of fascinating cases occurring in Nepal,
Afghanistan, Canada, and a 1965 case in the Congo with an accompanying memo titled Fragment Metal
recovered in the Republic of the Congo, origin believed to be an unidentified flying object.
Moondust does indeed have connections to the majestic documents in a fascinating
original document called the Bowen Manuscript. Moondust is definitely a recovery organization.
I mean it's space junk primarily, but occasionally it's down saucers. And so if there's some obvious
evidence that it's a saucer, they may have a different team that goes. But the Moondust people
were very much involved. And so that's logical that they would do that. I guess I wanted to
bring up one final thought for you is that many people say, oh, these are all photocopies.
And I guess I just wanted to highlight, you know, one of the leaked ones,
well, sent from Ford Meade from Freedom of Information Act office was this one,
Top Secret Magic. This is original onion skin paper that we've done forensic analysis on.
And for ink and pencil marks, and it has comments by Vannevar Bush, and it has hints of we have
anti-gravity craft in the 1960s. The Encyclopedia of Flying Saucers, the Bowen Manuscript,
and actually there's a book that it's on Amazon called The Encyclopedia of Flying Saucers by
Vernon Bowen who wrote it. And it's very well done history of UFO cases from 1960 and before.
So that's when he typed it, sent it into the Air Force, and never got it back until
39 years later. Wow. And the document has comments from Vannevar Bush. Yeah, it's like there's
comments in marginalia and in pen and ink marks like, you know, what is Don Menzel doing? Question
mark in relation to these comments in the topic. And then another one was in relation to could
these craft be our manmade, you know, experimental vehicles? And handwritten on the side in ink is
this should not get out, implying in my mind that there are deep concerns that we've got gravity
control craft. And so that's juicy. My research and my father's research on the majestic documents
is rich and robust and highly supportive of their authenticity and credibility. And I welcome
objections to it. And if you have some it's fake because statement or I don't like it because
I'm all ears. But I've not found any credible objections. All right. Thank you so much, Mr.
Wood. Thank you. What's up, guys? Thank you so much for joining me into this investigation
and documentary on the majestic 12 and majestic documents. Before I get into my usual ramblings
at the end of every video, I need to say a couple things. One, thank you, Mr. Ryan S. Wood. Thank
you for sitting down with me doing this interview, answering hours of questions and emails in the
majestic documents, the majestic 12, me requesting additional files, me requesting images and so
forth. This man is truly of incredible character and I am so thankful one of my biggest inspirations
in the field of ufology agreed to sit down with me and cover the majestic documents. For anybody
who has watched a single one of my videos, you know I reference this book Magic Eyes Only as the
greatest book I have ever read on UFO crash retrievals by Ryan S. Wood. I highly encourage
anybody to purchase this book because it also covers much of the majestic 12, including the
authenticating of the special operations manual. It also includes a full copy of the special
operations manual. Third, Ryan S. Wood has a beautiful tool I don't see referenced much.
This is a website called ufodex, u-f-o-d-e-x.com. What this is, Ryan S. Wood trained a chat GPT
model and scanned in between 500 and 800 UFO books. You can submit a question on any topic in
ufology and receive an answer from Mr. Wood. I myself have used this tool dozens of times
and I've used it in a lot of my past research, such as referencing the 1974 Koyamae case,
discussing a certain private corporation I'm going to cover soon, and I even asked it about
underwater bases that NHI might inhabit after reading and hearing about some parts of Lou
Elizondo's new statements. So, thank you Mr. Wood. Please get a copy of Magic Eyes Only. Please
go to majesticdocuments.com where you can read all 33 or 35 of the reports I reference today in depth.
Of course, with YouTube video descriptions, it's a little too tough to include all links,
especially when I have between 50 and 60 research files. So, you'll look in the video description,
you will see every document we covered today, which is over 30, you'll find the exact name.
Go to majesticdocuments.com, punch that in, copy and paste it, review the document while watching
the video. I think that's really important. When we're discussing a document, you can have it on
another monitor on part of your screen, kind of read through what we're going through. You know
me, I like to cite my work, so all of these documents will be available for you to read
super easily. Okay, on to my ramblings. The Majestic 12 has consumed my life for the past
couple of weeks to the point where I have not even touched this. And this is going to be my next
reading. I cannot wait to dive in, but I highly recommend anybody get the Magic Eyes Only book
and the book I referenced multiple times in the video, Top Secret Magic by Stanton Friedman.
If you want to learn more into the authentication of the Eisenhower briefing document, Cutler Twining
Memo, Truman Forrestal Memo, this is the book for you. It was written in the 90s, but this is a
beautiful piece that's so useful to investigate more into what we've been talking about today.
Stanton Friedman is a legend amongst Ryan Wood, Robert Wood, so please check out this book if you
want to learn more. It's fantastic. So now we can get on to some of my thoughts. Anybody who's
watched my videos knows more and more over time I've been referencing the Majestic documents.
A perfect example is my last video, the 1974 Koyama crash retrieval. I referenced the first
annual Majestic report as well as the IPU report. Before that, in my 1955 crash video near Del Rio,
Texas, I referenced the Eisenhower briefing document and the 1950 crash listed there,
also touched on by Lou Elizondo to have occurred near El Indio in Guerrero.
I made some statements public that I thought that the Majestic 12 was likely a real organization
and the Majestic files had probably been a mix of information and disinformation.
At that time, I had not spent the amount of time I have now pouring through the documents,
looking at connections, looking at research, and just immersing myself in so much time.
I think the Majestic 12 encompasses so much more than what I initially suspected.
What really took me by surprise was the amount of length behind authenticating the Eisenhower
briefing document and special operations manual. Those, of course, are two of the big heavy hitters
we talk about in this video. But towards the end of the video, you'll remember the Bowen manuscript
and you'll remember how the author, Bowen, I can't remember his first name, sent this in to the
Department of Defense in 1960 to get it reviewed. He never got a copy back. It wasn't until 1999
Timothy Cooper got this from a FOIA designation, Fort Meade, with comments all over it from Vannevar
Bush and Stamp Top Secret Magic. Now, of course, we discussed how this referenced Moon Dust,
that Vannevar Bush made comments on anti-gravity vehicles, but this, the discussion of Moon Dust
and insect-like beans reminded me so much of Dr. Saurbacher. And of course, I discussed that video,
Dr. Saurbacher, multiple times, but we have to remember that within the majestic files,
one, if not the key player, is Dr. Vannevar Bush. Of course, the beginning of the majestic leaks
occurred in 1980, but the thing is we can trace Dr. Robert Saurbacher discussing Vannevar Bush
directing UFO study in the U.S. government as far back as 1950, around the time of the alleged
MJ-12 connection. So, I never thought the Saurbacher connections would go so deep here.
Remember, Dr. Saurbacher, even when talking to Stanton Freeman, name dropped Dr. Eric Walker.
Dr. Eric Walker himself confirmed to know of the MJ-12's existence, to say it's real, along with a
really interesting quote that reminded me of Don Quixote, Chasing at Windmills. Perhaps what he
meant by this is you might have the majestic documents, because I believe this interview
came out in the mid to late 80s. As we didn't have all the majestic documents, I think that
he may have meant you might have these majestic documents, you may be able to read them, but you
will never get to the bottom of it. It's futile to try and fully grasp the extent of the majestic
files. And speaking of Dr. Eric Walker, what really interests me thinking about now is how
his claims about an ESP getting into the program and so forth. So, that was just fascinating to me,
the connections with Saurbacher, because remember Saurbacher described insect-like
beings as well in the Encyclopedia of Flying Saucers. Vannevar Bush underlining these subjects
is so fascinating. And let's not forget, at the end of the 14-page sample provided on Majestic
Documents.com, there's a section talking about Mussolini and Hitler being exposed to some sort
of craft in 1942. Vannevar Bush underlines this as well, almost underlines a whole paragraph.
This brings my mind back to the 1933 Magenta Italy case. Anybody else? It's just, it's really
fascinating. Some of the other documents that really interest me of course are the IPU report,
nine pages talks about the Sandia lab technicians, talks about the crew at Roswell. So much of these
documents kind of focus around Roswell, right? I think there's so much more work to be done on
the JFK assassination in MJ-12, so much more work to be done on Forrestal's death in the MJ-12,
because that's very interesting. I think many people think of a conspiracy around Forrestal's
death as well, throwing himself out the 13th story of a naval hospital room. So there's so
much more work to be done there, and there's so much more work to be done on the Majestic
Documents in general, right? As Mr. Wood has said, much of these documents, as he likes to say,
are onion skin where we have original copies. In fact, I'd say that's the minority of the reports.
Many of them are facts from Tri-X film, photocopies and so forth. So there's some
provenance work that can't be done on these documents, like Mr. Wood has done with the Bowen
manuscript, actually dating the ink back to 1962 of when Vannevar Bush wrote Moondust on the paper.
So I think if we look at the Majestic-12, we can't argue for the validity of all of these documents,
but I think it is a safe line of research to kind of understand the Majestic-12 likely was and
possibly is a real group tasked with the study, material exploitation, and reverse engineering
and crash retrieval of UFOs. How that looks today, I would reckon it involves much more of a private
sector. As beautiful as it is with the Saarbacher video, we get to see a snapshot of the early days
of UFO crash retrieval, and I think the Majestic documents are the perfect example of really
investigating the early days, the early players, the early organization, and the early procedures
of UFO crash retrieval. But anyway, guys, remember Magic Eyes only and top secret magic. Check them
out. MajesticDocuments.com. For the astute of you and my MMA fans, you will see this large signed
Alexander Volkanovsky poster from his knockout of Yair Rodriguez in the third round of UFC 290.
My wonderful girlfriend got me this piece for an early birthday present. It's not my birthday for
months, but I think she knows I'm such a huge Alexander Volkanovsky fan. She had to get this
for me, and that is the best gift I've ever had. So, of course, I changed the camera a little bit,
as you see, so you can get that in full view. Coming down the line, we got a lot of great
projects, guys. I know this one took a little time. I really wanted to get this right. This
video was so important. So, guys, please get yourself a copy of Magic Eyes only. Check out
MajesticDocuments.com and let me know in the comments what you think of the majestic documents
and how your opinion changed before and after this video. Please remember to like and subscribe,
guys. And remember, I got a Patreon. I'm not charging or paywalling extra content. Only support
what you think the channel is worth. And I thank everybody so much for their time watching an hour
and probably 40 minute video at this time. So, thank you guys very much and I will catch you
on the next video. Bye.