So here is your list, I'm not going to go through 145 sites, some of them are black sites, some of them are bases you know about like Wright-Patterson, Edwards, Nellis, Area 51 so called, but all of them are based on witness testimony and intelligence we've gathered over the last 30 years, and it's time for it to be disclosed.
Recently in 2024, Stephen Greer and The Disclosure Project released their entire catalogue of documents, communication logs, drawings, and other files. Love him or hate him, over the years Greer has provided valuable witnesses a platform to speak, and wrote in my opinion a truly fantastic piece of work, his 2001 disclosure briefing document, so while I have my problems with Greer, this document archive absolutely commands my attention.
Greer's list of UFO whistleblowers and witnesses features over 700 names, many of which are redacted. Here we find names we all expect, Michael Herrera, the late Dr. Robert Wood, Richard Doty, Robert Salas, Jonathan Wagan, even Bob Lazar, but we also find 22 pages of redacted names, some of these names are described simply as points of contact to others, but some have descriptions that might be well worth our attention.
Viewers of my channel may remember UFO Witness's redacted list, in which I derived the names and contacted two of these witnesses from poorly redacted documents uploaded by Greer. One such witness MS agreed to interview on UFO testing occurring at Dugway Proving Grounds, while the other witness TB was much more shadowy.
Today we cover the redacted entry that has captivated my attention and commanded my research for months on end. A witness I have been more than eager to cover, as I believe this witness's alleged first-hand experiences with UFO reverse engineering offer crucial insights into DOD and defense contractor involvement with UFO programs.
And before we get started guys, full disclaimer, I have been able to ascertain this individual's identity and have tried to contact him through myriad methods. Should he ever respond and be willing to go public, I will go to any lengths to speak with him.
But for operational security and his family's safety, I will not burn witness 11-063's identity. I have also attempted to encourage this individual to testify before Congress or contact the Senate Intelligence Committee.
For this project, I will only be using publicly available sources, no classified or hidden information will be disclosed in this video. And I would like to say, I have thoroughly vetted this individual through public online resources and can confirm his Air Force station at Nellis Air Force Base, Edwards Air Force Base, and the Pentagon.
As well as various positions within the U.S. Air Force as stated by Greer.
I first took note of witness 11-063, who I will further refer to as Ed, when Dr. Greer released his witness list. This astonishing entry reads, quote, Career Air Force Nellis Edwards, test director of Electronics Warfare Group, tested reverse engineer technology, was at the Pentagon DOE.
Unlike MSTB and myriad other witnesses, no communications or files existed on Ed at the initial release of the DPI archive files. It wasn't until late summer of 2024 that the Disclosure Project Intelligence Archive updated an additional section of documents, intelligence briefing modules, the DPI archive files, and the DPI archive files.
It was in these intelligence briefing modules that we would get our first leads on Ed. Within this section, we find Module 3 under UFO crash retrievals titled, quote, Covert Government Retrieval and Handling ET Vehicles, end quote.
In summary, we find some fascinating information adapted from a March 2024 oral presentation from Greer. Not only does Greer discuss 130-plus instances of NHI objects being downed and retrieved, involving major defense contractors such as Lockheed Martin, Skunk Works, and Boeing, but these operations are conducted using advanced electro-gravitic technologies and electromagnetic pulse EMP weapons.
I do highly recommend reading through the entirety of this module as it invokes the quality of the 2001 Disclosure Briefing Document and also makes mention of Witness MS and Richard Foch, a formal Naval Research Labs senior scientist who discussed large, silent, triangular alien reproduction vehicles over remote areas of dugway-proving grounds.
Towards the end of Module 3, we see our first discussion of Ed outside the witness list, quote,
Having left the Air Force in 2009, the Lieutenant Colonel was extensively briefed on operations not just at Edwards but also at Nellis and Area 51. He believes that since the operations he was involved in were illegal, he is free to discuss them publicly and is ready to disclose everything he knows in an open hearing under oath, end quote.
It was around the time of the upload of this module Greer finally uploaded two documents under Witness 11-063.
First, let's analyze what I would consider to be the less impactful of the two documents on Ed to understand his background and motives for contacting Greer in late 2023.
In presumably an internal Disclosure Project email, an unknown individual emailed Greer stating Witness Ed had been following Greer's work for some time and wished to answer Greer's call for whistleblowers.
This DPI employee states Ed served in USAAF from 1999 to his early retirement in 2015, where he ended his career.
According to the email, Ed additionally came from an engineering background, worked with the Department of Energy, and served at the Pentagon for seven years.
The email accurately breaks down Ed's service record, three years at Nellis Air Force Base, Nevada, three years at Hanscom Air Force Base, Massachusetts, and five years at Edwards Air Force Base, California.
In 2006, Ed was sent to Edwards AFB for the base's test pilot school.
It was here Ed would claim pilots at the Air Force Base are trained for unacknowledged special access programs using reverse engineered non-human technology.
Side note, Edwards is well known for its prolific and prestigious test pilot school.
This highly selective program trains pilots, navigators, and engineers on experimental flight platforms.
Originating from the Air Force Material Command's 412th test wing, the test pilot school's mission is to, quote,
conduct full-spectrum tests and evaluations of aerospace weapons, and to be the world's premier educational and training center for theoretical and applied flight test engineering, end quote.
An additional point, the test pilot school originated out of Wright-Patterson Air Force Base during World War II.
During his time at Edwards, after graduating the USAAF's highly selective test pilot school,
Ed would serve as the head of an electronic warfare group that tested NHI reverse engineered technology.
In this role, Ed claimed to serve as the intermediary between engineers who had direct reporting to him and test pilots when, quote,
they had a manned craft they were testing, end quote.
Interesting to point out here, according to the email, Ed agrees with Dr. Greer's stance on free energy systems from direct first-hand involvement in various projects.
A little bit of context here, since the late 90s, early 2000s, Greer has highlighted issues of suppressed technologies and systems levied from the reverse engineering of off-world technologies.
These technologies are famously referred to as zero-point energy systems.
To quote the 2001 disclosure document, quote,
Zero-point energy systems essentially generate energy by tapping into the ever-present quantum vacuum energy state,
the baseline energy from which all energy and matter is fluxing.
All matter and energy is supported by this baseline energy state and it can be tapped through unique electromagnetic circuits and configurations
to generate huge amounts of energy from spacetime all around us.
These are not perpetual motion machines, nor do they violate the laws of thermodynamics.
They merely tap an ambient energy field all around us to generate energy, end quote.
Zero-point and free energy systems are not the topic of today's video, so I recommend reading The Hunt for Zero-point by author Nick Cook,
Jesse Michael's video Aerospace Secret Search for Anti-Gravity, or even Greer's 2023 documentary The Lost Century and How to Reclaim It.
And it is interesting and worth noting that this internal disclosure project email states Ed is in complete agreement with Greer's stance on free energy.
Ed isn't the only witness to comment on zero-point systems either.
Take redacted entry 10747 for example, who is stated to be an ex-chairman and VP of a well-known corporation.
I have high conviction this company is General Electric.
According to Greer, 10747 has, quote,
Huge details and testimony regarding free energy and the military-industrial complex cover-up, slash, suppression of these technologies.
No several people killed and scared to death, end quote.
Towards the end of our witness testimony internal email, mention is made Ed had been tracking current legislation relating to legacy program member Amnesty,
and would be willing to testify to Arrow as long as Kirkpatrick was removed from the organization because, according to Ed,
the good doctor, quote, is an insider and is meant to squash information, end quote.
This is indeed a very charged statement and one I am sure many UFO investigators will agree with based off the actions of Sean Kirkpatrick.
And the way you combat conspiracy theories and the associated misunderstandings that fuel them is in fact in science and truth.
So if you've got evidence for a conspiracy, then that helps to investigate what the underlying truth is.
There has been none that has been substantiated for this.
And everything that has been brought to our attention and everything that was brought to my attention when I was in that position as the director,
we investigated and discovered that it did not come from where they thought it came from.
Most everything was explainable through other documentation, other programs, other people that had talked to other people.
It goes without saying Dr. K has very little goodwill with the public.
Like the lies and half-hearted debunks in the Arrow Historical Report Volume 1 or Arrow's 2022 contracts with Sandcorp, a company built to plug whistleblower leaks.
I have even made an entire video on Sean Kirkpatrick and his disinformation,
which is at this point somewhat outdated as it covered little of Kirkpatrick's role as an unpaid consultant after leaving Arrow.
So let's briefly cover a new revelation that supports Ed's accusations of the doctor injecting misinformation into the public.
Well, in a recent U.S. Space Command FOIA release by Twitter user tag underscore om,
we can find a January 2023 meeting scheduled by Dr. Kirkpatrick involving U.S. Spacecom and senior U.S. Joint Command staff.
The purpose of this meeting was, quote, UAP response and recovery and material transfer, end quote.
The witness testimony document gives us a brief overview of Ed, his background and motives,
but our next document is where our true research can begin.
This two-page set of notes roughly covers a phone conversation between Dr. Greer and Ed on November 25th, 2023.
Not only do these notes describe Ed's testimony in depth,
but also break down his military career by year and station.
The document is absolutely worth going through line by line.
Off the bat, Ed asked Greer if he has threatened legal action against Lockheed and Boeing,
as Ed was read into programs overlapping these two companies.
At the beginning of his Air Force career, Ed did indeed work with Lockheed as a range technical contractor in the early 2000s at Nellis Air Force Base,
along with some other smaller specialized contractors.
However, there is no mention of Boeing to the best of my knowledge in his work history.
Publicly, we can find myriad projects and current job openings for work between Lockheed and Nellis Air Force Base,
but there are a few of extreme interest here.
Check out this Lockheed Martin case study titled, The Importance of Intelligence, Surveillance and Reconnaissance,
in which the contractor was tasked with updating the system used by USAAF Warfare Center for Intelligence, Collection and Processing.
Lockheed Martin reconfigured a two-phase security classification system used by the National Geospatial Intelligence System,
yes, the same agency Crush was a part of when liaison to the UAP Task Force,
and the same agency recently mentioned by respected journalist Chris Sharpe as participating in undersea UAP crash retrievals.
The system was implemented to Combined Air and Space Operations Center at Nellis Air Force Base,
which is tasked with processing information for exploitation of time-sensitive targets.
I can't help but speculate here.
Although this Lockheed project arose from challenges in the Nellis Red Flag Advanced Aerial Combat Training Exercise,
could such systems be used to monitor UAP and UAP crash retrievals?
The idea Ed was right into UAP programs at Nellis Air Force Base as a First Lieutenant from 1999 to 2002
can possibly be reinforced later in the notes where Greer states Ed was briefed at Area 51 S4,
where quote, a major said they had caught slash captured lots of aircraft, end quote.
This small point will later become even more interesting as we learn that Area 51 Groom Lake Facility
is administered by a detachment from Edwards Air Force Base, California,
the base where Ed would transfer to and conduct the bulk of his first-hand work around UAP programs.
Ed states this briefing was conducted via a 30-minute video which showed inspection aircraft that were essentially invisible.
Inspection craft, what exactly does this mean?
Is Ed referring to crash retrievals or possibly alien reproduction vehicles, ARVs, for inspection use only?
This reminds me closely of the story of Mark McCandlish, whose close friend Brad Sorensen allegedly saw three ARVs
titled flux liners that were available for cleared personnel to inspect,
with paneling removed to highlight hardware of the craft.
The line these craft were essentially invisible further supports this thesis,
as I have covered first-hand witnesses before that have discussed ARV craft with cloaking mechanisms,
craft that look identical to the flux liner highlighted by McCandlish.
In an interesting detail, according to Sorensen and McCandlish,
these ARVs were shown at Norton Air Force Base, a mere 80 miles from Edwards Air Force Base.
If you're unfamiliar with the testimony of Mark McCandlish, have no fear, I will cover it soon,
as I believe it is one of the most impactful testimonies in all of ufology.
Greer goes on to state that at Nellis Air Force Base, Nevada, Ed worked at building 200,
under the redacted name of the first commander of the 98th Range Wing.
Now, let's break this down.
The 98th Range Wing, now called the Nevada Test and Training Range, began operations in 2001,
and serves as the primary military training area for the Nellis Air Force Base complex.
To quote Yousaf,
The NTTR is the largest contiguous air and ground space available for peacetime military operations in the free world.
The range occupies 2.9 million acres of land, 5,000 square miles of airspace,
which is restricted from civilian air traffic overflight.
The Nevada Test and Training Range NTTR provides the warfighter a flexible, realistic, and multi-dimensional battle space
to conduct testing tactics development and advanced training in support of U.S. national interests
while also conducting Department of Energy testing, research, and development.
The NTTR coordinates operational and support matters with major commands, other services, DOE,
and Department of Interior, as well as other federal, state, and local government agencies.
The NTTR acts as the single point of contact for range customers.
Analyzing the NTTR and its mission to create, operate, and maintain live and synthetic environments
and integrate partners to optimize warfighter capabilities,
this location sounds like an ideal choice for DOD and USG elements alongside contractors to test reverse-engineered technology.
To top it off, the NTTR South Range contains Groom Lake Area 51, a location deeply entwined with ufology.
His time at Building 200 at the NTTR may have seen Ed interact with Boeing, Lockheed Martin,
alongside the DOE, which I mentioned I could find no record of in his resume.
Circling back to the call notes, Greer made specific note to Ed serving under the first commander,
right around 2001, of the 98th Range Wing, or NTTR.
I have tried at length and failed to find the original commander of the 98th,
but I would like to take a long hard look at the commander from 2005 to 2007, Colonel Christopher Have.
I find this analysis necessary, as Ed may have implied the 98th commander has oversight to UAP reverse engineering programs.
Colonel Have spent 26 years in the Air Force linked to key roles in fighter aviation.
His post-service resume is of heavy interest here.
Following the Air Force and its service in the 98th Range Wing,
Have directed global trade controls at Boeing in Washington DC,
handling trade policy and technology licensing within major government departments.
Have additionally led a team at Raytheon Technologies, another defense contractor implicated with UAP study.
Here the Colonel managed relationships with key USG officials,
such as the Office of the Secretary of Defense and other military departments,
aligning Raytheon strategies within government objectives.
The Colonel also served as a special advisor on national security affairs to then Vice President Dick Cheney,
who has seen swirls of rumors recently implicating Cheney as a senior member of UFO programs,
where Have offered insights on foreign defense capabilities.
Have's resume, as well as his role as commander of the 98th Range Wing,
offers us a glimpse at a possible reverse engineering program official.
And speaking of the NTTR, in Greer's notes we can find a simple sentence,
quote, Ed saw man-made craft on the range. Was there quite a bit, end quote.
With strong conviction, we can assume the range in question here is the NTTR.
From this statement, we can also gauge that Ed is claiming Area 51 slash S4
and or Nellis Air Force Base has successful man-made reverse engineered craft.
Greer then comments on Ed being sent to Edwards Air Force Base in California in 2006
for range orientation, where Ed would go on to serve as director of redacted
for an electronic warfare group.
Referencing the witness testimony document, we can assume this director role was a test director
for a technology reverse engineering group.
We can also assume from witness testimony this station followed Ed's service in Edwards Test Pilot School.
What bolsters these claims from Ed is the fact Edwards Electronic Warfare Group stems from the 412th Test Wing,
the exact same wing that houses the Edwards-USAF Test Pilot School.
If Ed's testimony is true, the 412th Test Wing out of Edwards directly deals with the testing of
reverse engineered craft and technology of non-human origin.
This would also mean the 412th Reverse Engineering Program works in conjunction with the Nevada Test and Training Range.
This is one of the biggest takeaways of this entire research project.
If his testimony is true, Ed was briefed on UAP programs at S4 while stationed at Nellis,
where he was then sent to the 412th Test Pilot School and Test Wing to further this work in an Air Force Legacy
UFO program as a test director.
The documents state Ed served at Nellis until 2002 and was then sent to Edwards in 2006.
Where was Ed during this gap?
This period of time 2002-2005 saw Ed stationed at Hanscom Air Force Base near Boston, Massachusetts.
Greer writes that Ed worked with the Massachusetts Institute of Technology while at Hanscom,
working on foreign military assets but only saw terrestrial craft.
This mention of MIT is still of great interest to us.
I have talked before about the involvement of UARC or University Affiliated Research Centers with UAP programs many times.
Most recently with Dr. Eric A. Walker, head of Penn State's UARC, the Applied Research Laboratory,
who admitted he was involved in the Kecksburg UFO crash incident.
Well, MIT has their own UARC operating under the U.S. Army as well,
the Institute for Soldier Nanotechnologies whose goal is to
discover and field technologies that dramatically improve the protection,
survivability, and mission capabilities of the warfighter and of warfighter-supporting platforms and systems.
The only mention I can find of a relation between Hanscom and UAP
is an anonymous letter sent to Leonard Stringfield dated March 14, 1975,
which claimed to recount the testimony of one Colonel Sims, a pseudonym.
According to the letter, both Hanscom and MIT are two of the military bases and research laboratories
that perform UFO operations, alongside Edwards, Wright-Patterson, Carswell, Los Alamos, Sandia, etc.
Okay, so, Ed served at Edwards from 2006 to 2010, where he was allegedly formally
read into multiple quote-unquote advanced aircraft programs at Edwards.
The use of the word formal here is quite interesting, almost like Ed's time at Nellis saw him getting
bits and pieces of program information while his role as test director saw a complete briefing.
This echoes numerous claims that UAP reverse engineering programs are as if not more compartmentalized
than the Manhattan atomic bomb project.
Greer writes in 2008, when director of a redacted program, Ed was part of a Go Public plan via the Air Force.
The plan was called off in 2009 to 2010 and saw Ed move to the Pentagon.
The killing of the program was done by a two-star general.
Now, I have found no confirming evidence of this so-called Go Public plan,
but I have found a series of USAAF two-star generals, aka major generals,
that either retired as major generals or were at the time period of interest that may give us an answer.
One prime suspect is Major General Thomas K. Anderson, who reached the rank of major general in 2009 and retired in 2013.
Anderson's senior role oversaw him serving as commander of the Curtis E. LeMay Center for Doctrine Development and Education.
To quote the Air Force, quote,
The center is responsible for the research, development, and production of Air Force doctrine
and input for joint and multinational doctrine development activities, end quote.
General Anderson oversaw numerous key positions within DoD, such as the Air Staff,
Joint Staff, Combat Command Staffs, NATO, and Chief of Staff and Director of Intelligence for US Strategic Command.
Let us also inspect Major General Eugene Haas, who served as brigadier general during our window 2009-2010,
before being promoted to major general in 2012.
Haas served as vice commander Air Force Special Operations Command from 2009-2011.
Haas additionally acted as director for force structure, requirements, resources, and strategic assessment as a J-8.
Haas commanded my interest due to his extremely prestigious role within DoD and stationed at two Air Force bases
allegedly connected to UAP programs, MacDill Air Force Base and Fort Belvoir, Virginia.
Moving on, I would like to look at Major General Casey D. Blake, who earned his major generalship in 2015
and served as a colonel during Ed's alleged disclosure plan.
Not only did General Blake work as commander to Air Force Installation's contracting agency of Assistant Secretary
of the Air Force for Acquisition at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio,
but his most senior position saw Blake as the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Contracting
under the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Air Force for Acquisition in Washington, D.C.
Here he was responsible for quote, all aspects of contracting relating to the acquisition of weapon systems,
logistics, and operational support for the Air Force and quote, overseen support of $826 billion annually.
Although Blake may have been a colonel during this plan, he piqued my interest as during 2008 he served as director
program acquisitions, defense procurement, and acquisition policy in the Office of the Undersecretary of Defense
for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics for the Pentagon.
There are a total of four other major generals of interest here including C. Donald Alston, H. Brent Blake Senior,
Randy A. Key, but I want to lastly focus on Major General Christopher P. Ozzano.
Ozzano did not earn his major generalship until 2019, meaning during 2009 to 2010,
he is the least likely candidate to have decision-making power over a disclosure campaign, however.
His early career dovetails almost identically with that of Ed and is worth mentioning.
In the year 2000, Ozzano attended USAAF Test Pilot School at, you guessed it, Edwards.
In the early 2010s, the general would command the 412th Operations Group at Edwards,
before serving as the commander of the Air Force Test Center at Edwards.
At his senior station, Ozzano oversaw a $31 billion enterprise comprising of more than 19,000 military, civilian,
and contractor personnel across Edwards, Egland, and Arnold AFBs.
Greer makes special note to Wright-Patterson Air Force Base,
the infamous location we have discussed in almost every single video I have ever done.
According to Ed, Wright-Patterson has a tight connection with Edwards.
Ed even makes an educated guess Wright-Patt's Hangar 6, specifically held by Logix.
According to internal Wright-Patt documents, Hangar 6 was initially,
quote, primarily used by the Signal Corps for installing radios and antennas,
and after the war it became a facility for retrofitting and modifying planes.
The hangar featured several smaller doors instead of a giant hangar door,
which would later be used as the Wright Field Fitness Center.
However, the fitness center is located in Hangar 22, not Hangar 6 at Wright-Patt.
Besides blueprints and images of the exterior,
I can find almost zero internal images, reports, or articles in general on Hangar 6.
This facility will be a priority of my research moving forward,
especially analyzing for infrastructure to support living and or deceased biologics, as Ed has claimed.
From 2010 to 2015, following the failed coming forward plan,
Ed moved to the Pentagon where, according to Greer, he operated within research and development panel chain.
Little was discussed between Greer and Ed on his responsibilities at the Pentagon.
However, one interesting note is recorded, quote,
$34 billion, then $40 billion to non-Air Force authorization, non-Blue TOA, end quote.
TOA meaning Transfer of Authority.
This statement seemingly confirms statements made over the decades by numerous whistleblowers
discussing UAP programs being funded through USAP off-book black operations.
I will draw your attention to December 11, 2017,
where former Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, Catherine Austin-Fitz,
published a paper titled Black Budget of the United States.
Here she discussed $21 trillion found in unauthorized spending
in the Department of Defense and Housing and Urban Development Centers between 1998 and 2015.
Soon after publication, the DOD announced its first ever department-wide independent audit.
Fitz personally believed some unauthorized funding was utilized for domestic clandestine military R&D,
some of which was illegal UAP programs from DOD.
The primary testimony of Ed involves first-hand work on UAP programs
focused on the testing of reverse-engineered non-human technology at Nellis Air Force Base
slash Area 51 S4 and the 412th test group out of Edwards Air Force Base, California.
As we have discussed before, numerous factors, including Ed being briefed at S4
and then sent to the 412th for test pilot school before becoming Director of the Electronic Warfare Group,
where he acted as the intermediary between engineers and test pilots
and the 412th test group had manned craft to test,
we can conclude with high confidence Ed's work revolved primarily around the utilization of NHI tech
to construct and test ARV or alien reproduction vehicles.
Area 51 S4 has been discussed in ufology for decades
and is often immediately associated with the claims of Bob Lazar.
But what about Edwards?
Are there any other stories of UAP programs at the Californian base
that can support or detract from Ed's claims?
Well, for starters, we can go all the way back to 1957
to the testimony of Mercury astronaut Gordon Cooper.
Cooper claimed while stationed as a project manager at Edwards Air Force Base,
a group of photographers assigned to photograph remote positions of the base
observed a large, strange-looking craft above a lake bed.
Cooper's crew began taking films of the craft,
and according to Cooper, the craft was, quote,
hovering above the ground and then it slowly came down
and sat on the lake bed for a few minutes, end quote.
The camera crew estimated the object to be about 30 feet in diameter,
shiny silver in color, and featured three landing gear.
The crew got within 20 yards of the craft before it departed.
Cooper did, in fact, see the film, but stated the evidence was confiscated.
And this is a very brief summary of the story,
as I would love to cover it further in great detail.
Well, I was having some cameramen film the installation of a precision landing facility
that we were putting in right on the edge of the dry lake,
and this saucer flew right over him and put down three little gear
and landed out on the dry lake bed.
And they went out there, picked up their cameras and moved on out toward him filming,
and he lifted off, put the gear back in the well,
climbed out at a very high rate of speed and disappeared.
And so while I was going through all the regulation books
and finding out the number to call and watching them report it,
I had them go over and develop the film.
By the time they got back with the developed film,
I was on the higher and higher and higher level officer talking to me,
finally with the colonel telling me to, you know,
when the film arrived at my desk to put it in the carrier pouch,
there would be a carrier there at my office by that time already,
and they'd arranged for him to fly in our base airplane back to Washington with these films,
and do not run prints, etc., etc., etc.
So we stuck them in the carrier pouch.
Did you watch the film?
We didn't have a chance to run it.
I had a chance to hold it up to the window and look at it.
It was certainly a good film.
Good close-up shots.
In 1972, we can find Project Outgrowth out of the USAAF Rocket Propulsion Lab at Edwards.
A document titled Advanced Propulsion Concepts Project Outgrowth
sees discussion of an anti-gravity program and theoretical material
to change the direction and amplitude of gravitational fields.
Similarly, in 1988, a technical report submitted under contract
with the USAAF Aeronautics Lab out of Edwards
discusses the exploration of the Bifield-Brown effect explored at length by Jesse Michaels,
which allegedly converts electrostatic energy into propulsion.
Around the same year, 1988, Defense Contractor Science Applications International Corporation, SAIC,
a defense contractor I have directly implicated in the study of off-world technologies,
studied similar electronic propulsion mechanisms for Edwards Air Force Base.
We can also look to 1990, where journalist Scott Williams wrote an article in Aviation Week
in which 45 sightings of aircraft accelerating from near-hovering positions to supersonic speeds
were seen over Edwards Air Force Base, George Air Force Base, and China Lake Naval Weapon Center.
One such craft was described as triangular in shape.
But let's not forget the 1998 testimony of USAAF Master Sergeant Edgar Fausch
I have covered numerous times who commented on the infamous TR-3B reverse-engineered triangular craft.
Fausch claimed while working at the Defense Advanced Research Board in 1979
under the Jet Propulsion Laboratory at Edwards,
a full anti-gravity propulsion system was developed and a secret space fleet utilized this technology.
If you haven't yet, please watch my video on Lockheed Martin,
as I discuss the Fausch case in much greater depth,
including his station at the proposed Defense Advanced Research Center.
While discussing the TR-3B craft,
Fausch makes specific mention graduates from the 412th Test Pilot School at Edwards Air Force Base
pilot these reverse-engineered craft.
Many more enigmatic claims without direct evidence exist surrounding Edwards.
The infamous base was mentioned myriad times
within Leonard Stringfield's crash retrieval status reports 1 through 7.
In UFO crash retrievals, The Inner Sanctum, Status Report 6,
Stringfield makes mention of a Dr. Epigoni,
a pseudonym for a physicist who claimed to have worked closely with Oppenheimer, Einstein, and Teller.
Epigoni stated in the late 60s, early 70s he worked on something called Project Heaven,
a special project at Edwards Air Force Base.
The doctor claimed a flying saucer and its crew had previously landed at Edwards.
The craft was kept in a large hanger guarded tightly
whilst occupants were carted off to a secure building for evaluation.
The 12 five-foot tall bodies clad in silvery metal suits featured eyes of one color,
a nose, a mouth, teeth, and blood similar to the appearance of oil.
To quote Epigoni,
They, the U.S. researchers, came to the conclusion that since there was no deterioration,
to leave them alone because another craft might come in the area and rejuvenate or reactivate them.
The craft itself had no rivets, seams, or welding,
and was of a classic saucer design with a dome on top measuring 40 feet in diameter.
Other scientists informed Epigoni craft materials were made of materials they never dreamed could exist
and could not figure out a way to gain entry to the craft.
Epigoni stated as of 1990, Project Blue Heaven was still active,
it was run by the DoD, and the Navy had two to three similar projects.
The doctor's account is far more detailed,
and I promise we will circle back to this testimony in future projects,
but the landing of this craft and seemingly inert bodies reminds me closely of the craft donation theory.
When you say crash retrieval, what do you mean?
These are retrieving, non-human origin, technical vehicles,
call it spacecraft if you will, non-human, exotic origin, vehicles that have either landed or crashed.
We have spacecraft from another species.
We do, yeah.
How many?
Quite a number.
The strangest detail of this testimony is the claim the craft touched down,
the beans walked out of the craft, and laid on the ground.
It's worth noting, and Stringfield commented on this too,
Epigoni changed the body count from 12 to 4.
According to Stringfield and his fellow investigator,
they, quote, agreed that it appeared that he had consulted with his superiors,
and was advised to alter certain key details, end quote.
Also in 1991, Status Report 6, Stringfield recounts his discussions
with a first-hand witness to a UFO crash retrieval 15 miles outside of Edwards in 1971.
According to witness Debbie Clayton,
her and her girlfriend's family investigated a crash from the sky in broad daylight.
Reaching the craft site, Debbie observed an acorn-shaped craft
with an extremely similar description to the Kexberg crash.
Quote, we searched for markings, but found only some old scratches that we could not read.
Because it was upright, we couldn't see the bottom.
There were no windows or seams, appearing to be made from a one-piece mold.
If I remember correctly, it was a dark grayish color with greenish highlights,
not a color one normally sees.
There was a mild heat coming from the craft, somewhat like a car engine after traveling for an hour.
One more thing I thought was strange, there was no dust that clung to the shell.
Here in the desert, dust is everywhere and clings to everything, end quote.
According to Debbie, an Air Force car and truck arrived within 14 minutes
where men with rifles ordered civilians off scene.
Lastly, I want to cover an excerpt Michael Schrat discovered in the files of the late Stringfield,
which may allow us to directly connect Edwards to operating ARV and NHI craft alongside Area 51 S4.
In a letter dated April 5, 1980, one Mr. D. L. Dobbs discussed one M.H.,
a witness identity Schrat chose not to disclose.
M.H. had allegedly performed radio maintenance at the Atomic Proving Ground in Nevada
during 1961 to 1963 along with top secret radio work for USAF.
According to M.H., he participated in a top secret operation at Area 51 titled Project Red Light.
Test flights were conducted on a recovered UFO shipped from none other than Edwards Air Force Base.
The craft was not conventionally powered and stayed silent during operation.
Security was so tight on the project, program personnel were rotated every six months.
M.H. claimed to have heard rumors of a West Coast American defense contractor
encountering difficulties in many of the components comprising the craft.
And lastly guys, I want to cover a possible connection between reverse engineering programs at Edwards and Nellis slash Area 51.
In July of 1991, an alleged classified NRO document leaked to the public.
This document informed need-to-know groups and operations about civilian flying saucer organizations organizing protests in Nevada.
Stephen Greer claimed to have given the document to Admiral Thomas Wilson from the Wilson Davis Memo,
which at the very least we can confirm the meeting between Greer and Wilson.
Allegedly, Wilson told Greer he recognized one of the entities listed and that it was run by a contractor.
Addressed in this document includes Royal Ops, Cosmic Ops, Mag Ops, Magi Ops,
multiple USAP Special Forces Divisions in the 26th, 64th, 65th, 527th, Nellis AFOSI, Groom Lake, and Dreamland Area 51 S4,
AquaTech and SeaSpray Special Operations Group, and one Blackjack team.
According to Dr. Stephen Greer, inside sources including a source inside Blackjack Control told him of two entities,
Blackjack Control and Blackjack Team.
Blackjack Control is allegedly a Nellis-based facility participating in reverse engineering
while Blackjack Team operates in conjunction with Control but is stationed at Edwards Air Force Base.
So, but the key facilities I want to go through, and there are others, this is a list that I've updated,
I updated it for the president in 2009. A very chief one is Edwards Air Force Base,
and there's a whole constellation there, Haystack Butte, China Lakes, George Air Force Base,
they retired Norton Air Force Base, Tabletop Mountain Observatory, which is run ostensibly by NASA,
and Blackjack Control. So I had a source at Blackjack Control associated with the Edwards related facilities,
but the Blackjack Team you saw on that list was Nellis. So there's Blackjack Control and Blackjack Team.
I can find almost nothing publicly available to research on Blackjack besides a late 2010s, early 2020s project
between DARPA, the Defense Advanced Research Project, and defense contractors owned by Raytheon.
Project Blackjack was, quote, intended to develop and demonstrate critical elements of a global high-speed network
in low Earth orbit that satisfied DoD performance and payload requirements at a much lower cost,
with shorter design cycles, and with easier and more frequent technology upgrades, end quote.
Seen as the alleged NRO document dates back to 1991, I doubt these two Blackjacks connect.
What's going on guys, it's UAPGirb, and I'd like to thank each and every single one of you for joining me today
as we took a deep dive into Ed's witness testimony.
Now, I know I discussed this a multitude of times throughout today's video,
but I'd like to reiterate today's thesis once more for a final time.
Analyzing Ed's credible witness testimony, conclusions can be drawn of a joint reverse engineering program
focused on craft of non-human intelligence existing between Edwards Air Force Base, California,
and Nellis Air Force Base, Nevada, slash Area 51 S4.
This program stems out of the 412th test group comprising the Edwards-USAF Test Pilot School
and Edwards 412th Electronics Warfare Group.
Now, this research was some of the most enticing, exciting, and interesting I have done
since working on the Off-World Technologies Division, and I would like to compare these two testimonies.
The Off-World Technologies Division and the technology here focused more on singular pieces of technology
and almost weapons as described by RA.
Now, it was interesting to see the juxtaposition between this Air Force testimony
as the Air Force plants in conjunction with Lockheed Martin Boeing and possibly other contractors
actually work on the piloting and utilization of reverse engineered craft.
Whether these craft are triangular in shape, the classic TR-3B as proposed by Fausch,
or possibly the flux liner classic saucer shape as proposed by Mark McCandalish
that were allegedly housed at Norton Air Force Base 1988, I'm not sure. Perhaps it's both.
But the line that Fausch states that these pilots commanded the reverse engineered TR-3Bs
out of Edwards Air Force Base Pilot Test School jumped out to me after covering him so closely
and so long ago in my Lockheed Martin video.
This research was fascinating. I wish we could find out a little more on Ed's time at the Pentagon.
All we really have to go off there is the $34 billion and then $40 billion missing in transfer of authorization funds,
off-book funds. This can possibly support Greer's and other people's thesis that many of these programs
are funded through black budget operations.
I know that this program at Edwards, Edwards is a very populous base, so if this reverse engineering program
is indeed real, this must be kept to an exclusively small number of personnel in an exclusively small area.
Who knows? Perhaps Edwards is connected to underground facilities in this region.
I know Greer likes to say that the Ant Hill facility he posted a picture of recently
in the Hellendale facility, our dumb location, so possibly this is a kind of a connected area in which craft are stored.
After hearing Ed's testimony, what do you guys think? I would like nothing more than to speak to Ed firsthand
and hear all this information from himself, but unfortunately he has gone off books.
There is no way to contact this individual, whether by phone, social media, or email, and believe me, I have tried.
So, if Greer is right and this individual has testified revealing information he knows,
this testimony is indeed impactful beyond belief, but has he or is that one of Greer's embellishments? We don't know.
I'd like more than anything to see this individual, Ed, before the Senate Intelligence Committee or at November's open hearings.
Who knows? Maybe we'll be surprised to do so.
But let me know what you guys think about this alleged reverse engineering program at Edwards Air Force Base and Nellis Air Force Base Area 51.
Again, if anybody has any other further research to let me know about this, I would love to know.
I know that I drew a conclusion, I decided not to keep it in the video, about the Air Force Plant 42 near Palmdale sightings of Leight and Edwards.
These two facilities are only about 30 miles apart, which, you know, very interesting.
I think Edwards and Norton are also only about 80 miles apart, so this whole complex is deeply entwined to both UFO sightings and testimonies of reverse engineering programs.
I was also thrilled to be able to dive into the work of Leonard Stringfield and others to look at some more occasions.
I know we researched the Debbie Clayton acorn-shaped craft 15 miles outside of Edwards that was immediately swarmed by Yusuf Khrou within 15 minutes.
And the testimony of Dr. Epigoni, that one is very interesting, relating to the craft donation theory.
If you don't know what that is, certain individuals like David Grush have discussed that some retrievals of UAP are not crash retrievals.
These craft are just found left unattended.
This story reminded closely of the alleged 1957 Holloman Air Force Base landing in which a flying saucer touched down at Holloman Air Force Base
and occupants walked out of the craft to interact with Yusuf personnel.
In Epigoni's case, these beings walked out of the craft and laid down on the ground and seemingly turned themselves off,
which could possibly attest to the theory of biological robots, essentially, as many people like to call the grays.
There will be further research that needs to be done on Blackjack Team and Blackjack Control.
This just rang a note in my head from that 1991 alleged NRO document, but more research needs to be done here.
Thus far, I can find no connections between DARPA, really.
But this, to me, is the jumping off point of researching Yusuf legacy and contractor reverse engineering programs,
possibly housed at contractor sites, possibly housed at Air Force Base locations.
So let me know what you guys think. I really appreciate everybody joining me today.
Please remember to like and subscribe, share these videos around.
I got a Patreon if you want to join. I don't charge for any extra content. I don't gatekeep content.
All of my research is free for anybody to consume.
I only have the Patreon if you want to support what you think the channel's worth.
But guys, I have some awesome upcoming other projects on ARVs or alien reproduction vehicles,
including a deep dive on Mark McCandlish, which I hope to do soon.
I know that's been highly requested and I cannot wait to do so.
So without further ado, guys, I want to thank you all again for joining me.
And very soon we'll be back up with another show.
So thank you very much, guys, and I'll catch you all later. Bye.