The propulsion of these UFOs is unique, their ability to hover, their ability to accelerate
very rapidly, their ability to move at very high speeds, very much higher than anything
that we have achieved even with our supersonic aircraft.
All of these things, and particularly interestingly without sonic booms and the things that we
don't like about our supersonic aircraft, all of these things indicate a type of propulsion
which is unique, different than anything we know anything about, and which would be a
tremendous value if we could develop it and use it.
That's the reason I feel with a number of others who have studied it, that it is a subject
which deserves the highest type of scientific study and at an early date.
The advantages to be gained are perfectly enormous.
And how long do you feel it will be before we are flying in UFOs?
Well, this probably is a $64 question without a question of a doubt.
I think it depends a great deal on how rapidly we take them seriously and how soon we really
set up a scientific study team to work on the subject.
This is where we push the laws of physics.
You see, the technology we make is what makes the impossible possible.
And it doesn't stop there.
So far on this channel, we have devoted entire investigations towards Battelle Memorial Institute
and their possible work on shaped memory alloys recovered from the 1947 Roswell, New Mexico
crash, as well as Lockheed Martin and their intimate decades-long involvement in UFO legacy
programs.
After all, high-profile U.S. defense contractors have for decades been accused of actively
engaging in material exploitation and reverse engineering programs, focused on technologies
of unknown origin in conjunction with various factions within U.S. government, intelligence,
and military.
Overall, you know, the government has been the custodian of a lot of this, right?
And they'll hand receded out to a clear defense contractor to do some analysis, which I find
highly unethical.
You have basically a sole source arrangement, and you allow certain private corporate elements
to look at this, develop a potential insight, and then sell it back to the government for
profit.
And I think that's totally unethical.
Lockheed Martin and others do quite a bit of work, both in our atmosphere, in space,
and even underwater.
There are certain efforts to...
It's a tough question, you guys.
I left the Air Force and was sent out to California at that time to begin establishing my cover
basis for an independent, as an independent contractor, so that I could serve what was
coming down the line next for me.
And that is the path which led to the UAP subject.
These claims are not without merit, as since the inception of the U.S. military-industrial
complex, private defense industry has worked in tandem with military and intelligence to
bolster U.S. military might, protected by waived, unacknowledged special access programs.
I have directly accused Lockheed Martin, Battelle, Boeing, SAIC, and many other private institutions
and semi-private institutions, such as UARCs and FFRDCs, possessing, experimenting with,
and possibly successfully harnessing non-human technologies.
Today we focus our sights towards the U.S. aerospace and defense colossus and father
of the B-2 stealth bomber, Northrop Grumman.
Often overshadowed by the infamy of Lockheed and their involvement in the 2008 failed attempt
to divest recovered NHI materials to the OSAP program, Northrop Grumman has largely successfully
distanced itself from the spotlight of defense contractors engaging with UAP legacy programs.
In fact, focused discussion on the alien reproduction vehicle, Fluxliner, as relayed
by Brad Sorensen and the TR-3B reverse-engineered triangle discussed by USAF Master Sergeant
Edgar Fouchet, seemed to primarily focus on Lockheed.
These testimonies highlight the defense contractor successfully reverse-engineering non-human
craft to operate under human control.
But throughout such disclosures, Lockheed isn't the sole contractor accused of such
highly classified efforts.
Hardly mentioned, but always alongside in the shadows, is Northrop Grumman.
Could Northrop Grumman truly be involved in material exploitation of technologies of unknown
origin TUOs?
Just how far does their involvement with UFO studies go?
Join me today as we peer into the shadows to find out.
Hey guys, it's UAP Grubb and thank you so much for joining me as we touch back to UFOs
in the private sector, this time to Northrop Grumman.
The contractor I believe alongside Lockheed is the Paramount Aerospace Corporation entrenched
in UFO legacy programs.
From whistleblower testimony to analysis of Northrop's numerous acquisitions over
the decades, let's thoroughly dive into the legendary Northrop Grumman and their involvement
in UFO legacy programs.
Let's start by analyzing the history of Northrop and its many, many, many acquisitions
over the decades.
Northrop Grumman is an American aerospace and defense company employing over 95,000
employees with an annual revenue of $30 billion.
The industry giant has achieved extraordinary engineering feats such as aiding in the development
of the James Webb Space Telescope and directly creating the B-2 Spirit Bomber and B-21 Raider,
the world's only known stealth bombers.
Northrop Grumman operates in four major divisions, aeronautics, defense, space, and mission systems.
Outside of military, aircraft, space systems, and weapon development, Northrop also engages
in cybersecurity, information technology, and radar and sensor systems.
Briefly, I do take an extreme interest in Northrop's C4ISR, Command Control Communications
Computers Intelligence Surveillance and Reconnaissance, which falls under Northrop's land-based
critical technology services, sustainment, and modernization.
C4ISR is essentially the military's nervous system consisting of various electronic equipment
and technologies serving to aid the modern warfighter through data and intelligence.
I am currently working on a thesis that select contractors' C4ISR programs engage in deep-sixed
waved USAPs for crash retrieval and ARV testing, data, and analysis.
Let me explain.
Northrop was one of the premier contractors operating C4ISR for the Strategic Defense
Initiative instituted under Reagan in 1983.
Northrop created the first laser radar used in space for SDI.
I have discussed numerous times lines of research which state SDI focused on Soviet ICBM nuclear
defense, secretly studied and employed offensive capabilities against UAP, and siphoned program
funds to UAP legacy programs such as the DARS, Defense Advanced Research Center proposed
to exist in an ARPA document.
SAIC, Science Applications International Corporation, frequently secures massive hundreds
of million-dollar contracts for C4ISR at the Naval Surface Warfare Center crane.
I have published extensive research SAIC runs an off-world technologies division to house
recovered NHA artifacts at the crane naval location.
When discussing witness Ed in the existence of a joint ARV testing program out of Edwards
Air Force Base in Area 51 under the Edwards 412 test group, I made reference to a Lockheed-Martin
ISR case study.
In this study, Lockheed was tasked with updating the system used by USAAF Warfare Center for
Intelligence Collection and Data Processing.
Lockheed reconfigured a two-phase security classification system used by the National
Geospatial Intelligence Agency.
Yes, the same agency GRUSH was a part of when liaison to the UAP task force and the same
agency recently mentioned by respected journalist Chris Sharpe as participating in undersea
UAP crash retrievals.
The system was implemented to the Combined Air and Space Operations Center at Nellis
Air Force Base, which is tasked with processing information for exploitation of time-sensitive
targets.
At the time I speculated, although this Lockheed project arose from challenges in the Nellis
Red Flag Advanced Aerial Combat Training exercise, could such systems be used to monitor
UAP and UAP crash retrievals?
Although C4ISR is common and the nervous system of the armed forces, I do think analyzing
Defense Corporation C4ISR contracts and projects with USAAF Army and Navy can lead to knocking
on the door of UAP program operations.
And after that long discussion, finally back to the history of Northrop Grumman, NG arose
from the merging of two military aircraft companies, the Grumman Aircraft Engineering
Company and the Northrop Company in 1994.
Throughout its storied history, Northrop made a few very key acquisitions we will continue
to reference over and over and over again throughout this project.
One such acquisition occurred in 1999 with procurement of Teledyne Ryan, developer of
surveillance systems at Unmanned Aircraft.
In 2002, Northrop Grumman acquired TRW Inc., a corporation involved in aerospace, electronics
and the automotive industries.
Outside of computers, systems engineering, integrated circuits, TRW was a true trailblazer
in spacecraft construction, building Pioneer 1, 10 and numerous space-based observatories.
The defense giant considered TRW its quote-unquote capstone acquisition, signaling the end to
Northrop Grumman's aggressive purchasing streak.
Why was TRW considered the crown jewel of Northrop's purchases?
Well there is evidence to suggest this was due to TRW operating a portfolio of UAP legacy
programs upon purchase.
I think the investigation must be done to discover the UFO program portfolio Northrop
may have inherited from TRW.
TRW has long been associated with a rumored crash retrieval program run out of Wright
Patterson Air Force Base, a topic even touched on by Luella Zondo in his book, Imminent.
And let's mention that in June of 1960, TRW spawned the Aerospace Corporation.
The Aerospace Corporation has additionally been implicated in UFO legacy programs and
served as a place for employment for OSAP physicist and member of the Wilson Davis meeting,
Dr. Eric Davis.
I would additionally like to draw attention to the year the Aerospace Corporation was
founded in 1960 and relate this founding to the testimony of Lieutenant Colonel Philip
J. Corso.
Corso stated 1958-1962 oversaw the golden age of U.S. Army R&D where Army assets, universities,
laboratories, and private industry were leveraged to reverse engineer non-human technology
to bolster the U.S. war machine.
Analyzing Army primers from around this time highlight a period of massive innovation in
Army research and development.
The MITRE Corporation was born during this time in 1959 with lines of research to suggest
its formation was to engage in such research and development projects alongside Bell Labs,
Sperry Rand, etc.
The Aerospace Corporation founded just one year post-MITRE, maybe one additional corporation
spawned from TRW for U.S. Army legacy operations.
And worthy to note, both MITRE and the Aerospace Corporation are both known as FFRDCs, Federally
Funded Research and Development Centers.
Present day, the Aerospace Corporation manages the Aerospace FFRDC for the Department of
Defense and Air Force to support, quote, national security space programs, end quote.
We are truly the only space enterprise that exists in the United States.
And I mean this at the agency level in the government, the FFRDCs, and private industry.
There is no other organization that does national security space, civil and commercial, and
international as well, that ties these all together with both the breadth and the depth
that we bring to this problem.
I have spoken at length about FFRDCs, semi-private institutions that play a crucial hand in UAP
legacy programs.
I recommend any of my previous four investigations to hear more on the subject.
It is intriguing Dr. Eric Davis of the Wilson Davis Memo all but admitted the Aerospace
Corporation built from TRW is actively involved in UAP legacy programs.
And that up to that point, TRW had been a primary contractor in such UFO programs.
So all this talk about private contractors, you know, the big Lockheed Martin, what about
federally funded research and development centers such as MITRE, RAND, Triad, Oak Ridge,
and UARCs, University Affiliated Research Centers, where do they fall into this?
Only one, and I won't name it, started out as a contractor in the 1960s, starting not
too long after it was born, it was actually a spinoff of TRW.
So TRW was the principal investigator for the first roughly, what, almost 30, yeah,
practically 29 years.
Before we keep discussing TRW, let's highlight a former U.S. premier electronics manufacturer
implicated in TUO exploitation by Lieutenant Colonel Corso with possible ties to MITRE
and the Aerospace Corporation.
This being the company I just mentioned above, the Sperry RAND Corporation.
In his manuscript, Corso would reference the personal memoirs of Lieutenant General Arthur
Trudeau, chief of U.S. Army R&D and founder of the Army's Foreign Technology Division,
and how Trudeau would engage in frequent meetings with Sperry RAND's board, including legendary
General Douglas MacArthur.
Sperry RAND went defunct in 1986, and its former divisions became part of Lockheed Martin,
Raytheon, Honeywell, and you guessed it, Northrop Grumman, all companies implicated in UFO
legacy programs.
But let's get back to TRW.
TRW features some familiar faces of this channel many will recognize.
Remember if you will, Dr. Eric Walker, the scientist named by physicist Dr. Robert Sarbacher
as participating in UFO crash retrieval meetings alongside Vannevar Bush in the 1950s.
Walker started Penn State's University-affiliated research center, self-admitted he knew about
the Majestic 12 and was present at the 1965 Kexburg, Pennsylvania UFO crash.
I have always talked about how Walker is one of the most crucial names in UFO crash retrieval
and reverse engineering programs in the 1950s and 1960s.
Much intrigues me about Walker, including his position as former chairman of TRW.
TRW has also been discussed at length by respected researchers such as Richard Dolan as the primary
contractor running a crash retrieval program under the project name Zodiac.
Project Zodiac, an MJ-12-like entity, is not our subject today, however we may discuss
it soon as the story of Zodiac by pseudonym Sej Masters is utterly captivating.
And with TRW, we may just have a paper trail to connect them and Northrop to legacy operations.
In 2004, former Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, Catherine Austin-Fitz
wrote a paper called The Black Budget of the United States.
This paper stated a large portion of the nation's wealth had ongoingly been illegally diverted
into secret, unaccountable channels to support clandestine military research and development,
some to a majority of which had been suggested to be UAP-related.
While at the HUD department, Fitz came across information various high-profile defense
accounting systems were responsible for scrubbing and obfuscating the direction of these funds.
Although in 1990 federal law mandated every single U.S. government agency be audited,
the Pentagon never publicly faced a comprehensive audit until one was launched in December of
2017.
And not to mention since, the Pentagon has never passed an audit.
And this 2017 audit may have happened solely due to another Catherine Austin-Fitz university
paper detailing $21 trillion in unauthorized spending in the DOD and Department of Housing
and Urban Development from 1998 to 2015.
In the Wilson Davis memo, which I have talked about so many times, Admiral Thomas Wilson
relays to Dr. Eric Davis, the Watch Committee, the gatekeepers of the UAP legacy program
portfolio, told Wilson they are organized after an audit in the 1990s almost blew their
cover.
What this means is essentially a failed audit led to UAP programs being reorganized under
the Special Access Program Oversight Committee Senior Review Group.
Here is where we circle back.
In 2003, Northrop Grumman settled a lawsuit from the U.S. government for $111 million,
almost $200 million today.
This settlement was due to Northrop subsidiary TRW overcharging for government work done
on space projects in the early 1990s.
This suggests TRW's inflated space project contracts were implicated and uncovered in
the failed audit mentioned in the Wilson Davis memo that took place in the 1990s.
Timelines indeed match up, as the beginning roots of this lawsuit can be traced back to
1994.
TRW's likely involvement with UAP legacy waived unacknowledged special access programs
appeared as contract overcharging to the wider DoD auditing officials, leading to the lawsuit
against TRW settled by Northrop utterly fascinating.
If this hypothesis is accurate, Northrop settled the suit and reorganized their UAP portfolio
under the SAPOC Senior Review Group program reorganization that was relayed to Wilson.
To make Northrop's purchase of TRW even more interesting, shortly before Northrop
bought TRW in 2002, TRW had purchased BDM, Braddock Dunn & McDonald in 1997.
BDM was a technical services firm that headquartered at Fort Bliss, Texas, White Sands Missile
Range, New Mexico, and Holloman Air Force Base, New Mexico.
BDM specialized in and worked primarily with missile guidance, application optics, electronic
instrumentation, and radiation physics.
BDM was also founded in 1959, around the same time as MITRE and the Aerospace Corporation.
BDM was mentioned specifically by Commander Will Miller of the Wilson Davis Memo in the
year 2000.
The former U.S. Navy commander stated numerous government individuals such as Defense Intelligence
Agency directors, who in this case would have been Vice Admiral Thomas Wilson, were isolated
from UAP knowledge.
The quote-unquote keepers of the secrets resided in DoD middle management and civilian contractors
like Boeing, Lockheed, and BDM.
To learn more about Miller and why his words carry weight, I highly recommend watching
my video on the Wilson Davis Memo, sure it's my first video and it's very amateurish
but there's still some good information there.
BDM could warrant its own video, but for now, I leave you with this.
Just like FFRDC's, I have talked ad nauseum of Major General Albert Stubblebine and how
his department, U.S. Army InSCOM, and their previous special forces unit, the Intelligence
Support Activity, have been historically involved with UAP crash retrieval.
In 1984, Stubblebine was replaced as head of InSCOM and went on to serve as vice president
for BDM.
The following year in 1985, BDM would host an advanced theoretical physics conference
to discuss UFO reverse engineering opportunities.
And actually, let's not stop there with BDM.
In 1989, NASA mission specialist Bob Eshler was introduced to retired Rear Admiral Sumner
Shapiro from Bobby Ray Inman.
Inman was then board member of SAIC and Wackenhut, and former NSA director and CIA deputy director.
I have reason to believe Inman engaged with UAP programs in each of these four positions,
but that is not our topic for today.
Shapiro told Eshler factions within the U.S. possess extraterrestrial vehicles and that
he had even studied one at close quarters.
According to Shapiro, teams would take apart craft, pack them up, and ship them across
the country to different locations.
These craft featured unique interlocking components that had to be dissembled in an exact sequence
to be put back together.
Rear Admiral Shapiro was not only former director of Naval Intelligence, but also BDM international
board member at the time, 1989.
To this day, Northrop Grumman maintains a major corporate presence in Tyson Corner near
the former BDM headquarters.
All of this commentary on TRW, Teledyne Ryan, which we will get to shortly, and BDM serve
to highlight how Northrop Grumman and its many acquisitions interweave intimately, with
numerous cases we have covered on this channel.
If the claims of Philip J. Corso are indeed true, Northrop's modern-day legacy program
operations can likely trace its roots back to the U.S. Army's golden age of research
and development in 1958 to 1962.
This would also mean many of Northrop Corporation and Northrop Grumman's acquisitions were
to purchase companies that had active, ongoing UFO legacy programs.
This sort of context is crucial to establish before we explore whistleblower claims of
Northrop's operations in these programs.
And last thing before we continue, many individuals think of Lockheed Skunk Works division when
they picture UFO reverse engineering and material exploitation programs in the private sector.
Well in 1992, Northrop created its own quote-unquote answer to Skunk Works.
Northrop created the N.A.T.D.C., Northrop Advanced Technology and Design Center, to
focus on the company's core key defense programs.
While we have already discussed many of N.G.'s acquisitions and their ties to UFO legacy
programs from the 1960s to 1990s, let's back up and trace mentions and claims surrounding
specifically the Northrop Corporation and later Northrop Grumman.
I often think back to the words of U.S. Army Colonel and advisor to U.S. Army Futures
Command, Carl Nell, who once stated,
Non-human intelligence exists.
Non-human intelligence has been interacting with humanity.
This interaction is not new and it's been ongoing.
And there are unelected people in the government that are aware of that.
And so, Carl, that is quite a bold statement.
I'm wondering, and I'm curious, how confident are you that that is true?
There's zero doubt.
Nell has served as an outspoken advocate for David Grush and the existence of technologies
of unknown origin.
One has to wonder if this absence of doubt arose from Nell's position as Deputy CTO
and Director of Systems Engineering and Integration for 13 years on Northrop Grumman.
After all, while serving as Northrop's Deputy CTO, Nell was additionally serving as Command
Representative to U.S. CENTCOM for Army Foreign Material Program.
Northrop's earliest contributions to legacy programs may trace back to 1968.
M.S. Kahn and G.M. Andrew of Northrop Noir Air published a paper on the electro-aerodynamics
in supersonic flow, suggesting Northrop was researching methods to reduce drag of an aircraft
by creating an electrostatic field around the craft.
This may remind some of T. Townsend Brown and Electrogravitics.
In Nick Cooke's excellent book, The Hunt for Zero Point, one Dan Marcus is mentioned,
a pseudonym for a source in the British aerospace industry.
Marcus relayed to Cooke that in 2002, the Pentagon pulled the specific paper and, quote,
made it disappear, end quote.
Marcus would suggest the B-2 Spirit bomber applied these concepts to employ an electrostatic
field around the aircraft to reduce drag.
In fact, some UFO researchers such as Michael Schrapp and Dr. Richard Boylan take this a
step further, suggesting the B-2 employs reverse-engineered possibly electro-gravitic technology, leading
to the massive cost of the systems.
The question is, and Mark talked about this before, is there more going on to the B-2
than meets the eye?
The 18-week space technology, March 9, 1992, had a very interesting article from people
who worked at Northrop who were very upset that the technology associated with the B-2
program was not being trickled down to the public industry.
They talk about how the B-2 electrically charges the leading edge of the wing to reduce the
radar cross-signature.
That's what you see in this diagram right here.
And then negatively charges the exhaust gases to reduce the infrared signature.
This is the same type of electro-gravitic technology that T. Townsend Brown had originally
proposed in the 1930s.
So this technology might date back a lot earlier than we originally thought.
The first true mention of Northrop engaging with NHI technology comes from the work of
UFO researcher William Hamilton.
Hamilton's book, Cosmic Top Secret, is, in my opinion, the most underappreciated book
in all of ufology.
It is a truly excellent piece, decades ahead of its time.
For example, the 1992 book makes the first recorded mention to the term ARV and discussion
of the flux liner, which wouldn't rise to fame until Stephen Greer's 2001 Disclosure
Project event.
Mind you, Hamilton did misquote the ARV acronym, stating alien replicated vehicle instead of
alien reproduction vehicle.
However, my research has shown Hamilton spoke to Bill Scott of Aviation Week in Space Technology
to discuss the Brad Sorensen flux liner testimony in the early 90s.
The next time someone tries to say Stephen Greer coined the term ARV, send them this
passage.
And Hamilton actually told Greer about the 1988 Norton Air Force Base show flux liner
incident and actually passed along both primary witness Sorensen and aerospace illustrator
McCandalish to Greer.
Hamilton was one of the first to draw serious research to the Antelope Valley, California,
near Edwards Air Force Base.
Hamilton drew attention to Lockheed's Gunkworx, Rockwell, McDonnell Douglas, and Northrop
all having plants in Palmdale, California.
The nation's then chief center of aerospace technology.
In the middle of these complexes sat Air Force Plant 42, a name many associate with UAP programs.
The author of Cosmic Top Secret does not draw attention to the Northrop facility near Palm
Dale, but instead to a secret underground installation north in the Duhachapi Mountains.
Hamilton accuses the Northrop Tehan Ranch radar cross-section facility and accompanying
underground installation as a UAP program facility.
Very little is known about this facility and the underground extension, but let's see
what we can dig up.
This site officially serves as a radar cross-section range.
Quickly, what exactly is a radar cross-section facility?
To summarize, these facilities utilize high-frequency radio waves to test aircraft radar signatures.
The sites utilize large runways and pylons raised from underground on concrete diamonds
as mounting pads to blast craft and materials with radar.
Many RCS facilities saw construction during the Cold War.
This led the majority of installations being built underground to hide RCS pylons, equipment,
and technologies away from Soviet spy satellites.
In Cosmic Top Secret, William Hamilton discussed numerous statements recounted to him, such
as a 1988 sighting of a giant boomerang over the Northrop facility and a flying saucer seen
taking off from a building on the property.
The Northrop RCS facility has recorded several anomalous sightings throughout history, oftentimes
glowing orbs seen around the facility.
According to some researchers, the facility sees a disproportionate amount of sightings
compared to the Lockheed and MacDonald Douglas RCS facilities nearby.
And this isn't the first time I've discussed this Northrop location.
Remember back to my work on the triangular alien reproduction vehicle, the XF-131 Super Sentinel.
Let's reference forensic artist Bill MacDonald's 1992 piece, the Tuhachibi Triangle, in which
the artist drew a reverse-engineered triangular craft detailed to him by disgruntled engineers
from Lockheed Martin and Northrop Grumman.
The engineers hailed from the Northrop RCS facility at Tehan and Lockheed Martin Hellendale
RCS plant.
According to their testimonies, the facilities doubled as UFO reverse engineering and material
exploitation locations.
If you have not seen this investigation, I highly recommend watching as the XF-131 Super
Sentinel is absolutely fascinating research, and RCS locations have actually seen much
discussion in ufology, with the contentious Stephen Greer in particular labeling the Hellendale
plant as a staging ground for electro-gravitic ARV, and a forward operating base employing
EMP weapons for ARV testing and downing of non-human vehicles.
Now, interestingly, the Senate Intelligence and Armed Services Committee and other senior
officials had no idea of this.
The top people in the Special Forces who were outside this illegal black project system
didn't know about it.
I had known about it since the 90s, but I'd never, of course, flown directly over it because
it's classified airspace and very sensitive.
So you can see what looks like a trough and a runway.
It's just where the man-made UFOs that we've been building since the 1954-55 come
out, they go up and they hover, they're silent, they're electro-gravitic, anti-grav.
The diamond on the left, you see that looks like a runway with a diamond, it's not a runway
because they don't need to run and get, there's non-aerodynamic, they just go boom, up.
But they're placed on different diamonds.
I have a whole series of video and pictures of these that I don't have time to go through,
and that's where they're put at various elevations and then struck with an electromagnetic weapon
to see if it's hardened enough to withstand conflict, right?
Now this may seem extreme, but there is quite a bit of valid research to discuss weapons
that have been designed to down a UAP.
But what more can we factually learn about the underground portion of the Tehan RCS facility?
The Northrop site would then be discussed in Dr. Richard Sauter's excellent book,
underground bases and tunnels, which takes an evidence-based approach to studying subterranean
facilities, aka deep underground military bases, DUMs.
This is my absolute favorite book on the subject of DUMs, as Sauter tackles the subject often
associated with conspiracies with rigorous fact-based research.
Sauter states Northrop alongside numerous Fortune 500 companies such as Lockheed Martin
employ high-tech underground centers in California, and claims with a high degree of certainty
these facilities are, quote, heavily engaged in non-conventional high-tech aerospace research,
end quote.
Dr. Sauter is equally confident the underground portion of the Northrop RCS facility engages
in the same non-conventional research, but is unsure just how far beneath the earth Northrop's
activities extend.
Rumors persist under the site there exist as many as 42 underground levels and connective
tunnels to nearby facilities as well as Edwards Air Force Base.
The validity and very real existence of these locations and tunnels will be another topic
for another day, as there is quite a volume of valuable research to speak to the legitimacy
of interconnected deep underground military bases.
As a yes, I do plan on using Dr. Sauter's research for a full deep dive into DUMs, but
I would just like to say that TRW, Northrop's golden child, also has a storied history in
connected subterranean facilities.
In the 1960s and 1970s, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and U.S. National Committee on
Tunneling Technology, USNC slash TT, conducted myriad studies, reports, and patents on underground
ICBM-based design, tunneling technologies, tunnel boring machines, tunnel depths, etc.
TRW engaged and published a number of studies determining the viability of high-speed ground
transportation tunnel design.
For example, we can analyze this 1968 report where TRW discusses high-speed underground
transportation vehicles in tunnel diameters ranging from 80 to 40 feet, at a depth of
400 to 2,500 feet.
Another topic for another day as I stated.
Analyzing McDonald, Sauter, and Hamilton, the question must be asked, does Northrop
Grumman test and operate reverse-engineered NHI vehicles out of an underground facility
beneath the Tehan RCS site?
The Northrop, Lockheed, and McDonnell Douglas RCS locations do, after all, reside in close
proximity to Edwards Air Force Base, the former Norton Air Force Base, and Palmdale-USAF Plant
42.
Norton and Plant 42 are integral pieces to the flux liner ARV testimony of Brad Sorensen
and Mark McCandlish.
And carefully connecting research and analyzing the testimony of Lt. Col. Ed, I have accused
Edwards Air Force Base and their 412th test group as running a UFO reverse-engineering
testing program between Edwards and the Nevada Test and Training Range.
Several testimonies over the decades outside of Eshler, Miller, and McDonald's four anonymous
engineers have labeled Northrop Grumman directly as participating in UFO crash retrieval, reverse
engineering, and material exploitation.
Many will recall the testimony of Edgar Fouchet and the TR3B reverse-engineered Triangular
Craft.
Many write off Fouchet due to the absence of hard physical proof of his claims.
However, I do highly recommend viewing my piece on Triangle ARVs in general, as a tremendous
amount of research resulted from Fouchet's disclosures.
The 250-foot prototype and 600-foot operational TR3B models, according to Fouchet, saw test
flights over Edwards Air Force Base, conducted by the AFFTC Air Force Test Center, which
oddly enough operates under the 412th test group which we discussed above.
Strange as near Edwards, where these test flights allegedly occur, Northrop has nearby
installations both near Palmdale USAF Plant 42, as well as a mysterious underground location
where anomalous craft have been reported over the decades.
Fouchet also outright named the contractors responsible for the construction of TR3B.
FFRDC's Sandia and Livermore Labs reverse-engineered the propulsion device.
But the primary contractors of the project were listed as Lockheed, Boeing, Teledyne
Ryan and Northrop.
I would now like to shift to a fascinating few details from the whistleblower testimony
of Colonel Steve Wilson.
Wilson's testimony was made public around 1997, shortly before his death, through researcher
Dr. Richard Boylan.
Boylan has historically published some claims I approach with skepticism, so I tried multiple
times to connect with him regarding Wilson, but have heard nothing.
Colonel Steve Wilson does deserve his own video, as this enigmatic figure is well worth
investigating.
And disclaimer, we cannot 100% prove Wilson's 40-year military background, as numerous articles
exist on the web detailing his DD-214 in education, training and medals.
However, we do not have any scans or copies of Wilson's official records or images of
him in service.
For this reason, I do also recommend reading Kevin Randall's skeptical take on Wilson
and Boylan's reporting, which raises concerns, such as 40 years of service listed on Wilson's
DD-214, as well as seemingly misreported medals.
To summarize Wilson's disclosures, Wilson claimed in 1963, as a captain in the Tactical
Fighter Squadron out of Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, he was assigned to the Majestic
12 and promoted to major.
Here the then major learned of the Majestic 12's modus operandi, to control, quote,
UFO surveillance and interdictions, retrievals and analysis of records of extraterrestrial
spacecraft and occupants, and public access to any information about these matters, end
quote.
As part of his duties, Wilson would be assigned to the 1st Special Forces Air Command and
would undergo special training with Delta Force and the then Black Berets.
For 9 years, Colonel Wilson claimed to visit nearly every Air Force base in the world and
make contact with key people for the Majestic 12 unit.
Wilson states, whilst a Lieutenant Colonel in 1972, he was reassigned from 1st Special
Forces Air Command at Vandenberg Air Force Base in California to Area S-4, near Papoose
Lake south of Area 51, by men with CIA credentials.
I am skipping a tremendous amount of detail here, as this is not our subject for today,
but Wilson would travel 30 stories underground in the facility where he witnessed 8 different
kinds of non-human craft, as well as an extremely tall woman that appeared to be extraterrestrial.
According to Wilson, S-4 operated to test anti-gravity reverse engineered vehicles.
The first successful flight had allegedly occurred on July 18th, 1971, a year before
his station, which saw Admiral Bobby Ray Inman present for the test.
Interesting connection to Eshler, Inman and Shapiro, as we stated above.
After some time at S-4, Wilson would claim to head Project Pounce, an elite Air Force
NRO Special Forces unit which retrieved downed UFOs.
Oddly enough, Project Pounce can be observed in the disputed Majestic 12 Project Aquarius
document and, oddly enough, the 1953 Robertson Panel report.
Remember, the Robertson Panel served as a debunking panel to reduce public concern regarding
UFOs.
So Wilson has a big, unprovable testimony.
What does any of this have to do with Northrop Grumman?
In his disclosures to Dr. Boylan, Wilson additionally named US aerospace vehicles that had been
created utilizing reverse engineered non-human technology.
Many of these vehicles would feature anti-gravity systems, and after all of the research we've
done on this channel and the words of Jake Barber, maybe this isn't so far-fetched.
The implications of what you're saying also are that potentially there is some kind of
capacity to draw incredible amounts of energy from the quantum back end.
I've seen it.
You've seen it.
There's also, obviously, the capacity to use propulsion systems that are far beyond what
we're describing.
Yeah, that seems to be the case as well.
Anti-gravity.
They know about it.
Zero point energy.
Those secrets are being suppressed from our knowledge.
Wilson would state US clandestine military operations began flying the TR-3B reverse
engineered triangle but also discussed an anti-gravity disc that glowed intense orange
golden during flight.
Wilson claimed this craft was made by Northrop Aerospace at their secret facility northeast
of Lancaster, California.
This location is quite interesting, as it matches the underground Northrop Range we
discussed earlier in this investigation.
Wilson would even state the Northrop, Lockheed, and McDonnell Douglas RCS facilities were
connected alongside Area 51 and other sensitive locations via underground train systems.
Wilson claimed these tunnels were excavated by nuclear subterranes, which is actually
very interesting.
Nuclear subterranes are massive tunneling machines that work by melting rock with heat
supplied via a compact nuclear reactor.
Numerous patents for such machines were designed by Los Alamos National Laboratories in the
1970s, and don't worry, we will fully dive into this in the dumb video.
Boylan had reportedly witnessed this craft in test flight over Area 51 in the Northrop
complex near Edwards, dubbing it Northrop's Great Pumpkin Disc.
These two siding locations are another fascinating connection to ED and the joint reverse engineering
effort between Edwards, Contractors, and Area 51.
Wilson made additional mentions to a reverse engineered craft designated the XH-75D or
the XH Shark.
This craft is allegedly an anti-gravity helicopter designed by Teledyne Ryan San Diego Division.
Wilson claimed these craft were assigned to Delta Force slash the NRO for UFO crash retrievals.
This mention of NRO and Delta is indeed intriguing.
Delta Force, part of the Joint Special Operations Command, JSOC, has been accused of participating
in foreign UFO crash retrievals under the CIA Office of Global Access, as has indeed
the NRO.
In fact, the NRO was one of two intelligence agencies, the other being the National Geospatial
Intelligence Agency we discussed above with C4ISR, David Grush worked on as liaison to
the UAP Task Force, where he discovered the existence of UAP legacy programs.
The NRO was also one of three intelligence agencies alongside the CIA and NSA mentioned
by Edgar Fouchet as managing the TR-3B reverse engineered triangle.
Very little has been discussed on this craft, the XH-75D, original drawing by Wilson on
screen now, and almost no actionable investigation can arise from Wilson's incredibly brief
testimony on this craft.
The Colonel never discussed the intended application or function of the onboard anti-gravity system.
What I do find interesting is a 2019 design concept created by one of Lockheed Martin's
subsidiaries, the Sikorsky Raider X.
Dual rotor helicopters are not rare.
They are often implemented on helicopters designed for heavy lift.
One would have to ask why the XH-75D would need dual rotors with an anti-gravity system.
But the Raider X, cancelled in 24, sought to create a quote, agile, survivable compound
coaxial helicopter that will equip future aviators to address evolving peer and near
peer threats in the most difficult environments, end quote.
No further linkages beyond design exist between these platforms.
However, I do find it interesting the XH-75D, drawn by Wilson in 97, looks almost identical
to the concept craft proposed by Lockheed in 2019.
So is the anti-gravity disc and helicopter proposed by Wilson real?
Well, this is unfortunately a dead end of investigation.
As I said, Wilson's testimony must be considered little more than third party research.
Because while it is fascinating and ties intimately to some claims made regarding UAP legacy recovery
programs throughout history, there is little evidence or actionable data to pursue.
I would, however, like to leave discussion of Wilson with a chart he made regarding the
structure of UAP legacy programs.
Please note, the rendition I am showing now is a recreation of Wilson's 97 chart published
in 2001.
Numerous spelling errors can be observed here, such as in Lockheed.
This chart is titled Star Wars City in reference to the Strategic Defense Initiative, the program
we mentioned above, and a program I have discussed many times, instituted by Reagan
in the 1980s with possible ties to Eisenhower.
To state again, the SDI program instituted to protect the United States from ballistic
nuclear attacks has been referenced by numerous witnesses who have stated the program had
a backdoor functionality to act offensively against UAP and backchanneled funds to fund
UFO legacy programs.
From the chart, Star Wars City, located under the Cheyenne Mountain Complex in Colorado
Springs, Colorado, oversees the U.S. space counterintelligence headquarters within the
SDI as the nexus of UAP legacy programs.
Within this chart, there are numerous institutions one might expect to be associated with UAP
retrieval and exploitation programs, the NRO, National Security Council, National Security
Agency, CIA, NORAD, and Majestic 12.
Adhering to the SDI Colorado HQ and MAGI, there exists a list of contractors alleged
to engage with the UAP portfolio.
Contractors such as Rockwell, Martin Marietta, Lockheed, Boeing, McDonnell Douglas, and IBM
are mentioned.
We also find Decision Science Applications Inc.
DSAI was led by former Admiral and recurring character of this project, Bobby Ray Inman,
and most likely had its assets handed over to SAIC.
A contractor I believe is as involved in legacy operations as Northrop or Lockheed.
Another project for another day, as DSAI is quite a worthy investigation.
DSI, according to the chart and Wilson's testimony, consists of directors of relevant
UAP black budget divisions from the aforementioned contractors as well as Ford Aerospace, which
is now part of Northrop Grumman, and Teledyne Ryan, which was one of Northrop's premium
purchases.
While Teledyne Ryan did indeed play a vital role in the Strategic Defense Initiative,
the contractor was well regarded for designing and producing high-performance aerial targets,
which were crucial for testing and evaluation potential for missile defense systems as well
as developing advanced sensors that could be used for detecting and tracking incoming
ballistic missiles.
TRW, Northrop's crown jewel, additionally aided in the SDI program, such as using its
locations for high-powered chemical laser testing.
And as we mentioned above, Northrop itself takes great pride in aiding in the SDI program
in 1983, creating the first laser radar used in space.
It is fascinating, even in a testimony like Wilson's, we can still find links to Northrop's
many acquisitions and UAP legacy programs.
And now onto a whistleblower by the acronym of AH that appeared on Stephen Greer's 2001
disclosure briefing document.
And I must state again regarding Greer's witnesses.
Let us analyze the quality and claims of the whistleblower instead of the platform.
Unfortunately, Greer's poor operational security is ever-present, as clips of AH are listed
in the DPI archive as Arnold House.
I believe I have located this individual and have reached out to talk to him.
I have heard nothing.
Arnold's testimony revolves around the significant information he gained regarding UAP programs
while a surface technician at the Boeing Aerospace Company, as well as insights gained from
friend and four-star general Curtis LeMay.
As we dive in, it is crucial to maintain awareness House's disclosures are indeed second-hand.
As far as his testimony, House never participated directly in program operations.
His information was handed to him from friends at NSA, CIA, NASA, JPL, Office of Naval Intelligence,
USAAF, Northrop, Boeing, and various generals.
This information was so complete according to Greer, House briefed Bill Clinton in 1990.
I have no evidence to confirm this briefing.
The only possible link I can find is a letter to Clinton from Greer marked 9 July 2000,
where Greer requested the sitting president to disclose UFO-related USAPs at the suggestion
of their mutual friend.
I do find House very worthy of discussion as we can find correspondences with him and
Greer as recently as 2018 and as old as December 2000.
Perhaps House, like William Hamilton, has served as one of Greer's primary sources
of information over the decades.
In his taped testimony link in description, House stated one day around 1987 at the home
of General Curtis LeMay, the infamous general confirmed the Roswell, New Mexico crash.
House also learned from his NSA friend that Henry Kissinger, George Bush, as well as Ronald
Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev were all aware of the UAP subject.
His friends and CIA relayed to House that they, along with USAAF, had downed NHI craft.
Arnold even claimed he learned from a friend in the FBI that the Bureau had radar testing
that was causing interference with some of the craft resulting in crashes.
This echoes Lieutenant Colonel Corso's sentiments regarding the crash of the Roswell,
New Mexico craft.
House also learned and relayed there are underground bases testing and maintaining TUOs, likely
Dugway, Palmdale, California, Edwards Air Force Base, Eglin Air Force Base, and others.
Interesting we see Palmdale and Edwards pop up once again.
But now let's focus directly on Arnold's information regarding Northrup.
House's entire testimony could lead to an entire video, so maybe we will save that for
Whistleblowers Volume 3.
A.H. stated while at Boeing he met a man in the Army Criminal Investigation Division,
CID, who was involved in several crash recovery since 1947 and had served in Army CIC, Counter
Intelligence Corps, capacity.
The gentleman handpicked one of House's friends at the Boeing Aircraft Company to become
part of a UFO crash recovery team in northern New Mexico starting in 1980.
This friend of A.H. would somehow relay information regarding his time and legacy program operations
from 1980 to 1997, 17 years.
The time of these disclosures is not given, however as investigators we must assume that
his friend informed Arnold after leaving program operations in 1997.
House's friend was ultimately stationed and helped with reverse engineering efforts and
testing of non-human craft at Area 51.
He was not working for the US government or military, however.
His paychecks during these years in legacy programs came directly from Northrup.
The source would illustrate Northrup, Lockheed Martin, and Boeing all engaged in UFO reverse
engineering efforts at Area 51.
The facility itself from 1980 to 1997 held a tremendous amount of extraterrestrial debris
in a containment area.
This source would also tell House some of the program was shifted to a location in Utah,
likely Dugway Proving Grounds.
They moved most of the stuff from Area 51, at least 35% to 40% of Area 51 to Utah, just
basically those companies and of course Lockheed and Northrup.
This is very interesting as USF Master Sergeant Edgar Fouchet said the exact same thing.
Some Area 51 legacy programs were relocated to Dugway in the early 1990s.
I myself have talked about Dugway previously and plan to revisit with a contractor witness
who claimed to stumble upon a floating saucer craft within a classified testing area on
base.
Here is where House's testimony regarding Area 51 and Northrup gets really interesting.
This same friend told Arnold the A51 program to test NHI vehicles and exploit technological
materials was called Project Red Light.
There's a base near Lancaster and Palmdale area and near, this is very funny, it's near
Northrup.
There's an underground area out there too that he was aware of.
But he particularly mentioned and stayed focused on ANSA California.
There's some underground areas up there too that they're researching some of this technology
and at March Air Force Base through Project Red Light.
This should immediately become familiar to many of my viewers as I have referenced this
Project Red Light on numerous occasions.
I have traced first mention of this project to the files of the late legendary researcher
Leonard Stringfield, author of Crash Retrieval Status Reports 1 through 7 and relayed by
excellent researcher Michael Schratt.
In a letter dated April 5, 1980, one Mr. D. L. Dobbs discussed one M.H., a witness identity
Schratt chose not to disclose.
M.H. allegedly performed radio maintenance at the Atomic Proving Grounds in Nevada during
1961-1963, along with top-secret radio work for USAF.
According to M.H., he participated in a top-secret operation at Area 51 titled Project Red Light.
Test flights were conducted under this project on a recovered UFO shipped from none other
than Edwards Air Force Base.
The craft was not conventionally powered and stayed silent during operation.
Security was so tight on the project, program personnel were rotated every six months.
M.H. claimed to have heard rumors of a West Coast American defense contractor encountering
difficulties in reverse engineering many of the components comprising the craft.
I have drawn a parallel between Red Light and the testimony of Ed we have referenced
numerous times throughout this project, a joint Edwards Area 51 reverse engineering
program out of the Edwards 412th test group.
Well, Master Sergeant Edgar Fouchet additionally mentioned Project Red Light.
Fouchet claimed he gathered knowledge defense contractor E.G.N.G. was awarded an indefinite
contract for Project Red Light to support the DOE and military.
If you have not heard of E.G.N.G., this is the contractor historically implicated with
UAP programs made infamous in the story of Bob Lazar as the contractor that hired him
to work out of Site 4.
This contract gave E.G.N.G. responsibility to assist in the recovery of nuclear materials
in cases of mishaps and to provide aerial and ground security for highly classified
government and military sites.
If the testimony of Arnold House and his legacy program connections are indeed true, Northrop
Grumman could have indeed served as a project manager for Project Red Light, testing non-human
intelligence and alien reproduction vehicles in a joint contractor Edwards 412th test group
operation.
Absolutely incredible links to ponder.
Hey guys, it's Gerb and thank you so much for joining me and sitting through this entire
investigation into Northrop Grumman and their involvement in legacy program operations.
By this point I think the video will be about an hour long so I really appreciate you joining
me through this journey.
As you probably noticed and if you've seen my other work on Battelle and Lockheed, you
know we have a lot less tangible paper trails to work with here with Northrop.
We have no Project Stork, we have no direct mention of Lockheed and so forth.
But almost in a way I find that a little more intriguing for my research.
You know with Northrop we devoted so much time to look specifically at Northrop Grumman's
acquisitions.
TRW, Teledyne Ryan, BDM, connections to Aerospace Corporation and FFRDCs.
And I find this so fascinating how Northrop's involvement outside of mentions of Fouche and
a couple other mentions here and there and comments from Jack Northrop at the beginning
of the video, they seem to purchase buy up companies that had legacy operations.
You know TRW and its implication in the Wilson Davis Memo and the Phil Pentagon audit that
almost outed the senior review group, $200 million today Northrop paid to settle that
lawsuit for TRW.
Now they acquired them I believe for $6 or $7 billion, so that's a drop in the bucket
but it's interesting that a year after the acquisition Northrop's still okay with you
know what TRW you're implicated in this massive lawsuit but don't worry we'll pay for it.
So I find that sort of research absolutely scintillating instead of just direct confirmations
and direct ties like we had with Lockheed and Battelle, I also find all of the whistleblower
testimony of Northrop to be incredibly fascinating you know I wouldn't be surprised to see full
projects on Steve Wilson and Arnold Howe soon and like I mentioned I've tried to connect
with Howe because I do believe with a high degree of certainty I have found that individual
and Colonel Steve Wilson is no longer with us he passed in 1997 but his testimony is
still shrouded in mystery and his legitimacy in USAF is still surrounded in mystery so
a lot more to explore there but I find it really interesting from the work of William
Hamilton to the testimony of AH that there's still these little comments that are ubiquitous
around testimony that I still find to be quite accurate mentions of the SDI and UAP legacy programs
mention of Northrop's involvement in underground facilities mention of underground facilities
mentioning you know dating to Fouche as well projects being moved from Area 51 to Dugway
Proving Grounds even mentions of Area 51 and Edwards as we see in Arnold Howe's Red Light,
Fouche, etc. So the question must be asked why is Northrop's involvement in legacy programs
legacy programs operations so shrouded why do they pass under the radar alongside companies
like Boeing and Raytheon while Lockheed Martin while Battelle these guys I mean even General
Electric to a certain degree are always labeled as the prime contractors well I do have somewhat
of a thesis there I think Battelle bar biological storage at probably Fort Detrick or Fort Belbois
is a little bit out of the game they're a little bit said and done I think the three
four primary players if we want to say are Lockheed Boeing who is likely a project manager
for operations Northrop and Raytheon I think these are the big guys I think that
Lockheed is sort of like a hound dog Lockheed will respond to a beck and call they will do
what is required of them they are the loudest in the room etc. I think Lockheed is they will
take advantage of a situation and they are opportunists the reason I say this is the
2008 material transfer to OSAP that was blocked by again Glenn Gaffney and the CIA Directorate
of Science and Technology Lockheed itself offered to divest itself of materials now was this to
get in the good graces of the CIA the OGA the DS&T the NRO probably
did Lockheed give up materials they could reverse engineer did Lockheed give away
materials that they think that any other corporation or agency could reverse engineer
and garner insights from probably not this was probably materials they thought well if we can't
figure it out no one else can so we might as well you know get in good favor with some people and
get rid of these materials which is likely from the 1953 Kingman Arizona crash but that's a whole
another conversation Northrup their work seems to be shrouded in much more secrecy they are not
offering to divest themselves of material they are often staying in the shadows they are often
tag-lined in testimonies like Fouches as the person in the shadows so that begs the question
what work are they doing well I believe it's material exploitation reverse engineering and
testing of ARV and likely project managerial responsibilities for the red light project if
that is still ongoing or if that has shifted since Ed's time around Nellis and Edwards and I ending
in about 2006 to 2008 so if that project is still ongoing I think that Lockheed operates similar to
and I forgot one on the mountain rush more of legacy operations SAIC I think lock I think
Northrup alongside Lockheed alongside SAIC Boeing and perhaps Raytheon they operate across all
segments of US military I've commented numerous times that the army the air force and the navy
their programs are extremely compartmentalized stove piped as Eric Davis said and don't really
have much interaction with each other the common threads here are the contractors that interact
in programs across compartments and possibly the UARCs and FFRDCs that do as well there might be
some some small contractors that help out with air force responsibilities here and then one such
company might be alien science and technologies helping Ed and the project red light if you want
to call it that out at Edwards but the project managers the the companies that seem to do quite
a bit and engage in all facets of legacy program operations operate across all of these boards
so is Northrup still ongoing in research I would probably say yes and Northrup has is up to their
eyeballs just like SAIC just like Lockheed and just like Boeing but these are my personal opinions I
think that even though much of the research we have studied today is still whistleblower testimony
and a bit nebulous at some points like Steve Wilson I still think there are numerous fascinating
ties I mean again I want to harken back to Northrup's many acquisitions and even date that
back to Sperry Rand when it went defunct its departments going to Northrup Grumman and Lockheed
and others and connections to the Corso testimony all of these neat little threads that kind of tie
Northrup and its purchasing streak interwoven into stories of legacy program operations it's
very fascinating in a sense this project was almost a little bit more conclusive to me than
even Lockheed or Battelle I would like to know what everybody else here thinks you know perhaps
Northrup's silence is a sign of danger we don't know all we can do is continue to investigate
and if you have any other insights into Northrup or or testimony I would love to hear from you and
to tell me what you think in the comments with that guys we will move on because I think I've
been ranting now for about eight minutes please remember to like and subscribe always look forward
to the next project we'll get back in live soon because I would like to talk a little bit about
concurring events you know with the whistleblower testimony of Jake Barber, Dr. John Blitch, Don Paul
Bales and so forth and Fred Baker but I don't want to make that my channel I'm not a news of
the day type of guy as you all know you know there's a lot of space between the videos so
we'll figure out something there so please remember to like and subscribe guys I do have
a Patreon you can find that on the channel page I don't gatekeep content all of my research as
everybody knows is open source so only support what you think the channel is worth you're not
getting much extra there it's just going to help me out make these investigations purchasing better
camera equipment because ever as everybody can see this camera isn't great and you know maybe
funding my trips to go speak to witnesses which I do plan to do quite soon so thank you so much
again for joining me and I will catch everybody on the next show later everybody thanks