Well, I had contacted Admiral Bobby Ray Inman, who was the head of the National Security
Agency in the United States, deputy director at CIA, director of naval intelligence and
a variety of intelligence posts, a technologist and clearly someone that if this was really
accurate, that there really were UFOs and non-human intelligence around, this is a man
who had to know.
So I was able to contact him thanks to a contact through Admiral Lord Hill Norton here in the
UK and this conversation, he alarmingly not only indicated that these issues were covered
under national secrecy laws, but that the United States government did in fact have
possession of the hardware associated with this. In other words, this was an actual physical
phenomenon as a craft, a spaceship, several of them and they were in operational condition.
The particular incident we were involved in, we were just under a mile and a half of water
in North Atlantic. What had happened, they had picked up a, there's a survey vehicle
working in the North Atlantic that had picked up some radioactive signal. It was almost
a perfect symmetric piece of metal with a marking around the edge and it was just a
triangular shape, but no glass, nothing that would appear to be a nuclear weapon.
From Roswell in 1947 to Jake Barber in 2024, on this channel we have discussed extensively
UFO crash retrieval operations performed by UFO legacy programs involving the United States
Army and Air Force. Over the past decades, these retrievals are alleged to have occurred
over the continental United States, Mexico, Peru, Vietnam, the former Soviet Union, China
and numerous lands around the globe. In several US incidents, rapid reaction response teams
are detailed to fly in via helicopter, drive in via flatbed truck or utilize any vehicle
system to retrieve non-human craft and transport them to clandestine above and below ground
military installations. But what about retrieval operations that must be conducted in the oceans
of our planet? What happens when UFOs crash into water or USOs, unidentified submerged
objects must be recovered? How are such operations conducted in the most mysterious corners of
our planet where only roughly 26% of our oceans floors have been mapped? This would of course
require the most powerful seafaring military on the planet, the United States Navy, and
some measurable special access programs, internal intelligence offices, corporate
programs and partnerships with shadowy US intelligence apparatuses. But does the Navy
just retrieve UFOs and USOs in our water? Or do they, like many retrieval instances
we have covered on this channel involving the Army and Air Force, additionally engage
in storage, exploitation and reverse engineering of technologies of unknown origin? For this
reason, I want to dive in and explore the MODIS operandi, operational history and key
players in US UFO Navy legacy programs. From the research we will explore in this project,
I theorize naval UFO programs can be delegated to four major components of operation, monitor,
collect, store and exploit. These operations are likely conducted out of the Office of
Naval Research and Office of Naval Intelligence in conjunction with US Special Forces Command,
shadowy intelligence organizations like the highly secretive National Underwater Reconnaissance
Office and Navy Special Program, and involve US naval stations like NAWC China Lake and
NSWC Crane, while engaging with defense contractors and FFRDCs such as Lockheed Martin for utilization
of their now retired deep-submergence rescue vehicles Mystic and Avalon. This investigation
will explore in tremendous detail the three components of naval UFO programs I outlined
above, UFO and USO collection, NHI craft storage and technologies of unknown origin, TUO,
exploitation. One major cornerstone I theorize exists in naval UFO programs, monitor, will
be largely omitted from today's exploration. While the topic of possible undersea UFO bases
or installations is well worth investigating in the future, I have covered the topic of
USO reports twice already on this channel. These include discussion of OPNAV 3820, a
naval regulation restricting maritime UFO reporting. With that being said, let us look
beyond the veil to analyze naval UFO legacy programs.
Hey guys, it's UAP Grb and I am thrilled for you to join me today as we take a direct
investigation into UFO legacy programs under the United States Navy. We will direct our
focus on three key pillars relevant to today's discussion, collection, storage and exploitation
of non-human craft and technology. In this investigation, we will analyze the alleged
structure of naval UFO programs, study key figures associated with said programs, evaluate
a handful of incredibly intriguing USO retrieval cases, and identify naval installations alleged
to hold non-human craft and biologics.
I've been sitting on this information for quite a while now and I felt quite nervous
about it because the retrieval program undertaken by the CIA and elements of the US Navy is
probably one of the most tightly guarded secrets in the US government and those protecting
it can be quite nasty and I was warned about that.
On 20 September 2024, excellent UK-based journalist Christopher Sharpe in the Liberation
Times posted an article titled, quote, paradigm changing UFO transparency legislation fails
in Congress for second consecutive year. The piece discussed the unfortunate dismissal
of the UAP Disclosure Act in the fiscal year 2025 National Defense Authorization Act. This
exclusion of the UAPDA is another topic for another day as such bombshell legislation
could very well have begun the unraveling of UAP legacy program secrecy. The September
20 article pivots rapidly discussing multiple programs orchestrated by the CIA's Directorate
of Science and Technology and its Directorate of Operations, alongside Department of Defense
and Department of Energy components that have for decades bypassed democratic oversight
to retrieve advanced technologies of unknown origin. If this CIA DS&T sounds familiar to
you, it is likely because this CIA component has been accused on myriad occasions by Chris
Sharpe and Dr. Eric Davis as directly participating in and obfuscating data around UFO retrievals.
For example, Glenn Gaffney, former CIA DS&T Director, has been labeled as the gatekeeper
who ceased Lockheed Martin's attempts to divest UFO materials, likely the 1953 Kingman
Arizona crash, to the OSAT program in 2008. Additionally, former CIA DS&T Deputy Director
Doug Wolf aided in founding the CIA OGA, or Office of Global Access, in 2003. Wolf and
the OGA have been accused by Sharpe and others as participating in retrievals outside of
the United States with JSOC, Joint Special Operations Command. Anyways, the 20 September
Sharpe article proceeds to detail some truly startling revelations,
include the retrieval of objects from beneath the oceans, involving the CIA's Directorate
of Operations, the National Underwater Reconnaissance Office, coordinated between the CIA and U.S.
Navy, United States Special Operations Command, and submersibles from the Woods Hole Oceanographic
Institute. Additionally, the retrieval of objects on foreign soil is conducted with
the involvement of the CIA's Office of Global Access and Joint Special Operations Command.
Sharpe directly named military and intelligence organizations involved with ocean-based retrieval,
including two institutions almost never discussed, the Neuro-National Underwater Reconnaissance
Office and WHOI, the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute. But before we break down these
statements, I must detail the evolution of this article as it allows us to study, in
Chris Sharpe's own words, information detrimental to his safety. By 22 September 2024, the article
was revised, redacting all information about the Navy, Neuro, Woods Hole, NGA, NRO, JSOC,
etc. The new, bare-bones edition still discussed the CIA, DS&T, DOD, and DOE, but all true,
actionable data was stripped from the piece. Sharpe was accused by some Twitter users as
making quote-unquote stealth edits to remove information from the article, but he responded
by stating quote,
This is sourced information. There is a real, extremely dangerous reason little information
has been released about such programs. Content from the article was removed because of the
threats posed to me, end quote. By 25 September 2024, five days after the original posting,
Sharpe would once again edit the article and say quote,
Okay, so someone has recklessly put me at extreme risk, so I have updated last week's
article relating to the UAPDA, reverting back to details previously mentioned. This time,
the details are far more specific, so here it is, the alleged undersea retrieval program,
end quote. This third edit is quite similar to the first piece, but expands on multiple
departments and agencies named specialized assets and expertise to carry out undersea
craft retrievals. In this latest iteration, Sharpe states for operations, Woods Hole provided
deep submergence vehicles to quote,
Support retrieval efforts, end quote. Deep submerged rescue vehicles or DSRV will be
a crucial aspect of a USO retrieval operation covered much later on in this project. The
third iteration does powerfully claim the undersea craft or quote,
Transfer to the Office of Naval Research, which subsequently hands them over to defense
contractors for detailed analysis, end quote. From this article, we can extract a powerful
thesis, the US Navy works in conjunction with the CIA, DS&T, alongside JSOC or SOCOM forces,
intelligence agencies such as the NRO, NGA, and Shadowy Neuro, as well as defense RDT&E
facilities and private contractors to retrieve and store non-human craft found deep undersea.
But let's really break this down, analyzing the targeted role of the CIA's Office of Global
Access alongside JSOC in global soil-based craft retrievals, we can assume a similar
structure for undersea retrievals where the CIA, DS&T, serves as the logistics coordinator
while JSOC provides men-at-arms, industrial security, human intelligence, etc. In this
apparatus, the NRO and NGA would harness reconnaissance satellites to provide SIGINT
or signals intelligence to retrieval teams while the Shadowy National Underwater Reconnaissance
Office provides unknown methods of underwater reconnaissance. In such a system outlined by
SHARP, retrieval operations would be done in tandem with the US Navy and contractors such
as Lockheed Martin and their DSRV and Dry Submersible, as well as non-profit research
facilities such as Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute and their many deep submergence vehicles.
Finally, in this hypothesized naval UFO program, craft would be taken to various Office of Naval
Research locations before being transferred to defense contractors to study. But in this program,
I do think SHARP is missing a key step here. Many speak on joint USG contractor UFO legacy programs,
but a cornerstone of my work has been discussing the missing intermediary, federally funded
research and development centers FFRDCs and university-affiliated research centers UARCs.
I will not bore returning viewers of these details, but I often speak on how these semi-private
government-controlled RDT and E-Centers act as liaison between USG slash DOD and US defense
contractors for UFO reverse engineering and material exploitation programs. Such institutions
would serve as subject matter experts and provide necessary R&D work on project materials.
This would in turn keep knowledge access and TUO programs quite strict, only allowing contractor
personnel with a need to know full insights into the full extent of the non-human materials on
which the programs focus. The Navy employs numerous UARCs and FFRDCs often entwined with
unacknowledged special access programs, special access programs, and controlled access programs.
Such UARCs include the Applied Physics Laboratories at Johns Hopkins University and the University
of Washington, as well as the Applied Research Laboratories at the Universities of Hawaii at
Manoa, University of Texas at Austin, and Pennsylvania State University. Penn State's
UARC was established in 1945 by Penn State President Dr. Eric A. Walker. Dr. Walker was
named by physicist and consultant to the DOD Research Board Dr. Robert Saarbacher as participating
in 1950s UFO retrieval and reverse engineering programs alongside Dr. Vannevar Bush. Walker
would be contacted by various UFO researchers in the 1980s and make some startling revelations,
not only admitting he himself was present at the 1965 Kecksburg, Pennsylvania UFO crash,
but also claiming he knew of the Majestic 12 and to engage in UFO legacy programs one would
need to know about ESP, Extrasensory Perception. It is interesting how a former TRW board member
and founder of Penn State's UARC would essentially confess he was part of a UFO legacy program.
And by the way, as recently as 2013, the Office of Naval Research has displayed a keen interest
in studying ESP. The ONR would even publish a, quote, revolutionary program looking into
six cents among humans to train personnel on intuitive decision-making, end quote.
Additionally, according to the testimony of Randy Anderson, the Navy, specifically the Naval Surface
Warfare Center crane and contractor SAIC, has engaged in recovered technologies that respond
to human consciousness at the underground off-world technologies division. The Navy also engages in a
tremendous roster of programs with FFRDCs well worth our interest, primarily the Center for
Naval Analyses run by the CNA Corporation based out of Crystal City, Arlington, Virginia.
Returning viewers will recall how I recently implicated Crystal City and a likely massive
underground facility beneath a neighborhood in Pentagon as a major center for UFO legacy programs
SAPs and USAPs. Many of the acronyms Sharp listed in his work regarding undersea retrievals need
much further analysis. And as we move forward in this investigation, it is paramount to recognize
the Navy has indeed participated in at least one acknowledged USO retrieval operation. Recall the
1962 Bluegill Triple Prime detonation and subsequent UFO recovery discussed by late presidential
advisor Harold Malmgren. This event took place during Operation Fishbowl, a series of high-altitude
nuclear tests. The Bluegill Triple Prime nuclear test accidentally disabled a nearby UFO that
went careening into the waters below. The downed craft or quote-unquote pod was searched for and
recovered by the USS Safeguard. Historical logs from the Safeguard discuss the vessel alongside
others such as the USS Engage steaming to the water crash location, searching in a square grid
pattern and employing divers to recover a quote-unquote pod. During net recovery of this pod,
the Safeguard actually lost power and the pod was released for helicopter pickup. This is a
massively consequential case I would like to explore in more detail later on but let's continue
with this investigation. I would be willing to wager most watching this channel have heard of
the National Reconnaissance Officer NRO. The NRO is considered alongside the CIA, NSA, DIA,
and NGA to be one of the big five U.S. intelligence agencies. This agency within the
U.S. DOD has historically designed, built, launched, and operated reconnaissance satellites
providing signals intelligence to the NSA, imagery intelligence to the NGA, and measurement and
signature intelligence to the DIA. David Grush worked for both the NRO and NGA where he
additionally served as the intelligence agency's liaison to the UAP task force. Since 2023, the NRO
has had a provable program that tracks UAP, Project Sentient, uncovered in FOIA documents.
Sentient serves as a quote ongoing research and development program end quote that analyzes
satellite data with AI capabilities. The program was also tasked with analyzing UAP data such as
a 6 May 2021 incident where a small tic-tac object was detected. The Sentient report states
this tic-tac to be similar to other objects observed in redacted operating areas. In 2021,
the NRO contributed to the ODNI's or Office of the Director of National Intelligence's report
to Congressional Intelligence and Armed Services Committee on progress made by the UAP task force.
This discussion of the NRO and UFOs are interesting seen as they contradict a 2015
statement made by the NRO which stated that no documentation relating to UFOs and that the
topic was quote outside of the scope of NRO responsibilities. Furthermore, the NRO has
conducted numerous searches in the past and has located no records end quote. The NRO has of
course additionally been implicated in providing assistance for UFO crash retrieval operations.
These accusations have been made by Chris Sharpe discussed above and witnesses I have covered on
this channel numerous times including Stephen Greer witness A.H. as well as Youssef Master Sergeant
Edgar Fouchet who claimed the NRO alongside the NSA and CIA managed the TR3B Reverse Engineer
Triangular Alien Reproduction Vehicle. A fascinating document allegedly released by the NRO surfaced in
1991. I have covered this document before in relation to Blackjack Control and Blackjack Team
a possible joint reverse engineering group out of Edwards Air Force Base in the Nevada Test and
Training Range. This document is again worth our attention because of the countless groups of
interest mentioned throughout. These include MagiOps, Red Flag MOC, Sea Spray SOG and Aquatec SOG.
Allegedly Stephen Greer gave this memo to Admiral Thomas Wilson from the Wilson Davis
Notes in a 1997 meeting. This meeting did occur this is not disputed however according to Greer
Wilson recognized at least one of the clandestine groups listed in this memorandum for record from
the NRO. Though the NRO likely works with the CIA DS&T and Navy for USO retrievals they are
not our focus for naval legacy programs. The NRO was born based on a recommendation to President
Eisenhower during a National Security Council meeting. The agency was formed to coordinate the
Air Force's and CIA's reconnaissance activities. Lesser known is an additional agency formed to
coordinate the CIA's and Navy's reconnaissance activities the National Underwater Reconnaissance
Office. This agency NRO is known as the hidden younger brother of the NRO. Implications about
this agency and naval USO retrievals are scant seen as NRO is a classified black agency but we
will do everything we can to investigate. NRO itself has been widely considered to be a special
access program according to publications made by the Association of Former Intelligence Officers
quote most SAPs involve technology projects at the Department of Defense there are relatively
few SAPs involving sensitive human intelligence collection or exploitation methods examples of
ongoing non-technology SAPs include interrogation protocols for high-level battlefield detainees in
Afghanistan managed by the Defense Counterintelligence and Human Center of the DIA and every single
capability of all special mission units of the Joint Special Operations Command one entire
government agency the National Underwater Reconnaissance Office is protected by a SAP end quote.
From this statement we can learn NRO is an extremely rare example of an entire intelligence
agency being protected via a special access program but do not be mistaken NRO is a very
real program and we can find snippets of its very existence here and there including a drastic
revelation we will touch on soon. This includes mention of NRO in a 1975 submission of documents
to the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence. Included in a long list of National Security
Council intelligence directives is a National Security Decision Memorandum 40 which details
both NRO and NRO operations. According to the Historical Dictionary of International Intelligence
by Nigel West NRO began during the Cold War as a joint Navy CIA group to coordinate and fund
special projects conducted by submarines. In his book the U.S. Intelligence Committee Jeffrey T.
Richelson was able to learn even more about NRO quote. In 1969 as a result of an agreement between
the CIA and U.S. Navy an underwater counterpart to the NRO the National Underwater Reconnaissance
Office NRO was established with Secretary of the Navy John Warner as its first director. The office
served as a means of managing the conduct of submarine intelligence missions and exploitation
of their product. Those missions involved the recovery of sunken submarines the Soviet K-129
taping of the underwater Soviet communication cables the Ivy Bells aka the Declenson program
ocean floor mapping under a program named desktop an imagery and SIGINT collection from submarines
a program at one time designated the Special Navy Control Program end quote. Author Jeffrey T.
Richelson was even denied FOIA requests on NRO. From what we can learn the agency has deployed
several highly specialized ships and submarines including the USS Parsh, the Hughes Glomar
Explorer, the USS Halibut, the NR-1 and more recent the USS Jimmy Carter. Of particular note
is the United States first nuclear-powered submarine launched 1969 the same year as
Neuros founding and retired in 2008 the NR-1. This sub carried out numerous highly classified
missions including search, object recovery, geological survey, oceanographic research and
installation and maintenance of underwater equipment. One publicly acknowledged NR-1
mission occurred in 1976 with the recovery of an F-14 lost from an aircraft carrier.
Neuro seemingly performed operations to swarm a stranded Soviet submarine in 1981 in Swedish
waters. In response to statements made by former Secretary of Defense Casper Weinberger stating
Neuro submarine operations in Swedish waters were routine defense tests a senior US official said
I don't know why Weinberger said what he did. Covert submarine operations is the most secret
thing we have. The decisions were taken by a subcommittee of DIA and CIA people most likely
the National Underwater Reconnaissance Office but I will neither confirm nor deny any operation in
Swedish waters end quote. An additional high ranking CIA officer confirmed with the International
Peace Research Institute Oslo that US covert submarine retrieval operations were run in
Scandinavian waters by Neuro whilst directed by Secretary of the Navy John Layman from 1981 to
1987. Analyzing the inception of Neuro and the retrieval of the K-129 Soviet submarine as detailed
by Jeffrey Richardson we may gain some keen insights into the organization and their alleged
UFO retrieval missions. In Blind Man's Bluff the untold story of American submarine espionage
Neuro was established under CIA director Richard Helms to address the sinking of the Soviet
submarine K-129 outside of Hawaii in 1968. Though the office was intended to act between the CIA's
directorate of science and technology and office of naval intelligence quote from the day Neuro
was formed the CIA took charge end quote. Neuro has seemingly seen a tug of war of control through
the CIA and Navy but by 1972 the Navy regained some control of Neuro seen Secretary of the
Navy John Warner serve as its director. However through Neuro the Navy and CIA DS&Ts usage of
the Glomar Explorer may be worth analyzing more. To address K-129 the CIA built the ship the Glomar
Explorer mentioned above which launched in 1972 to recover the sub under project Jennifer aka
project Azorian. Astoundingly the ship carried a modern day price tag of 1.68 billion dollars.
I would like to thank medium author underscored for this great piece titled General Motors Glomar
Explorer Lockheed Martin and UAP connections his article will be in the video description.
The piece explores the Glomar Explorer being involved in hidden programs beyond the scope of
K-129 Soviet submarine recovery in 1974 and was additionally used for nearly two decades by
Lockheed Martin. Since the ship was a Neuro creation we can reasonably assume these clandestine
operations and Lockheed Martin's usage were conducted under Neuro. The article discussed how
in 1978 Ocean Minerals Company whose prime contractor was Lockheed Missiles and Space Company
now Lockheed Martin leased the Glomar Explorer for quote-unquote deep sea mining operation.
The question must be asked did Lockheed, Neuro and the Glomar additionally partake in these undersea
UFO retrievals? After all later in this project we will address a scintillating 1970s UFO crash
retrieval case in which the Glomar Explorer allegedly retrieved a downed non-human craft.
We will also discuss an incredible 1991 USO recovery in this project and touch on how I
believe Neuro provided transportation and logistics assets to the Navy's project Sand Dollar,
a clandestine highly compartmentalized project that was tasked to retrieve military sensitive
hardware and other items with national security importance from the seafloor of the continental
shelf in deepest marine environments. Sand Dollar seemingly gained actionable leverage when in 1964
Chief Scientist of the Special Projects Office of the US Navy Dr. John Pania Craven launched the
Deep Submergence Systems project which saw the Navy drastically improve deep sea engineering
and exploitation capabilities but much more on this later.
The most astonishing discussion of Neuro actually comes from a man mentioned dozens of times on this
channel who self-admittedly served as its director.
Thank you. I became the Director of Naval Intelligence 13 September 1974, brand new flag selectee that year.
I also had a second hat and they still don't want me to talk about it even now,
of Director of the National Underwater Reconnaissance Office.
Seeing it highly classified, that's the organization that procured all of the sensitive
reconnaissance systems to collect intelligence under the surface of the oceans.
Bobby Ray Inman allows us an extremely rare opportunity to understand naval UFO
slash USO legacy programs as well as the likely involvement of Neuro.
Inman served as a highly decorated four-star Admiral in the US Navy from 1951 to 1982,
while also serving as the NSA and CIA Director and Director of SAIC and Wackenhut.
Of course, if you are unfamiliar with these two companies, SAIC is a premier contractor I have
discussed and will discuss later in this video as being heavily involved with UFO legacy programs.
SAIC was likely the contractor described by former US Army Green Beret Randy Anderson as running the
off-world technologies division below the Naval Surface Warfare Center crane.
Wackenhut was a contracted security company I have covered before that has oftentimes been
implicated as providing industrial security forces who have guarded UFO-related SAP locations.
And of course, Inman's dual roles within US intelligence and the Navy
also suits an organization like Neuro perfectly.
Anyways, Inman states in the above clip he took a hold of the highly secretive Neuro in 1974.
Inman had only spoken publicly about Neuro once before in an October 2021 interview with David
Zerler, the Director of the Caltech Heritage Project. At this time, Inman served on Caltech's
Board of Trustees, to which he had been appointed in 1989 on the behalf of the Jet Propulsion
Laboratory, NASA and Congress. While discussing JPL's future as a productive national asset working
alongside NASA, Inman was reminded of his Navy and NSA days during his tenure in the National
Underwater Reconnaissance Program. According to Inman, Neuro served as a black program due
to its constant need to pursue evolving, cutting-edge technological capabilities
to outsmart adversaries. Later on in the interview, Inman touched on his role as Director
of Naval Intelligence and Director of Neuro, whose very existence was still classified.
In Inman's own words, he was harassed for even mentioning the office, quote,
In recent years when I talked about it, I got a pretty hot letter telling me I was not permitted
to talk in detail, since they were all still classified, end quote. According to Inman,
Neuro was in essence a black program that, quote,
So from Inman, the U.S. Intelligence Committee in Blind Man's Bluff, we can learn the Director of
Neuro dealt with technology acquisition and was also a high-ranking naval official ranging from
Secretary of the Navy to Director of Naval Intelligence. Also recall how Inman states he
was exposed to Neuro's Glomar Explorer in Hawaii. In 1974, the K-129 Soviet wreckage was picked up
1,560 miles northwest of Hawaii, however. Once again later in this project, I will bring up an
alleged UFO recovery in 1973, conducted by the Glomar in Hawaii. Could Inman possibly have been
involved in this retrieval in an official capacity? But why exactly are these words
from Admiral and former Neuro Director Bobby Ray Inman so important? I have spoken on this topic
quite a few times, but as this directly involves U.S. Navy UFO legacy programs, let's dive back in.
In 2022, on the Project Unity show, Inman claimed he had found, quote, unquote,
plausible explanations for all UAP sightings. In my years active service,
I became intrigued by the whole issue of UFOs. And as I dug into it,
I found there were plausible explanations for virtually everything that we had observed.
Until recently, with the openness of Admiral Timothy Gallaudet, naval officials quite often
denied the existence of UFOs. This dates all the way back to 1951, where the Office of Naval
Research physicist Ernest Liddell stated in a public magazine article that all UAP reports
were mirages or balloons. He stated trained observers were being fooled. These 2022 statements
by Inman contradict much of this man's storied history. I started out extremely skeptical about
this whole thing. I thought this was just rubbish from the tabloids, but I was surprised to find
thousands of U.S. government documents from intelligence agencies that tended to indicate
that there was a little bit more to this than met the eye. So I went to seek guidance from the
various highest levels of the United States intelligence community, and I was quite alarmed
at what I was able to learn. In this report that we're now going to show, we're going to hear a
conversation featuring you. Tell me the context of that conversation. Well, I had contacted
Admiral Bobby Ray Inman, who was the head of the National Security Agency in the United States,
deputy director at CIA, director of naval intelligence, and in a variety of intelligence
posts, a technologist and clearly someone that if this was really accurate, that there really were
UFOs and non-human intelligence around, this is a man who had to know. So I was able to contact him
thanks to contact through Admiral Lord Hill Norton here in the U.K. In this conversation,
he alarmingly not only indicated that these issues were covered under national secrecy laws,
but that the United States government did in fact have possession of the hardware associated
with this. In other words, this was an actual physical phenomenon as a craft, a spaceship,
several of them, and they were in operational condition, which I assume suggested that they
had been in contact, that they had been given these craft for some reason or another,
because they certainly weren't crashed vehicles. In a 1989 telephone call,
Admiral Bobby Ray Inman would tell NASA mission specialist Bob Eshler, deputy director of the CIA
DS&T, Everett Heineman, would be the best person to ask if recovered vehicles would be available
for technological research outside of military circles. To quote Inman in this call, quote,
The deputy director for science and technology at CIA is named Everett Heineman. He is in fact
getting ready to retire in the very near future. That may make him somewhat more willing to have
dialogues than he otherwise would have had. When I knew him in that period seven to ten years ago,
he was a person of very substantial integrity and just good common sense. So as a place to start,
he would clearly be high on the list, end quote. And we actually have recorded snippets of this
phone call between Eshler and Inman. Do you anticipate that any of the recovered
vehicles would ever become available for technological research outside of the military
circles? Ten years ago, the answer would have been whether as time has evolved, they're beginning to
become more open on it is a possibility. Eshler would go on to receive this call from Admiral Inman.
Mr. Eshler, this is Tom King in Admiral Inman's office.
Yes, you would be breaching confidence and or violation of the three laws and discussing
his involvement in any matter. Interesting how Inman, a former neuro director, would refer Eshler
to a CIA DS&T director for recovered anomalous vehicles. CIA DS&T was of course one half of the
founding agencies behind Neuro. To note, while Heineman served as CIA DS&T deputy director from
1979 to 1982, he would go on to direct Program B and the National Reconnaissance Program from
1982 to 1989. Possibly, this is where a neuro director and NRO program director first encountered
UFO legacy programs together. Heineman and Eshler arranged to meet at the CIA's headquarters in
Langley, Virginia, 10 August 1989. In this meeting, Heineman would deny any knowledge of UFO or UFO
legacy programs. However, in 2022, Twitter user RGH underscore UFOs would contact Heineman regarding
comments made by Inman that Heineman was knowledgeable on US UFO programs. In this instance,
Heineman did not deny but instead said quote, I am a long way and quite a few years from working in
the area you are researching end quote. Heineman would offer to answer any questions relating to
UFOs but never responded to RGH and as of this time, I have additionally attempted to contact
Heineman to no response. RGH's inquiries into UFO programs revolved around Heineman's time in the
NRO's Program B. As we just mentioned above, Program B served as the CIA's initiative to build
and operate satellites for SIGINT purposes. Heineman was the first chief of the facility for
the ground element of the program in Pine Gap, Australia. It is fascinating to think Heineman
could have been working on UFO legacy programs in the 1980s out of the illustrious and infamous
Pine Gap for a joint CIA and NRO program. More pertinent to our investigation today,
Inman would additionally connect Eschler with another former Director of Naval Intelligence,
Sumner Shapiro. It is unknown if like Inman, Shapiro served on the NRO. In 1989, Eschler met
Shapiro under the pretense he was interested in working with a group that managed UFO information
and at this time, Shapiro was retired as Director of Naval Intelligence and served as an executive
with BDM International. BDM is of course a former defense contractor purchased by Northrop Grumman,
I directly accused of being involved with UFO legacy programs. Shapiro told Eschler,
factions within the US possess extraterrestrial vehicles, that he, Shapiro, had even studied at
close quarters. According to the former DNI, teams would take the craft apart, pack them up,
and ship them around the country to different laboratories. These craft featured unique
interlocking components that had to be disassembled in an exact sequence to be put back together.
However, Shapiro was incredibly careful with what information he divulged to Eschler,
never specifying where vehicles and technology were taken to protect classified information.
Eschler would meet Shapiro for a second time in the Admiral's Virginia home in 1990. This visit was
far less actionable and concluded abruptly. According to Bob Eschler, as relayed by author
Timothy Goode,
But before we move on from discussing Eschler and insights he gained from senior naval officials,
Eschler would also claim Navy EMP experiments were utilized out of Pensacola Naval Air Station to
down UFOs for retrievals. These involved Empress and Empress II on board EMP generators.
Inman and Shapiro are not the only naval officials who have spoken on UFO legacy programs.
In 2021, now deceased former Navy Director of Science and Technology Development,
Nats Kobitz, told Ross Coulthart he was, during his service, read into a Navy UFO crash retrieval and
reverse engineering program. Although Kobitz didn't actively engage with TUO or Technologies
of Unknown Origin, he was read into an active program that had retrieved multiple UAP.
For many years, for over 30 years. And sadly, when I caught up with him, he was dying from cancer.
And fate dictated that I caught him at the perfect time. And over several months, he finally opened
up to me about what he was on his own admission, read into. He was briefed on the program. And he
told me that he had been read into a classified program involving retrieved non-human technology,
recovered alien spacecraft. He eventually admitted that he was officially briefed that America had
retrieved multiple non-human craft. And that he was aware there was a secret operation underway
for decades, in his words, to undertake to reverse engineer them. He admitted that most of what he
knew was effectively hearsay, although from some excellent official sources. This is something he'd
been briefed into in his official capacity. He did admit that on one occasion he was flown to Wright
Patterson Air Force Base, literally taken deep underground, taken to a secure room and shown
what looked like some kind of bulkhead from a craft, which he believed was constructed in a way
that defied conventional explanation. The craft's skin and inner bulkhead were composites bonded at
an atomic level. He suspected it was non-human intelligence technology. But being the scientist
he was, infuriatingly, he wouldn't say to me it was alien tech. He would just say it was something
he had never seen that any human could make. Nat was a patriot. He was a decent, honorable public
servant. He respected the fact this program was being kept secret for a reason. But as a scientist,
he also recognized that the American public, and especially Congress, had the right to know
what was being done with taxpayer dollars. And he frankly told me that as far as he knew,
there was no good justification for keeping it secret.
Remember all the way back to Chris Sharpe's mysterious reporting on USO legacy programs
involving the CIA, DS&T, Navy, Neuro, SOCOM, and others. To quote Chris in the third iteration of
the article, quote, it is further understood that the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution has
provided deep submergence vehicles to support these retrieval efforts, end quote. Woods Hole,
or WHOI, as I will call them here, is quote, dedicated to advancing knowledge of the ocean
and its connection with the earth systems through a sustained commitment to excellence in science,
engineering, and education, and to the application of this knowledge to problems facing society,
end quote. The nonprofit research and higher education facility is dedicated to the study
of marine science and engineering. During the Cold War, 1985 to be exact, the US Navy deployed
a classified mission to investigate the wreckage of the USS Thresher and USS Scorpion,
which had sunk in the North Atlantic Ocean at depths of between 10,000 and 15,000 feet.
Sounds like a neuro investigation, no? Well, this mission led to the discovery of the wreck
of the Titanic. The operational team and vessel that discovered the RMS Titanic was from Woods
Hole. WHOI employs a host of highly advanced underwater vehicles that include human-occupied
submersibles, remote-controlled vehicles, autonomous and towed robots. These include
the AUV-centric autonomous exploration vehicle capable of exploring depths of nearly 20,000 feet
or 6,000 meters, the HOV Alvin, a three-person research submersible, and the HOV Deep Sea
Challenger, used by filmmaker James Cameron. WHOI works closely with US military, specifically the
Navy, where it develops technology including ocean battlespace sensors, unmanned undersea
vehicles, and acoustic navigation and comms systems. As a matter of fact, going back decades,
Woods Hole was involved with the Atomic Energy Commission, the precursor to the Department of
Energy that highly likely housed UFO legacy programs while also serving as the gatekeepers
for UFO data and materials, misclassifying such as trans-classified foreign nuclear material.
From 1948 to 1949, a gentleman named William Webster served on the Military Liaison Committee
for the Atomic Energy Commission. Webster was not only a member of the Massachusetts Institute of
Technology Corporation but was also a trustee of the Rand Corporation and Woods Hole Oceanographic
Institute. WHOI even manages the Navy Oceanographic Research Laboratory for the Department of the Navy.
This WHOI lab is now part of the Naval Research Laboratory, NRL. However,
the National Oceanographic Research Laboratory was formed by a Federal Contract Research Center,
or FCRC, the precursor to FFRDC, which I talk about quite often. Present day, Woods Hole also
manages projects for the Office of Naval Research, such as Project Sundance. In fact, since 2002,
Woods Hole has been awarded over $3.4 billion in federal awards in the form of contracts,
subcontracts, and grants. Analyzing such contracts, we can find some data of extreme
interest, such as National Defense R&D Services with the Naval Surface Warfare Center,
whose crane division I have directly accused runs an underground installation with Science
Applications International Corporation housing the Off-World Technologies Division. Historically,
WHOI has been awarded these contracts by NSWC via sole-source contracts, a contract method Dr.
Eric Davis has spoken of, that are used in UFO legacy programs to maintain compartmentalization
in secrecy. Woods Hole is given such sole-source, indefinite delivery contracts because, quote,
the government believes that the supplier has unique capabilities that cannot be otherwise
obtained, end quote. And speaking of SAIC, Woods Hole has also been granted R&D contracts with SAIC
and NSWC Crane Weapons Systems Division, JXN. But it doesn't stop there. Woods Hole has been given
numerous indefinite delivery, indefinite quantity NSWC contracts to build, fabricate, integrate,
evaluate, and support unmanned undersea vehicles, specifically for the Naval Undersea Warfare Center
installations. And now we finally get to the most interesting part of this video, a deep-sea
USO recovery experience that ties together much of what we have discussed on today's episode.
This story first appeared on Art Bell's Coast to Coast call-in episode on 19 April 2002,
and I plan on using clips of the audio here. However, if people would be interested in fully
released audio where I work with a 3D artist to recreate the encounter, please let me know.
On this live radio call-in show, Art Bell was contacted by a retired Marine Corps Lieutenant
Colonel. The caller, first named Mark, had been assigned to 22 Area Camp Pendleton to work with
the first air delivery unit before being stationed at Okinawa, Japan at the Fatima USMC air station.
It was here he began doing rescue diving work on weekends alongside a Navy crew.
Mark would form a friendship with a lieutenant in the Navy who would go on to become a commander
of a DSRV or Deep Submergence Rescue Vehicle Unit. The friendship I made later came back that
I was assigned or requested to join this DSRV unit and did and was reassigned to Virginia.
And basically what we did was deep sea rescue and recovery. If we had a downed aircraft,
we would go and try to rig the craft to get it back. Anything, any anomalies that we wanted to
look at, basically we were sent. There were several teams that did the same thing we did.
How deep did you go? We could go two miles, excess miles. You're pretty much pushing it.
This particular incident I wanted to tell you about was about a mile.
You're saying you could go over 10,000 feet? Yes.
Wow. All right. Anyway, go ahead.
Well, I'll say the particular incident we were involved in, we were
just under a mile and a half of water, North Atlantic.
The specific mention of DSRV is critical to this entire investigation. The United States created
two deep submergence rescue vehicles that operated within the US Navy from 1970 to 2008.
Mystic DSRV-1 and Avalon DSRV-2 were products of the Lockheed Missile and Space Company in
Sunnyvale, California. DSRVs are to this day, some of the most technologically advanced
submersibles in the entire world. These two vehicles were capable of deploying anywhere
in the world, transported within a truck, C-5 Galaxy, or naval vessel to piggyback
efficient routes to rescue crews of stranded submarines within 72 hours.
These highly advanced submersibles employed a guidance system more complex than Apollo 11's,
allowing the DSRVs to hover in place in strong ocean currents to mate with disabled submarines.
The Navy conducted numerous exercises with DSRVs 1 and 2, but no official rescues were ever conducted.
And this is due to no American subs sinking since 1971. In 1972, saw the introduction of DSRVs 1
It is interesting to note, DSRV was born from 1964's Deep Submergence Systems Project, DSSP,
to increase and develop the Navy's deep ocean engineering capabilities.
The project was initially founded out of the Navy's Special Program Office,
and DSRV's launch date of 70-71 dovetails closely with the beginning of Neuro in 1969.
Interesting how the DSSP was also founded partly out of the loss of the USS Thresher,
the same sub Woods Hole was attempting to find when it discovered the Titanic.
If this story is true, this means DSRV, Mystic, and Avalon's practice missions
were really to retrieve underwater aircraft and vehicles.
And this is most likely fact, as Dr. John Pena Craven, Chief Scientist of the Special Program's
Office of the Navy and first head of the DSSP wrote regarding DSRV and classified operations,
There were many highly classified missions associated with national security that could
not be accomplished without a DSRV system. The specific operational needs of these
missions could not be anticipated, but they were certain to occur.
Thus, a DSRV designed, constructed, and deployed for every conceivable rescue mission
would also be available for the intelligence mission impossible that were sure to occur.
Craven's words here are particularly interesting. In 1964, Craven was tasked with spearheading the
Deep Submergence Systems Project, which led to the creation of the DSRV and other deep clandestine
subs, like the NR-1, to respond to unprecedented events at dramatically extended operational
depths. In 1965, Craven was given a high-level intelligence briefing by a naval intelligence
officer and was informed on the existence of an extremely sensitive program named Sand Dollar.
From Craven's book, The Silent War, The Cold War Battle Beneath the Sea, we get a rare chance
to learn more about this program. Sand Dollar was tasked to retrieve militarily sensitive
hardware and other items with national security importance from the seafloor of the continental
shelf in deep marine environment. According to The Silent War, Sand Dollar was buried within
the structure of yet another secret program, itself hidden within the Polaris subprogram.
This hierarchy and compartmentalization of programs is something we have observed
extensively in the Wilson Davis notes and throughout our investigation today.
Craven even wrote the program is still classified to this day, that being 2002,
quote, I was shown an inventory, itemizing the items to be known on the seabed and a map of
their distribution throughout the world, end quote. To expand on this statement, quote,
The salvageable items of interest were spread around the globe. There were plenty of interesting
objects on ocean floors worldwide, not just in the Bermuda Triangle, and there was an equal
distribution of these objects between those that were lying on the continental shelf and those in
deep oceans. There was a skew in favor of the continental shelf because of the shallow water,
rocks, and shoals, but much of that hardware had either been salvaged or scattered by storms,
end quote. Craven would even discuss two vessels previously mentioned to have been used in
operational capacity by the Neuro, the Halibut and Sea Wolf. Craven claimed there was no need
for maximum security for these submarines because they themselves, quote, they only transported
top secret equipment and teams of industry specialists who would carry out unknown missions
in unknown parts of the sea. The performers and the performances were invisible, end quote.
As we explore this undersea recovery with DSRV units, we can now study the case with a strong
thesis in mind. Chief scientist John Craven was tasked by the U.S. Navy to drastically increase
naval deep sea diving and engineering capabilities to retrieve undersea objects discovered by an
astoundingly compartmented program called Sand Dollar. Craven's 1964 Deep Submergence Systems
project would lead to the creation of clandestine submersibles that were capable of retrieving,
quote, unquote, items of interest from the sea floor. Some of these submersibles, such as the DSRV
units, would be shuttled via motherships, including Neuros, Halibut and Sea Wolf.
So now the question must be asked, was Sand Dollar the Navy's first UFO legacy program
designated with the discovery, monitoring and retrieval of UFOs? After all, Craven would state,
quote, could I organize and manage a program to carry out this mission using the assets of the
DSSP? Furthermore, could I carry it out in such a manner that my family and friends and closest
professional colleagues would have no idea that I was involved in such a project? End quote.
From the DSSP, the Navy planned to build six DSRV units and additional DSRVs known as Deep
Submergence Search Vehicles, DSSVs, that were never officially built outside of Mystic and Avalon.
These DSSV DSRVs were intended for sea floor exploration and recovery and to be capable of
clandestine operations with an operational depth of 20,000 feet. So while we dive into Mark's
story, I do think it is possible he and his Navy unit were assigned to a DSSV, not the two
acknowledged Mystic and Avalon DSRVs. If this is the case, no such vessel in which Mark was operating
was ever publicly acknowledged to have been built. But back to the story, our story takes place in
the early summer of 1991 at a depth of roughly 1.5 miles in the North Atlantic 250 nautical miles
or roughly 288 standard miles outside of Aberdeen, Scotland. Looking at 250 nautical mile radius
outside of Aberdeen compared with the Atlantic Ocean depths, we can draw a reasonable estimate
of where this retrieval incident would have taken place. Let us also account for some error in Mark's
estimate and give a generous plus or minus 20% room for error in radius here. Therefore,
our radius could be up to 50 nautical miles larger, so we have a standard radius of 345
standard miles. And folks using the superior metric system here, I am sorry guys. Waters in
the Atlantic near the UK are actually quite shallow, however, 345 miles almost due west of
Aberdeen sees depths reaching over 8,000 feet, which is over our mile and a half claim. This area
of ocean is known as the Rockall Trough, east of the Rockall Plateau. Hopefully further data can
come from this very specific location at which this retrieval is alleged to have occurred.
Mark's DSRV crew had been sent from Virginia and as we know from a 2011 Nuclear Regulatory
Commission emails detailing the tsunamis in Japan, both the east and west coast of the United States
had employed a quote, very operational ready deep submergence rescue vehicle, end quote.
On the DSRV, Mark served to operate computer equipment on the optical and electronic recognition
side and also worked on mechanical aspects of the vessel with mechanical arms and rigging for object
retrieval. Mark's team was dispatched after a survey vessel in the North Atlantic had picked
up a radioactive signature on the seafloor. A second vessel equipped with a side scan determined
a vessel to be resting on the seafloor. Naval authorities thought this to be a crashed foreign
nuclear submarine. However, the radar signature had shown the object to be smaller than any
known nuclear sub. Upon diving, Mark's DSRV attempted to contact the vessel and immediately
realized this was not a sub, but shaped more like an aircraft.
The vessel came back, it was much too small to be any sub that they were familiar with
and at that time we came on site. But you were getting some kind of nuclear signature from it?
Right, there's residual radiation from it and the concern was was it a weapon, some type of
concealed weapon source or was it actually a power source? Right. And we were brought out
from Virginia, steamed out, and not to give you specific minutes, seconds, location, just
approximately 250 miles out of Aberdeen, Scotland is where we were. You can draw a circle and
narrow it down pretty quick. At that depth you can limit the waters. Yes, sir. But upon diving,
we went down, like I said, just under a mile and a half and we contacted the vessel,
which we immediately recognized not as a submarine but more of an aircraft.
Communications back to the top, we were told to go observe, photograph, determine what we have.
We thought at that point we had possibly a Russian or Korean aircraft with some type of
contained weapon source. So we went in. Yeah, that would be logical. We went in and this
particular vessel was partially in the mud, submerged or buried under some mud, had been
there for some period of time. And how much were you, what were you seeing of it? What shape?
What we saw was the, I would say the rear two-thirds. It was a triangular shape. It was
wedged more. Triangular. And best way I could describe it, it would be nosed in with about
two-thirds exposed to the back. Yes, sir. And as you come out, the triangular shape at the back,
it was rounded as it came to the corner, what would be the corner of the triangle,
they were rounded on both sides. Oh, really? Obviously not a conventional aircraft.
Well, one comment was made in the DSRV, the Lieutenant Commander is also a good friend,
was my comment was, I don't believe it's Russian. And his comment was, if it is,
it's not Russia right now, you know, joking. And what, you know, the best way I can describe it,
it was a charcoal gray in color. It had some markings on the side. Sir, listen, I'm coming
to a break at the top of the hour. Can you manage to hold on? I can, if you'd like, yes.
I would like, yes. Stay right there, all right? You located this craft, which was a triangular
in shape, and you were seeing the back portion of it. Right, at this point, we'd come over
almost what you, I would best describe as broadside to the craft. The nose, what I would
determine is the nose end was submerged in mud. Mark and his crew had no matching craft or pattern
to cross reference this craft. The 60 to 70 foot charcoal gray triangle with smooth edges,
no windows, rivets, seams or bolts, a rounded rear and hieroglyphic writing along the side
did not lead the crew to suspect terrestrial origins. Mark and his Lieutenant Colonel friend
both thought the craft to be extraterrestrial, but did not relay this to the surface out of fear of
psych evaluations and to not risk communication interception. The surface LPH vessel ordered the
DSRV unit to return with still photography and video of the craft. We do need to quickly address
the markings on the side of the craft that Mark relayed. And there were markings on the side of it
which were in the in the skin itself. And how would you describe those markings?
You know, and I've heard this before, people try to say hieroglyphics and all of this. It was not
a, it was not any language or marking which we would typically see, Russian, Arabic, nothing
we were trained or had seen previously. But hieroglyphic-like. Well, I'll say
hieroglyphic-like, but more geometric patterns. There weren't large walking individuals with bird
heads. And, you know, I think of hieroglyphics, I think of individuals with a head like a bird
or a wolf and then human body just didn't have those type of patterns. It was more geometric
shapes, but you could tell some of the actual characters repeated. Quite a bit of it was
in mud and then there would be gaps throughout the mud that you could see some repeating of
the character. I have covered in great detail the high confidence 1965 Kecksburg, Pennsylvania
crash retrieval in which numerous town residents observed U.S. military forces retrieve and
transport a 12-foot acorn-like bronze craft. Many such witnesses described hieroglyphic-style
writing around the circumference of the lower lip of the craft. And additionally, Danny Sheehan has
stated in the classified project bluebook files, he has seen images of a crashed UFO saucer that
displayed geometric hieroglyphic-style characters along its circumference. This is a fascinating
detail and connection to these other cases. After 12 hours of waiting after returning to the surface,
the DSRV crew was ordered to dive again, this time taking a marine archaeologist. The archaeologist
made sketches of the craft and even traveled down with his own personal computer. Where did
this go from there? I mean now you've got this thing ID'd, were you suddenly out of the picture
or? Well we're in the picture up to the point where we're rigging and recovering.
As I said, we took down a marine archaeologist and one thing that was very interesting,
that this individual, we actually monitored currents, did some things, temperatures and such
at the site. He was making quite a bit of notes and you know really not making a lot of comment,
but he did make the comment when we asked you know is this recent because there was no
disturbed area around it, best way to describe it. It looked like it had been in place
and he said that it wasn't any more recent than at least 30 to 40 years,
which really threw us back because this thing looked like something beyond you know where we're
at development-wise aircraft and I still hadn't ruled out that it was not experimental aircraft
at this point, someone's. But the point that he made that the buildup of the silt mud in the front
end would appear that this has probably been in place for a period of 30 years or somewhere in
the range 30 to 40 years. And you have, was there an attempt made at recovery? There was a recovery
made, not an attempt made, there was a recovery made of the craft. What do you know about that?
On the third day of the operation, the DSRV crew dove for a fourth time, this time to
retrieve the craft. The team first used thrusters to remove silt and mud from the craft's midsection
so Mark and others could attach equipment to try and lift the vehicle. Immediate problems arose as
this crashed USO did not fall under the same procedures and weight estimations used for
conventional aircraft. Due to this, the DSRV crew had to make size and base weight estimations.
The craft's weight estimations was based on the closest size conventional aircraft, the F-14.
We had thrusted away a lot of the silt mud from the vehicle. Still had a section,
probably about eight foot, that was trapped or under depth. It was more of an angle to it.
So when we rigged it to bring it up rear first, use the best language I can. We were going to
try to lift the rear end up and bring this thing up on an angle and try to keep everything intact
and go. We're rigging it with our calculation for the rigging and the weight, brought it up and
it went probably about two and a half to three times the ascent as what we anticipated,
which immediately gave us a feel that we're dealing with something extremely light.
Trailing the craft as it ascended, the DSRV crew noticed the underside of the craft was completely
smooth. No piping, exhaust or mechanical features existed on the underbelly of the triangle. When
the vehicle was recovered, Mark got a clear look at the craft. It proved to be six to eight feet
longer than an F-14 at 62 feet, meaning this craft was 68 to 70 feet long. Mark stated nothing like
that existed in 1991 and as of the show in 2002, still nothing like that existed. The craft was a
solid metal form with no cockpit and no windows. It was a little bit longer than the aircraft would
be, probably six to eight feet, I would say, in excess of what you would anticipate for an F-14.
Colonel, a straight out question is, do you believe that you recovered an alien craft?
I've had conversations with the individual, my friend that actually was there, we're still in
contact quite often. I can't definitively say that it was. I can only say that it was
an object that didn't belong there and certainly would not have belonged there
30 or 40 years prior to when we were on site and no visible means of, you know, if you
anticipated it was an aircraft and I saw a cockpit, I would say it was definitely somebody here that
was in development, but technology would not allow you to fly craft 30 or 40 years ago.
Within four hours, Mark and his entire crew were steamed off site. Mark received no feedback or
debriefing on what the vehicle was, nor did he and his crew receive any threats or warnings
not to speak about the incident. However, Mark did state when he joined the DSRV team, he was
ordered to sign some pretty lengthy NDAs. As we know from Dr. Craven and DSRV for clandestine usage,
this does not come as a shock. Mark would be subject to such intense secrecy regarding his
work on the DSRV. Mark stated even if the DSRV retrieved a U.S. vehicle, they were not allowed
to discuss. Art Bell got the original sketches of the retrieval by the naval lieutenant colonel
and Mark told Bell he would connect him with the naval officer. I am still trying to chase down
this case with the help of some high-profile naval officials. More investigation does need
to be done on this case since officially DSRV's Mystic and Avalon had an operational depth of
just over one mile and it would be unusual to employ USMC divers for the time. For this reason,
I do think back to the 1964 proposal of six DSRV and DSSV under the Deep Submergence Systems
project where only DSRV's 1 and 2 were built. Remember back to the words of Dr. John P. Craven,
chief scientist of the Navy Special Projects Office who discussed many classified operations
were performed by DSRV teams. I do think it possible DSRV units outside of Mystic and Avalon
were built with capabilities akin to the DSSV units. 20,000 foot operational depth capacity
with a greater capability for seafloor navigation and object retrieval. And it is interesting of
course to point out the 1964 Deep Submergence Systems project DSSP which aimed to increase
and develop the Navy's deep ocean engineering capabilities for Project Sand Dollar which resulted
in the creation of DSRV occurred just two years after the October 1962 Bluegill Triple Prime US
Navy UFO recovery. Additionally, this case piqued my interest due to the presence of a crash triangle
so often in my videos I discuss many triangular sightings being alien reproduction vehicles.
Whether this be the TR-3B XF-131 Super Sentinel or a long list of prototypes I have wagered to be
built in the late 70s into the early 2000s, I believe the U.S. saw heavy clandestine
experimentation within USAPs to build triangular shaped alien reproduction vehicles. But this
triangular case harkens my attention back to the alleged Special Operations 1 Majestic 12 manual.
In this piece, the SOM-101 allegedly written in 1952, details are given to extraterrestrial craft
types including triangles which according to the document were very new and very rare at the time.
The DSRV retrieved the triangle allegedly in 1991. The marine archaeologists claimed the triangle
had been buried for 30 to 40 years, meaning the crash likely occurred between 1951 and 1961.
Interesting how this date range coincides with the Majestic 12 Special Operations manual,
claiming new triangular extraterrestrial vehicles were being spotted at the time of the 1954 manual.
If these retrieval events are true and the inside sources of Chris Sharpe are correct,
water-based USO and UFO recoveries are stationed at naval installations and locations of the Office
of Naval Research, where they are then utilized in material exploitation programs. Let us review
some cases and testimony throughout history of downed craft stored at naval installations.
We will reference numerous sources here, including the latest data from the USAP,
we will reference numerous sources here, including the legendary Leonard Stringfield,
whose work I referenced often in my dumb video. Stringfield's crash retrieval status reports 1
through 7 are in my opinion the best crash retrieval work done by any investigator.
I will also omit stories of China Lake and the testimony of Randy Anderson and the
off-world technologies division, as I have covered these stories and installations and
experiences in depth in the past. Leonard Stringfield was once contacted by letter in
1978, tipping him off to Derward Buddy Hack, a CPO radar observer who in 1952 while stationed
at the Naval Air Station Sunnyvale, California, disappeared out of sight. While serving at the
naval installation, Hack, according to his family, accidentally entered a large door of a hangar that
was temporarily unguarded. There, he encountered a massive saucer-shaped craft with rows of windows,
and when the guards returned, they forced Hack out and threatened him. Stringfield contacted
multiple members of Hack's family, who confirmed hearing the story, including his mother, who not
only confirmed Hack's disappearance, but also the saucer story. Hack's mother would hear him say,
it was certainly no aircraft of ours. In 1979, 6 February 1979 to be exact,
Stringfield received a letter from one Joan Jeffers. Jeffers stated she knew a retired
Ustav Colonel who enlisted in the 40s and retired in the 70s. While stationed at an Air Force radar
facility, the Colonel would attend weekly commander's calls at the Naval Air Station in New Brunswick,
At one such meeting in 1956, the Colonel was shown a film by Major Lester Goldberg that was apparently
shot by the USAAF. Interesting side note here, one Major Lester Goldberg did in fact serve at the
Brunswick Naval Air Station at this time and was the commanding officer of the 654 Aircraft Control
and Warning Squadron. The film showed a circular metal silver colored disc on the ground. The
interior of the craft was well lit and featured smooth walls. The film also showed at least three
bodies lying on tables. The beans were short and they all looked similar in appearance,
featuring a sheen or gray color. None of the beans had any external ears or hair,
all appeared to be dead. Further sources of Stringfield, like the anonymous Lieutenant
Colonel X, would even state the Navy housed biologics. Such as in 1975, when Lieutenant
Colonel X claimed, quote, bodies are now being flown outside of the US to a secret naval
installation on an island in the Pacific Ocean, end quote. Now the US Navy does employ multiple
DoD Laboratories and MRTFBs or Major Range and Test Facility Bases in the Atlantic and Pacific
Oceans. These include the Atlantic Undersea Test and Evaluation Center on the Andros Island,
Bahamas, and Pacific Missile Range Facility in Hawaii. There is also incredible research
I plan to explore in the future conducted by Dr. Richard Sauter that similar to deep underground
military bases, the US Navy employs deep underwater military bases. And those familiar with my
discussion of MRTFB will recall such installations as Dugway Proving Ground, Edwards 412th Test Wing,
NAWC China Lake, Fort Hachuca, the Nevada Test and Training Range, and more. Lieutenant Colonel X
also brought forward an interesting connection to the Majestic 12 Special Operations Manual,
which claims deceased biologics were taken to the Wright-Patterson Blue Room while living
entities were taken to the OpNAC BBS-01. Some have guessed OpNAC is similar to OpNav, which is
the Office of the Chief of Naval Operations, while BBS is the Bermuda Biological Station,
an Atlantic-based installation now called BIOS. In Crash Retrieval Status Reports 3, Case 15B,
Stringfield relayed a cat and mouse game with Witness AF and his brother Pete. This story took
place at the Naval Air Base Yuma, Arizona, now called the Marine Corps Air Station Yuma,
which is directly near Yuma Proving Ground. If you remember back to my video on Dums,
the US Army Corps of Engineers took a tremendous interest in building underground installations
beneath Yuma County, Arizona. This case in question really frustrated Stringfield.
What seemed to be a case of great potential, including the emergence of photographs of a
saucer in military custody, became less so with the passing of time. Following a series of alleged
interferences, my sources said they feared even greater consequences and backed off into oblivion.
Stringfield reckoned this case to either be a ploy or example of the lengths legacy operations
will go to silence informants. Witness Pete, a former US Marine, claimed to have photographed
a saucer-like craft at the naval installation in Yuma, Arizona in 1967. Stringfield tried for
months to meet Pete and his brother AF and organized to receive the photos by mail. AF
even claimed to have sent numerous letters to Stringfield that were likely intercepted.
Stringfield would speak to the men on the phone and learn Pete had been approached by some sort
of agency to stay quiet. An intriguing case to mention, but a massive dead end for both
Leonard Stringfield and us. Our most fruitful case in Stringfield's status reports can be
found in UFO crash retrieval status reports 3 under case A7. This case takes us to the Great
Lakes Naval Base in Northern Illinois in 1973. While we discuss this case, do keep in mind the
Office of Naval Research has a major Chicago department less than 40 miles away from the
Great Lakes Naval Station. Our encounter comes from one witness R.K., an E4 grade instructor
in gunnery school at the Great Lakes Naval Base from March 1973 to September 1974,
destined for intelligence school. I myself am aware of R.K.'s true name and am trying to vet
this individual. On 14 July 1980, R.K. came to the House of Stringfield and relayed his encounter.
In September 1973, while instructor in gunnery school, R.K. was assigned to guard the premises
of a large quonset hut at Great Lakes Naval Base with orders not to let anybody within 100 yards.
While on duty, R.K. was approached by a naval officer who handed him a sealed envelope to
deliver to the commander in the quonset hut. Entering the facility, R.K. observed a strange
metallic craft 30 feet in length and 10 feet in height resting on a wooden platform. According
to R.K., quote, it was light silvery blue and shimmering. It tapered like a teardrop with a
flange running along its topside from one end to the other and there were no windows, end quote.
R.K. could not linger in the hut due to the presence of other guards. Thus, he delivered
the envelope and returned to his post. R.K.'s encounter bore striking resemblance to the
testimony of a sailor he had met in San Diego just weeks prior whilst on special assignment.
According to this sailor, a UFO identical to the one R.K. would observe in the coming weeks at the
Great Lakes Naval Station was shot down by the Navy between Hawaii and the mainland in June of
1973. This UFO was picked up via destroyer's radar and came into view making three close passes and
one direct overflight over the destroyer. According to the sailor, the UFO was shot with a lucky hit
and crashed into a 350 foot deep water. The San Diego sailor claimed the object was retrieved by
the Glomar Explorer and shipped to Hawaii and sent stateside and finally to Chicago.
The sailor even provided R.K. a sketch that was identical to what he had seen.
But just hold on a second here. The claims of the Glomar Explorer retrieving the craft
are of significant consequence here. Glomar was run by Neuro, a joint naval and CIA DS&T effort.
If this story is true, this means the Navy, CIA and intelligence organizations such as Neuro
downed a UFO and retrieved it from sea. The craft was then shipped to an ONR location
where due to being guarded on a wooden platform was likely destined for further transport and study.
This incident mirrors perfectly the 2024 claims of Chris Sharpe's informants.
Other cases of naval bases and the Office of Naval Research possessing both information of crash
disks and the materials themselves are plenty. In 1994, former New Mexico State Rep J. Andrew
Kissner stated sources within White Sands Proving Ground and the Naval Research Lab
briefed him on recovered flying disks in 1947. These disks were given to the custody of the
Atomic Energy Commission and studied by national laboratories such as Los Alamos, Sandia, Rand,
MITRE, etc. This is very similar to my modern-day hypothesis of DOE working alongside FFRDC
and UARC to exploit UFO materials. According to Kissner's naval sources, the UFO programs were
signed into presidential executive order under Truman in 1948 with the National Security Council
serving as program coordinator. With support from the Air Force Systems Command, the Research and
Development Board ran by Dr. Vannevar Bush in the Naval Research Lab. Interesting to note as well,
in 2005, USAAF veteran Stephen Walker would claim while serving at the Naval Support Facility in
Diego Garcia, he was exposed to the Navy conducting sensitive operations outside of a large hangar at
the northern end of the airfield. Base personnel were ordered to stay away from this quote-unquote
empty hangar. One night while the flight line was evacuated, the base was locked down and personnel
were ordered to stay inside, away from windows, for the arrival of a classified aircraft. Walker
claimed that despite listening for the craft for nearly half an hour, he heard no jet engine, no
brakes, no tires hitting the pavement, no idling, or no Air Force sounds. This experience is very
interesting when analyzing the claims of Master Sergeant Edgar Fouchet, who claimed UFO programs
were moved out of Area 51 in the early 90s because of intensive scrutiny from the public on Groom Lake.
UFOs, especially the TR-3B reverse engineered triangle programs, were relocated to various
installations including Dugway Proving Ground and Diego Garcia.
Special Navy Control Program
I must now circle back to early discussion of Neuro and reference back to U.S. Intelligence
Committee and discussion of Imigent and Sigint collection from submarines. A program at one
time designated the Special Navy Control Program. Special Navy Control Program is quite similar to
something called the Navy Special Program, or NSP. The NSP is a highly elusive naval office that's
similar to Neuro we can only find snippets of. The first ever mention I can find of the Navy
Special Program is in a 1974 Omnibus National Security Council Intelligence Directive alongside
the NRO. Remember, the NRO was not declassified until 1992, so this mention of the National
Reconnaissance Program, which is the direct funding mechanism for the NRO, is likely to
obfuscate the program. But what exactly is this Navy Special Program mentioned alongside the
National Reconnaissance Program, especially in the context of this NSCID, not wanting to
bring undue attention to both of these programs? Now, since Neuro was created between the Navy
and CIA DS&T, you may think Navy Special Program refers to Neuro. However, the Navy Special Program
is itself a very real office. Indeed, the Navy Special Program Office serves as an umbrella
control system for several naval clandestine undersea operations. However, in this context
and due to the extreme secrecy of Neuro to this day, as highlighted by Inman, Neuro could have
certainly been rolled under the NSP. To further this thesis, we can look back to an 11 December
1975 declassified memo for the Deputy Director of Central Intelligence and others. Here we get a keen
look at the organizational structure of the Navy Special Program. The Navy Special Program was once
designated to run parallel to the National Reconnaissance Programmer NRO under the Executive
Committee for the Director of Central Intelligence and the Assistant Secretary for Defense for
Intelligence. Someone really ought to ask Christopher Mellon about the Navy Special Program,
seen as he himself served as former ASD slash I. The NSP, according to this memorandum, serves to
act for intelligence collection, similar to the NRO, DIA, or CIA. Having previously detailed the
duties of Neuro, I do think this description means Neuro is likely hidden within the NSP here,
especially given the time frame 1975, where throughout our investigation we see Neuro's
activities really ramping up from its creation in 1969 throughout the 70s. Therefore, with the
Navy Special Program acting as an umbrella office for numerous Navy clandestine operations,
including possibly housing Neuro, it is no stretch to theorize a program that conducts undersea
retrievals of anomalous craft alongside Neuro that sends such vehicles to the Office of Naval
Research Locations. To then be studied by federal elements and defense contractors would be hidden
within the NSP. These operations would be compartmented and rolled under the Navy Special
Program Office. This process for Naval UFO legacy programs would likely remain the same today.
After all, as of 26 May 2023, we can find requests for approval for Special Access Program facilities
by the Navy Special Program Central Office. Naval legacy programs hidden within the NSP for
extensive classification and compartmentalization carry sound logic, especially when factoring in
statements of former Rear Admiral Tim Gallaudet. Admiral Gallaudet has spoken on Congressional
Record that whilst he is aware of testimony of Naval UFO legacy programs, he did not directly
encounter them or was not briefed during his prestigious position within the Navy. We can
find one intriguing acknowledged CIA program that likely utilized the Navy Special Program,
Project Palladium and its director, Samuel Gene Poteet. Poteet served at the NRO,
CIA DS&T, as well as served as the technical director of the Navy Special Program Office,
where he provided Naval Reconnaissance Systems expertise for the CIA Directorate of Science
and Technology. Poteet was a senior central intelligence agency scientific intelligence
officer, inventor, teacher, and association executive. He, quote, provided scientific
expertise on space and naval reconnaissance systems in the Directorate of Science and
Technology and served at the National Reconnaissance Office as technical director of the Navy Special
Programs Office, and as the executive director of the Intelligence Research and Development Council,
end quote. Under the CIA, Poteet spearheaded Project Palladium in the 1960s with heavy use
of naval assets, ships, and submarines. The project employed a variety of clandestine submarines,
radar reflectors, and jamming tactics to trick and gauge Soviet radar capabilities.
Essentially, Palladium performed to fill Soviet radar systems with fake UAP signatures. Of course,
our true interest here lies with Palladium's usage of clandestine subs and Poteet's connection to the
Navy Special Program Office. According to excellent researcher Jeff Cruickshank, references to Project
Palladium can be found in the Majestic 12 documents. The Terse memo, dated 28 June 1961,
is a majestic document Ryan and Robert Wood have rated with a moderate to high authenticity.
This memo allegedly sees JFK write to the Director of Central Intelligence, Alan Doles,
in a National Security Memorandum with the subject, quote,
review of MJ-12 intelligence operations as they relate to Cold War psychological warfare plans,
end quote. It is intriguing to see Alan Doles did indeed meet with JFK twice, 28 June 1961.
Cruickshank argues the psychological warfare plans referenced in the Terse memo directly
reference Operation Palladium. Although Palladium didn't get its iconic name until April 1962,
when Dr. Albert Whelan took over as head of CIA DS&T, the description of Palladium would appear
again in further majestic documents, and this is supported in the Medium Confidence Operation
Review The MJ-12 Project, allegedly written by Alan Doles on 5 November 1961. This document
describes how the CIA was mapping the Soviet air defense system by using airborne electronic
countermeasure equipment and balloon decoys. Such a purpose was to provide a true picture
of how Soviet air defenses perceived UFOs. The memo discussed future similar psychological
warfare plans very similar to the Terse memo. Details of Project Palladium appearing in early
MJ-12 documents dropped to Jamie Shandery in 1984 prove significant, seen as according to an
article by Jean Petit in Stories of Intelligence Research, only six people knew about Palladium
in the 1960s. Since Palladium was not declassified until long after 1984, this implies whoever wrote
these select majestic documents was well aware or a part of Project Palladium. As a matter of fact,
the first time Palladium would be discussed was within a classified manner in a 1998 CIA
journal written about by the aforementioned Jean Petit. Historically, the Navy special
program saw heavy compartmentalization and incredibly strict need-to-know access.
In this 29 October 1974 CIA memo titled Clearances held by NSIC, or National Security Council
Intelligence Committee working group members, discussion was held around National Security
Council working group programs overlapping certain compartmented areas of the Navy special
program. For read-on access, clearance requests were required for a redacted name and National
Security Council member and CIA officer Richard Ober. This NSC memo was sent just a few days after
the NRO memo from 1974 we discussed earlier. We can additionally analyze a fascinating 14 December
1984 memo written to US Navy Rear Admiral and Director of Naval Intelligence John Butz.
The memo thanks John for his personal sacrifices in arranging meetings in spite of a tooth injury.
The writer, from within the staff of the Director of the Intelligence Community,
additionally informed Butz they had received a letter from the Secretary of the Navy John
Layman concerning the Navy special program. Remembered, Layman additionally served as
Director of NRO. This letter apparently took a month to get to the desk of the Director
of Central Intelligence. The writer additionally suggested John Butz include a representative from
Everett Heineman's department on the redacted special ad hoc requirements committee. Remember,
Heineman was labeled by Inman as the CIA DS&T member knowledgeable on UFO legacy operations.
The work here on the Navy special program is just the beginning for me and the ties to other
subjects we have covered today is extremely interesting. After all, I have found and
attempted to contact numerous former Navy special program personnel. These include a man who served
for three years as a diver in the Navy special program with the Mobile Diving and Salvage Unit
1. I have also contacted one Mr. P.R. who served for eight years as Project Lead for Navy Special
Program Office and SOCOM Acquisition Program Office. How interesting this ties into the work
of Chris Sharpe regarding USO retrievals, the Navy, and SOCOM. Especially intriguing,
seen as Sharpe implicated Lockheed Martin Dry Submersible as participating in USO retrieval.
And since 2023, SOCOM has declared operational capability with Lockheed Martin Dry Submersible.
And finally, I have contacted one Mr. W.H. who served for two years as an Office of Naval
Intelligence Chief Information Security Officer for the Navy Special Program. And please understand,
I am protecting the identity of these individuals as they very well may wish to speak on the NSP.
So,
believe it or not, today we have only scratched the surface of naval UFO legacy programs.
In the beginning of this project, I separated naval legacy programs into four distinct categories,
monitor, collect, store, and exploit. Of course, monitor has been omitted from today's discussion,
as has majorly exploit. Has the Navy successfully created seafaring ARV,
a deep sea equivalent to the flux liner? This, of course, will be another topic for another day.
Today, we have investigated the Navy Special Program Office, an Office of Naval Research
conducting undersea UFO and USO crash retrievals alongside SOCOM, private entities such as Lockheed
Martin and Woods Hole, and intelligence organizations such as the NRO, NERO, and CIA, DS&T. We have
also discussed a myriad senior naval officials such as Sumner Shapiro, Bobby Ray Inman,
and Nat Kobitz, who have all commented on the existence of crash retrieval and material
exploitation programs. We have barely begun to dive in and discuss the FFRDCs, Naval UARCs,
and DoD, RDT, and E facilities that are highly likely involved with naval UFO legacy programs.
Outside of mention of Lockheed, Woods Hole, and SAIC, we have barely even discussed contractors
in UFO legacy operations. Outside of sole source contracts, we have yet to really even dive into
how legacy operations within the Navy are funded. I have spoken before on Witness Ed, who claimed
the existence of a joint UFO reverse engineering program between Edwards Air Force Base and the
Nevada Test and Training Range. After his service at Edwards, Ed would proceed to work at the Pentagon
for the Air Force's RDT&E panel chain, where he would claim in two separate years $34 and $40
billion disappeared to non-authorized transfer of authority funds. Ed would additionally work
as liaison between the Pentagon and various defense contractors as an F-35 program subject
matter expert. As a test director for an electronics warfare group dealing with
reverse engineered UFOs out of the Edwards 412th test group, I have theorized Ed's work on the
F-35 also dealt with anomalous technologies. This is no stretch, as the F-35 program has historically
carried an incredibly bloated budget of $2 trillion. Such bloated budgets with backdoor clandestine
UFO programs may have also occurred in the Navy, and we may get a keen look at such an instance.
In 1985, the US Navy faced a massive controversy for an incredibly bizarre occurrence. Scandal
arose when in 85 it was discovered the US Navy had paid Grumman Aerospace Corporation $660 a piece
for ashtrays to be included in the E-2C Hawkeye. The Navy only began to investigate how many of
these ashtrays had been bought and why they cost so much when an investigator for the House Government
Operations Committee discovered this egregious oversight. From this investigation, it had also
been determined the Navy was paying Grumman $400 per socket wrench that were used to adjust the
seats of F-14s. And the Navy had also increased payments for ground locks from $102 in 1982 to
$2,710 a year later. Shockingly, this investigation would also reveal years prior the Navy had been
charging itself $954 for ashtrays. For such infractions, Defense Secretary Caspar Weinberger,
who made some contested statements about NeuroAbove, removed three officers prior to any
investigation. And Grumman aircraft whined that piece prices were so high due to needing to make
a small number of parts to spec. The damage had been done, leading to House Committee investigators
looking into larger naval contracts and discovered, for example, profits on aircraft carrier contracts
were in excess of $753 million or 29.7 percent. And contractor profits on a single Trident 735
submarine were in excess of $96 million or 22 percent. Where was all this excess money on
contracts and parts going? I wager since we are discussing contractors such as Grumman,
which I have directly implicated in UFO legacy programs before its merger with Northrop,
these funds were siphoned off legitimate contracts or parts to fund clandestine,
deep-sixed, UFO crash retrieval and material exploitation programs. So after all of this,
today has mostly served as an expose into naval legacy crash retrieval operations and
necessary logistics. More and more in my videos, I plan to speak on naval and special
USO legacy programs. This is due to multiple sources of mine informing me,
Navy USO programs are more secretive than even standard UFO legacy operations.
And as I said at the very end of this video, from multiple individuals that have worked
in legacy programs to are tangentially aware of them have informed me that the US Navy's programs
are the most secretive there are. Why is this? Is it because the Navy deals with weapons technology
as in the Randy Anderson case with the gauntlet and the orb that supposedly experienced energetic
discharge during recovery? Or is it because the Navy, specifically the ONR, is a pristine
stop for craft? Or is it because the transmedium capabilities of UFO are the most coveted aspect
of material exploitation and monitoring? Or is it possibly because some of the secrecy stems from
the possibility there are undersea UFO bases and inherently if this is where some craft are stationed
and departing from, this implies much secrecy. And that sort of makes a little sense as we've
seen with Neuro, underwater reconnaissance systems, clandestine submarines are some of
the United States most highly regarded secrets. We have five major intelligence agencies, the CIA,
DIA, NSA, what am I missing, NRO and NGA, but Neuro is not on there and we've seen and proven
today that Neuro does exist, so why is Neuro not listed? Neuro is really what kicked off my
investigation into this subject back in September with the work of Chris Sharpe when he detailed
and changed the article about undersea retrievals in the ONR, JSOC, SOCOM, Lockheed Martin, Woods Hole
and Neuro, this really kicked off my interest. One of the most intriguing aspects of this project of
course was Bobby Ray Inman, a regular of this channel admitting that he was Director of Neuro
and I'm really glad we got to explore a little bit more into Inman and his interactions with
Echler and Bobby and sorry, excuse me, Everett or R. Evan Heineman as well as Sumner Shapiro.
Again, as I stated, I've received no contact back from Heineman and I've also tried to contact
Shapiro's family. They have not gotten back to me either. I would like to get statements from
some other people surrounding this case, but Neuro really kicked off this operation and as we've seen
with Neuro, as a black program agency, all of its operations have been shrouded in secrecy.
Whether this entails usage of the Glomar Explorer, the Halibut, the NR1, the Sea Wolf, there is so
much secrecy surrounding Neuro and that bridges really perfectly into the 1991
retrieval case under witness Mark. Now, as I said in the video too, I'm still vetting this case.
I'm working with some individuals to try to identify Mark, to try to identify the
Naval Lieutenant Commander and trying to track down those original sketches. I know Art Bell
has passed away and he was the point of contact for both of these, but I am trying to track that down.
So, Mark's story involves a DSRV or as I hypothesized from Craven in the work under the DSSP,
a DSSV, Deep Submergence Search Vehicle. I think those depth capabilities and mechanical arms and
rigging for retrieval of craft suit a DSSV more than a DSRV because DSRV was specifically created
for transfer of crew from a submarine where a DSSV was specifically tailored, never built,
to retrieve vehicles and to retrieve items. Did this fall under Project Sand Dollar? As we saw
with Project Sand Dollar under Craven as well, Sand Dollar involved items of interest on the
sea floor of particular interest were radioactive or nuclear emitting items. And as we see in Mark's
case, the original side scan from vessels and other vessels that picked up the signature of the craft,
this was emitting some sort of radiation to the point where the DSRV crew initially thought this
to be a downed Korean or Russian aircraft with some sort of nuclear technology. And it is
interesting to see as Mark said he steamed out of Virginia that the 2011 Fukushima documents
detail that DSRV units were ready and able in the east and west coast of the United States.
So let's talk about that incident a bit more because it's very rare we can ever find an under
sea retrieval. The only other example I can think of is Shag Harbor which occurred in 1967 and I
would like to tackle that case in the future, especially because there is testimony of the US
Navy kind of coming in, the US Navy divers, and coming in and really taking over the retrieval
operation. But Mark's DSRV crew observes a triangle. And as I said in the video and as we talk about
in this channel quite often, I oftentimes attribute human origin to triangular craft, whether this be
the TR-3B, the XF-131 Super Sentinel, which I almost put more credence in than the TR-3B,
or other prototypes that we discussed throughout the 80s and 90s in the TR-3B video. But this craft
featured hieroglyphic-like writing alongside its outer edge, which similar to Kexberg and Danny
Sheehan's account is not rare but not common in UFO crash retrieval incidents. The description of
this craft is very similar to other NHI craft, no landing gear, no mechanical systems, no cockpit,
no glass, no windows, etc. What interests me is the aftermath of the retrieval. Mark states that
after the marine archaeologist and four dives were able to observe the craft and they were able to
get it off the ground and retrieve it, that after a couple hours Mark and his crew were steamed off
site and were never warned not to speak about this incident, warned not to talk about it or
signed further NDAs. Now Mark inherently had to sign NDAs and non-disclosure agreements for his
work on DSRV, which as we know from John Payne or Craven, were sent almost exclusively on
clandestine operations, so it stands to reason there's a heavy amount of secrecy when you sign
on for this crew. But it almost appears as if the steamer of the LPH vessel that discovered the craft
and the DSRV was still trying to figure out what the heck they had uncovered because it took a
couple hours for Mark and his crew to be steamed off site and they were never briefed on the
incident, debriefed, or discussed it further. I do hope Mark is still alive and I would like to speak
to him, I very much would. And then what is interesting with Neuro as well as the connection
to the 1973 Great Lakes Naval Station case, of course Stringfield published on this back in the
80s. So the Glomar Explorer and its work with Neuro wasn't very well known if at all at this time.
The Glomar Explorer had been known for project Azorian retrieving one-third of the Soviet K-129
submarine, but just the connection of witness JK stating that the San Diego sailor that he met that
saw basically the same craft he saw had told him that it had been shot down between Hawaii and the
mainland by a destroyer and retrieved by the Glomar Explorer. And this was early 1973. And then there's
fascinating connections that Bobby Ray Inman stated that in the early 70s, 72 to 74 to be exact,
he became aware of the Glomar's activities out in Hawaii. So there's a lot of really
connective tissue here with these statements. And I know I say this in most videos, but our work
with the Navy is really just beginning here. There are so many more facilities we need to look at,
so much more investigation into China Lake because the Navy and if Chris Sharpe's reporting is
correct, the ONR specifically is almost a staging point for housing craft. Now this makes me wonder,
is this, does the Air Force, if they retrieve a craft or the Army, if they retrieve a craft,
do they initially stage at Naval locations to then be transported again? Does the Navy just
satisfy Naval UFO legacy programs for storage of craft or do they also operate alongside Army and
Air Force? This would surprise me as everything I have been told, investigated and seen is that
Army, Air Force and Navy almost act siloed. Very different programs, sometimes doing the same thing
but almost no communication to adhere to the compartmentalization of these programs where
only the intelligence community overlords really know what's going on between programs. So that
would be really interesting to track down. But anyways guys, if anybody watching this video
has any experiences or connections with individuals who have retrieved undersea craft or know of
stories of undersea craft retrieval, please contact me and I would love to speak to you.
But let me know what you guys think in the comments. This was a wonderful project for me
to pursue and I really hope everybody enjoyed it. Let me know what you think. If you have any
thoughts, comments, things to add, please remember to like and subscribe. I have a Patreon,
I don't gatekeep content, that's not what I do. Only support what you think the channel is worth
and I will catch everybody on the next episode. Thank you so much and see you later.