The program you are about to see concerns the mysterious deaths and mutilations of animals
in the United States and other parts of the world.
Due to the graphic nature of some scenes, parental guidance for children is advised.
The film you are about to see, called A Strange Harvest, was first broadcast in May 1980.
The subject is a mystery which has haunted ranchers and law enforcement for the past
decade, the mutilation of animals, especially cattle, throughout the United States and Canada.
Since the first broadcast, mutilations have continued, but with little or no media coverage,
perhaps because it's easier to accept the usual explanation of predator attack.
However, in the past few months, since September of 1982, I have received 12 mutilation reports
from sheriff's offices, all relating to bizarre cuts, not predators.
One of those happened right here in this field on September 16th, 1982.
Bill and Linda Desouris grew up on this ranch land about 30 miles east of Colorado Springs.
Raising cattle has been their life, and neither had seen anything like the dead cow they found
that September day.
About noon, we went out to check the cows.
We had some cows that were about to calf, and everything was okay.
So we went back to the house, had lunch.
About, oh, all afternoon, we'd worked out on the truck all afternoon.
It was a pretty day, and we hadn't seen or heard anything.
Went about five o'clock, had to go to Kremlin after low to hay, so I was in a semi and the
cow was over a little ridge, but I could see off a sweet road the cow laying there dead.
I got the bait, and I called my wife and told her to go check on it.
Half of the udders were gone.
You could see into the stomach cavity.
The rectum had been partially removed.
The eyes were bulging out.
I was horrified at the thought of what could do this in broad daylight when we had checked
the cows only a few hours before.
That cow was the Desouris' third mutilation.
In the fall of 1979, they found two of their year-old heifers lying 100 feet apart in a
pasture.
Both were dead, and their rectums had been cored out.
Cause unknown.
One deputy sheriff in Wyoming is so frustrated with the mutilation mystery that he has gotten
his local crime labs cooperation to investigate mutilations as they would human murders.
This fall, we had 10 mutilations, eight in Sweetwater County and two in Daggett County.
And in 1975, we had 16.
From everywhere I go, they tell me that it's predators, which I do not believe.
Why do you feel differently?
Because I don't feel a predator can do these things.
I don't feel a predator can come up and chew a half of a bag off of a cow or the end of
the penis off of a bull and not touch any of the rest of the cow.
I've been around predators, and they'll go inside the abdominal cavity first and eat
the insides, which is easy eating.
What would be your own personal feelings about who or what would be doing these mutilations
and why?
I wished I knew.
I don't have any idea who is doing it.
We have investigated several things, cults, different things like this, but we haven't
come up with any answers to any of our questions as of yet.
Treating it like a human murder would give you what kind of different information than
you've had in the past?
Well, treating it as a human murder, I feel that we can get the crime lab in Cheyenne
to help us with our analysis of the animals, of what may cause the death, maybe even if
it was some kind of a poison or something that they're using to kill them or how they
are using it to kill them.
It will just give us more answers to a lot of the questions that we have on mutilations.
Two of the Wyoming mutilations were like the one in Colorado on the Desuris Ranch.
Half the udder removed, teats cut, and rectums cored out, all without signs of blood.
The Wyoming state veterinarian said about one of those cows, quote, it was dead before
it was mutilated with a cutting instrument.
The mutilation was not done by an animal.
And in a carpenter Wyoming case, the veterinarian wrote in his necropsy report, right front
and rear mammary glands missing, left front and rear teats missing, vulvular area missing
approximately five inches into pelvis, leaving rectum intact, hole in center of skull approximately
two millimeters in diameter on the surface of the skull and one millimeter in diameter
on the inside of the skull.
No evidence of gunshot.
Cause of death, possible injection of material into brain with unknown object.
Lab analysis found nothing.
Who or what is killing and mutilating these animals and why?
Most everyone in the western United States heard about cattle mutilations in 1975.
And a couple of years later in 1977, most people thought cattle mutilations had gone away.
The number of newspaper articles declined.
And ranchers, many of them, stopped reporting their dead and mutilated cows to law enforcement.
But the cattle mutilations never did stop.
And by the spring of 1979, United States Senator Harrison Schmidt of New Mexico
was concerned enough to call for a conference in Albuquerque on April 20th
to talk about cattle mutilations.
And I began wondering again, what was going on?
In the past few months, I've traveled through Wyoming, New Mexico, and Colorado exploring this mystery.
I've talked with journalists, law enforcement people, ranchers, and scientists.
They have shown me their photographs, their reports, and their files.
In this program, you will hear the testimonies of many of these people
who have been involved with this puzzling phenomenon over the past decade.
Some of their statements might shock you,
but they're all part of this amazing story that I call A Strange Harvest.
A Strange Harvest
In September 1967, on the King Ranch in the San Luis Valley of Colorado,
an Appaloosa mare called Snippy was found dead and stripped of flesh from the neck up.
Some said this was the work of flying saucers.
Who or whatever did it, no one knows.
Since that time, and perhaps even earlier in this century,
thousands of cattle, horses, and other animals have been cut up in strange ways
throughout the United States, Canada, Puerto Rico, Panama, the Canary Islands,
and possibly other South American and European countries.
Some people call it cattle mutilation.
Whatever it's called, it's a strange harvest.
Parts missing are usually an ear, an eye, the tongue, the lower jaws stripped of all flesh,
the sexual organs are cut out, the rectum is cored out,
and in some cases, the blood is gone.
Adding to the mystery is lack of tracks or other evidence.
Mutilated cattle have been found on wet sand or rain-soaked ground with no tracks around them,
not even their own.
And the mutilations continue.
Between May 1979 and January 1980,
over 30 cattle in Canada have reportedly suffered this strange fate.
Iowa had eight reported mutilations in the last months of 1979.
Other states that had reported mutilations in 1979 were
Colorado, Wyoming, New Mexico, Arkansas, Kansas and Nebraska, and Texas.
Who or what is killing and mutilating these animals?
Could it be cults, predators, helicopters, UFOs, deranged individuals,
secret government project?
Is any of these the answer?
Are all of these part of the answer?
Some ranchers believe that whoever's doing the mutilating must be using some kind of aircraft.
The Greenhorn Mountains in southeastern Colorado rise above the sagebrush cattle grazing lands
that stretch for thousands of square miles around Walsenburg.
Here in July of 1979, rancher C.E. Potts found one of his prize bulls dead and mutilated.
We were passing down this road and there was a thunderstorm coming up behind us
and we were rushing down by to smelt this animal as we went by.
So we come back to check on it and found it had been mutilated.
Then we examined it and its sexual organs were all taken out and everything
and one of its eyes was taken out and its eyelashes was taken out.
What about the idea that it's predators?
Well there wasn't no predators and not a predator bothered it since it's been dead even.
It couldn't have been killed by a predator because all the surgical work was done by an expert.
I really didn't think there was anything to it until it come home to me.
Now I know there's bound to have been mutilated or anybody who can see good could see it was.
The strange thing about it is that we have never found any blood on them.
No blood?
No blood, no.
Tracks?
The only tracks that we found on the first one were some tripod tracks
and they formed something like a triangle.
I didn't know what to think.
It was kind of strange because we had never seen anything like that before.
It still remains a mystery.
In all the states it's happened, it's a mystery.
It goes on to turn what I read and hear about.
I got called this summer from Canada on two mutilations.
They called me and the way they described this, it's just typical of our mutilations we had in 75.
If it goes into Canada and there have been reports that they've come up out of Puerto Rico
and some other parts of the world, if it goes on to an international scale,
do you think that would exclude satanic cults and a military operation in our country?
Well, yeah, it'd be inclined to, my way of thinking.
And if they're excluded, what is left?
I don't know. I don't know that either.
The Colorado Bureau of Investigation received 203 reports of suspected mutilations
in a nine-month period between April and December of 1975.
Colorado State University's diagnostic laboratory received 35 carcasses.
Only 19 were in good enough condition to perform lab examinations.
Of those 19, nine or about half were considered to be cut with a sharp instrument.
The rest were generally described as the activity of predators.
It's true cattle in Colorado are going to die each year from hard winters, disease,
lightning strikes, predator attacks, and other natural causes.
But in northeastern Colorado, another favorite spot for the mutilators,
Tex Graves, former sheriff of Logan County, insists the 93 mutilated carcasses he investigated
were not natural deaths.
The very first one we had was southwest of Sterling.
When we first looked at it, it was just unbelievable that you could take an animal
and do this too without leaving some kind of track, some kind of evidence behind,
such as cigarette butts, matches, handprints, footprints, but there was nothing.
The animal looked almost horrible, and it was something that I didn't really want to believe then.
We probably had five or six others before I really did believe something strange was going on.
We had one up north where we believed the animal was paralyzed and was alive when it was being mutilated.
An eye and an ear, the tongue, the rectal area was taken out, but the animal dug a hole with its head,
but none of the other parts of the body moved, not even the legs.
What force could hold down a 900-pound steer while its ear, tongue, rectum, and sex organs were removed?
I asked Dr. Albert McChesney, pathologist and coordinator of the diagnostic laboratory
at Colorado State University in Fort Collins, Colorado.
His lab did all the analysis work on the 35 carcasses sent in from the Colorado Bureau of Investigation.
Well, I would, of course, surmise the animal was dead before they were removed.
But how would the hole be dug where its head is? It's been moving to dig that hole.
Many times when an animal dies, they go through an agonal phase just before they die,
and they will paddle their legs or they will beat their head or swing it back and forth,
or they might even have some central nervous system involvement,
which would make them be in coordinate, make them lie down and to struggle for some little time,
and this would dig the hole where the animal's head is.
I'm not trying to discredit the fact that there can be mutilations,
but I just want to show that there is a very good chance that something else could have caused it.
Here is the very first cow that Sherrick Tech's Graves and Sterling ever went out on.
Would a natural predator ever strip a jaw clean like this one?
I cannot tell you whether this would be from a sharp instrument or from scavenging.
Many times when an animal dies again, the pressure will cause their tongue to extend,
and this will allow animals to start eating on the front end of the animal.
And if so, this cleaning of the jaw and the cheek muscles
would be just a natural extension of that entry into the body tissues.
Doesn't that look like a nice clean curve of a cut around there in that lower jaw?
It does. It looks quite clean.
But once again, we have to have all of our facts together before we can draw a conclusion.
If I could see whether hair was cut or if there were deeper incisions,
perhaps I could tell you specifically.
But to look at one like this, I would say it's within the realms
of either scavenging or sharp knife mutilation.
It could be either way.
One other place in 1976 north of town on a very hard pasture, almost like hard brick.
We found tripod marks 12 inches across.
The tripod marks were 14 feet apart.
We found one set that had gone in the ground roughly 8 inches.
And it would take a good post hole digger or shovel to dig in like this.
It indicated something very heavy had sat down in this area,
yet there was no tracks leading from it nor to it.
Almost nightly when this was going on,
we could pick out a very brilliant, huge, brilliant light in the sky.
We had a newsman take pictures of it with a very high powered lens.
But all we got out of this was the movement of it and the light showing very brilliant.
Several times we observed smaller lights come out of this aircraft
and then come down toward earth.
This huge, brilliant light would hang in the air and then when it would move,
it could move up and down, backwards, forwards, travel very rapidly.
And after a while, these smaller lights would join up with the larger one and then they'd disappear.
Another law enforcement officer who saw strange lights back in 1975 and 76 is Bill Waugh.
Bill was the under sheriff in Elbert County for 8 years working with Sheriff George Yarnell.
He retired in 1979.
A policyman and I were sitting out there one night.
The sheriff was up in a plane and I happened to look in the rear view mirror
and I saw this orange ball of light come up from the ground.
So I nudged the policyman with me.
We jumped out of our car and this light came at us.
It was up then, up off the ground, flying higher than the car.
They get up just about to the car and then make a complete 90 degree right angle turn.
And in the cockpit I could see three little lights, a red one and what looked like a white one,
and either a green or a blue.
One man looked out of his window at night just before he went to bed and the horse was standing out there.
He got up the next morning, sat down to breakfast and happened to glance out
and the horse had been mutilated right there.
It was in the summertime.
They had three, they had a house and two trailers where people lived in.
And they all had their windows open.
They had dogs around the place.
No one heard any dogs barking.
No one heard a thing.
And that was right up by the house.
A Colorado man named Drexel Lawson has a livestock removal service.
He's been working a nine county area around Denver and Colorado Springs since 1977,
picking up dead livestock.
He's been working for a long time.
He was a mother of 6 children.
He worked around Denver and Colorado Springs since 1977,
picking up dead livestock.
Over a two-year period, he hauled off about 4,000 dead animals,
including several mutilated cattle.
My first mutilated pickup was in 1977.
And frankly scared the hell out of me because I wasn't I wasn't used to seeing things like that
I think it scared me and it's down to me so much was when livestock die they normally will
Lay in thrashing the grass or in the dirt this cow
looked like she'd just been
actually just picked up or
or turned over and
None of the grass or the dirt anything around her was
Was disturbed or destroyed in any way from from her dying
She had had had any blood the blood was completely drained from I would say that it would be
virtually impossible to withdraw
Not even all of the blood but just significance amount of the blood from an animal without leaving some telltale mark that
Blood vessels had been cut or that some the animal had been killed in this manner
Probably closer examination would have shown that in the dead animals body the blood had gravitated to the deeper organs or to the downside
Do you know of anything on the earth today in medicine or military that could drain the blood from an animal I?
Have no knowledge of it if it's there
all the
Mutilated cattle that I've gotten
Where the rectum tissues been taken or the muscle tissues been taken it's been a very very precise
surgical type
incision and it's been cleaned not
Not hacked like an animal the animal has to grab you by it has to tear in order to remove that tissue
And this has all been smooth
What's your own personal?
Theory or feeling about who or what is doing the mutilations
well, I feel strongly about UFOs the
Incisions a lot of times looks like some type of burn or laser
the eyes on
particular cattle that I picked up that's had a
Marbly clear look which looks like it's a flash burn or
some type of a laser burn
the
The term laser burn came up in several conversations with ranchers and law enforcement people
So we decided to see how laser surgery is done
This instrument is called a co2 laser. It will be used to remove scar tissue from a woman's vocal cords
This mobile laser unit stands about eight feet high and weighs about 400 pounds in the hospital
It is powered by AC current from a wall plug
Experienced medical technicians need 20 minutes to get the laser unit ready for surgery
Clearly, it's not a convenient tool to drag around remote ranch lands
but because of the alleged burns found on some mutilated animals a few people have jumped to the conclusion that maybe lasers are involved
It is true that lasers seal off blood vessels as they penetrate tissue
So there is little or no bleeding the depth of penetration is controlled by the power of the beam and length of time
It is on when the laser beam hits tissue heat is generated which turns cell water to steam and vaporizes away
Could a laser do the strange cuts found on mutilated cattle
We asked dr. Arlen Myers an experienced laser surgeon at Rose Medical Center in Denver
I
Have been examining two photographs of alleged cattle mutilations in Logan County and
They showed two quite distinct pictures. One is a large hole that has surrounding burns and charred material
The other is a very nice clean cut and has relatively normal underlying tissue
the first picture I think
Conceivably could have been caused by a burning or lasing type instrument
Although I think it would be very difficult given the state of the art today
At least to my knowledge to bring a device to a field and inflict this sort of damage on a piece of livestock
In more reality, it would be easier to bring the animal here
We asked dr. Myers to use the laser and try to make a perfect 1 eighth inch deep circle in a chicken
You can see the red aiming dot and we're going to begin to remove some of this tissue
And you can see as it's as it's removing this tissue
That the burn is fairly flush notice the dark
scab that forms
around it and we can
continue to
Remove this tissue in deeper and deeper levels the laser
Evaporates water and that's why we're seeing all the smoke
This piece of flesh that we're using has no blood in it
But even if it did it would have the same bloodless sort of charred appearance after the tissue was removed
In trying to duplicate what I saw in the pictures if I were to try to deepen this hole
there are some limitations with the instrument that I'm using the
Maximum point of focus of the beam is at a certain length and in order to make this hole deeper
I would need to move the instrumentation deeper toward the flesh and just continue to burrow the hole
Okay, we're going to go to the scaffold
And try to demonstrate what sort of
Let's leave this here for some contrast and we'll take this second
Piece of flesh and I'm just gonna make a similar size circle and try to duplicate this wound over here
Simply with a with a knife when I remove this
Piece of skin
That there's in contrast to the laser
No
Surrounding scab or blackness
And this is just a clean a clean wound the edge is
Nice and smooth and the underlying tissue is unaffected of course by the knife
Compared to the laser burn the surface of the removed tissue was darkened and somewhat burned
Here is the scalpel cut again
not perfectly round a few angled edges and
Here's a perfect oval cut on a steer. We filmed in San Luis, Colorado on October 6th
There was also a perfect circular cut around the eye. The tongue was gone and the lower jaw had been completely stripped of flesh
Two deputies from the Castilla County Sheriff's Office took us to the mutilation site five days after they had first examined the fresh carcass
Well, I don't look it's changed a little bit hey, but look at this now, this is still very very evident here. Look at this
Of course, you know our photos will show a complete circular clean cut, but you can still see it here now. Look
Now this looks kind of dry
But if you'll recall when we first spotted this that was just like if you've taken a pair of scissors and cut out a round
Piece of paper, you know, like you might do a kid might do in school. That's how good it was and if you'll notice something else
Say that an animal had
Taken that piece of skin
How can you explain the fact that if he's out to eat and out for flesh that he wouldn't bore right through that
soft portion of the stomach and get into the entrails, which is typical of the way that
Animals attacked dead while carcasses
That just doesn't make sense to me
That mutilation in San Luis, Colorado happened around September 29th, 1979
Two weeks later. There was another one in Chama, New Mexico and by December there had been more scattered mutilation reports in Kansas
Nebraska Wyoming and Iowa and the number of mutilations being investigated by the Royal Canadian Mounted Police had climbed above 30
Lou Girardo is the chief investigator for the district attorney's office in Trinidad, Colorado
It's not difficult to tell a predator kill I mean a coyote or a bobcat or a lion, of course will grab and tear
It wasn't that way with any of the mutilations I covered and the first two were amazing
The others had been completely removed with a very clean
Apparently a surgical cut
No blood were around the wounds. No blood were around any of the either the animals no tracks
Checking the area where the two cows were laying. They were underneath some tall oak
We checked the upper branches just in case we had heard of the mutilations in other parts of the country
Or the possibility of the animals being dropped removed from where they were killed and dropped in the area where they were being found
There were no broken branches
No tracks of any kind human or otherwise led to or from the animals the sheriff stayed away from the animals
The sheriff stayed away from it
after he saw what he did see and
There was no explanation of what had happened to the animals according to the rancher the night before they had been seen in good health
I
Think was wrong with them the next day. They showed up dead and mutilated
another interesting fact a few days after
We usually see the report from a woman who lived in the area of a real dark colored helicopter with a sling attached underneath
Flying near the area where the mutilations that had taken place with the bodies of the carcasses of the animals were found
And that's not the only time
helicopter had been reported prior to
or immediately after
The mutilation there seemed to be in the area one time or another
none of these choppers had been
Identified no identifying marks all the reports come in that the choppers were silent
And I have never heard of a silent helicopter. They were always making some type of noise
But these reports were that there was no noise
You
Descriptions of dark and silent helicopters as well as unidentified bright lights came up in almost every conversation about the cattle mutilation mystery
Some people suggested that the Cobra helicopter developed for air attacks in Vietnam was a quiet helicopter
We went to Fort Carson an army base in Colorado to film a Cobra in operation
We
Asked the pilot to go out one mile circle and fly back over us at 500 feet
The Cobra was definitely dark, but never silent especially on takeoffs and landings
when
We first started hearing reports about the cattle mutilations here at Fort Carson, Colorado
We often wondered ourselves what type of helicopter had the capability of lifting such an animal from one side to another
It's there's not too many helicopters in the local area that had that capability that I've seen
Around here. There's certainly are not any here at Fort Carson except for the much larger helicopters and
Because of the noise that would generate from these helicopters
No animal is going to sit still to allow these these helicopters to get within any close proximity
Of them as they make their approach or land to the area. Is there such thing as a silent helicopter?
No
Not a completely silent helicopter
No, the helicopter will always make some sort of noise that will scare an animal away that is not used to that type of noise
From the reports that we've read and heard on news and newspapers it would require somebody of great ability to perform
These acts and anybody that I know of in this particular area
Certainly not the military if I had to choose between aliens of some sort coming down and
Doing these things to the animals and lifting the animals as compared to having a helicopter of our size
Or smaller helicopters doing these things. I would probably be more apt to choose the alien
Aspect of the cattle problems in the military or any other type of small helicopter
Now just here this late summer for the early spring
One of the investigators I've been working with for five years dropped in the office and we discussed what was new
And he said well the thing is now I'll tell you he says and I'm inclined to agree with him
That who is doing this now is very possibly creatures not of this planet
Now that you know that shakes you up a little bit creatures not of this planet you know you're thinking of Buck Rogers and things like this
But that's the way it is seriously right now
That it's very very possible that these mutilations are being done by creatures from outer space
There's a state patrol officer in Dulce, New Mexico who has not only seen UFOs
But received a substance that dropped from a strange craft that hovered over Taos, New Mexico
Gabe Valdez has been investigating cattle mutilation since 1976
It's got to be a highly sophisticated agency that has total secrecy and the money and technology or something else involved
But as far as an occult group being involved in it I think it would have been broken a long time ago
So what's left?
Either government or extraterrestrial
You first have to operate under the premise that you believe that some government agency would be responsible for that
To me it's ludicrous, it's almost ridiculous to conceive that that would be a possibility
You're dealing with, if you're talking about the CIA or you're talking about some government spy agency
It just doesn't make sense to me that they would be involved in at random mutilating cattle on individual ranches or farms
If they were involved in something like that they would have the resources to do it under controlled conditions
So I've never even entertained that thought even though it's one of the theories that has been thrust into this investigation
North West of Laramie, Wyoming lives a rancher farmer named Pat McGuire
His father and grandfather were Wyoming ranchers
He settled down here in 1972 with his wife and eight children
In September 1976 on a ridge about two miles from his trailer house
Mr. McGuire, his brother and his cousin Mark Murphy found two mutilated cows
The following hypnosis session with Dr. Leo Sprinkle, director of counseling and testing at the University of Wyoming in Laramie
is Pat McGuire's effort to recall more details about an extraordinary incident that happened to him at the time of the mutilations
Dr. Sprinkle is one of the world's leading authorities in cases involving UFOs and human abductions
He has personally worked with 47 people since 1967
Pat McGuire was his 28th case and the first concerning cattle mutilations
Whenever you're ready just go right ahead, you can talk and describe your experiences
It was Sunday
Me and Marks
We were driving around checking the cows
Come upon a cow that was dead
They cut the nose off, tongue was out, the sex organs were gone
One brother said it must have been from a sex cult from the university
Out here messing around, I said, probably was, I said, we'll catch him yet
Okay, Pat, you're doing fine, I'd like to have you now turn your attention to the evening that you and Mark were looking at that craft
You were looking through the scope
I said, Mark, let's get the hell out of here
I said, let's get the hell out of here, I said, that star's coming, I said, either that or my eyes are bad
He said, it's coming, it changed from a pure white to an orange
I said, Mark, I don't know if it's picking up a cow
I said, yeah, hear that cow?
Hell, she's bawling
And it seems to be hovering there over the ridge
Right, hovering, picking up the cow
Can you see the cow?
No
But you can hear the cow?
Right, terrible
Terrible, bawling?
Terrible, worse than I ever heard a cow
I've heard a few
Okay, then what happened?
Then all of a sudden, like they threw a valve or a switch, everything stopped
The craft is still there
The cow wasn't no ball
No sound from the cattle?
No, it's like they threw a switch
It was weird
Back of my neck, hair on the back of my neck was straight up
The next day, you said you drove over there?
Right
What do you find when you drive over?
We didn't go over there until 10 o'clock in the morning
We waited until it was damn good daylight
We weren't taking a chance
We went and looked all over, along the side of the hill
All we found was another cow in two miles, just a lone calf, bawling for its mom
I said they took her
We never found her, never did find her
I've drawn a picture of the spacecraft that I'd seen that night
The ridge was 300 feet
The tip stuck above the ridge, and that would give you a size of a football field
As it proceeded down from the sky, it was a pure white with the flashing red and yellow and blue lights
Then it turned to a 4S orange, the whole ship did
It stays this color, and of course it'll glow the whole area up right around where the cow was
The area was deep red, and that's where you could hear that cow bellowing
You can feel yourself even going deeper
What you are about to hear is perhaps the first and only known eyewitness account of a mutilation
Because Dr. Leo Sprinkle is recognized as one of the world's leading authorities on cases involving UFOs and human abduction
He was contacted by the Aerial Phenomenon Research Organization in Tucson, Arizona to do hypnosis work with this woman
Her name is Judy Doherty
On a clear moonlit night in May 1973, Judy was driving back from a bingo game in Houston, Texas
She and her mother, daughter Cindy, and brother and sister-in-law watched a strange bright light hover in the sky
After that night, she suffered terrible headaches and anxiety
In 1978, she underwent one hypnosis session which brought out part of her unusual experience, but not all of it
She also had several psychiatric and personality evaluations, all with results in the normal human behavior range
The second hypnosis session with Dr. Sprinkle occurred on March 13, 1980
Now you're standing outside your car, now you're looking up, you can describe your impressions
What are your impressions?
It's like a spotlight that's shining down on the back of my car
And it's like it has substance to it
I can see an animal being taken up in this
I can see it squirming and trying to get free
And it's like it's being sucked up
It's taken into some sort of chamber
It's a little round, tiny room
And I get nauseated at watching how they excise the parts
It's done very quickly, but the calf doesn't die immediately
For some reason, the calf's heart isn't taken, and I don't know, it seems like it's still living, and that upset me very much
And then I can see the calf being lowered, it's like it's being dropped back down
And when it's on the ground, it's dead, I can see that it's not moving
But I feel very sick to my stomach, what I witnessed
You see the animal being cut up?
Yes
How is it being cut up?
Dissected
With knives?
Instruments of some kind
Can you describe the instruments?
They're like a knife, but they have different kind of handles
More like a razor that doesn't have movable parts, but like a straight razor type
There's tissue, it's laid out, flat and smooth, it glistens
And then needles, there's needles in it, or what appears to be like needles, it may be probes, I don't know
But it has a tube connected to it
And the same thing with what appears to be testicles, can't tell
There's a probe or a needle or something inserted
And the tube leaving
The same with the eye
Is anybody else around you?
I feel the presence of other things, but I don't know what they are, I can't see them
Do you feel you're standing by the side of the road, by your car now, or are you standing someplace else now?
I feel in two places at once
Ok, describe how you feel
I feel like I was able to see what was going on in the craft, but I was also standing beside the road
Ok, just let yourself focus on what is happening inside the craft
Be aware of who is around you, it's ok, you'll be able to describe who is standing around you
It appears to be two little men
Two little men, how do they look?
They look, their hands look funny, they have long claw nails like
They have very large eyes, they're very hypnotic
Like they're so big that, and they don't blink, their eyes do not blink
It's almost like a snake
They were very snappy about their movements, and they knew exactly what they were doing
And I felt a little better, because for some reason they projected that it was necessary this be done
That it was for our betterment, for the betterment of mankind that this was done
That they were more or less watching out for us
So you felt better when you had that impression of not only precision but also a benevolent or a kind attitude toward people
I can't say that they were kind
But concerned?
I can't even say that they were concerned, they were just like doing a job that evidently it affects them too
And it has to do with somehow nuclear waste or testing
They've been here for quite some time and they test the soil as well as our water, as well as our animal life, our vegetation
When I question why they aren't saying more, and why they can't stop it if they're so knowledgeable
And they get angry, I don't know, I don't understand that
You don't know why they get angry?
I don't know why they get angry and I don't know why they can't stop it if they're so knowledgeable
At one point in the hypnosis session, Judy doesn't understand why she can see her daughter Cindy in the car one minute and gone the next
Breathing deeply and easily, let yourself relax, you can be aware of yourself standing by the side of the car, you can be aware of yourself standing in the craft
And now let yourself be aware of where Cindy is
I know I have a feeling of fear
Okay, let yourself go on through the experience
Let yourself go on through the fear
What impressions come to mind?
I just visualize her on a table
Okay, what happens next?
I'm afraid that it's going to happen to her, what they did to the animal
Just let yourself relax
Forget it, no, I don't want to
You can tolerate it, you know it's alright
Just let yourself go on through, just relax deeply
You know that everything is going to be okay
You see Cindy on the table, what happens next?
I'm just afraid that they're going to hurt her
Yeah, you're afraid, but you let yourself go ahead and let yourself go on through the experience, you can be aware
Just let yourself relax deeply
You can be aware of what happens next
They put her to sleep, I guess
Okay, they put her to sleep
Okay, what's happening now?
They're just examining her, I guess
But I'm so afraid that they're going to cut her or something
Do you say anything?
They don't listen, they just ignore me and just go back to work like it's nothing
They don't seem to have any emotions, they don't seem to care, I thought they were going to harm her
I thought they were going to do what they did to the animals
But they don't harm her? No
Okay, what does happen?
They just take some samples from her
What kind of samples?
I don't know, just scrapings, like they go inside her mouth
I can see them, they just kind of scrape little pieces off
Any other samples?
That's all I can remember
The preceding scenes were taken from a four-hour hypnosis session
Dr. Sprinkle stated afterward that Judy Doherty is, in his professional opinion, a sincere, honest, and credible person
What happened before our camera was her first complete and vivid recall of her 1973 experience in Texas
They would listen, they just went about their work
They didn't have any emotion or feeling
They couldn't seem to understand why I would even be upset
Just like it was routine business for them
Like a laboratory animal or something
If extraterrestrials are the ones mutilating animals, what do you think the implications are then for this planet?
Throughout the mutilations, all of us involved have been concerned with the possibility of the mutilations going from animals to human beings
Understandably
Thank God to this point it hasn't happened
Whatever they're doing with the portions of these animals they are taking, I haven't the slightest idea
There's a reason for it, it's not haphazard
There's a pattern to it
I don't know, I think it's a wait-and-see game
What else can we do if we do have beings from outer space doing this
With the capabilities to do things like this
What can we as a human race do?
If they have the knowledge and the technology that it looks like they have, we're powerless
So maybe it's a wait-and-see game, I can't see anything else to do
If a secret probe was being conducted either by our own intelligence agencies or by UFO entities
Then they shouldn't be leaving a mass of carcasses all over the states because this only invites investigation and speculation and wondering
I would suspect that the carcasses are being left by design to stimulate our particular culture to wonder as to what is happening, who is doing this
If we are dealing with surreptitious, covert, highly cautious culture contact between highly developed extraterrestrials and our Earth planetary civilization
Then one of the primary considerations that we must deal with is the problem of culture shock
In any possible contact between civilizations such as I've described
I think that the superior civilization would be very careful to slowly condition the subject culture to its presence
So as not to induce what we label as culture shock
Which is a very profound psychological, sociological, philosophical disturbance among a people when exposed to a culture which shocks their traditional values, their institutionalized concepts, etc.
This is speculation of course
But an overview of the UFO phenomena leads most of us who have been in the field for a long period of time to view it as cautious, reconnaissance, conditioning of the planet Earth
Thank you for watching