You're tuned to the Zimbabwe Broadcasting Corporation, Radio One, and here is a special
announcement.
If anyone has video footage of the meteorite showers, or whatever they were, please get
in touch with Tim Leach of BBC Television very urgently.
BBC Television News.
I was not so frightened in the war zones of Angola or Rwanda as I was when this story
hit.
Hundreds of people today phoned the ZBC and BBC correspondent in Harare saying they sighted
an unidentified flying object last night.
These things were flying in a pattern and there was no sound.
No wings, no nothing.
Shiny over thing.
Hello.
My name is Tim Leach from BBC Television News.
I understand that you had some strange experience.
Yes, that's right.
It was a bright, radiant light.
I've never seen anything like it in my life.
It was the absence of noise I didn't like.
There has been much excitement after how many times I've seen it.
There has been much excitement after hundreds of people reported seeing a mysterious bright
object.
We suddenly looked up and we saw this thing coming over the top of the hill.
As it sort of came at the breast of us, it suddenly changed from this glow to let's say
two big red orange balls.
No sound.
Look.
It's going.
Is that what a meteorite does?
No way.
That's incredible.
Eyewitnesses say it had a bright light at the front and flew at great speed.
The object was also seen by two international airline pilots who reported it to air traffic
control at Johannesburg airport.
There were three of us that saw it.
Myself, the copilot and the pilot in the other aircraft.
South Africa's top meteorologist says there's no rational explanation for the bright light
and it could be one of the most widely reported unidentified flying objects.
None of it made sense, so I phoned the BBC in London and I said, what is this meteorite
show?
And they said, no, no, no, no.
It's got nothing to do with Africa or Zimbabwe.
The meteorites come down in an arc.
They don't fly parallel to the earth.
What about this Russian debris that's coming down?
No, that doesn't work either.
Sorry.
Well, what is this?
Viewers with more information can either contact the ZBC or BBC in Harare.
For at least three or four days, people from all over Zimbabwe were phoning us at the BBC
to say, we've seen something weird.
It was a helicopter or what?
No, no, it was just a big round wall.
The bottom was flat, but it was round like on top of my wall on my house.
And then I got this call from Aerial School Rua that the children had seen a CFO landing
and these funny men in body clean suits, black suits, weird.
I went roaring out there in the car with my sound man.
Aerial School, 19th September, 1994, 12.12 local time.
Can you tell me what you saw on Friday?
Well, it was just glinting in the trees.
And it's like there was a man and he walked towards us and he walked back again.
What does he look like?
His face was like this and his eyes were down here.
Like, what, further down his face?
Yeah, much further down than us because I was here.
You don't think it was somebody in fancy dress doing a prank or something?
No.
And how tall about?
About, say there, sitting on the spaceship.
How do you know it was a spaceship?
Wasn't it a helicopter or something like that?
Well, it looked like it was like a disk, like a round.
And whereabouts was it?
In the trees over there, between the third pole.
And did you girls see that as well?
Yes.
We asked them to draw pictures of what they saw on Friday.
And after looking at those, I definitely feel that they did see something.
What do you think that was?
I agree that it could be something that we are not common with.
But to actually say that it was a UFO, I would be reluctant to make a decision like that.
All the other journalists in Harare were not taking this seriously.
But I took it seriously because this story got bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger.
And I needed to know what was going on.
Who do I talk to?
And then I spoke to some contacts and they put me in touch with Cynthia Hind,
a person for UFOs in Zimbabwe.
Cynthia Hind's coming up and I believe she's being a Geiger counter.
She did mention it on the telephone.
Well, I think we'll wait and see what happens then.
Just come and sit on these chairs along here.
These are the grade 7s for the oldest children here at the school.
They say they saw something.
Did you all see something?
Yes.
What's your name?
I'm Danielle Mandy and I saw this silver thing in amongst this clump of trees
with this one thing sitting on the side and another thing sort of like running up and down the top.
It had a long top and a flat top around the sides.
What was around the side?
Just saw like a platform coming down the side.
Did you see anything else?
Yes, we saw a black man running around.
A little man or what?
From where we looked he was about this small but we were quite way away so he was about our size.
What did you see?
I saw something silver on the ground amongst the trees and a person in black and that's all I saw.
You saw a person alongside the silver thing?
Yes.
Have you heard about UFOs before this?
No.
You didn't know anything about it so it was something quite new to you?
Yes.
Were you afraid?
Because nobody should panic, we don't know what it is and it could be just something.
There was a Russian satellite that went up on the 27th of August and it's a possibility something came down
but it would not account for the figure you saw.
I think for the moment you should keep everybody away until we've had some analysis of what's going on.
It was in between the gap of this one thing behind the pile of wood.
Yes, I can see that.
Where do they think it was?
They told us it was in between these two poles here.
In between these two poles?
Yes.
Can you try to guide us though?
What equipment have you brought with you?
Gunter is a highly technical chap.
Because it's difficult and very expensive in this country, he's made his own Geiger counter.
We're going to check it out and see if there's any radioactivity there.
He says really some changes, the Geiger would be going faster.
So this is just normal background radiation?
Yes, this is about normal.
I was helping Cynthia out more in technical terms.
So Cynthia found me quite useful in maybe explaining in a way certain phenomena.
Maybe it was a certain time of the year where certain meteorological events occurred
like the Leonard meteor shower or the Perseid meteor shower.
So we used to try and eliminate all the natural events that might be happening in the sky
before we thought maybe there might be something more to it.
How sceptical are you?
Well, I would like to see some evidence.
But you don't think you've got the equipment at the moment?
No, I haven't.
But from what I see from some of the children, I do believe that something happened.
I'm not all that gullible, but this to me is a very typical case.
And I've handled several hundreds in southern Africa.
I certainly believe the children have some extremely interesting pictures
and there's certainly some of the things they've told me they couldn't have known about.
Impossible.
I can remember it like it was yesterday.
It was easy to put down because that's exactly what I'd seen.
So, you know, something that I'll never, ever forget.
In 94, I was in grade two at the time at Ariel.
My teacher was Mrs Cheeple.
What I can remember was we were playing around in the playground area.
It was one of those rare occasions where the teachers were having a staff meeting,
so it was quite a long break.
We were happy to have them because it was more playtime.
And there was like a flash of light and it was bright silver.
Everything shot past.
At the time, I mean, I remember it well.
We were on the field playing our football and a friend of mine came by and said,
Luke, Luke, do you see that in the sky?
What is that? What is that?
So I was looking up and I saw it.
And it was, for one of a better word, you know, a UFO.
I wasn't sure what it was, but it was a silver object that was in the sky.
And we were both, like, looking at it.
And I only saw it for possibly a few seconds.
And it seemed to move off a bit and then suddenly vanished.
And we were both sort of standing there looking up saying, you know, jeez, what was that?
But didn't put too much thought to it and obviously went straight back to playing our football match.
A few minutes later, there was a whole sort of commotion going on
and there was a whole bunch of kids down at the bottom of the playground.
We were sitting on one of the logs that we always sat on eating our lunch.
And I noticed that people were pointing at this one thing or something in the bush.
And I got up to see what was going on because one person actually started crying.
And, you know, like I said, because we were the older group on the playground,
we all, people in my year, just were kind of concerned about what was going on with everyone else.
There was a big group of kids all sort of gathered right at the bottom of the playing field,
pointing and making noise and shouting and screaming.
And I went up to them to sort of see what was going on and try to, you know, calm everybody down.
My initial thought was somebody had hurt themselves or something.
OK, so if I was there, sort of say a couple of hundred metres up, it was right there.
So it seemed to be right on the cross-country course.
I remember seeing two flashing lights and I saw like a big silver,
like a saucer kind of thing that was hovering and then it landed or hovered on a stone.
And I saw two figures come out, really black, but their face,
you could actually see not much of their face, but it was really, really white in colour.
Skin pigmentation was very, I don't know how you can, pale doesn't even, it looked plastic.
You know, it looked like someone who had had too much botox.
Now when I think about it, I'm like, that's exactly what at the time I didn't have a colour or a word for it.
But that's exactly what it looked like.
It was very smooth and soft looking.
It looked like you'd slide right off if you tried to touch him, he'd just, yeah.
I suddenly realised that he's not quite normal.
I didn't actually know about UFOs and aliens at the time, so I just thought he was a strange person.
But it was the eyes that made him.
So that kind of shape, I think the eyes were obviously a lot more fluid, round, shiny, protruded.
Almost like rugby balls or American footballs, huge eyes on the side of his face.
And so I looked over and sort of thought I could see something unusual going on in the bushes as well.
And I was like, yeah, yeah, there's got to be something, it looks like there's something there.
And the realisation that there was something moving, and it appeared to be coming towards us as well, I felt scared at that point.
The panic spread. I was looking for my brother and sister to make sure that they were okay.
And when I did have them, then we continued to look onward.
They just seemed confused, like, what is going on? One moment we're playing, next moment everybody's looking, pointing, and everybody's in a panic.
That was a little bit scary.
I'd just turned 28.
I ended a relationship. I was engaged for six years.
You know, this whole topic definitely weighed on our relationship.
So I moved in with my folks.
I'm thankful that I'm here right now and with my family, who supports me.
As for future goals, plans, work, I have no idea.
But I feel alone.
Dear Emily, I hope this finds you well.
As you may have seen on our Facebook page,
next month we will be celebrating our 25th year as a school.
I know it's short notice coming from Canada, but we'd love to have you join us.
If you can't make it, know that you are always welcome to visit your old home.
Love, Judy.
Okay.
It brings up a lot for me.
It's a reminder of pain, of holding something inside.
I don't want to hold on to those feelings anymore.
Hi, everybody. My name's Nicky, okay?
And that's Ivan with the camera.
And we're going to actually speak to a few of you who did see something that day
and ask you what happened, what you felt when you saw it, and that sort of thing.
You know, so very, very casual.
You must just say exactly what you want to say, okay?
What were you doing on the day?
Well, I was looking, and I saw this maroon colour in the sky,
and me and my friends were following it.
And then we saw this light in the Massasa trees.
Then I saw something shining, and somebody sitting on it,
and they were wearing pure black.
We saw the light in the sky.
We saw something shining, and somebody sitting on it,
and they were wearing pure black.
We saw this black figure running in a slow motion.
The strange thing was it seemed to be in very slow motion,
which to us seemed very interesting,
because Cynthia had come across this kind of event in some of our other cases
around the world where she had reports of, you know, alien encounters.
Cynthia, how long have you been investigating UFO phenomena?
About 17 years.
I'm the continental coordinator in Africa for MUFON.
MUFON has over 5,000 members, most of whom are scientists.
You interviewed the children. What was your conclusion?
I believe them.
I believe they saw what they said they saw.
I think that perhaps some have been influenced by others,
and they've added a little bit here and a little bit there,
but basically they drew in their drawings many things
that I don't think that they could know about.
And how big was the figure?
It was about as big as a grade 6.
How tall would you have said?
Maybe about three and a half feet.
There's another one. He was a bit short.
As an investigator, I've learned that if they tell exactly the same story,
then there's corroboration. They've got together and they're doing it.
But if they tell a similar story, but from different viewpoints,
to me, that's the truth.
We saw two of them. One was standing in front of the ship,
and then the other one had long hair,
but the one was standing in front. He didn't have any hair at all.
Tell me with your hand how big the arms were.
They were shaped like something like that.
Big head and big black eyes, and he was dressed in a black bodysuit.
What did you think it was?
I don't know. I just thought it was some kind of alien from a different planet.
What are they talking about?
I had no experience of UFOs or anything like that,
apart from seeing Steven Spielberg's film,
Close Encounters of the Third Kind, or whatever it was.
You're all bonkers.
I was just a hard-ass journalist, sceptical as everybody would be.
What is this? I want to know. I mean, the BBC want to know.
What is going on here?
There's a truth behind your environment shaping who you are.
For me, growing up in Africa was normal. It was just home.
You're growing up in an area where you need to be aware of your environment.
This is not living in America.
You're in Africa. You're in Zimbabwe.
We didn't grow up around TV.
People liked to joke about, oh, do you have running water?
Yes, that was luxury, actually.
That's something you were lucky to have, or electricity.
Because the places that we went to, a lot, I mean, they had nothing.
You live in a mud hut. That's true.
You live every single day to live and hope you can.
Yeah, so it's completely different.
This place...
Okay, Mom, Dad, do you remember this place?
We used to stop here all the time.
This is really, I feel, at home.
To go back to Ariel means I get to go back to the spot where it happened.
I don't know how I'm going to feel.
I don't know what it's going to bring up,
but I feel really blessed to be able to do that in my life.
My family's religious, and they came to Africa for mission work.
My brother and sister also attended Ariel.
They were very traumatised about the event.
Talking about it in a religious environment
wasn't something that was allowed to be done.
I was very quickly removed out of the situation,
so it was... you know, it was a very difficult situation.
I was very sad, because I didn't know what I was going to do.
I was very quickly removed out of the situation,
so it was... it was packed up, everything,
and we flew into Canada.
I didn't get to have the opportunity of growing up
with the friends in that environment who had had that occur to them.
I'm looking forward to reconnect again.
I haven't been back to Ariel for just over 20 years.
Oh, my gosh.
Holy...
I have the class rest.
Hi.
How are you doing? Good, how are you?
Good. Emily.
How are you? How are you?
I'm good. Yeah, and you?
Good. I'm really glad to be back.
Back. Yeah.
Come on, what is that? Home.
It is home. It is.
It is. Home.
Always. Yes.
It's good to see you. Thank you. Oh, my goodness.
That's Rachel.
This is Paul, my brother, who also attended the school.
So, we're family three here.
So, will someone be able to show me around the school?
They're just going to show you around. Oh, hi.
How are you? It's nice to meet you, too.
I'm walking where I used to step. Yes.
It feels incredible.
OK, we've got a special visitor in our midst.
It's Emily Trim, and she was here at Ariel's school 21 years ago.
Was Mr Mackie here when you guys were here? Yes.
Do you remember Mrs Wacha? Yes.
Yes.
She was, I think, my grade three teacher.
Was she? Yes.
And then she came, sort of like stalking me in the supermarket
as far as you were following me.
And I told you, it was full of you guys, and I was like...
You know, I really loved her, but I knew she was going to hate me
and do that to me.
Jeanette doesn't live in this country.
It really doesn't matter much.
Hiya!
You having a good day? Yes.
Yes? Is it lunchtime right now for you?
Yes. Yes, wonderful.
There were the boundary logs here. OK.
And that field wasn't there. Yes.
It was all brush, you know.
And you guys went down to go look?
Well, I was right on the log when it actually happened.
You were there? Yes, I was here.
And you saw them?
You are the ones who drew those funny pictures.
Yes. OK, nice to meet you.
And where are you staying now?
OK, OK, OK.
You have the shower down there.
And this is your room.
Everyone's got a fan.
I don't have mosquitos on the floor.
You don't have which? Mosquito nets.
It's OK.
Music
And what did your other friends say?
They were scared.
We wanted to tell the teachers, but some of us were too shy to.
We ran down to the teachers and we went into the office
and we started telling the teachers.
And then they said maybe there's nothing.
And how did that make you feel when they said maybe there's nothing?
Well, we felt very sad because we did see something.
Cheryl, what was your reaction when Candice and Tegan told you
about the UFOs and the aliens that they saw on Friday?
I don't know really.
I find it very hard to believe.
I've always taught my children seeing is believing.
Unfortunately, I didn't see, so I don't know if I believe.
We always joke with the children, all these little green men come out
and they say, no, Mummy, but we did see.
So I don't know.
I do believe Candice to a certain extent.
What did the man look like?
Why would they make up such a story?
And kids of that age, 6 to 9, 10, they wouldn't be able to sustain such a story
for such a long time and one of them's going to crack
and then it would be like unrolling a ball of string
and all the rest of them would crack as well.
So would you want to talk about it to friends
or people you meet in the future when you get older?
Or would you want to just forget about it?
No, I don't want to forget about it.
I want to keep it in because I knew that it was true
and I want to talk to other people about it.
They were fascinated.
They accepted it and they're full stride.
They knew what they'd seen.
They weren't stupid.
Children are so much more open than adults.
I've always kept an open mind about the life of the universe
and everything, God, Buddha, whatever you want to call it.
My story was something I hadn't encountered before.
In October 1983, I went to Zimbabwe,
which was just going through massacres
and I went all over Africa being a cameraman,
doing what's called bang-bang, which is serious war zone.
I'd done a lot.
I'd done Angola, Rwanda, Liberia, Nigeria.
I'd done lots of war zones.
A lot of my friends and my crew were killed.
I survived.
That was my job.
But this was a bolt out of the blue
and I wasn't expecting it because I was a realist.
It was totally out of my remit.
I could handle war zones, but I could not handle this UFO thing.
It just didn't make sense.
And that's when I had to call in extra help.
Cynthia Hine put me in touch with Dr John Mack
and I got his number at Harvard University.
Jim Leach from BBC Television News in Harare, Zimbabwe.
Message for Dr John Mack.
This concerns a UFO sighting over a school
where it hovered, landed, a black man got out.
But of course, we're having difficulty being taken seriously
in spite of being the BBC.
Please call me as soon as you can.
Thank you.
I said, listen, I don't know what's going on,
this is way outside my normal ball game.
What do I do?
And John Mack said, as soon as I can break away,
I'm coming over.
And he did.
With his credentials
as head of the Department of Psychiatry at Harvard,
I sat up and took notice.
That took it to another depth.
And the stories are consistent.
There's some details that are not consistent,
like that boy saying the two different days.
Do you think it's possible that one imaginative child
had a story and kind of stirred the rest of them?
No, I don't believe.
I honestly believe they saw something,
but for me to actually draw a conclusion as to what it is,
I don't think I could do that at this point in time.
How many of them reported seeing the craft?
Something in the region of about 60.
More of them could have seen it,
just too embarrassed to talk about it,
or we actually haven't had the grade 1s and 2s involved,
which are the old 6 and 7-year-olds.
How long would you estimate that the scene actually lasted?
It took over about 10 to 15 minutes.
Really, that long?
Did they describe any other sensory experiences,
like smell or sound?
I don't think at all.
I don't think anybody's actually asked them that question.
You've talked with the BBC people and with Nikki Carter here before, right?
Yes.
But the experience is still fresh in your mind, is that right?
What were you doing at the time?
I was playing in the playground,
and then we saw something silver,
and then we quickly ran to the logs
and we saw a silver thing,
and we saw a man standing next to it.
And what did he look like?
Well, he had big eyes that, like, pointed.
Pointed big eyes.
Yes.
Maybe you could just draw the head.
Do you like to draw?
Yes.
OK, put the chair up a little bit.
These are what? What are you drawing here?
The eyes.
And I couldn't see his nose and his mouth,
but his nose was pretty small.
So the eyes were large, is that right?
Did you look into the eyes?
Did you have a sense that you were...?
No, all we saw was his eyes. They were black.
Black, but, like, were they looking at you,
or were you looking at him?
Seen that he was looking at all of us.
Have you ever seen a UFO?
I never have, no.
And I didn't see anything of me.
No nose, you didn't see a nose?
No.
I just, my heart kind of went faster and then slower
and then faster and then slower all at the same time.
Was that, that was excitement?
Yeah, excitement and scariness.
And scary, and happy, you said happy too.
Yeah.
Happy because...?
Because I saw something strange and something peculiar
and something nobody had ever seen.
Hayley, something scared you, is that right?
Yes.
What scared you?
The noise.
The noise that we heard in the air.
You heard a noise in the air?
Yes.
What was it like, like a roar or a buzz or a hum
or what kind of a noise?
It was like someone was blowing a flute.
And that scared you?
Yes.
And what did you do when you were afraid?
I ran away from it.
We told the teacher, but she said just forget about it.
So people who have these experiences are very serious about them.
I think that generally speaking when something powerful, important, exciting, scary has happened
that it's useful to talk about it, to have open discussion.
And it doesn't mean you have to impose a point of view.
But it's not about what we believe, it's what their experience is
and how they find the adults around them being receptive to that experience.
And you said that you saw two, what would you call them?
Aliens.
Aliens you call them.
And where were the aliens in relation to the craft?
I saw one over here and I saw one of these men by the spaceship.
Looks like it was guarding by the big spaceship and there was another one running.
Running in the grass.
And how did he run compared to the way a kid would run?
He ran normally like us, but bouncy as if a human would run on the moon.
You mean as if there were less gravity, seemed light?
Yes, but not as much as a human on the moon.
Not that extreme?
When he ran his distance he stopped and he looked at us for a while and then he ran back again.
The one thing I've told everybody is we are dealing with children here.
Sometimes the imagination can get carried away with them.
How many of you still think they were just making it up?
The thing that caught me was that there were no adults outside.
None of us thought we just happened to be in a staff meeting.
I totally believed the children.
They came running up here in such a panic and even if we had staged it
they could not have run all together like that.
We just heard them screaming, screaming, and they were here.
And a child can't make that up.
And children know when other children are conning them.
And they were like, about a hundred of them just came here.
They didn't see anything.
I think they made a belief story that they actually created.
What do you think started the story?
Since during that time they talk about meteorites and all that.
I suppose somebody created the story and they sort of thought maybe
he had seen something.
You think that the children's imaginations are getting carried away with them.
But I became convinced when I saw the drawings,
because so many of the drawings were similar,
and also when they wrote their stories in their storybooks,
they definitely seemed genuine.
Because they all wrote completely different stories,
but they had seen the same thing.
And I think that's what convinced me
because I think I was as skeptical as everybody else.
It wasn't just aerial school.
There were a lot of different occurrences that happened
over probably that whole week.
I live here at the school, so I try not to think about it at all.
Because if I do, I have sleepless nights.
Then you have sleepless nights.
I do.
I've had a lot of sleepless nights since it happened.
So I try to put it out of my mind.
What do you think about the reality aspect of it?
Seeing is believing, I don't know.
And I'm also scared of the unknown.
So it's something that I block off
because I'd rather get on with school.
Do you think the kids are telling the truth,
or do you think they're kind of...
I think they are.
I'd rather not think about it again,
because now if I think about it tonight,
I'll have another sleepless night.
Because I'm waiting for an alien to come through the walls.
Some of the kids in my class are so frightened,
I actually can see that.
It must have affected them so much that they sort of imagine
something will happen to them.
They're still young and you don't know how to act
and how to speak to them.
You're a bit careful.
If we're going to keep discussing this,
the parent is going to be knocking on my door every single day.
I don't think you can generalise
when it comes to something like this.
You've got to be extremely careful
in which way the parent is going to jump.
If you're going to jump the wrong way,
you've caused a problem.
You've caused a problem.
You're not solving it.
You're probably all aware of this caution
that Colin is talking about.
We had one child who was very upset by the whole thing.
Unfortunately, he's not at the school anymore.
He's actually gone back to Canada.
He was having sleepless nights
and this was a 12-, 13-year-old child.
Basically, the cause of that was his parents refused
to discuss the situation with him.
His parents were very religious
and, according to them,
this sort of thing doesn't happen.
Just down that road, yes.
Oh, my gosh, I can't believe I'm going to see Mrs Wacha.
And shit, her name suits her, too.
Yes, it does. Mrs Wacha.
Exactly.
I remember she was very strict.
She was very, very strict.
Everything was done by her.
There we go.
Judge Wacha.
Oh, Mrs Wacha's coming.
Mrs Wacha's coming out now.
Oh, he's here.
Do you remember?
Yes, Mrs Wacha.
Mrs Wacha.
I'm now old.
I'm now old, I know.
You don't see me to be old?
No.
I missed you.
You missed me?
I was a little bit difficult.
Wasn't I?
No. You?
Oh, you were...
you were strict.
You were strict.
That is exactly what I want to hear.
Yes.
You were strict.
But you were fair, you know?
You were fair.
I was very fair.
Yes, strict.
And it was beautiful.
Beautiful.
There's this business of
us being
asked about the aliens
up to this end.
Because you saw
those things, you saw those people.
We asked the
school children
then
to draw.
You remember?
You also drew.
So Mr
Maki asked us
we put all the papers
according to the classes,
finished this class,
drew the other,
drew the other.
All the same.
We ended up
concluding that
certainly we saw
people.
They're going
where to?
How did they come there?
Who are they?
The people.
We couldn't tell.
That's what the story is.
That's what you saw also.
Yes.
I had kept those
papers myself.
You did?
I don't know what happened to them.
I'm looking for mine.
You can't find it.
I can't find mine.
Because I had thought
it was something I must also
hold onto.
I didn't know
what that meant.
These eyes, did you look at them?
Yes.
What feeling did that give you when you looked in the eyes?
It made me shake a little.
It was a terrifying feeling.
A terrifying feeling.
What made it terrifying?
How did he look at you?
Like an old what?
An old woman who hasn't seen a kid before?
I'm going to ask you to do something.
Try to
just be in that feeling for a moment.
Try to remember that terrifying feeling.
Can you do that?
I know it's unpleasant but nothing bad will happen.
Just try to tell me
what's in the terror?
See what you find
in the terror.
What it might be about.
It was making me
all scared.
My heart was starting to pump faster
and it was making me all woozy.
Like woozy, losing.
Like you were going to faint?
Did you faint?
No.
Then I was looking at him, right?
Then he was looking at me back.
I had to stop and look inside you.
It kept on making me feel faint.
But you kept looking?
Why did you keep looking?
Something attracted me to look at you.
Something attracted you?
The other man, his eyes
looked at me as if I want to.
Things like that.
I want to what?
I want you.
Like I want you to come with me?
I want you to come with me.
I want you to come.
Did you go with him, do you think?
No.
Only my eyes went with him.
And my feeling.
And your feeling went with him.
So was there a part of you that wanted to go with him?
That felt drawn to go with him?
Yes.
Can you say what that felt like?
It was scary and
a little excited.
And a little
I shouldn't go.
And yet I want to go.
Yes.
John Max seemed to have brought out that information.
Because we just took it
in a very analytical way.
We just said what did you see?
And what did the aliens look like?
What did they do?
But we never thought there might be
some kind of emotional
deep effect.
It really gave you goosebumps
if I may put it that way.
There's something more going on here
at the eye.
What made you scream?
I was just getting very
scared.
What were you scared would happen?
Don't be afraid to say
even if you think it's not
sensible.
Just tell me what you were afraid might happen.
I thought the aliens
would attack me.
Would attack you and do what?
Hurt you? Yes.
How did you do that?
It looked evil
because it was just staring at me.
With what?
Staring at you as if what?
As if to do what?
As if I wanted
to come and take us.
I know this is hard.
I know it's hard.
Try to...
It's hard to put in the words
what you felt, I'm sure.
John did this
public meeting
in Harare.
He did an incredible
performance.
He did an incredible performance.
He did an incredible
service to the community
who were worried
and just wanted answers.
Dr John Mack is a
true academic.
He's a professor of psychiatry
at Harvard University.
I think we're very, very lucky
in this country to have somebody of his caliber
so can we have a big hand
for Dr Mack?
I'm thrilled to be here tonight
and have a chance to talk with you about
this phenomenon.
I'm trained in adult and child psychiatry
and adult and child psychoanalysis
and
I'm a relative newcomer to the UFO
field
and the reason for this trip is
the incident that took place in
Rua at the Ariel
School.
A number of you, I'm sure, know something about
what took place there.
The children we talked with
clearly were talking about
a phenomenon that
occurred in physical
reality. The stories were consistent
and the way they talked about it
left virtually no
question in our minds
that what happened was
just about what they
said happened.
I know it was strange. It was very weird.
It got so scared.
If I had to describe that day
the first thing that I remember is
the light and the sound is the main thing that
just strikes me and then
the two shadows, but
especially the sound and the light.
The light because it was so bright, the sound because
it scared me.
Yeah, we heard a sound in that
direction. It was sort of like a
buzzing noise. It was a very, you
know, it was like a buzzing.
The buzzing of what you would hear
at an electric station or
anywhere close to that.
Like something's
being zapped almost.
It kind of sounded like bees but more like
a
yeah, like a machine
bee sound. Just very
strange. At first I thought maybe it was just
me that heard it but the other kids
around me had heard it. It sounded like it was coming from
everywhere. It went louder and louder
and then it stopped and we ignored it like, okay,
I don't know what that is. And then
a couple of minutes later it started again and it
was much, much louder, like
really, really loud, like a swarm of bees and that's
when I started getting scared and everybody started getting scared
and then we started running away
from there.
I noticed
that there was a large
shape amongst the trees which we
couldn't really figure out what it
was. It
looked like a big
rock. It looked
like water was trickling over
it and the sun was reflecting in
that water.
That's the best way I can describe it. It didn't
look like a
smooth metallic object as
you would think
when you were looking at a UFO on
TV as we depict them.
It looked natural. It didn't look
like anything manmade.
You saw it again
appearing in
kind of like in spots. You saw it and you didn't
see it, you know, and then you saw it again
in the same general area, but
it was, that kind of was
like I said, what made you think
twice, like, okay, did I see it? Didn't I
see it? But when everyone, you know, then
everyone else started saying, yes, I see it. And it
was the same thing when we
saw whatever beings were
there, you know, it wasn't like
they were just standing and looking at you.
You would see them in
various places
at various times, so
you didn't know if it was one, if it was more than one.
He moved kind of strangely,
I'd say.
Almost like a
very graceful sort of moment.
You know, not like you're
stumbling around or anything. You don't like sort of
like glided
while he was walking.
There wasn't any gravitational
pull. It was a very fluid.
So when he
was moving, it was very
fluid and flowy and
it wasn't kind of jerky or
slow.
The strange thing was
it was running in slow motion.
As if you would watch a replay
in a football match, it was running
in slow motion diagonally
down the field.
And then suddenly it would reappear in the corner
where it started and do the same
thing. And then it would reappear
and do the same thing.
And that was
frightening. More frightening
than seeing what these
things actually were was
not being able to see them long enough, I guess.
It
really ripped
my socks off.
It was unbelievable.
I've got to justify myself
to the BBC and
how am I going to explain to
a serious BBC editor
in London that this is not
an April Fools joke in September?
The BBC always have
this policy that you don't
run with one source.
You've got to get two or three, preferably
three. And I had
twenty, thirty, forty.
Now, I put a
lot of stake on the physical evidence
but I don't
primarily
emphasise that, not because I don't think
it's critically important. I think the physical evidence
is very valuable.
But for me, my strongest
institute is my
clinical investigative
approach to create trust,
to bring forth
whatever it is, and the memories
and experiences come flooding back.
Now, the fact
is that people aren't threatened when
they come forward about this.
Children, very reluctant
to tell their parents. And a mother
or father may say to a child,
oh, you must have been making it up.
Your imagination is too
lively. And then the child sort of
grumbles and they go inside and they do
what I call going underground.
They know
what happened to them, but they don't
tell anybody.
I mean, you just felt nobody really
cared.
Who do you talk to?
How do you understand it?
The people in my life that were supposed to
be the closest and
the support system.
It didn't feel like
it was there.
There was nobody there to say, now it's okay
to talk about it. So we never did.
And as children, you have a huge imagination.
So you see those sort of things and not know
what they are. And you're left with
this, well, where am I?
Limbo state of, am
I safe or am I not safe? So it
was, I think, as a protective mechanism,
block it out, turn it
off, don't go back to it.
I haven't really
talked to anyone about it.
I usually kept it quiet.
Because most people probably
think I'm
nuts.
You're not exactly going to bring up
this kind of conversation at a
bar or a restaurant
or, you know,
people think you're crazy.
It's very hard. It's kind of strange, I guess, because they don't believe you.
Some of my close friends
know about it, but it's more like
not a joke, but they're like, oh, you crazy type of thing, like
laughter type of like, it's something funny to
something to laugh about.
If this had been ten years ago,
I wasn't in a place where I really wanted to talk about it.
I just didn't want to be associated
with that. It's very self-conscious.
Yeah, it's kind of hard to talk about it.
It is.
Because it's not something that I bring
up to anybody.
Ever.
My husband
doesn't even know about it.
...
True expression of how
it felt at times.
It's really, really difficult to face yourself.
That's a scary time.
Very, very scary time.
A lot of this was done in black
at first, because I think that's how
it's really feeling.
This is
me, with my hands
over my eyes, trying to
hide away from
everything that's been going on.
It got really,
really dark.
I love this piece.
That's why I started
using color. It's still a stern
face, but
I think it's more confident.
Yeah, this one.
So, here.
This is the
mouth being zipped up.
This was like
when all you want to do
is just talk.
And you feel like you have no one to talk to.
I didn't realize that I affected
children that much.
But it obviously has.
It was quite difficult, wasn't it?
My mum and dad would not have believed.
They believed that something had occurred,
but it was very difficult to integrate.
It's very difficult to put your religion
and see the Christian side of it
with that happening.
Sorry, Mr. Satoli. Yes, come in.
Hi. How are we doing?
How are you? Yes.
Hi, how are you? Good to see you.
It's good to see you too.
Absolutely.
Connecting and
seeing the school again.
The event that occurred here
in 1994.
That's what I'm here for.
That's wonderful.
Maybe, if you want more,
if you don't mind,
we can do the tradition thing. Do you mind?
I would love to do that.
Because culture is a huge part of this.
I'll walk you out and then you can
visit all these sacred places
and you can talk to them.
So when you go up there, you're like...
Yes!
Good to see you, isn't it? Good to see you too.
Later. Miss Pitts? Thanks, Mr. Satoli.
You're welcome.
I saw these beings
and they have
black eyes.
We got those ones and we
experienced them.
Quite a lot. A lot? Yeah.
And is it the same description
as how I describe it with
that? Yes.
They come in different versions.
I don't know what you've heard.
We just heard that the aliens
came and they landed
at Ariel.
What you are seeing
and what you are experiencing
is, I can
conclude that
they are spiritual messages
that you have to
deliver to them.
That they are
spiritual messages.
spiritual messages that you have to
deliver.
I'm supposed to talk about this
with...
You don't have to keep it
for yourself. Yes.
You have to share it.
By sharing
then you can be able to change
people's hearts and minds.
So you have to speak
out.
If they don't hear
speaking, maybe you have to shout.
You have to shout.
The significance
of children is that they are not
yet exposed to the world
and they communicate
better with the spirits
and the nature. So
it's always good to have children.
If you want a message to be delivered
it has to be delivered to children
because the child grows
with the message.
We are now going to
the burial sites of the chiefs.
This is the grave
of the royal chief.
The Arios landed on the
center of the grave.
The sacred shrine.
Yes. So it's very important.
It's very important. The Arios landed on
the center of the sacred shrine.
Which means they were entangled
by the chief's graves.
The grand sisters of Zimbabwe.
The ministerial
abbeys have been here for decades.
Did you hear about it?
Yes.
I was quite informed.
Can you point to us where the
Arios school is from here?
This is Arios school.
This is where it happened.
This is where they landed.
Oh my gosh.
Had you had those thoughts before this
experience? No.
How did those thoughts
come to you?
Did they come to you from
the craft or from?
From the man.
And the man
did the man say those things to you?
How did he get that
across to you?
Well, he never said anything.
It's just that the face
is the eyes.
What do you imagine
is his reason for visiting Earth?
I think it's about something
that's going to happen.
Like what?
Pollution or something.
Pollution? Yes.
And how did he get that idea of
pollution across to you?
The way he was staring.
The way he was staring? Yes.
Somehow there was a message about
pollution from the way he was staring?
Yes. I think they want
people
to know
that we're actually
making harm on this world
and we mustn't get too
technology. How did that get
communicated to you? I don't know.
But somehow it did? Yeah.
It came through my head. Through your head?
Did it, like
through words? My conscience I think.
Your what? My conscience.
It came through your, your conscience told you?
Yeah. I mean while you were
in contact with the being you mean?
While the thing was looking at me.
While it was looking at you.
It was like this lake of calmness
in his eyes. I was
compelled to look at him. It wasn't like
I wanted to look away
from him. Time became
very
still and very bizarre.
In my mind, technology
and not, not good
feelings about technology either. It was like
technology was a bad,
dirty word. I think that he
was saying to me, beware of the technology.
Don't go into it too heavy
because it's not going to be good for you.
It was only when I was
looking at him and his face and his
eyes that I got that.
As soon as I looked away from him, that's
when all of reality and
everything that was happening came back to.
And that's when I realised that
something really strange
is happening here.
It was fascinating.
This was imagery
coming through for them
communicating, but it's
done through right in your brain.
You were saying that
you thought that maybe they were trying to tell us
something about the future.
Can you say more what your thought is
or what was it like?
It was like in the world, all the trees
would just go down
and there
would be no air and people would be dying.
I think that
in space there's no love
and down here there is.
There is love? Yes.
Is there anything we can do with that love
as far as taking care of the Earth?
You talked about
the message that we don't
take care of the Earth.
No. Why not?
Several of them talked about
a message being transmitted
through the eyes, that the beings were
trying to tell us something.
What gave that a certain edge of
sincerity was they weren't offering
solutions, like we've got to become environmentally
conscious and do something about the Earth.
I'd say, well, what are we supposed to do?
And they would say, well, no, that's not
what they were conveying.
They were simply telling us that this is
what's going on and they felt very upset
about it, but it wasn't like
an ecological
political program or something.
So that gave it a kind of authenticity.
But first,
no news coverage took it seriously.
And I leave you to check for
little green men and flying saucers.
And then when Reuters got hold of it,
it got very serious.
There was a bit of a buzz and it was all in the news
and everything. You had people that knew
about the school from all over.
Not just in Zimbabwe,
but it was all over the world.
Ariel School
in Roua,
on the other side of the world,
an unusual visitor called it
to a Zimbabwean playground.
Unexplained mysteries.
Something major has happened in Africa.
A unique mass encounter
between aliens and school children.
Hello, welcome back. Someone who started off
as a skeptic, a Pulitzer Prize winner
and all the rest of it, have actually been convinced
that the people you interviewed at great length
and talked to you about their encounters with aliens,
that they were actually telling the truth.
There is something out there.
There's some kind of authentic mystery here
which my training in psychiatry
just hasn't prepared me for.
With all the skill that you have, you're a top American psychiatrist
at Harvard, you would be able to tell
when people were telling fibs.
That's what I'm supposed to be trained to do,
is to distinguish between fantasy, dream,
psychosis or authentic experience.
And this has all the marks
of authentic experience.
We just stared at it and we heard this flute,
sort of like a flute noise.
Then I saw this
black figure running in slow motion
and then I didn't want to see it
so I looked away and I looked again
and I wasn't there anymore.
When you looked at those children,
they were absolutely credible.
And you can look at their faces,
even on television you can look at their faces
and know if they're bullshitting or not.
And they weren't.
We came away convinced
that an extraordinary event occurred here,
one of quite unique,
I think, in UFO history.
If there's anything that could
convince a skeptical,
closed-minded public
that some kind of intelligence
that is not, as the headmaster said,
of this world, then this event
should persuade people.
And I believe
overall, this is a phenomenon
of enormous complexity,
meaning, and value for understanding
of ourselves, who we are,
in the universe, and we're just beginning
to grasp what this is about.
Meet Dr. John Mack,
a believer
in aliens from outer space.
What would the academics up at Harvard University
think about all of this?
We started to hear
that John was getting to be in trouble.
His practice was beginning to be
largely about the investigation
of these strange phenomena.
He had started support groups
so that the various people
who had reported
these strange phenomena
could hear the stories
from each other and begin
to feel a little bit normal.
No matter how I looked at it,
they were talking the way people
talk about something that's
happened to them.
I was stuck with this dilemma.
What do you do at that point?
Do you say, well, I'm sorry,
there's got to be some kind of mental illness
I never heard of before?
Or do you say, maybe what I thought was possible
wasn't complete?
I've been humanly more honest
to say,
there's something I don't know here
and to follow your clinical instincts.
What did you say?
What did you tell your mom?
This is Kaylee talking now.
Go ahead.
I said, mommy, I saw an alien at school
and then my mom said
my mom never believed me.
Yeah?
Did it upset you when your mom didn't believe you?
Yeah, sometimes.
Kaylee!
Hi!
How are you?
It's so nice to see you.
How does it feel?
It's crazy.
Do you want to take a little walk?
I know, we have to look.
Let's look.
I was trying to find mine
and I've been looking to find all my pieces
because I don't have my drawings as well.
See, like these ones you can't see.
I know, that's why I'm like...
Right?
It's not here.
Well, we could keep going.
Tell me what you remember.
See, I was playing rugby over here
in this open part over here
with the little boys.
Yeah.
And then all the logs were down there.
We're all here.
And then, I don't know why
I remember a huge tree like this down there.
Because that field wasn't there.
This is where I kind of...
Yeah.
...remember it happening.
Like standing over there
and then ran.
I must have run there closer to...
I remember being close to the tuck shop.
Well, that's what I remember right here.
And I remember Liesel and I right there.
So it must be there.
Yeah.
And...
Yes.
Miss Bates found some of the drawings.
Miss Bates found some of the drawings?
And an envelope on her desk.
Up in the office there.
But I think it's been such a run around
this morning.
They tried to do things.
So they just let us know they're there.
Oh, how exciting.
I hope mine's there.
I really hope mine's there too.
They both there. I haven't opened anything.
I haven't looked.
Oh, my gosh.
You must be kidding me.
I'm scared.
I'm kind of scared too.
Okay, you open it with me.
We're together.
We're here together.
Let's take a peek.
Oh, my gosh.
I can't see it very nice, but I'm sure
this
was a tree.
I've drawn this again.
Exactly.
Like this.
You see, it's still shining
as well.
I saw like a crazy light.
Oh, my gosh.
With this
coming down.
I
think I blocked out a lot,
man.
You remember, like we keep saying, like
I think we blocked out a lot.
Yeah.
Holy
shit.
Wow.
I know. I think a lot of people
didn't believe us.
It's
beautiful.
so peaceful.
I have the best memories
here. Me too.
With us.
I've been so terrible.
Well, Miss Bates, she wants
to see you.
She's a little hurt because she feels
like the students have avoided this place
for such a long time. Well, you see, that's
the thing is like. I know. What
happened. I know.
I think that's why I've never come
back. I didn't want to deal with
coming here and remembering
all the stuff. I think that's
the honest God's truth that why I didn't come.
Yeah.
So 20 years later.
We still have the same
story.
But that's the funny thing is like I'm adamant about
this tree and the
right and there on my picture, which I don't
even remember drawing.
It's there.
And I drew that.
I can't wait to show my mom.
You have to see it to believe it.
If somebody's a staunch believer that it's not,
how's me
telling them my experience
going to change what they think. It will change
what they think about me. It's not going to change
what they think about the universe. And I don't
like that. But
with 60 of us all saying
it together, that will change
what that one person thinks of the universe.
Many of you are going to
think my guests today have lost
their minds. To be honest,
their stories do sound
really crazy. But
we were intrigued by this man.
He is Dr. John Mack, who does
believe their stories.
The president's lawyer said
what do you think it's like for the dean of the medical
school to see
one of his professors on Oprah Winfrey
saying that men, women and children are
being taken by little green men.
It does reflect
I think the
anxiety that this caused.
Well, doctor, is the profession embarrassed
when one of your colleagues puts forward theories
like this? Oh, yes, we're very
embarrassed and embarrassed for the profession
and a little worried about John
himself. What has gone off the rails
a bit? Well, John is a man
of great gift and great
intelligence, but he's also a man of
who tends to take on enthusiasms
and this time he's gone
too far.
We're worried about him. We hope he'll
pull himself together
and come back.
I sensed
that I ought to try to get ahead
of the curl on the high exposure
that I had, but I was too late.
There was
something afoot.
They were putting together a committee
to look into
the work and see if I had
maintained the standards of
the Harvard Medical School.
I am
Arnold Relman. I am
a physician.
I was asked by the dean of the Harvard Medical
School to look into John's
activities in view of
all the publicity and the fact that
John was using the Harvard Medical
School's name quite liberally
and applied that the Harvard Medical School
was somehow sponsoring what he was doing.
The dean wanted to know
what is he doing?
His research is shattering preconceptions
about alien abductions.
He's studied over 100 people
and is convinced they are telling the truth.
John, you have a very high profile
and the fact that you're a professor at Harvard
tends to make people believe you. Do you think
you could be seriously misleading people about what's going on here?
The concern
is what
is his relationship to
the subjects? Is their
psychological welfare
being protected?
And is this
a violation of
medical standards?
Woo!
I miss this place so much
and, you know,
just after talking to Mrs. Watcher
the kids and the school
and the music.
I'm like, what's going on?
It's a horrible feeling
to feel alone.
Come on, you've got us now.
You've got the whole Ariel family.
Like, everybody's there.
Like, look out for you.
Trace and...
Everybody's there for you.
Everybody's looking out for you.
God, I needed that, you know?
So badly.
They forget that there's a human being
behind all of this
and nobody asks
for it to happen.
Music
There's Liesl.
Liesl fungi.
Graham.
I remember her too.
I remember the face
but I can't remember the name.
There are many people
who probably are not going to believe
certain things until they happen to them.
Period.
That probably is
even more pronounced in the West
compared to many other cultures
because we have
advanced so far technologically
because our technology
which is based in science
is so dramatically powerful
that people start thinking
that must be all there is.
A lot of the criticism
about John and John's work
presupposed
that it was simply
impossible that people
could be visited by aliens,
that aliens even exist.
To reduce knowledge of reality
to purely the physical world.
What about the
whole emotional world,
the spiritual world?
When you go into subatomic reality
there is no material world.
There's only possibility and probability.
The new findings in physics,
if you take them seriously,
are just as undermining of the dominant worldview
as anything I'm talking about.
Baloney.
Old-fashioned physics, new-fashioned physics,
quantum mechanics, string theory,
you gotta have evidence,
you have to be able to measure something.
I am morally
and virtually certain
that what we're dealing with
is some kind of
internal psychological phenomenon.
It is inconceivable to me
that these people
are being abducted by aliens.
If they were, then the whole
world as we know it
is upside down.
Harvard University was
the kind of global champion
of the classical liberal
worldview.
And he was trying to propose
an alternative worldview
with the reality of extraterrestrial
intelligence.
A worldview
is a kind of psychic glue.
It sort of orients you.
It's what allows people to think
they know who they are
in the worlds that matter to us.
Family groups that we're in,
institutions, schools.
What's possible is
a matter of worldview.
A culture decides what's real.
What's real in this culture is completely different
than what's true in other cultures.
I really think
human egoism in the broadest sense
is what is at stake.
Our sense of value,
our sense of who we are.
Are we powerful? Are we
in charge of our own fate?
Freud said there's three big blows to human
egoism.
And the first was the
discovery by Copernicus
and Galileo that the
Earth was not at the center
of the cosmos. Second was
Darwin's finding that we're
not particularly different from
the other animal species.
Freud claimed his was a third, that
we're not really in charge of our own
individual lives. And this
I think could be a fourth.
We're far from being the most intelligent
or advanced
creatures in the cosmos.
I think in the broad
scheme of things,
it's not a socially good
thing to do. It promotes
the cult of mysticism
and magic
and superstition.
You know, the ex-file kind of mentality.
They're out there and the government
won't let us find out
about it.
It's childish. And it's
not good for the American public.
Why should this be so remarkable
when we claim to believe
in God and all kinds of spirits
and yet there's something about this
one which takes a form that
is particularly disturbing to us?
There's a lot of perumphing
that goes on. Well, we don't
really want to be identified
with this kind of science. It's okay
to be identified with other
bizarre views that
might emanate, but
we have our limits too.
Remember, we're a university that has a divinity
school. We know
the boundaries. Theology
is okay, but extraterrestrials
no. Angels, yes.
Extraterrestrials, no.
Let's just sit
down and rationally
objectively talk it through
because there's a lot we don't
understand. There's
a lot we worship in our
various religions
that's meaningful and
inexplicable.
You can't just rule
stuff out willy-nilly because there
is a magical
side of life that is very
precious.
I'm a Christian
in my beliefs, but
that doesn't mean to say that I think
there's no other types of
forms of life that exist in the universe.
There is a God,
but there's also
other things around
that can't be explained,
you know.
It's another
creature.
They teach you there's no such thing as
aliens because, I mean, God created just
human beings. That's what I was taught to, that's what
I grew up thinking.
The universe is so big so I can't
completely say it's a fact that there's no such
thing as life outside of
Earth's solar system.
The universe is a beautiful, strange place and we're just human
beings and we can't
know everything.
Maybe we don't have the capacity
to understand it.
We may be just exploring
the limited
reaches of space.
Beyond that, we
absolutely know nothing in terms
of life or how life
exists elsewhere.
Maybe
it's too disturbing.
In the beginning of
my going public with this,
I received absolutely
no general acceptance.
There were no particular
advantages to be gained and every
disadvantage. There were assaults
from every direction in
terms of the main part of my profession.
If it was an opportunity, it was an opportunity
to commit professional suicide.
It's a dirty subject.
If you want to sustain a career in
the BBC after having been in
many war zones, you don't
suddenly come up with a UFO
story, which was
absolutely waterproof.
Then they just said,
Tim's suffering from the
stress and strains of all the war zones
he's done. He's lost the plot.
He's gone bonkers.
I think that's what my career
with the BBC
end.
Gone.
I think I
lost my credibility
because you don't talk about
these things.
When I was in residency,
John's office was on the
main floor of the
psychiatric wing.
When I came back in 2004,
his office was off-site
and I actually took that
as a sort of metaphor for him being
pushed out and extruded
in a certain sense.
Finally, the dean
of the medical school wrote
a letter to John
basically apologizing
and saying that
it was unfortunate that he had
misconstrued what it was
that they were trying to do
and reiterated this
totally foolish position
that they had that all the
dean was trying to do was to get some information
so he could respond to
calls that he was getting.
And so they ended up dropping
the entire thing and
letting him go back into doing his
normal work at the university.
I accept
Dr. Mack's statements at face value.
He is inquiring and probing
and he has the right to be wrong.
The most fundamental right
that any academic has
is the right to be
wrong. Prove
that he's wrong. That's the job of other
academics.
He became the iconic figure
of someone from inside
a major institution
who was willing to take the risks
and pay the consequences
for what he believed in.
My
respect for John Mack, for his
courage, the difficulties
that he's undergone.
I think any human being
would have to admit
that if the UFO phenomenon
is occurring, as the report
suggests, it's the most important
event in human history.
Are you going to miss me when I go?
Oh my gosh, I'm going to miss all of you.
I really thank you for everything.
I know
I felt so welcome here.
Too obvious.
Yeah.
Good evening, process.
Come on, you'll be fine.
I will.
You'll be fine.
Music
music
Having
a good time
having a good time
It's a very precious thing to me to be able to have this drawing again and look at it
and say after 21 years I'm still depicting it exactly the same way and I can put it with
The rest of them I have probably over 300 pieces and it started here.
I don't know what it means for me further down the road but I feel more confident.
It's a stepping stone forward to go out, show my art, share my story and feel good about
it.
With my family they've been extremely supportive throughout this whole thing and they've understood
that this is something that I've had to go through.
My mother has started speaking a bit about it.
My father for the first time at the dinner table brought it up but I don't know if this
is something that they'll ever be able to accept completely but I know that they love
me and they trust me.
They know because they were there that something happened.
I'd like to introduce Emily Trent, one of the witnesses at the Louisa and Bob Way in
1994.
That was the day my world shattered and my outlook on the world became something completely
brand new to me.
I'm thankful for going through such a process and a journey in life which has led me to
discover, look deeper into the meanings of things and become more self-aware.
And I appreciate you taking the time to allow me to speak and thank you for your understanding
in something so very personal.
I don't know why it had to be Rua, small rural farming town.
I truly don't.
But for whatever reason it did.
It happened.
I'd like to know what we've seen and find out what it wanted.
Why us?
Why us kids?
You know.
It was a wonderful experience actually because I know definitely I'm not going to see something
like that ever again.
Maybe, who knows?
It's something that I will pass on to my kids one day.
They might be just here as observers.
We're just an interesting part of the local community.
Like we go to safari in Africa, see this other creature which is unique to that world.
For some people it is scary, very scary because it kind of makes them feel humanity is not
in complete control of their destinies and we think we are the dominant species on the
planet.
But maybe we are the dominant species on the planet but maybe not the dominant species
in this corner of the universe.
I think it's left me open-minded, I think it's a bit arrogant to say that we are the
only life in the galaxy or the universe.
Yeah, I think it's good to speak about it, speak about it.
If there was one experience I'd like to relive it would be that particular experience.
I don't really say I swear man it was there, that sort of thing, you don't have to believe
me.
I'm sure a lot of people who have seen it barely believe themselves.
I don't think that the answer is out there, I don't think that I'm going to find an answer
from Googling it or from talking to others about it.
I think it's a long story is the answer.
I think the answer will come maybe in this lifetime, maybe in the next, I don't know.
I'm glad I was there, it really stretched my mind and gave me a new perspective on life
the universe and everything really.
I would not have missed that for the world, that's all I can say.
Would you like to see him again?
Yes.
You would like to see him again?
And if you saw him again what would you do?
I'll ask him some questions.
What would you like to ask him?
I'll ask him what is he doing on earth and what does he want with us?
I'll ask him.