Attention, projectionists. Adjust the lens so that your picture will be focused properly before the show starts.
Flying saucers have invaded our planet. Washington, London, Paris, Moscow are key targets. The whole world is under attack.
People of Paris, attention.
Attention.
In 1952, the Central Intelligence Agency, faced with a huge public interest in flying saucers, brought in a panel of scientists, very senior scientists.
We know it now as the Robertson Panel.
They concluded that there was nothing to these flying saucer reports as objective devices of some kind, but that nevertheless, the government had to exercise great care to debunk the stories and individual civilians who expressed an interest in flying saucers ought to be carefully watched, said the Robertson Panel.
And I believe that to be the founding document, the document giving the long-range strategy that has been followed by the U.S. government.
The general feeling amongst people who have devoted a big chunk of their life to studying UFOs, I think is fear that they have been taken for a ride.
That these cases are hoaxes, but sophisticated hoaxes carried out by their own government.
What do you want with me?
Let's take one step at a time.
We are looking at Richard Doty, the professional disinformer, trained to lie.
I'm Richard Doty.
There's probably about 80% of false information being presented, about 20% of factual information.
Unfortunately, the UFO community doesn't know which is which.
And that's your job to keep it that way?
That was my job before.
I'm a private citizen now, but back in the early 80s, it was my job to confuse the UFO community.
Doty was representing himself, as I recall, as basically this sort of deep throat.
Doty had this wonderful way to sell it.
I'm with the government, you cooperate with us, and I'm going to tell you what the government really knows about UFOs.
Doty found a lot of gullible people in the UFO community that would easily believe what he said without any type of scrutiny.
My commander told me, well, there's this guy, Special Agent Doty, and you've got to be careful,
because the impression I got was he had made the Air Force a little nervous, maybe.
They didn't say, you know, egg on their face or anything, but they were just very cautious.
The main reason that we in the UFO field recognize the name Richard Doty is that a man named Paul Benowitz,
a self-made man, a very successful businessman, was systematically driven insane, wound up in an insane asylum,
under treatment for a long time, lost his business, had to turn it over to his family,
and was destroyed by the efforts of Richard Doty.
You hear about the ones that something goes wrong.
You hear about the ones where there's an unfortunate incident or, in some cases, there are failures.
It was unfortunate what happened to Mr. Benowitz,
but they were supposed to protect something, and they did their job.
That's the part of the base that Paul Benowitz could see.
You can see the Manzano Mountain here, where all the nuclear weapons were stored.
The second Air Force base is the perimeter fence.
Paul Benowitz's house is right over here,
and his excellent view was afforded from this exclusive area of Albuquerque.
You basically have a front row seat.
August, September of 1979, Paul was standing up on his deck and looking out over the roofs towards the base,
and these lights he saw would probably be about half a mile away.
There was two of them. They'd lift up from the ground rather quickly,
and then very quickly go around, shoot that way around the side of the mountain,
then drop down behind it, and they did the same thing every time.
For anybody, that would pique your interest. What the hell is that?
He had an interest in the UFO subject.
It was about the only thing he was interested in besides his business.
He had a company called Thunder Scientific.
It was one of the main instruments for high-profile people like NASA and even the Air Force.
A lot of people said he was a genius with electronics,
and he decided that he was going to listen in on what was going on at the base.
Maybe he could pick up some radio signals about what this thing was,
and he knew about where to start looking,
and he started picking up these bursts of information.
When he started to decode the signals, he thought that it had a connection to whatever these lights were.
He decided it was something to do with technology that wasn't ours.
He was a good American, so he called up the Air Force base.
They connected him with Richard Doty eventually.
Paul didn't know initially what he got.
He didn't analyze it.
When he had gotten the first series of transmissions,
he recorded them, and then he contacted the security officer for Kirtland.
I began a dialogue with Paul, trying to find out everything he had,
and as I did, then I learned that a lot of the information he had
wasn't anything to do with a Soviet threat or some kind of hostile threat against Kirtland.
It was information that he had gathered because of the fact he was a scientist,
and because he had sensitive and sophisticated equipment.
He was collecting emissions coming from the base,
and we had to decide on what we were going to do then.
Were we going to allow this to happen, or were we trying to convince him otherwise?
They sent Doty and a physicist.
Paul was being occupied with the other guy.
Rick was taking pictures of all of Benowitz's equipment in his house.
The more he had contact with me and others within the intelligence community,
the more he started analyzing the information.
So we kind of planted the seed in Paul that what he was seeing and what he was hearing
and what he was collecting was, in fact, probably maybe UFOs.
It was very easy to convince Paul.
Paul was a World War II veteran.
He was very patriotic. He always flew his flag.
Those type of people you can convince that, listen, just tell him, Paul,
you can't tell anybody else about this because it could get in the wrong hands.
So immediately Paul became a cooperating source,
and he held everything that he had gotten in secrecy.
Doty was feeding this man all kinds of lies about UFOs
and aliens being kept underneath a mountain nearby and so on and so forth.
And Benowitz, of course, was believing all of this.
He had two films of an object flying.
One picture depicted an object that looked like it was flying out of the mountain,
and it looked like some kind of saucer-shaped object.
He immediately then thought that there were UFOs coming out of Manzano.
The second film was of an object that was something experimental that the government was doing.
When he filmed that, then again the flag went up that he just filmed a classified project.
Paul made a presentation to the Air Force officials on what he had been doing
and about what he had been collecting.
He showed some of his film. He showed some of his pictures.
He had an audio recorder that was playing the sounds that he had collected from the base.
The highest-ranking person in the room, which was a burgadier general, said,
you have some very convincing information, Paul.
And that kind of set everything in motion with Paul to let him think that, yep, he does.
From the point he came in and gave that meeting,
they decided all his perceptions were going to be directed
exactly the way that the intelligence organizations wanted.
We'd briefed everybody in the room, so they knew what we were doing, basically.
And so after the meeting, there was a number of questions asked to him,
what do you want the Air Force to do?
And Paul says, I'd like a grant to investigate UFOs on the base
and a grant to continue this contact that he claimed he had with some of these aliens,
which, you know, that's a different story.
At one point, another agency was conducting an investigation,
and they set up a surveillance across the street from him.
And Paul's son contacted me and said, leave my father alone.
You guys are across the street, and you're bothering my father.
He's getting to the point that he's being paranoid.
Well, I knew it wasn't us.
He said he saw people coming in and out of the house
and looking out from the curtains and things like that.
And as it turns out, the NSA had some people in this house.
They were watching him and actually beaming messages
straight across the street into his antenna setup.
He had started picking up these signals,
and the NSA was scared that anybody could figure that out.
They decided to just take complete control of what he was seeing
and give him exactly what he thought he should be getting.
They replaced his computer with their own computer.
The computer had software that would decode the messages he was getting
and the way they wanted him to see them.
And if you look at the transcript of it, it seems like almost gibberish,
but because people want to pull out content from a random order,
it starts to make some kind of sense.
They said that they were from a planet with no water
and they were trying to find a new place to live
and they wanted to take over the Earth and they can only trust Paul.
They were going to have some kind of agreement with him,
but he said, you can't trust anything they say.
These aliens are evil and served to make him look silly,
which is exactly what they're trying to do.
Paul actually thought that these UFOs had to be coming from some other place.
Paul, on his own, went up to Archuleta Peak,
which is up in northern New Mexico, around Dulce, New Mexico,
and he did his own investigation, basically.
Dulce and Archuleta Peak area had a superstition for many years,
way, way before we were ever involved.
There were strange lights and strange stories about that area
coming from the Indian tribe that lives up there.
If somebody wanted to hide something here, it'd be pretty easy.
It's very remote.
It's supposedly the site of an underground alien base.
That rumor got started in the early 1980s
because of what was told to Paul Benowitz
by the Air Force Office of Special Investigation.
Paul is a pilot and he had a plane and he flew around those areas
and he saw things and he filmed things up there,
that again presented a problem for us,
because what he was filming up there
was actually a secretive military installation
that was training commandos.
So then we had to convince Paul that what he was seeing up there was again UFOs.
The Air Force actually put him in a helicopter
with Rick Doty the first time
and flew him up to a place above Dulce called the Archuleta Mesa.
And before they took him up there,
they dumped a bunch of props up there.
They flew him up there, flew him over the Mesa
and said, you're right, Paul, there's stuff here.
There's some evidence of what's going on.
Why don't you check this out for us?
So I would go with Paul up there,
and we actually camped out there a couple times,
and we actually saw some things that startled me,
which were fully explained later,
but one of the things of interest was lights coming out of the ground,
but the way the lights, these beams, were coming out of the ground
in a pulse kind of manner
that it looked like there were saucers flying out of these mountains.
And I actually saw this,
and I was somewhat concerned that maybe Paul stumbled onto something.
Paul was flying what he called his missions up around Archuleta Mesa
and would send back fascinating letters,
five, six, seven, eight pages long,
handwritten with pencil sketches of what he'd seen,
and finally he started sending large format 8x10 photographs
taken with his Hasselblad in which he'd say,
well, here's the black atomic-powered ship that crashed last week,
and he'd circle it, and oh, I'd look at that,
and bless his heart, I couldn't see anything that resembled
or crashed anything.
Something actually did crash near Dulce on the Mesa in the late 1980s.
Benowitz just happened to be flying over and took some pictures of it,
and so the disinformation campaign had to be ratcheted up even more.
The Air Force, they knew it was something that they were testing up in this area
and that had gone off course and crashed.
Of course, they told Paul Benowitz that it was some sort of alien craft
that had been given to the humans to use
and that they had shot it out of the sky as some sort of a lesson.
Agents would break into his house to see what he had,
and at one point he had these pictures of whatever had crashed up there,
and they were very interested in getting these pictures, so they did.
From then on, he went up and just took pictures of where it had crashed.
What probably crashed there was some sort of unmanned aerial vehicle,
and now they're over in the Middle East,
controlled, killing people in cars as they drive across the desert.
In 1985, they didn't really want anybody to have any knowledge of this kind of thing.
They took great pains to explain to him that it was this atomic-powered aircraft
that the aliens had helped us with and, you know,
bring down that laughter curtain again so people just wouldn't pay attention.
They'd think it was another UFO nut.
Somebody gave him a satellite picture of the landing area.
In 1983, he went up there with me and the chief of police for the Hikari Apache Tribe.
They had made a landing pad, and he took us right to the spot.
They were giving him this information, some of it was true, some of it wasn't.
And I think that was the biggest problem that he had,
coping with why this, why not the other, see?
He thought that this was the place where the aliens were getting together
to take over the world, and he wanted to trap them all there,
kill them all in one fell swoop and save the Earth.
By the mid-'80s, he was getting to the point where he had written all these letters
to congressmen, senators, TV stations, even President Reagan saying,
this is what's going on, the Air Force is cooperating with me.
These are the people who are cooperating with me and giving me this information,
Ernest Edwards, Richard Doty, all this.
He would put their names in these letters.
He'd get answers back saying, we're not interested in the UFO subject.
And there was this kind of cognitive dissonance.
Here are people in the government telling him, yes, you're right,
this stuff is going on, let's keep an eye on it.
And then elected officials and other people in the media saying,
we don't know what you're talking about, this isn't very important.
And nobody seemed to care what he was talking about except the Air Force.
So many people knew ultimately about Paul Benowitz and that sad, strange,
horrible story that it got way out of the realm of just a cute flying saucer story.
Paul was convinced that everything he was doing was UFO-related.
I actually sat down with Paul and told Paul, listen, Paul,
I think you ought to stop.
I think you've gone as far as you can go.
And this is a friend.
This is Richard Doty, a friend.
It wasn't Richard Doty, a special agent with OSI talking to him.
I said, this is a friend talking to you, Paul, because I became a friend with him.
He was a very wonderful person.
And I didn't want to see him harmed.
And I said, Paul, stop it.
Listen to your son, listen to your wife, end it.
Get rid of the equipment, lock the stuff away.
Go on with your life.
Go back to your work, your business, and stop this.
Paul listened to me, and I thought maybe he was going to take my advice, but he didn't.
He continued and continued and continued.
And at that point, we ended the investigation.
We ended every involvement with Paul Benowitz.
By 1988, things were so bad that his family decided that he was going to go back to work.
By 1988, things were so bad that his family decided to take him to a psychiatric facility
and see if they could try and save his life.
And he said that aliens would come at night through his wall
and inject him with something that would make him get in his car and drive out into the desert.
And he didn't remember what he was doing or why he went.
The scary thing was there actually were injection marks on his arm.
This is a friend talking to you.
Years later, I sat down with Paul at dinner and told Paul
exactly that everything we did was a sanctioned counterintelligence operation
to convince him that what he was seeing was UFOs
and that what we didn't want him to know was that he tapped into something on the base
and we didn't want him to ever disclose that.
Paul looked at me and said, you don't have to lie to me, Rick.
I know it's UFOs related.
He was caught right in the middle of it.
And then he was used.
If he hadn't been for Paul Benowitz, I would have never known.
70% of the stuff that was going on.
What kind of stuff did you find that would make you think that there was something underground there?
Well, the entrance to...
I mean, a big enough entrance to get a truck or a plane or something through?
Yes.
You saw this?
But it wasn't where Paul said it was?
No.
Well, the first case of a catamolation in Dulce, it was June 14th, 1974.
People do kill animals and steal the meat and it's different. It was different.
Why did they just take the udder and the lymph nodes and the tongue at the base of the throat and remove the tonsils?
And we were finding the evidence at the mutilation of the gas masks that were made by the military.
Radar shaft and the tranquilizers that were in them. Atropine. They were injecting them with atropine.
I was up front with the ranchers.
They were losing cattle and nobody was compensating them.
I wasn't hiding anything. I never did.
I'm established as somebody who is doing all of this news and documentary.
So I start getting newspapers. People are sending in, Linda, what is the answer?
Okay, this is what I'm going to do next.
I'm going to get to the bottom of this animal mutilation mystery.
And finally, in October of 79, Lou Giroddo was the head of the district attorney's office in Trinidad says,
with our cameras running, finally.
Well, investigators and I have come to the conclusion we're dealing with creatures not from this planet,
is the way he put it, which is in my film, A Strange Harvest.
And to set all the reasons why.
The orange lights that he and a deputy had seen go into the ground, come out, split in two,
go into the ground, come out, split in two, in pastures where they had mutilated animals.
We did follow one and it stayed there.
It was hovering on top of the cattle, Manuel Gomez's cattle.
And when I was going to try to intercept it myself, it flew over me.
But this looked like a saucer type aircraft.
But you could see lights in it blinking.
Why do they put lights here?
If they're from outer space, they don't need any guidance with lights.
I was an analyst in the agency responsible for chemical weapons analysis.
So the embassy would always give me security escort and bodyguard.
Special Forces guy came and I said,
hey, what do you know about these crazy stories about these helicopters that are taking and mutilating cattle?
Oh, he says, you know, my real job is I'm in a special group in New Mexico.
We've been doing something that is really, really interesting.
He said, it just blows my mind.
We got these helicopters that I'm flying, he says.
These helicopters are all fixed up.
First of all, we got no markings on them.
Second of all, they're really fast.
Third, they're really quiet.
And they got a lot of lights.
We got red lights.
We got white lights.
We got strobe lights.
I said, what are you talking about?
He says, we pretend we're UFOs.
What the hell is that?
Do you know anything about this?
Where did all that information come from?
Why do you listen to those people?
They lie.
It's like, yes, but they talk.
And if they talk, once in a while you're going to get a piece of something in that huge pile of crap
that will actually connect to what you want.
And if you don't let them take you somewhere like they did with Paul,
kind of keep an even keel, I think you're okay.
You just have to listen.
That's the thing.
So are you saying the Dulce base or the Dulce architecture, let's call it,
exists or doesn't exist?
Have you investigated the RAND Corporation's involvement in tunneling in that area?
Oh, yeah.
I actually put some of that in the book.
Nuclear waste facility there.
No, not waste, but they exploded an atomic bomb underneath about 10 miles from Dulce
to try and get gas out of the ground.
A stupidest idea.
They couldn't use the gas because it was radioactive.
New programs of the Atomic Energy Commission and other agencies
are designed to expand the usefulness of nuclear energy.
Before work is begun on any of these programs,
the government thoroughly evaluates the health and safety factors, often for several years.
Project Gas Buggy was an underground nuclear detonation
that took place in 1967 in Dulce, New Mexico.
It was an attempt to release natural gas reserves from the subterranean environment
in a severely version of what we would now recognize as fracking.
Some people have suggested that the cattle mutilation program
was actually a covert monitoring program for assessing the radiation leakage levels
into the environment, into the ecosystem, and into the food chain.
Senator Harrison Smead had a conference here in 1980
because the ranchers were asking for help, and I met Paul Benowitz there.
He was taking a bunch of pictures of the aircraft that was coming out of the Kirtland area,
but we were watching the same aircraft fly in the Dulce area.
Everybody's looking at this sophisticated aircraft,
and of course they say, well, they're the ones that are mutilating the cattle.
One agency was doing the cattle mutilations,
but the people that were doing the research on the aircraft
used the cattle mutilations to test their aircraft so that people think it was a UFO.
And it helped the cattle mutilation things.
It's a wonder they didn't crash into each other, you know.
Would we use perception to help shroud what we're trying to protect?
Absolutely.
If you've got an aerial platform that is highly advanced
and the public who happens to get a glimpse of the thing from time to time,
if they're convinced that it's from Venus and there's no way it could be our military,
well, hey, you know, that's awesome, hell yes.
If I'm the agent running the protection for that particular program,
and that's helping me cover something for years, I might even feed the fire.
Doty and others would probably defend their counterintelligence efforts as being patriotic.
They are carrying out work assigned by people who have decided
that there must be a policy of denial in the interest of national security.
They're working for my government.
They're working in agencies of the government
that is supposed to be protecting of the people, by the people, for the people.
How did it all turn upside down?
At the core, there is something that they want to keep people away from, a real truth.
I'm Richard Doty.
I'm here at the UFO Congress in Laughlin, Nevada, as a private citizen,
just enjoying the sights and sounds.
Disinformation is designed to appeal to the person that it's operating on.
The more dramatic you can be appealing to that prejudice,
the better you're going to get your hooks into the person you're trying to get.
In Paul Benowitz's case, he was talking about UFOs,
and so if the Air Force wanted his full and undivided attention,
they would talk UFOs with him, which is exactly what they did.
Benowitz was filming really highly strange craft.
The counterintel's job is to come in and muddy the waters
to make him look like a fool and one of the cover jobs.
It's been a cover story in the U.S. for a long time.
Tell the media, tell anybody who will listen,
that they're using UFOs to cover up advanced technology,
when the truth is exactly the opposite of the words.
In spades?
Yeah, however, within that arena,
there have been points at which disinformation has entered the stream, you know, and there's no...
From FDR, huh?
It became seen as necessary to create an active disinformation program
in the late 1970s and early 1980s,
and the reason for this is twofold.
One was the American Freedom of Information Act.
It's curtain time.
An ingenious printing element that works faster than the eye can see.
Watch it in action.
Thousands of pages of documents were released from places like the CIA, the FBI, all the military agencies.
Documents proving the lie that agencies across the board were interested
and were tracking the UFO phenomenon.
Right there.
During the late 1970s, a variety of leaks started to occur.
Now, they're just stories, right?
But the problem is that there were many of them,
and they seemed to have a coherence about them.
Researchers at the time were in a very optimistic mode.
I wouldn't say they were giddy so much as just hopeful
that if they got the right leak or the right document,
that they just might be able to smash the wall of secrecy.
Then what happens?
Then we get entrance into the field
by individuals who start leaking documents of dubious origin,
whose provenance was basically unknown,
that cause now 25 years worth of dissension in the research field.
And it's the same within the mainstream media.
Serious media never in their news coverage
truly seriously promoted the extraterrestrial hypothesis.
What they did do is move that to the realm of entertainment.
Any time someone brings up such ideas seriously,
what you find is the serious media says,
well, you've been watching too many movies.
So in a sense, you could argue that the movies are used
to inoculate the public against these truths.
So that these demonstrably false UFO stories become inoculations.
When the doctor inoculates you from a disease,
he gives you a little bit of it,
and then your body's immune system recovers, deals with it,
and now you're kind of immune to it.
Look at the UFO conferences.
Where are they held?
Usually in small, dingy hotels
with rather limited numbers of people participating.
I mean, there has to be a reason why it's perpetuating.
You don't see conferences on leprechauns,
so why do we still have conferences on UFOs?
One of the keys to a disinformation campaign
is to have a feedback loop,
and you need people on the inside to feed back to you
the results of the operation.
Probably, Doty's first success
in rounding up a useful asset,
as they say in the intelligence field,
or a useful idiot,
as they also say in the intelligence field,
was his recruitment of a man named William Moore.
Now, William Moore, I think very significantly,
was the co-author of the first book,
about Roswell.
I was given the task of making contact with Bill Moore
and basically finding out what he knew and who he knew.
Bill was a little reluctant to disclose everything to me.
For obvious reasons, here I am a government agent
coming in and introducing myself
and wanting to know more about Roswell.
But there's techniques that we use,
that we're trained to use,
in gaining that person's confidence,
and I used those techniques against Bill Moore,
and they worked,
and Bill Moore took me into his confidence,
and we had a professional relationship
as far as him providing us information
about the UFO community
and agreeing to say things that we wanted said
regarding the UFO community,
or within the UFO community.
The process of studying this phenomenon
and the people involved with it,
of assessing the claims and the counterclaims,
and of dealing with the question of how we as Earthlings
will react to the discovery of a race
of extraterrestrial visitors
and how they will react to us.
All of this and more,
one finally looked at in perspective,
leads us to the inescapable recognition
that in studying the UFO phenomenon,
we are at the same time becoming more aware
of ourselves as individuals.
Moore was singled out
because he had achieved considerable celebrity
within the UFO field
and a certain authenticity
that would recommend him to politicians and journalists.
And remember, it's the politicians
and the journalists who are the ultimate target
of all of this disinformation.
I went to visit Bill.
He had a bad back.
He was lying flat in his back.
He couldn't move.
He was like in traction.
And I remember him very dramatically saying to me,
aliens do exist.
UFOs are real.
I know that now for a fact.
Just seems kind of almost like a bad science fiction movie.
But that's kind of what was going on at the time.
He was very invested in the science fiction world
and invested in maintaining these contacts
that he had supposedly inside the government.
At one point, Bill Moore had played me
an early tape recording of a conversation he had with Doty.
And Moore was telling me, you know,
this is a huge breakthrough
and this guy is like on the inside
and he's going to give a lot of stuff away.
And I just remember even back then
that I was kind of suspicious
that it just sounded a little too good to be true.
But I was kind of curious as to why somebody
who supposedly was in Air Force Intelligence
was speaking so openly
about some of these incredible things.
William Moore was using his position
as an executive of an outfit
that was called the Aerial Phenomena Research Organization.
And in fact, Moore admitted
that he paid off the secretary of that organization
to send him reports at once when they came in.
And they went directly to Doty.
Bill didn't believe everything I was telling him.
And obviously, he's a very smart person
and a lot of the information I was telling him wasn't factual.
If you're a UFO researcher
and you were offered documents that nobody had ever seen
that pointed the way to what the government might know about UFOs
and in exchange you basically had to report
on what people were thinking,
what rumors were making the rounds.
That's what he was offered
and in exchange he was offered something
that nobody else had gotten up to that point.
Pure, unadulterated information
that would lead him to the center of the answer,
the answer to the question, you know,
what does the government know
and are there actually some sort of non-human intelligences
interacting with the human race?
Moore later was part of the series of break-ins
into the Benowitz House
and the Psychological Warfare Program.
Again, self-admitted by Moore.
Moore was not working alone.
Others, I'm convinced, went for the same deal
and the deal was very simple.
You cooperate with us
and we will give you the information
that the U.S. government has deep down in those vaults.
Now, this is the Faustian bargain
that William Moore went for
and he came up short on it.
It became apparent to me
that my supplying information to the government
through Doty, on the activities of Paul Benowitz,
Apo, and to a lesser extent several other individuals
was to be a part of this equation.
I also discovered that whatever it was
that Benowitz was involved with,
he was the subject of considerable interest
on the part of not one, but several government agencies
and that they were actively trying to defuse him
by pumping as much disinformation through him
as he could possibly absorb.
Being a very small part of that process
gave me, I thought, something of an advantage.
It became my intention to play that advantage
for all the information I could get out of it.
Benowitz, for his part...
Frankly, I'm a little ashamed
of some people in this audience
regardless of what you believe, what you hear, or not.
They had to stop the talk about four or five times
just because of all the yelling.
People got mad, ran out of there.
I saw a woman start crying and leave.
People kept saying,
Where'd you get that crap from, Bill?
And one guy said,
I'm gonna get a fire hose
and ran out the back.
Very dramatic.
Bill's admission to working with government agents
was the first acknowledgement
to the degree to which our government would go
in an attempt to keep the cover-up going.
And I think people were angry,
maybe not so much at Bill,
but at themselves for only naivete
as allowing that to happen and refusing to acknowledge
that they could have been just as easily duped.
It's scary to think,
gee, somebody I trusted
might be playing me for the fool.
Bill Moore, I think, probably believed
what he was preaching.
I think he was one of these people
that wanted to believe
that he was one of the chosen few
to spread this information,
to be the Moses of mythology, UFO mythology.
Moore's book was well received
and, in my opinion, well done research,
but very troubling because the thesis was
that Roswell was a real spaceship that crashed
and that the U.S. government has the parts.
I believe that he was singled out
precisely to ultimately discredit him and Roswell
to keep the press and the politicians off of Roswell.
July 8, 1947.
The Army Air Forces has announced
that a flying disc has been found
and is now in the possession of the Army.
Army officers say the missile, found sometime last week,
has been inspected at Roswell, New Mexico,
and sent to Wright Field, Ohio, for further inspections.
The key thing to remember about the alleged crash
of a UFO at Roswell in 1947
is that by the time of Paul Benowitz's involvement
in the UFO field,
it had been entirely forgotten by the UFO community.
And it was only with the publication in 1980
of the Roswell incident by William Moore and Charles Berlitz
that the elements of the Roswell story,
the crashed spacecraft, the recovered alien bodies,
the pact between the American government
and the extraterrestrials to back-engineer their technology,
all of these things have eventually become
the core story of the American UFO mythology.
Their craft crashed somewhere
after coming all these 50 light years, they crashed,
and then they sent another one that crashed again
and sent another one that crashed.
There were about nine crashes in the Southwest
in the late 40s.
And that would indicate to me, or at least suggest to me,
that we were testing something that was crashing.
Roswell happened.
Two crashes, one in Roswell and one in West.
They didn't find the craft for a couple years.
It was all one crash, but it took them a couple years
to find the second crash site.
Things are getting weird, man.
Now, Doty played a massive role
in the perpetuation of the Roswell myth,
many of the ideas prominent in the UFO subculture,
for two decades.
And it was completely avoided.
Rick Doty is certainly a fascinating character
and clearly a trickster.
A man who probably has trouble figuring out
whether he's lying or not these days.
It would not surprise me if people were selected
so disinformation.
It would also not surprise me if some of the people
were selected because they were not very bright.
They lacked certain critical judgment,
but were very energetic in putting out certain messages.
And I do often think that some of the people
in the government agencies who have been involved
in the UFO field were kind of pushed
or nudged in that direction.
They just go into the field and muck it up automatically
by themselves without any external controls.
Rick is not the man you're after.
It's the person in the control position
that's important here.
In my opinion, he was simply a pawn
in a much larger game, just as I was.
What we are hearing today about malevolent aliens,
underground bases, secret treaties with the U.S. government
has its roots firmly planted in the Benowitz affair.
The entire story of a secret treaty
between the U.S. government and the aliens
of exchanges of technology between us and the aliens,
of battles between aliens and American armed forces,
and of aliens allegedly having implanted
hundreds of thousands if not millions of human beings
for the purpose of taking over the world
and using us as cattle or slaves
came about as a result of the disinformation process.
I know because I was in a position to observe
much of this process as it unfolded,
and I was providing regular reports on its effectiveness
to some of the very people who were doing it to Paul.
There wasn't a whole lot that we did.
There was just a simple, really, really simple nod
and statement to Paul that what he was seeing
was probably UFOs.
It's generally assumed that the counterintelligence operation
conducted against Paul Benowitz was designed
to throw him off the scent of some kind of classified
experimental technology that he was accidentally filming
over Kirtland Air Force Base.
But when you stop to think about it,
this doesn't make a whole lot of sense.
If the Kirtland-based personnel really had wanted him
to stop his investigations,
they could have ordered him to do so.
Instead, they encouraged him to continue his research
and indeed facilitated his growing delusions
about an extraterrestrial invasion.
What this suggests is that rather than a campaign
directed against Paul Benowitz,
this was an information war on the American UFO community.
And there are a number of reasons why Air Force intelligence
might have wanted to use Benowitz as a conduit
for disinformation.
Psychologists were constantly seeking evidence
for the extraterrestrial conspiracy and the UFO cover-up.
They were digging through documents,
they were hanging around secret air bases,
and quite likely stumbling upon genuine military secrets.
And a more serious possibility was that Soviet intelligence agents
may have been infiltrating the UFO field
in order to extract this kind of information
about new technologies.
It's no coincidence that the timing of the operation
against Paul Benowitz dovetails with the development
of the stealth program.
And at the time, this was the absolute pinnacle
of global aviation technology.
And that's exactly the sort of thing
that Soviet agents would be looking for.
If you guys are doing a film,
I do not want to do an interview in a film
in which you're going to try to communicate
that there's nothing to the UFOs,
that advanced technology is being used to cover...
I mean, that all you're doing is...
That's not what we're doing.
It's just playing into the government,
absolutely what they want people to do.
That's absolutely not what we're doing.
People trying to put out documentaries on UFOs
seem to be teased over and over
and then have the rug pulled out from under them
at the last minute.
In the late 70s, a rumor started circulating
that there was a film of a UFO landing
at Holloman Air Force Base in New Mexico.
And apparently, a UFO came and landed
at the Air Force Base on the tarmac.
A group of people went up to meet him.
There was some sort of exchange of information.
Then the alien got back in his ship and took off.
I have wondered that that film,
I think as many people have wondered,
was an abortive attempt at some kind of disclosure.
We began with an invitation
and met with Paul Shartle,
who was head of security for the depository.
That's where all the films from the military are sent,
all out at Norton.
We talked about possible programs
such as three-dimensional moving holography,
atomic fission, a dog program
where they trained shepherds to do reconnaissance,
and a lot of laser work at Wright-Patterson.
Then he said,
I want you to come with me into this studio.
We went into a studio, which was a clean room.
He said, what would you think if we told you
that in the early 70s,
there was a landing of an alien craft
at Holloman Air Force Base
and our TDY, temporary duty guys, had filmed it.
And I was just sort of scratching my head thinking,
UFOs? What are we talking about?
So he said, look, if you're interested,
you should bury that under the other projects
because a UFO sends up a red flag.
So he said, if you're interested,
go talk to Captain Somebody
and he'll start a liaison with the Pentagon,
which we did.
I was told that there was footage,
and that was sort of like a carrot.
You know, you'll be provided with a film
that we have 900 feet of Ektachrome.
And off we began our project.
We had a legal contract with the Pentagon
and an agreement on everything that we were going to be doing
and their total cooperation.
They fulfilled every one of our requests.
They vetted our information and gave sanction to it.
They really did not influence the content at all.
I was quite surprised.
Even the people at Holloman did not say,
what are you doing? What are you talking about?
They seemed to confirm that something had happened.
And the film was not forthcoming,
but I knew where it was and what it was
and was told by one of the people we worked with
that it was confiscated at the last minute
because it didn't seem appropriate.
So we ended up having to go to animation.
But everything else was documented,
as I recall it happening.
It was a daylight shot of a light ascending
on Holloman Air Force Base.
And then with that little clip,
that's all that I can tell you that was genuine.
A landing of a craft at Holloman, it was film.
Very brief.
That's all I can tell you. It's genuine.
Just that snippet?
Just a light coming down from above.
It was very not that distinguishable.
It was just among other footage.
That's all I can tell you.
And just to say on camera,
you never saw the Holloman landing footage?
Not really.
Okay. Can you elaborate?
Can we just wait for the car?
Saved by the car.
I'm trying to think how to answer that.
I knew what the film was about, all the details of it,
but I never saw a real projected version.
Is there a still of it?
Yes.
What is your bottom line, beginning, middle and end?
Our bottom line is that there is a UFO phenomenon
that's genuine and needs to be studied and taken seriously,
and that one of the things that makes that difficult
is the muddying of the waters by people like Rick Doty,
Walter Bosley and others who are working for FBI, OSI,
whoever else they're working for, CIA, NSA,
and that they are making the work of people like yourself
and us and others who want to understand
what's really going on very, very difficult.
Okay, and thank you for your attention.
We're ready to roll here in just one turn.
If you believe it's true,
you have to buy in to this fantasmagorical,
conspiratorial, bizarre, nonsensical, ridiculous story.
And you know, when I sat down with Rick,
his response to me is, you know, it's really all true.
He was scared.
Rick's great strength is he's a wonderful storyteller.
He's a very friendly guy.
He builds relationships easily.
My immediate instinct is to trust him.
I saw him.
He was a human only.
Not a human.
I think it's very easy to mislead people in the UFO community.
You get them going down a certain trail.
You give them certain leads,
and you just watch people chase their tails
over and over again looking for the truth.
I was living and working in New York when Linda Howe
actually came and stayed with me for a few days,
and it was right in the midst of her working on this HBO project.
Linda sort of was, I believe, on the track at the time
of thinking that this was the film
that was going to, again, expose everything.
And I believe she was in touch with Doty at the time.
I think, in fact, she had even gone to meet him face to face.
And that was very curious to me
because I'd known about this guy through Bill, you know, Bill Moore.
And so I thought, hmm, now he's kind of hooking Linda in the same way.
Doty says that he has names of people who are witnesses.
A security guard has a gun melted in his hand.
There's a disc. Beings.
I want to investigate that story.
The original plan, Linda Howe, was to obtain everything she knew,
as much information as she knew,
and try to find out what she was going to air in this documentary to HBO
and whether we wanted it aired or not.
So I drove her out to Kirtland, to the OSI office.
I took her into a special room.
I told her it was the commander's office,
which wasn't really necessarily true.
The first thing that shifted this from being
what I thought was going to be a five-minute meeting,
get these names and addresses and phone numbers and go on,
because I had already set up other things to do,
that documentary that you did broadsided the government.
How do you mean?
Nobody ever expected that a credible journalist
would ever take on the animal mutilation story.
It was like something was shifting in the air.
Where is this going? What is happening here?
He narrowed gave me a list of names, phone numbers.
Instead, he said,
my superiors have asked me to show you something,
pulled out this manila envelope, pulled out these pages,
and as he's handing them to me, he says,
you can read these. You cannot take notes.
You can ask me questions, but I want you to move
from the chair you're sitting in to that chair.
Everything that was done there was being filmed
by other agents in another room.
It was a two-way mirror.
And I'm looking at the top page in its all-caps briefing paper
for the President of the United States of America
on unidentified aerial vehicles.
And I'm trying to read what is the most remarkable series
of letters in words that probably has ever been handed to me,
because this was new. I was innocent.
And it started out about all these places
that the government of the United States had retrieved
disks that were identified as extraterrestrial.
I knew some names, like Roswell.
There was Aztec, Magdalena, south of Laredo,
and down in Arizona, there were...
My mind was kind of reeling at how many places
this is saying because all of us had only heard of Roswell,
really. And eventually it came to paragraphs
that are as indelibly emblazoned in my mind
sitting here today as they were then,
and the one that probably is the one worth sharing
for all of this.
These extraterrestrials manipulated DNA
and already evolving primates to create Homo sapiens.
And I remember reading that sentence over
several times trying to absorb
the implication of its meaning.
Because if Homo sapien
is a genetically constructed species
by extraterrestrials,
we are then by definition a planet
of six and a half billion androids.
If we are androids, what purpose are we serving?
All of that hit me reading that sentence.
Then on the last page,
paragraph, paragraph, paragraph, paragraph,
project garnet all caps.
All questions and mysteries about the evolution
of Homo sapien on this planet have been answered
and this project is closed.
The plans that I showed her came from our special office
in Washington with the operational plan
and what I was supposed to do
and the plans to show her these.
I'd read them before, I knew what was in them
and I realized that some of the information contained in there was real.
But then I realized that you have to give real information
in order for a person to think you're credible.
So I knew what was in there and I gave them to her
and I did what I was told to do.
When you look back at it, they must have had meetings
about how do we stop
a persistent and dogged reporter
who has already demonstrated
that she's going to go after a really, really difficult subject.
How do we stop her?
When you look back,
it all makes sense.
She wanted me to tell her things
that I couldn't tell her
and at one point then she went public with my name
and she did what Paul Benowitz and Bill Moore didn't do.
She publicized the fact that she had a...
she was deceived by a government agency
named the OSI
and although there were many other people
involved in operations, she named my name
and I became a public figure.
We actually played a trick on Linda
that kind of paid her back, so to speak.
Not anything that harmed her in any way
or anything like that, but we kind of
planted something that she ran with
which wasn't factual and I think she realized
that maybe she should keep her mouth shut after that.
The forged documents shown
to Linda Moulton Howe by Richard Doty
would form the basis for the Majestic 12 papers
which expanded upon the story of the Roswell UFO crash
and provided the foundations for the future
UFO mythology in America.
And over three decades later,
these documents are still dividing
the international UFO community.
Before, it had always been inferred
that a cover-up was underway.
There was talk about who was involved and so forth,
but there was never any paperwork.
Here's the paperwork.
A package showed up at the home of Jamie Chanderay
who was Bill's sort of writing and research partner.
What it contained was a canister
of 35-millimeter film. They developed it
and what was on it was photographs of this document
saying that there was a group that had been controlling
UFO information, how it was released to the public
and how the government should deal with it.
Regarding the MJ-12 documents that were released
to Jamie Chanderay or Bill Moore, I had absolutely nothing to do with that.
The document could be real
and because of the nature of it,
it was a perfect perception management device.
People have to realize that these things
may not be to cover up the truth about flying saucers.
It may be more to gather information
about how the public responds to manipulation.
When I print off the sum total of all of those documents,
you get a stack about this thick.
When you read them through,
as one day I decided this is what I'm going to do,
it's very impressive.
To have faked it would have required a team,
a high-level team of very, very expert individuals
who know everything about document creation,
science and technology of the 1940s and 50s
and a whole bunch of other things.
I looked at them and initially I thought they were good forgeries
but over time my opinion of their quality has gone downhill.
The use of a zero in front of a date,
the use of an extraneous comma,
the obviously photocopied signature,
they just keep getting worse and worse.
If they were faked, the only thing that one can say is
the UFO topic was considered important enough by these people
to create the most elaborate,
incredible, detailed series of papers
and one would have to ask if they're faked.
Why?
There were some investigations conducted by FBI,
OSI,
regarding the MJ-12 documents,
extensive investigations just to determine
whether these things were legitimate,
whether they had any information,
and then who released them?
I was interviewed as a suspect.
Did I do these?
But it was proven that I didn't do them.
But somebody outside the government created it
and in that particular instance, I don't know if the government
would prosecute them.
Doing that would lend credence to the document itself
and the only other thing to do is just say,
we end investigation and not tell anybody what the outcome was.
I like to think of UFOs as weapons of mass deception
and the role of the intelligence organizations
and the military in propagating the UFO mythology
as somewhat analogous to what evolutionary biologists
call a punctuated equilibrium.
The UFO mythology develops of its own accord
and the Mirage Men will just drop
a new piece of data, a new meme,
some new faked documents into the mix as and when
it's expedient for them to do so.
And there's no real need for a sustained
UFO deception campaign because
the folklore is just perfectly capable
of sustaining itself.
The US government had
a one secret program
in which 12 astronauts
were sent to an alien home world
Serpo, 38.4 light years away
from the years 1965 through 1978.
When the returning astronauts
came back, I believe there were seven,
that report was finalized into
a report called Project Serpo in 1980.
Rumors about this kind of thing have been
flying around since the 1960s or 70s
so it's got some kind of historical provenance.
In November of 2005, Project Serpo
was sent to my UFO thread list.
I received an email from someone,
he requested to be anonymous.
When I first read
that bombshell email,
it was far different than anything
I'd ever received and
even though it was a version that was
different than what I was familiar with,
it had the ring of truth. Somebody within the
government would have to be cooperating because I can tell you
that a lot of the information,
not all the particular details,
but a lot of the information is factual.
I believe that it is
a disinformation campaign to lead people astray.
That said, a good disinformation campaign,
a good perception management campaign,
will always include nuggets of fact and truth.
And some of those nuggets of fact and truth should be,
if you're going to do it effectively,
not for extreme facts or truths.
They brought back
thousands of soil samples,
samples from the even civilization,
and I believe all these artifacts are now ensconced
at bowling air force base, and photographs too.
There's always a possibility that the Serpo story
was created for disinformation
to present to the Soviets back
in the Cold War and somebody stumbled onto it.
That's always that possibility, but I don't think so.
It's not a professional job.
Myself and three others
were working as a research team
looking into the Serpo story.
We really wanted to get to the bottom
of Rick's involvement in it.
People within the UFO community immediately said,
hey, is Richard Doty involved in this?
Did Richard Doty do this?
I never had anything to do with the Serpo story.
We were adamant at this time that Rick Doty
was the person sending the information,
but we didn't have any proof, and the only way
we could get that proof is if we could see
an actual copy of the original emails
is one of the greatest novelists and writers
of the 21st century, it's not him.
We came up with a plan. We'll use the same name
and just contact Victor and let him think
that his anonymous source was back in touch with him.
We asked Victor to send us copies of the emails
that we allegedly had sent him, which meant
we could look at the headers of these emails
to determine where they actually came from.
We asked one Rick Doty to compare against
that it was indeed Rick Doty's IP address
on the request anonymous emails, and as it turned out later,
he was also several other people in the story,
all contacting Victor, and Victor thinking
he's been contacted by a multitude of different people
when in fact it was all one person, it was all Rick Doty.
I didn't create it. I didn't conspire
with anybody else to create it.
I didn't create it by somebody else,
and those people I don't know.
How do we ever know what we know?
Apart from Victor Martinez, who really started this thing off,
I'm the only name who's known.
We've got this anonymous storyteller
who's a brilliant campfire who's entertaining us
with this incredible tale, and we're sitting here
with bright eyes, with the flickering flames,
thinking, wow, tell us some more.
The idea of disinformation is it's meant to be believed.
With Serpo, the first response is,
well, this is fascinating, but it's ridiculous, you see.
Of course there's an aspect to me that wants to believe
this wonderful story. I had no idea where this would be.
Richard Doty came to the Loughlin Conference in 2006.
He presented himself as somebody
being given information to reveal to the public.
He didn't quite know why, but thought it was very important.
What's strange about the Serpo thing and Richard Doty
was that he denied continually and vociferously
that he had anything to do with it,
yet he came to the Loughlin UFO convention
to see what was going on there, to hear Bill Ryan talk
in person rather than just on the radio,
and basically had his hands in a lot of things that were going on
or at least looked like an interested bystander.
Why should he be interested in this silly story?
Wonderful question. We don't know whether
Anonymous got this from the movie or whether
Spielberg had the tip off that this was one of the ways
as many people in this community suspect
that over the years the public have been
gradually acclimatized to the possibility
of this contact with an extraterrestrial race
by seeding little parts of the truth here and there in movies.
It's the best way to get ideas to the general population.
This might have been one of the ways of doing it.
I think the information should be
should be brought out to the public.
Let the public decide whether this is real or not.
Whether you think the information is real or not
or whatever proportion of that might be the case,
this is a government operation. If it's a government operation,
these guys wouldn't be doing their job if they weren't following me every step of the way.
Ever since the middle of November, I've been assuming that
I'm being monitored. If they're not doing that,
they're not doing their job. It's like I'm one part of a team,
but I don't even know who the other team members are.
That I'm being bugged.
I mean, this may be paranoid. Whatever's going on,
it's happening at a government level
and, therefore, everything that I do is being watched.
I have to assume that I'm being tested.
You know the whole war more stuff. I wasn't around then.
But they ran him around ragged just to see whether he would make a good scoop.
Just to see whether he was willing to obey orders.
I have to assume that there's something more at stake.
You see...
You also have to have a very good bullshit protector as well, though.
Yes, I know.
Since 1985, I've talked to
18 people at the cabinet level or above,
including four presidents.
About a third of them have said,
it's true. About a third of them have said,
I've heard it. And I think it's true.
And about a third of them have said, I don't have a clue.
I do think, though, Dr. Green,
that this is important for you to investigate.
Turn that off for me.
The trouble with the whole UFO thing
is there are so many people who make up BS stories
that no one can check.
You know, somebody can step forward and say,
I'll tell you what's going on in UFOs.
And they can say, I briefed the president.
I've done this. I know what's going on.
I don't know. I think there's too much BS in that field.
Part of the problem
that UFOs created
was that there were people within the government,
within the Air Force, within the CIA,
that existed.
And because they had stature, because they had rank,
their opinion was considered proof.
Unless we understand
and work effectively for the principles
upon which our American way of life is founded,
the structure will crumble.
Well, before going to Norton Air Force Base,
going into a clean room and being told that we had had a landing
and that we needed to be respectful.
His name was all over the wall as head of security
and his boss and everything agreeing to it.
I didn't believe it then.
But then when confronted with the information,
I now realize after working with intelligence people
that it's a reality.
And they stand behind the idea that they don't disbelieve it.
It's just so far it's not proven to be a threat
and that's the way they got out from under it.
In the intelligence community,
there are definitely people
that are interested in extraordinary phenomena,
particularly UFOs, definitely believers in that,
because you don't work in that profession
and it's not just a profession, it's a world unto itself
without learning some things.
How many pictures do you need? How many eyewitnesses?
This is something that controls possibly even this program.
What is known of the truth of them, these other beings?
What if the truth is bad?
Could be. What if we're their farm animals?
What if they eat us psychically?
I don't know. There's a lot of possibilities here that are not good.
I think that we are surfing on the wave
of a huge adventure,
of the opportunity of humankind
rolling into a totally new era.
And that wave might break one of these days.
Even the Vatican recently has come out in preparation
saying, hey, listen, you know, there is anybody out there
that are all God's creations and they're our brothers and sisters, really.
I mean, what a setup that is for what might be coming next.
We're really a byproduct
of extraterrestrial intervention.
We're really, I mean, this is my view,
that we've been genetically altered
by maybe not one,
maybe perhaps several extraterrestrial races.
The government obviously doesn't want to tell us.
They don't want it, otherwise they'll disclose everything they know.
And the most important players, the aliens don't want disclosure
because they could disclose any time.
I mean, they control most of the cards.
I don't have any files, any photographs, anything to show you.
I just have a lot of personal research.
I have my professional experiences
and I have the bona fides, the tested bona fides of the sources,
and I have my intuition.
And those things all fit together
and you kind of get a picture.
There is a planet
that orbits Sirius, the dog star system.
They are human.
They are very much interested in us
and they have been key to our survival.
And they are capable of coming here.
Certainly others have come here.
Now, could that be
part of disinformation?
Absolutely.
I read things even today that we'd fed to Paul Benowitz
or to Alin Howe or to Bill Moore
that I'd fed to him.
And I see that today and it's surprising that that stuff's still there,
but it just shows that we were a professional organization
and we did our job and that information is still out there.
The people whose job it was
to make the subject look ridiculous over the last 50 or 60 years
have done a very good job.
I don't know where they're from.
I don't know. I don't know where they're from.
I know they're not, like, from Detroit, you know?
That's as far as I can take it.
So again, when somebody starts saying, well, here's who they are
and here's why they're here,
I was selected to participate
in a special access program within the counterintelligence community.
My supervisor just selected me and said,
you're going to be briefed into a program
and you're going to be responsible for investigating
everything associated with this program.
The first part of the briefing dealt with
the United States Air Force
who were countering unauthorized disclosure of technology to the public
by using the UFO phenomena as a cover.
And then the second part of the briefing
was where we were actually shown
and briefed about
the United States government's
involvement with extraterrestrials
since the late 1940s,
which was obviously the most interesting part of the briefing.
Well, they showed us a lot of things.
They showed us a film, which was late 40s or early 50s film
of a recovery operation, which they talked about
as being in Roswell.
They showed crash debris, they showed extraterrestrial bodies,
and then there was also a briefing showing a live alien
sitting in a room talking to people.
The director of this film talked about the continuation
of a connection between the United States government
and extraterrestrial civilizations.
After viewing this, I was not sure
if it was real,
if they presented it to us for some reason,
maybe some kind of psychological conditioning.
I don't think I initially believed any of it.
But after the film was over with,
an Air Force colonel in uniform
then started talking about the operation, the program,
and how the United States government,
and it was always the United States government,
it wasn't Air Force or Army, it was the United States government,
how they progressed from the early days,
meaning the crash retrieval operations
in the late 40s until now,
which was the late 70s.
And then the more he spoke, the more I realized
that what I saw was real,
that this guy wouldn't be standing here talking to us
with the people in the room
briefing into this high-level program if it was hoax.
A fractured hall of mirrors
with a quicksand floor
that nobody knows exactly what the truths are,
and everybody has found themselves
completely suspicious of the motives
of any human being,
because counterintelligence in England
and the United States and a lot of other countries
have worked overtime to misinform
and to tell the public and the media
there's nothing to the UFO phenomenon.
It's a lie.
I have a question about it,
and my work is to try to shed some light on
what could be so threatening
out of some other intelligence
from some other part of the universe
or it's been here for two billion years
and it's not extraterrestrial,
we're the new ones on the block.
What is it that is considered so threatening
that governments would kill people to keep it silent?
They can't come forth and say,
yeah, okay, we had contact in 1947 and all this is real.
What would that do? That would open up the Pandora's box
because there would be millions and millions and millions
of people asking questions that somebody has to answer.
The easiest thing for the government to do is to say
no comment or not. It didn't happen.
But there are so many people,
so many people within the government
that have come forth with information saying
it did happen, it's real.
And the reason I'm doing it is because
I asked the government a long time ago,
hey, what am I supposed to say? And they're going to say
you stick with the fact that it's not real.
Then I went to them and said, listen,
you're telling everybody that it's not real,
and I know it's real, and you know it's real,
and all these other people know it's real,
so I'm going to tell the public what I know about it.
And the government basically said, do what you've got to do.
Let's take one step at a time.
You're looking at Richard Doty.
You're taking a glimpse into
a whole machine
that now has a life of its own.
Well, I was a young man,
and I had heard about UFOs, but you know,
I didn't believe it was even possible
to have a UFO.
But then I went to an Air Force base,
Air Force base.
They took me aside and said, you know what, guess what?
We have an alien among us.
And I said, you've got to be kidding.
And they said, would we kid anybody?
So I went up to the Air Force base,
went up to the Air Force base,
and now I stand before you
saying that I am a true believer
in UFOs.
UFOs.
Give me a UFO.
UFOs are real
indeed.
That is so dumb.
I didn't even make any sense.
Music