In January of 1996, North American Aerospace Defense Command, NORAD,
warns Brazilian authorities their radar has picked up UFO activity near Virginia, Brazil.
By January 20th, news coverage across the globe explodes with stories of a UFO crash.
Strange creatures are reported by military and civilians in the town of Virginia.
Varginha is a Brazilian city located in the southern region of the state of Minas Jedi.
Varginha is considered the seventh best city in Brazil to live and invest,
and became known internationally in 1996 for the alleged appearance of alien creatures
in the episode that became known as the Varginha incident.
This following story is based on truth and lies.
A strange creature was captured and then taken to another state.
The school principal read the official note, denying the whole story.
We have nothing to hide.
The tendency of the governments is to cover up everything they can't explain to their population.
Can she say what feeling she got from the creature?
The Varginha case is considered the most well-kept secret in the military circles of Brazil.
We're in Sao Paulo, Brazil, about to go and investigate the infamous 1996 Varginha UFO incident.
It's an alleged crash and reported bodies.
So we're going to go see.
Oh, okay.
Oh, yes.
I'm basically trying to figure out what took place in Varginha, Brazil, January 1996.
Many people say there was a UFO crash, debris and bodies recovered.
My objective here in Brazil is to find out, put some clarity on what happened and where this debris ultimately ended up.
They were captured and kept in captivity.
Then they were taken to the hospital here in the city and later they were removed from the city.
So this is the daughter of one of the most famous UFO researchers in all of Brazil.
Yeah.
And he is no longer with us.
Yes.
So she has brought some of his research, illustrations, documentation from the 1996 Varginha UFO incident.
An unidentified flying object, importantly crashes.
And then you have beams associated with the craft alive and walking through the town.
It sounds so spectacular.
It sounds so unbelievable.
It's hard to wrap your mind around it.
And I didn't believe it when I first heard about it.
This is the design.
The girls drew this for her father.
That's her father.
Yeah.
They were in the fireman station.
So this is the fireman.
They believed this fireman was involved in the capture.
And they saw a UFO that looked like it was definitely going to crash.
Liliane and Valkyria, right after they saw the creature.
Yes.
Marco Cherisi.
Yeah.
Who captured the creature with his bare hands.
Yes.
And later died.
This is an original artist's rendition of what the girls saw.
Wow.
Look at that.
Brazil is one of the most amazing locations on earth.
I mean, you've got Ubatuba in the 50s.
Yeah.
You've got Clares, Aparazón Plateau.
You've got 1986 UFOs over Brazil with Sao Paulo.
It was amazing.
I met with a radar operator.
And then you have this crash in 1996 in Varginha.
These are some of the best cases in the world.
1957.
Witnesses observe an object descending at extreme speed from the skies
toward Toninhas Beach.
Before hitting the water, it explodes.
Fragments collected on the beach are sent to a lab to be analyzed.
This headline reads,
Scientific Analysis Confirms Extraterrestrial Magnesium
from the Alleged Ubatuba Flying Saucer.
Photographer Almiro Barraúna and the crew aboard a Brazilian Navy vessel
witness a disc-shaped object maneuvering over the ocean.
He grabs his camera and takes these shots.
She had an immediate third degree contact.
What was the size of the disc that you saw?
It was a huge plate.
A huge plate.
Inside the device, there was another person.
But I don't know if it was a man or a woman.
When the disc came out,
the lights went out.
The lights of the building went out.
The lights of the entire sanatorium went out.
Previously classified Brazilian Air Force documents
contain accounts of several UFOs
witnessed by both civilians and military personnel.
We detected at least nine forms of objects.
Shades.
Ships.
A flying disc.
All reports were sent by the First Command to Brasilia.
Shown here are several unknown craft captured on camera
by the Brazilian Air Force.
Some officers even claimed to see occupants.
1986.
Over São Paulo, six Brazilian fighter jets
chase more than a dozen UFOs.
A plane?
Who are those guys? Three of them?
Are there more of them?
Wow!
Here on Radio 6, there are 150 of them in front of the bank.
One of them is behind us.
This week, high military authorities from Brazil...
The Ministry of the Air Force confirms this encounter
in a press conference.
The UFOs.
Our goal was precisely to approach and identify.
We couldn't even approach, much less identify.
It's a disc.
I couldn't believe it.
When I saw the reaction, I thought,
how could it be?
Then it went down very fast.
It approached.
I don't know what it's thinking.
I got it.
The object gets very close to the houses.
It passes behind a post.
It walks through the bay with irregular movements.
I don't know how to explain what it was like
to do those movements.
She got to meet Carlos de Souza in 1996.
He was the man who saw the UFO crash.
Carlos' dream was something that marked me a lot.
What caught my attention was his gestural communication.
The body speaks.
I'm a psychologist today,
so I have no doubt that he was telling the truth.
Going back to 1996 and seeing the witnesses
and seeing the location of the creatures,
seeing the original illustration,
the rendition of what the creature looked like
from 1996 and holding it in my hands,
it was fascinating.
The photograph of the military man, Marco Cherizzi,
who apparently handled one of the creatures,
it just takes you back in time to 1996.
It was just a really, really fortunate opportunity for us.
I'm thrilled, and I can't wait to get to Virginia,
to be honest with you.
I want to just say hypothetically for a moment,
if it did happen,
how significant of an event would it be?
I bet you that everyone would say
there's nothing more significant in this story
if it was true.
I just ask people to suspend judgment,
listen to the testimony,
and then draw your own conclusions.
Hey, we're just going to drop me off for something,
get some drinks while they go around the block or wait.
Upon arrival in Virginia,
the filmmakers want to hear from locals
regarding the alleged 1996 UFO crash.
A large monument in the shape of a flying saucer
is a clear indication that the town embraces the story.
Armed with handmade signs that read,
If anyone knows what happened in 1996,
please talk to us.
The team takes to the streets.
What does he think about the case?
Does he think it happened or didn't happen?
What are your feelings on Virginia?
The 1996 Virginia UFO incident, what do you think?
It's a very vast universe,
and it's very likely that it did happen.
Things are heating up right now, guys.
We're finding some witnesses.
Both guys are really important here.
Okay, let's bring it.
They see a UFO.
The UFO gets closer to them
to the point where it's at the height of that streetlight.
Okay, so then what happens?
So...
So, a lot of people in this town
have a little piece of the puzzle.
We were only here for an hour and a half,
and I can't believe how many people we got to come forward.
What I love about this case is it's recent enough
where people either heard accounts
or experienced things themselves.
So right now, we are going to meet
with the mayor of Virginia.
So I'm very curious if an elected official
will talk about the details of the case
and whether he believes it really happened.
These sorts of things.
Good morning.
Good morning. Thank you.
Thank you.
Water?
Yes.
Good afternoon, Deborah.
Look at this.
Oh, that's nice.
That's great.
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Verge.
I'm extremely curious.
As an elected official,
the mayor of Virginia,
does he believe that this case happened
as the witnesses are reporting it to have happened?
This is not an obituary, it's a person who died
and who was part of that moment,
who is a police officer.
And the girls I had contact with,
including one of them,
was the girlfriend of a nephew of mine for a long time.
So I have the conviction that it really happened,
in fact.
I didn't witness it, but the reports of the people
make me believe that it really happened.
The witnesses in Virginia, for me,
are some of the most compelling testimony I've ever heard.
So I didn't believe that a UFO crashed in Virginia, Brazil,
when I first came here.
But after 10 years, I've been here...
I wouldn't have imagined getting an interview
with an elected official like the mayor of Virginia.
If you would have told me I'd be doing that 10 years ago,
I wouldn't have believed it.
Not only that, but he was basically saying
that he felt that the Virginia case was true,
that it really happened.
I think we have to remind ourselves
how far we've come in the last decade.
Put me on that farm in January of 1996.
What happened?
It was the size of a micro-bus.
The size of a micro-bus.
And there was no sound.
We kept watching it because it was smoky.
It was covered in smoke, of course.
But I even played with it.
What was that? A submarine?
Because it was working, right?
Then he kept looking at it until it disappeared.
I was standing still, right?
Because I kept listening to the noise,
to make some noise.
In the window of the car, he was looking.
The shape of a...
Like a chariot.
You know what I mean?
Because of the speed it was, it looked like it was in trouble.
I'm very slow.
1996.
Crash witness Carlos de Souza
describes a similar object in this exclusive interview.
I'm here today to tell my story.
January 13, 1996.
Carlos de Souza is traveling from São Paulo to Minas Gerais
early in the morning,
planning to meet with friends to fly ultralight planes.
In this direction,
with this broken part,
he went towards the highway.
I was passing by the highway down there.
He was about...
400, 300 meters, more or less.
And he was losing altitude.
Losing altitude.
He went to the road.
He made a 360-degree turn.
And he kept losing altitude.
He gained altitude again.
And when he got to the place I'm about 100, 150 meters from,
he totally lost his engines
and he went down.
As if he had lost his sustainability.
He totally lost it and fell to the ground.
There must be some people in there
and these people will need help right now.
Now, 26 years later,
the team travels with Carlos de Souza to find the crash site.
Turn around.
Right.
Be careful of the dust.
He's trying to remember.
So where did the trees go?
If they don't... How did you know they were there?
I don't remember. I was 26 years old.
He doesn't...
26 years old.
I remember he has a house on the hill.
Is this looking familiar? There's a house up there.
But if it's close to a house,
then it's got to be further down this way.
Unless the house is gone.
I think the house is gone.
You do?
I'm not sure if it's this way.
Maybe it's up here.
It was like this, up here, you see?
It was something like this.
But there were trees on this side,
there was a bush on the other side, some trees,
and there was a very big path here.
I mean, I could...
Very big.
More or less around here.
Will you take a look over there?
He says he needs to stop.
Yeah, stop.
Yes, please. Let me...
All right, let's go.
Okay.
What does that mean?
Yeah, like, at the grass, it was around here.
Okay.
He wants to go there.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
So it was a white house, and it was a small house.
Yeah, it was a small house, and the grass was burned.
The grass was burned.
Why was the grass burned?
So is the house gone?
It was around here.
So the house is gone.
Yeah.
I mean, it could be here, or it could be there.
We walk over to there, and look.
If it's close to the road,
it only can be in a couple places.
Does he want to walk up closer to...
He said the house was close to where the crash was.
Yeah.
200 meters.
Yeah, it's like...
600 feet.
Well, I say we...
I say we take a closer look.
I mean...
Yeah.
You know?
But it's not...
Yeah, we got to do it, man.
We got to find this spot.
Is there a house down there?
Right down through these trees?
Yeah.
Well, let's get closer to there, then.
Let's drive down the road.
Let's drive down to get closer.
There is a house.
This is a field.
Yes, yes, yes.
Mm.
Aqui, oh.
Aqui.
Aqui, aquí, oh.
Aqui, oh.
Aqui, aqui.
Aqui.
Aqui, oh.
Wow.
Aqui.
Here.
It was here.
This tree was gone.
So you see the house there.
Here.
It came, hit, lifted, spread.
Spread.
Here.
It was here.
The fence of the house was that one.
It was here that it fell.
This is the spot.
The beings died here.
Was this object big enough to have potentially beings inside?
According to Mr. Sosa, this area was covered with debris from the UFO crash.
This is his first time at the crash site since 1996.
I immediately smelled ammonia.
It smelled like rotten eggs.
A very strong smell.
I had to cover my nose with the shirt I was wearing.
To be able to get close to my eyes, I was already dizzy.
The first thing I noticed was that it was something very different
from what I was expecting.
First, the smell.
It didn't make sense, that smell.
I saw a piece of aluminum.
It was a piece of paper that you wrap chicken in to roast.
I grabbed the paper and I grabbed a chair.
It was very light.
A chair.
But when I let go of it, it came back in the same shape.
So he gets out of the car, he sees the piece, right?
He picks the piece up, he folds it.
He said it was really light and it was shaped kind of like this.
Yeah.
And then he picks it up and he folds it in and it opens itself up.
And it was really light.
Yes.
Like aluminum.
At what point did the military come to him right after that happened?
Yes.
The military came from this way and arrived.
Yeah.
Carlos Sosa came from here and the trucks came from that side.
Okay.
Within minutes, trucks from the military base ESA arrive on the scene.
Go, go.
Yeah.
Send him away.
Send him away?
I think some guy...
Go away, go away, go away, go away, push him away.
No, but...
Go away.
Send him away, send him away.
I'm ordering you to go away.
What does bora mean?
Go away, go away, go away.
Go away?
Go away.
And I'm ordering you.
I'm ordering you.
Yeah.
I'm ordering you to go away.
So then he pulled his gun out and said, I'm ordering you to go away.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Here.
Wow.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
After giving this interview shortly after the incident,
Carlos de Sosa vanishes for 26 years.
Can we just walk to exactly where this took place?
Seven days after Sosa witnessed the crash,
Ruber Ladeira leaves this gym
when he and several friends see two military trucks driving into town.
They follow them through the neighborhood
and come upon a military blockade.
One of the people in his group said this is a free country and I'm going through.
It was him.
Oh, it was him?
So he...
So he said, hey, this is a free country, I'll do what I want, and then what happens?
So...
This is the local TV news station that covered the case back in 1996.
He was deeply involved.
He was also good friends with Marco Turizi,
who's the military police officer who allegedly handled the creature and then died.
Thank you.
Yes, of course.
Absolutely.
Describe what happened back in 1996.
It was the first time that a military police officer
Absolutely.
Describe what happened back in 1996, what you witnessed, what you saw.
Well, I know the city.
There was a light.
I said, well, I'm going that way because I'm going down.
But when we got there, there were army trucks.
Oh, no, you can't go through here.
Why can't I go through?
No, it's a national security issue.
Oh, no, but then I'm going down because I'm going...
No, you can't go to a national security issue either.
It didn't make sense to us.
Or rather, it made sense as we were convinced
that there was something going on and a process of covering up.
There's another part, when there were interviews,
when it was Euclides and Calado, the two boys from here,
they went to the Sergeant of the Weapons School of Three Hearts.
Then they came to ask a question.
Then the sergeant went in there, came back.
Then he came back.
No, but you're not going to say anything about the case.
If you ask one more question, you're going to be arrested.
From ESA.
It was Euclides and Calado.
If they were to, like, investigate further,
they probably would have put them in jail.
Okay, I'll quickly mention.
So we have special authorization from the city of Varginha.
And we have a universal key,
which is provided to us by, I think, Katia's husband.
And so we're going to film the use of the special key
to gain access to the exact location
where the encounter occurred back in January of 1996.
Action.
Again.
There we go.
See how easy that was?
I wanted to film here because this is obviously going to invoke
memories of the encounter.
And I think that we're going to get a more dramatic,
more real on-camera testimony from the girls doing it here
as opposed to somewhere else.
Media across Brazil and the world cover the story.
Tell us, walk us through what happened.
What did you see? Where did you see it?
So, passing through here.
I passed by and it caught my attention,
the design of the lock.
And I looked.
I saw the creature.
When Liliane screamed and I looked,
I felt, like, afraid.
So I looked in the eyes
and I saw that he was terrified.
I was terrified. The creature was terrified too.
Because what I saw held me back.
It held me back here in that place.
But I saw that he was afraid of us.
So, it was a exchange of fears,
both him and us.
But the red eyes, the skin and the lily,
you couldn't see it with your mouth open, laughing,
no, happy, no, sad,
and it didn't end.
1996.
Based on the girl's testimony,
artist Betty Rodriguez creates this drawing.
What I find makes their story so credible
is that there were three of them.
I want to hear from Valkyria,
because she was the youngest.
What were her thoughts at the time?
Did you run? Like, put me there.
She was a creature
that was in a corner,
leaning, afraid.
The fear of us,
the same way that we were afraid
of this being that we don't know what it is.
These eyes, compared to my eyes,
how much bigger?
Three times bigger.
I want to walk over by the wall
and I want you to tell me
where exactly the creature was.
The creature there.
Wow!
And we passed by here.
Really close.
Then I screamed,
ran out,
and the two came.
I didn't realize
that's closer than I expected.
It's like eight feet away.
They were eight feet away from this creature,
broad daylight.
It was 3.30 in the afternoon.
This is the exact location
when she made eye contact
with this creature.
Was there a moment of any kind of communication?
Did she feel anything at all?
The heat, the sun, the skin.
OK, so this is Valkyria.
This is Katya.
And this is Liliane.
You see the eyes.
They didn't draw a nose, they didn't draw a mouth.
It was all about the eyes.
I want to understand,
first of all, the moment of contact
with the eyes,
meeting the eyes.
I really want to be there, I want to feel it.
When they locked eyes with this being,
what were they thinking?
They all ran out of here quickly.
So they were scared.
Were they scared because they felt threatened?
Or were they scared because
they just simply didn't know what they were looking at?
I remember when we came down
and we were all scared,
scared, running, then we stopped.
But down there,
the three of us stopped like this.
What happened? What did you see?
So the three of us saw the same thing.
Let's run.
And we ran until we got to my mother's house.
I saw the girls meeting
because mothers
have a feeling.
Then I saw Katya
almost carrying this one
or vice versa,
I don't know.
I saw them very nervous,
walking slowly, one dragging the other.
At the time, we were
always children, we were children of
Catholic people,
who could be demons.
That's why we were afraid
at the time.
And do they
get in the car and drive here?
Do they walk here? How did they get here?
And what did they see when they got here?
Can she draw
the footprint,
the shape of the footprint?
Here.
See, see, see.
Small finger, long finger,
and another finger like this.
It was this
that I saw on the ground.
I couldn't stand the smell
here in my nose
for twenty days.
I don't know where
that smell came from.
I washed my nose with alcohol and water
to get rid of that smell.
That strong smell.
Ammonic.
It's not ammonic.
It's a smell.
No, it's worse than...
I don't know, because for me it was ammonic.
What a strange smell.
Let's go.
Then I took it like this and said, let's go.
That's the exact location
where the girls saw the creature right through that wall
where we filmed already with the girls.
I didn't realize that Marco Ciresi,
the military officer who allegedly
captured the creature with his bare hands,
did it right over here.
Roughly three hours after the girls
witnessed the strange creature,
military police officers
Eric Lopes and Marco Ciresi
drive down this road
on the lookout for something unusual
when suddenly it runs right across their path.
It was captured by Marco Ciresi
with his bare hands
easily and taken to the hospital.
After he captured the creature,
he was smelling
the creature in his body
and in his clothes
because he had this
strange feeling of something greasy,
sticky over his body
that came from the creature.
He developed this
disinfection
that wouldn't go away.
And for two or three weeks
the creature was
getting worse and worse
and worse.
And it looks like that his immunity
system was shut down.
These were the words
used by one of the doctors
who treated him
who said that he never
saw in his whole
medical career
anything like that.
And that infection
killed him.
I had to work
to take care of
Marco Ciresi
who was the soldier
who said he was involved
in the case at the time.
And we
took him to the ICU
and did all the treatments
and he died
from an undetermined cause
an unknown cause
at the time
by us doctors.
All the witnesses
that claim
that Marco Ciresi
handled a creature
a strange creature
it doesn't have to be from another world
it was a strange creature
he gets some unknown infection
you did everything you could to save him
and he died.
Do you believe that there's some credibility
to that story?
It's like a downfall
to try
to help himself
to save his life
because he realized
that he was going
and according to his sister
he was prevented
from reporting this.
Marco Eli Ciresi
of 23 years old
the family only knows
that he participated in a secret operation
do you confirm
that your brother was on duty
on that 20th? I confirm.
My name is Marta, Marta Tavares
your sister from the military
who got involved in the case
of the alien in January 1996.
When her brother falls ill
she asks about his involvement
with the case.
Is it really true?
His answer is
look, this story is going to be a pain in the ass.
On February 10th
Marco Ciresi
is admitted to Regional Hospital.
He went to the CTI
at 7am
he said to me
try to find out what I have
because I want to know what I have
I'm not feeling anything
he went to the CTI
Dr. Luiz Severo
Luiz Alberto Severo
who was the Plantonista of the CTI
asked for the funeral
to be done as soon as possible.
In this test
he says
that he has a presence
of toxic granulations
in 8% neutrophils
where an unidentified substance
was acquired
therefore
he died of a general infection
but without a cause
just.
Roger, what's the main purpose that you go to Virginia
for a nephrological research?
The main purpose for being here
is to look at the
physical evidence
aspect of this case
which is what I specialize in.
It is
June the 7th
2002 and
I'm here in Virginia, Brazil
with the
Chief Investigator
on the Virginia episode
Ubajar Rodriguez.
renowned UFO researcher
Dr. Roger Lear
travels to Virginia
to investigate the case.
He documents
multiple key witnesses on video.
This footage
has never been released.
She is the wife
of a deceased
member of the military
police. I think we should at least
know what her husband's name was.
Does she know if anyone has seen
a medical report?
They took a long time to deliver it
and they asked for money and they
were missing pages.
She searched
for explanation but nobody would give any.
Was Marco Alicciresi the only person
infected
who died? We don't know.
Were
these two creatures the only
ones that remained alive after
the crash? We don't know.
We only have
very detailed
information about
the existence and the capture
of these two. One captured in
the morning and one at evening
of the same day
January 20, 1996.
According to credible reports
there were two captures on January
20th.
Hours before the girls' encounter
the fire brigade captured
a being.
This capture was thoroughly investigated
by leading Brazilian researcher
and lawyer,
Ubirajara Rodriguez.
The lawyer and professor
Ubirajara Rodriguez, who is also
an ufologist, said on TV
that he found evidence that the story
is authentic.
We are not going to abandon the case.
Obviously not. All the information will be
welcome.
This is the fire department that
responded. Dr. Lear teamed up
with Ubirajara. They questioned
the fire battalion allegedly involved
in the capture of the first creature.
This is the creature.
This is the kind of equipment
that is used to catch it.
The fire department
was dispatched to this location
after receiving several calls
from concerned residents who
reported seeing something strange
in the area.
You have problems like
a marimbu box, a pet, a dog...
The fire brigade.
The fire brigade was assigned.
They themselves didn't know what they would do
when they arrived here.
We went looking for other witnesses
and found content.
We were up there, we went down
to the fire brigade and immediately saw
people saying that the fire brigade caught
an animal right here.
Was it strange? Was it an animal?
What kind of comments did they make?
I cried a lot. I cried like a child.
And because two arrests have occurred
on the part of the bomber's body in the morning
and on the part of the military police in the afternoon.
The army truck entered by this gate here,
got in over here.
Did it catch the creature?
It took the dead creature from inside.
Got the creature already dead from inside.
In the presence of several elements of the military police of the ICERC
and the presence of several elements from the military police,
from the army, several doctors, nurses.
And this convoy left the place.
Both creatures left at the same time.
And the creature that was alive got to Campinas alive.
The team drives to meet with a family who saw a UFO
hovering over the area of the encounter and capture.
Okay, let me ask.
How about we film the back of their heads talking to me?
No, I don't want to.
No, you're not going to show the sir.
Hey, I'm just going to tell you the story.
Hey, Fernanda, we have two options, okay?
One, we blur his faces, no problem, and we will do that.
Two, we film from the backside,
and their faces aren't seen ever.
Like doctors, and they all saw the UFO right over this area.
It looked like they were looking for something,
like it was doing a grid search.
And this is a very respectable family.
They don't want their faces on camera.
They want to talk and tell what they saw,
but they don't want their faces revealed on camera,
which happens.
Okay, so we're standing in very near the area
where the girl saw the creature.
It was 1996, January.
This entire family saw something they want to share with us,
but they don't want to have their faces revealed.
So what did they see?
It was all...
Like you can see on this wall,
there was nothing abnormal.
It was something like...
I don't know if it's from another planet,
I don't know what it is.
It was an album, I was going to sleep.
There was no way, I don't know.
And I was still...
Now I can tell you how many minutes
they were with me on the star.
Every 15 minutes.
And I was looking at each other.
Stopped.
Stopped and doing this.
And I was looking for something around here.
It was very red.
But it was red, red, and very patched up.
And I was looking.
I was crazy about something.
And we kept looking.
What I'm seeing here today,
I'll never see again in my life.
I don't know why God gave me this opportunity to see.
Is it real?
Did this happen?
There's no way, I don't know.
This case of Virginia was real.
I think it was a week or so.
It was.
Then people came.
They turned around.
Yeah, yeah.
The phologus came.
The people from NASA came.
From NASA?
I don't know.
They were Americans too.
They came here.
They stayed for a long time talking to us at night.
And one of them called me and said,
this conversation didn't take place.
They left.
Did I hear...
I heard Americana.
You say the American.
Yes.
What was that about?
Some American officials came here to talk about what they saw.
Americans.
Were they military?
Were they police?
Who were they?
Is there any way that there is a conventional explanation to what they saw?
I just want to go over that interview and what I find.
First of all, they hesitated on whether or not they even wanted to go on camera.
They cancelled yesterday.
Today they were like, we don't want...
Sorry, bus coming.
We don't want our faces on camera.
It was like an entire family and they all saw this object and it was really big,
shaped like a disc.
Zero noise.
You have witnesses like that.
They're friends of the doctor, the guy that we rent the house from,
that you could just tell they've been sitting on that story for 26 years,
how excited he was to finally share it.
GUNSHOTS
It was a normal day when suddenly, on the school's pole field,
this marine helicopter came down to me.
And then there was a big movement of cars from the Navy entering the barracks.
I was in the line at the bank, normal to receive, when I saw a Navy truck standing on the side of the infirmary,
and they put a metal box in a hurry.
There was unusual activity at the base.
There were helicopters from the Navy, which in itself was unusual.
He sees a box. Was the box unusual?
The Navy guys wanted to hurry. With that line at the bank, the guys left.
The school commander explained that he was having some rumors that they were in Varginha to get a creature.
That this creature was there, that the whole press was wanting to get in from the barracks.
It was very strange. Very strange.
In my company, because it was the company that was most directly involved in this matter,
because it was the case that transported,
so within my company I avoided talking.
Then these drivers who were going to Varginha were called up there,
at the command of the battalion in the pavilion, and we never saw them again.
So to this day, has he spoken to any of them that went to Varginha?
No. No.
Nothing?
Yes.
According to the witness, it wasn't only the drivers who were never seen again.
Their captain, Edson Ramirez, also left without a word.
He went to Brasília.
He was a person who was very friendly to everyone, he talked to everyone, he could help everyone.
He was not a person who would simply say, tomorrow I'm going away, I'm not going to ask anyone.
January 1996.
A radiologist has an unexpected visit by the military while on duty at Regional Hospital.
He agrees to share his story, provided his identity remains concealed.
There was an unexpected visit by the military while on duty at Regional Hospital.
Inside the ward, with the door closed, there was a military ESA truck.
Inside the ward, there was another military jeep, and I think there were about 8 to 10 police vehicles.
No one entered and no one left.
So we have a big military presence on the outside of the hospital.
We got two army and two police on the inside of the hospital with a box and something inside of a black zipped body bag.
They asked me to do the radiography of the parts that were requested.
Cranial, cervical spine, thorax, abdomen, pelvis, legs and arms.
Their gaze was fixed.
I was observing myself all the time I was doing it, but they didn't say anything.
They didn't even communicate with each other.
The revelations were made and at that moment I didn't even see any danger.
I didn't see anything.
It was all collected by the military on the day.
Normally I check the images to see if they are within the standard.
But that day was not checked by me.
Do you understand?
One of the people inside, you did your job, thank you very much.
End here, don't say anything about what you saw, what you did.
What did it smell like?
It smelled strong, mixed with a kind of sulfur or ammonia.
When they took whatever it was in that black bag and they left the hospital,
the military and the police, with that bag and that thing, did the smell leave?
The smell still remained the next day.
The people were complaining.
They were impregnating me with my breathing.
It felt like I was breathing.
I felt it for three or four days.
Three of the most strange, bizarre points of this encounter.
The first thing I found strange was that they had selected me to do this type of procedure.
That could have been done by any professional at the time.
Another thing is to get there and ask for a seal.
A seal on everything that was done in that room.
And another thing is not to let me have access to the images I made.
And then thank me and ask me not to say anything else.
Stay quiet.
Probably about ten months ago, Marco managed to reach a vetted, legitimate witness
who was involved in the transportation of the, they call them ET, or the Bean.
This guy was so scared.
Marco spent, I think, eight to ten months slowly developing a relationship with this guy.
And about four days ago, he agreed to meet with me and Marco, just the two of us.
So we drove late into the night.
We met him at a bar when we arrived.
He was with another guy.
He took us to a different location.
We sat outside and we talked for a couple of hours.
About coming forward, appearing in the documentary.
I've never, ever had the opportunity to interview a witness that potentially handles an extraterrestrial being.
I worry about the military getting wind of what's going on because they're clearly paying attention to this witness.
I'm worried about him getting a phone call, reminding him of his oath to secrecy.
I don't want to put someone else's family in harm's way.
So you're always in the back of your mind in a situation like this.
You know that at any moment, the carpet can get pulled out from under you and it's not a done deal until it's a done deal.
Listen, I wonder if we should rent a hotel room and then have him come to us.
Because then we can get all the gear inside the hotel room and then he can just show up and walk in.
Marco coordinates with the witness Military X to secure a safe meeting location.
Yes, I made appointment with him in some hotel right here, close to here.
And then so I think we have to go to the hotel first.
Yeah, we go check in and then he just walks in.
Yeah, exactly.
That's yeah, that's good.
Feel that, that anxiety.
I feel that that anxiety in my stomach.
You know, it's just like pull this off and it's just like first time.
It'll be the most compelling testimony ever revealed on the history of this case.
No question.
Oh my fucking God, I feel so steep.
I know.
Entrada.
This is the hotel.
I would get a quick shot of it and I'd shut these cameras off right now.
Can you guys do that?
Shut everything off.
Guys.
Yeah.
Right.
Right here.
Where?
Here.
Fuck this room is small.
This is where you can use these cameras in here.
Oh my God.
Okay.
He's trying to find a room with two beds.
You better.
Okay.
Yeah.
Mark it.
Okay.
Okay, anytime.
Okay, so we are sitting here with Military X who clearly doesn't want his identity revealed,
which we're not going to do.
And he's going to provide enough detail, not too much, but enough detail on operations that
he was involved with with the Virginia case.
Okay.
When he was in humanic dust, this is where he saw part of the creature.
Yes.
What was the atmosphere like?
What were the looks on the faces of the other people in the room?
Yeah.
What was it like?
Can he put me in that room?
When he looked and he saw the leg or part of the leg and the foot with the V, what did
you think?
Okay.
Is a military base is roughly 20 miles southeast of Virginia.
According to witnesses, the army operations originated from here.
Is there filmed footage, video footage of the creature that he knows about?
He says that on January 22nd, 1996, he drove the creature from Humanitas Hospital in Virginia
to ESA Army Base, where it would remain overnight.
Okay.
Does he have any idea where the creature went?
Because it went to Reginas, then Humanitas, then ESA, then Campinas.
And then what happened?
According to Military X, he transported a creature from Humanitas Hospital in Virginia
to ESA Military Base in Tres Corazones, where it stayed for the night.
Early the following morning, the convoy continued their mission, heading south on Formal Dias
Freeway, then west on Dom Pedro to SBX Army Base in the city of Campinas.
And now, things that I don't know, I can't prove, but comments from the time that would
have gone to the United States, that we wouldn't be able to really keep the creature here.
The team meets with Brazilian Air Force traffic control officer José Manuel Fernandes.
His unit was responsible for monitoring specific airspace over the state of São Paulo.
Do you know anything about this case?
What I know is that Yusaf lands in Campinas, Yusaf's plane landed in Campinas and two helicopters
took off from Campinas Airport to the unknown place, which we later found out was the city
of Varginha.
Was it Americans involved or was it just the Brazilians involved?
Only Americans, only.
And how does he know that the Americans were involved?
Because they landed without the authorization of the Brazilian government, it was a secret mission.
It was a plane from Yusaf.
I know it was nine o'clock at night, the boys were already sleeping and knocked on the door.
I then opened the door innocently thinking it was the other guys who had come here,
the Birajara or the Pacatini, for example.
At first, there were four men that I had never seen in my life, all dressed in black.
One brought a suitcase in his hand and the other one with a bag and said,
close the door, close the door.
And I was afraid of that.
And then they said to me, Mrs. Luisa, we are here.
Only one spoke, the rest, one signed and the other was quiet, listening only.
We came here to make a big proposal to you, because you can get rich now if you want.
And I didn't understand that very well, because I was even preparing to go to bed too.
And then I said, but about what?
That you tell the girls that they didn't see anything.
The money that's in this suitcase that we're going to give you can only come out of Brazil.
Then I said, young man, I can't do that, because something my daughter saw,
I can't treat them like liars and be a liar too.
So I can't do that.
If you'll excuse me, if you leave my house, I'm going to call the police.
They insisted a lot, insisted a lot.
Soon they left.
And I ran to the gate to see what car it was.
And left on a farm.
But it wasn't from Brazil.
It was people from abroad.
It was from Brazil.
At that moment I touched a gas station to have a coffee.
To relax a little.
And then two people came to my side.
They were black, very tall people.
They touched my side and spoke to me.
Mr. Carlos de Souza, married to someone like that, his daughter is like that.
They described my whole life there.
I said, who are you? Who do you want to know?
How do you know that?
It was clear to me.
Look, you didn't see anything. You shut up.
Go away.
If someone asks you something, you didn't see anything.
You don't know anything.
Otherwise things will get weird for you.
So go away from here.
I was scared at the time.
It was a black Opala.
Or a very dark blue, almost black.
And without a plate.
They put it together and went away.
That's it.
The commander of the car was Cabo Lopes.
Because he is the living proof of what happened.
He participated in the capture.
My brother was subordinate to him.
Has anybody seen Eric Lopes? Has anyone ever tried to talk to him?
People have tried. And nada.
With the help of Virginia Mayor Vergi,
the team connects with Mr. DeCosta,
a military police corporal in 1996.
His son, Romulo Ribeiro, agrees to escort them to the home of Eric Lopes.
To get there and you can talk to him.
I'll give you a present and pass it to you, who are the professionals.
Thank you.
All right.
Oh my God, are you kidding me?
Let me go up carefully.
Eric Lopes is the military police officer from P2,
who reportedly drove the car during the second capture with Marco Ceresi.
Not even the family of the deceased officer,
has been able to get a statement from Lopes.
Look at this.
Hiding.
Hiding, huh?
If the reports are true,
he is the only living witness of the second capture.
Officer Lopes has been unreachable for 26 years.
We waited.
He talks first.
Oh my God.
I'll go with him. I'm going with him.
Tell him that the mayor has blessed us.
Tell him the mayor said...
This is Eric Lopes?
Let me just, hold on, please, let me ask you a question.
Please.
Uh-huh.
His friend loves his friends.
Okay.
Hold on, hold on.
Just ask him one question for me.
Will he ever come forward and make a statement?
What's happening?
This is the house of Eric Lopes.
Yeah.
But he doesn't like to talk.
And the threat is that they might shoot us
because we're on the property trespassing.
They're currently talking right now.
Okay.
So Eric won't talk.
What just happened? What happened?
Is that Eric Lopes?
Who is that?
That's Eric Lopes.
He doesn't want to talk at all.
Turn me down, turn me down.
Okay, okay.
Oh my God, that was Eric Lopes.
Just saw him.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Okay, okay.
We'll go talk.
Did you get him? Dave, did you get him?
Please tell me you got him.
That was Eric Lopes.
You got him in the window?
Yeah.
Oh my God, you got him.
He's here. Confirm.
I'm Eric Lopes.
And if you say,
we shot if you don't leave here.
He will shoot you? Yeah.
Fuck.
If that guy had nothing to hide,
he would have just said so.
That guy was driving the car
that Marco Treese was in.
Right, what we just did.
The interview yesterday was pretty good.
For what?
No, right now it was pretty gnarly.
The area.
Ask him if we can talk about what we just did.
Okay, okay.
Which way did he go?
To the left.
Are we stopping here?
Okay.
Oh, my God.
What exactly did he say?
Okay.
And he believed that Eric Lopes was serious?
Yes, he was.
Thank you.
This photo, in this report,
was the first time
that my mother participated.
The first and only time.
I'm indignant
because of the attitude
that the police have,
where 25 years ago
they would tell my mother
that there really was a creature,
there really was,
but that they couldn't admit
the truth to the society
because the population
would collapse.
If his story is true, he is walking around with a level of confirmation that only a handful
of people on this planet have.
What does that feel like?
I remember the words of Mark when I met him.
One of the first things he said to me was,
Wow, I wanted to be in your place.
I wanted to be in your place.
Because you lived something that I dream of living.
And I'm honest, for me it's different, because it's not something that attracts me.
It's a story, it's something that I lived, that marks for a lot of people,
it marks for the world, it marks for the human being.
But you guys are looking for that.
I didn't want to live that.
I'm honest.
I didn't want to live that, because that brought me a lot of trouble, a lot of trouble.
I went through all my private situations after that with Mark,
I had a lot of trouble.
I wish it hadn't been us, because we went through a lot together,
and a lot of trouble, until today.
But today we can see with different eyes.
May 8th, 1996.
With mounting pressure from media and witnesses,
the military base ESA holds a press conference.
General Lima addresses the crowd.
What for?
For the press conference.
Why?
Because you don't want to prove the facts?
The facts?
I don't have to.
I just wanted to tell you.
They made us shut up about this story.
That it wasn't ET, that it was crazy, that it was bullshit, that there was nothing about it.
So it's where we don't even like to talk about cops, about ESA, about anything like that.
It's the same thing.
Do you think I would go through the same thing I did for 26 years?
People, family, really, playing, enjoying myself?
Never would I do that.
What did I gain from that?
Nothing.
I never get a real with that.
There's no interest for me to win.
If I say I got a coin, I'm lying.
that I was going to give my last testimony.
And I have to thank you too for giving me this opportunity to speak.
But I want you to keep looking,
always and always, for you to never let go.
Never let go of that.
For more information, visit www.mooji.org
It all happened to me because it happened at the Maiolini farm.
That's where this whole story began.
That's where it all began.
It was at the Maiolini farm.
For more information, visit www.mooji.org
The accumulation of aspects, the girls who saw something,
the other people in the town who saw something,
this wasn't an isolated event where you got one witness saying,
oh, I saw something extraordinary.
Not at all.
These seemed to be relatively naive young girls.
And there were fire department people involved,
who saw the beings too.
And one nice thing about it is it takes the onus away from saying,
things only happen in the United States.
Well, there was United States involvement,
and it wouldn't surprise me if they paid to pick up the wreckage
and all the rest of the stuff.
Why not?
Makes sense. Cheap way to get information.
Let the other guy do the work.
The
fire department
As I'm the second lieutenant of the reserve of the Brazilian Army,
and through my contacts, a sergeant who worked with me at the time
told me that the boxes where the entities were
were taken to the preparatory school of Campinas,
the preparatory school of Cadetes,
and from there it was to Unicamp, to the hospital of the clinics,
where after a security perimeter was made,
they were examined by the team there,
then the Americans came and took these entities
that were in boxes to the United States.
Why Varginha wasn't treated like the other cases?
Many people ask, but why Varginha wasn't treated like the other cases?
Probably because it's the most important case
in which there was cooperation between Brazil and the United States.
It will always be our word against everyone.
But there is still something to be raised.
It's a mystery that remains.
I believe that the Varginha case is much more important today
because it is more recent and some of the events have not unfolded yet.
Do you have any connection with the eyes?
Did she make any, like, feel that she saw eye to eye with the bee?
Mm-hmm.
Ah, she took it out of here.
I'm suffering.
I thought she would, but she didn't let me.
This won't ever be the end.
This is the end.
Mm-hmm.
Were there live aliens seen walking around this town?
I have deal with this case in 1996
because I have some friends from there.
He told that, oh, you don't know what is true,
but I know what I saw.
Oh, damn.
Oh, yeah.
Really?
Weight off his shoulders.
Yeah.
God, I just wonder, like, what they said to these witnesses
that 25 years later they still don't want to talk about it on camera at all.
It's, like, unbelievable.
It's like you offer them even compensation that it still won't do it.
I know. It's like money doesn't hold and won't do it.
It's weird.
The reason why they haven't made overt contact
is because we're so aggressive.
Come on.
Would that smell make a good perfume?
I don't know.
It smells like sweet.