It's no laughing matter the way I feel this morning I shouldn't be laughing at anything
now look Hank one's fun but there's a limit you call me up in the middle of night you
tell me to grab a plane to Washington and now all this malarkey about flying saucers
of course most of these reports are obvious nonsense brother you said it a lot of highly
imaginative people some neurotic I'm just playing liars all swore they saw the flying
saucer we tracked down every report across examined every witness and found out it was
all about not all of it like some experts commercial and Air Force pilots also claim to
have seen it you're not trying to tell me you really believe there's a flying saucer I'm not sure
there must be a spark of fire somewhere under all that smoke well even if there is one hang
what good is it well if it's true what the expert witnesses say it'll outfly anything we can put in
the air they works on a revolutionary principle that we can't even guess at yes Mike it appears
it was designed for one purpose to carry the atomic bomb now the first country that learns
the secret of the flying saucer will control the skies of the world I don't want that country to
be Russia if there is such a gadget how do you know the Russians aren't the ones who already
plan because we have reason to believe they're looking for it too one of our undercover agents
has been working inside a communist group that's been operating around this district you know
huh used to be quite a town there still is a last report from our man said that some Russian Air
Force officers had slipped into the territory from Siberia he heard that they were trying to
locate the flying saucer somewhere near the Taku Glacier Russia apparently knows something
that we don't it certainly is a tip worth investigating don't you agree oh sure all
party a job I suppose but what's this all got to do with me because you're going to do the
investigating for us are you nuts or something if the whole intelligence service in the Air Force
can't find it just how do I figure because you were born and brought up in Alaska because my
old friend your father still owns most of the timber and the gold mines and the fisheries and
the part of the country we're interested in so that qualifies me as a bloodhound huh it qualifies
you as a native any of our men would be immediately suspected because they're strangers oh what about
that guy you already got planted up there well it's just possible that something may have happened to
him since we got his last report now when you get to Alaska I'm not going to Alaska I'm having too
much fun in New York besides my polo team starts practice tomorrow at Meadowbrook man of distinction
a good picture of your Mike very natural you're known all over as a sportsman the playboy and
a good two-fisted drinker so we'll plant it in the Alaska papers that you're coming home to
recuperate from a nervous breakdown a nervous breakdown I feel fine you'll feel even better if
you take this job Oh look Hank it just won't work so why don't you get yourself another boy Mike I'm
not asking you to do this for me I'm asking you to do it for the country I gave my country five years
of my life that's enough how would you feel if tomorrow a flying saucer would drop an atomic bomb
on every key city in the United States would you feel you've done enough all right all right
stop waving the flag I'll go but I won't like it by the way I was talking to your father an hour
ago the phone he told me to tell you that his job will be waiting for you to Seattle that the
caretaker be instructed to get the taco hunting lodge ready for you so you had it all planned
it's cutting a few corners to save time well at least you can do ain't over me a drink what do I
leave afternoon playing for Seattle your tickets you and your nurse my nurse look our story is
that you're suffering from a nervous breakdown now for appearances sake you've got to travel
with the nurse look Hank I can tell you right now I'm not gonna have any nurse send me slangly
and please want to meet Mr. Thorne I'm in the my nurse very good idea Hank I really ought to
have a nurse I thought you'd agree the this is Mr. Trent Mike miss Langley how do you do
mr. Trent miss Langley is one of our best operatives fact she's also a trained nurse
he's quite incidental oh sure sure that's great I think I'd better take charge of the tickets mr.
Thorne well how do you like that
we reached Seattle I managed to slip my mornings for about an hour
then they got me in tow Shanghai had me aboard dad's yacht and we were off to Alaska
like the man said water water everywhere and not a drop to drink three days out I was getting
fed up with the whole business flying saucers so much bunk
I was beginning to feel a little better when we were cruising up the inland passage I
almost forgotten there was such a thing as beautiful scenery outside of a nightclub
hey V a whale
watch him always gone do you think he'll come back if I was him I wouldn't
want before we reached you know quite a town as towns going Alaska none of the
store club gang ever got up there for I used to have a lot of pals there should look them up for old
times sake a skipper pull in here Juno no captain either we'll go directly to the lodge
open up come on open up
skipper wouldn't drop anchor my keeper put him up to that the fact that I let myself in with
this little caper didn't help my disposition and the taco glacier in the end of our journey
the hunting lodge was just across the river
so long skipper
mr. Brent that's right well old Pierre far away I'm Hans the new caretaker
oh this is beautiful mr. Trent yeah just like San Quentin come on warden
what happened over here I do not know sir I understand he just disappeared I'm sorry
to hear that my father hired you huh that is so mr. Trent oh this miss Langley the
doctors thought I need the nurse oh what a beautiful view did you ever see the Empire
State building in the moonlight time for you to rest now mr. Trent rest what I got
a rest from a house senior Russian spies on their lately spies I don't understand spies
you know Russian spies there's some Russian fishermen down the taco village that I know
the spies that I know nothing about sir any flying saucers would you please show me to
my room take miss Langley sings upstairs on I'll take the room down here hey you afraid
to leave me down here myself you know I might get in the mischief you already have
we knew all the answers we wouldn't have to be here why did you come down tell me about
the Glacier all right there it is 18 billion tons of ice the great tackle
glacier built by Mother Nature a hundred thousand years ago how am I doing
what do you suppose those men are probably salmon fishing this place is driving me nuts
it's a funny thing when I was a kid I used to think was wonderful up here in the wild
too bad you had to grow up it's still wonderful you can have it be let's take the skip and go to
Juneau no mr. Trent okay I'll go alone no mr. Trent no mr. Trent no mr. Trent only just once
you'd say yes Mike yes Mike why don't you just relax and enjoy it we mustn't forget what we're
here for somebody had a brainstorm that saucer isn't real it is really strictly for laughs
hey quite a nice know we got here we're all ready to stand a siege to pick yourself
a gun while there's still time I have an automatic upstairs in my suitcase but
let me have it you might hurt yourself I assure you I know how to use it keep that in mind
oh I'm sorry Hans I didn't know you were out there would you or the lady like some more
coffee perhaps sir no thanks excuse me I think I'll go to bed you sure you can find your way
upstairs over yourself I think I can manage what about me you what do you mean well I'll
be down here all alone with my pulse and temperature I might ever relapse during the
night oh I think you'll live call this living good night pleasant dreams I doubt it very much
good morning miss it's straight up yet no not yet he's supposed to rest shouldn't he nurse yes
of course who all this wonderful fresh air and sunshine I never knew it could be so warm in
Alaska in summer yes sometimes it's as warm as today but the big ice that never melts well you
mean the glaciers I love them you think I'll freeze to death if I take a swim before you're
not pleased to death no but she will maybe yes morning babe oh good morning Mr. Trent she
ain't flying sausage yeah look mr. Trev we've got to be very careful what we do and say from
now on oh sure there's a Russian spy behind every rock and bush you may think it's a very funny
but we're here on a serious mission so you're going swimming who we're supposed to behave
naturally well I'm all for that hey hearts what's your breakfast I'm starving
during the next few days the Langley and I followed Hank Thorne's orders at least she
followed them and I followed her many Russian spies were watching us which I doubted very much
they saw only a patient and his nurse supposed to be enjoying the fresh air the sunshine and
the scenery it wasn't hard for me to take when he was a part of the same
if Thorn's agent was still around he never showed himself to us while we were waiting
for him to appear well we weren't exactly standing still
hey gidget
Oh, did I make a face down?
Baby, you scored.
You forgot your thermos, Mr. Prent.
Red six on a black seven.
I saw it.
Please, Mike, not now.
Oh, why not?
Oh, I get it.
We're not human beings anymore.
We're still Hank Thorne's stooges.
For Pete's sake, V, how long does this go on?
I don't know.
I suppose until we finish our job.
What a job.
You still don't believe the flying saucer
really exists, do you?
Oh, sure, like spots in front of my eyes.
It's a man.
Hear something?
Yes, don't you?
Jet plane, maybe.
Or probably a meteor.
Traveling in circles?
We certainly don't think it was...
Of course.
Oh, Hans.
Say, did you see anything falling in the sky just now?
Only the Aurora Borealis.
The Northern Lights, sir.
With sound effects.
Listen, there was something up there in the sky
and it wasn't Northern Lights or any kind of airplane
I've ever heard.
It was a flying saucer.
Yes, I guess perhaps it really was.
V, I'm going to Juneau.
Oh no, Mike, you mustn't.
But honey, it's the only thing to do.
I'll look up some of my old buddies and find out all the dope.
There must be somebody in Juneau who knows something about these saucers.
Mr. Thorne told us to stay here.
But we're wasting time.
Mike, we've got to stay here until orders are changed.
You're prettier than my old top sergeant,
but baby, you talk just like him.
Good morning, Hans. Is breakfast ready yet?
No, miss, but soon.
I think I'll take a little walk first.
Oh, Hans.
Never mind, I found it.
Good morning, Hans.
Miss Langley up here?
Yes, sir.
I believe she went for a walk in the woods.
Fine, I think I'll take a little exercise myself.
Thanks.
Oh, Hans, I just saw a bear.
They're dangerous, aren't they?
A man was killed by one near here not long ago.
Phew.
After this, I'd better stay out of the forest
when I'm alone.
Where's Mr. Trent?
He's gone.
Gone?
What do you mean?
He's gone.
Gone?
What do you mean?
In a skiff to Juneau, I think.
Isn't there another boat here?
No.
I must get to Juneau at once.
There's no way.
Oh, yes, there is.
There's the barge from the Goldman.
It always stops here.
I better get dressed.
What'll it be?
Scotch.
Look, Mac, we recommend the ride.
See?
Sure.
I'll play it safe.
OK.
It's a long time since I've been to Juneau.
Looking up some old friends.
You don't say?
Chuck Thorpe used to come in here a lot.
You know him, don't you?
No.
Spike Ainsley?
Well, you must know old Matt Mitchell.
He's quite a character.
Never heard of him.
Say, uh, what's his name?
Mike.
Say, uh, did you notice anything funny around here last night?
You see a lot of funny things in a joint like this?
No, no, are you?
I mean, up in the sky.
Oh, sure.
Angels.
They fly over Juneau every night.
In flocks.
So long, joker.
Anybody here seen Matt Mitchell?
No.
You seen old Matt Mitchell?
Not tonight.
Oh, sure.
There was a guy like that in here a little while ago.
Regular screwball, you know what I mean?
Kept talking about angels flying around at night.
Thank you.
Anybody here know Matt Mitchell?
No.
Give me a ride.
Hey, honey, I'm looking for old Matt Mitchell.
You seen him?
He just left.
Double ride.
Where's old Matt Mitchell?
How should I know?
Old Matt Mitchell around here.
Right.
Leave the bottle.
Saves time.
You're a busy guy.
I can see that.
You still have a lot of friends in Juneau.
I've been looking all over for them.
And they're gone.
They're all gone.
Is that a fact?
No.
It's a sad thing to lose all your friends.
A very, very sad thing.
Sure tough.
How'd you like to make a new friend?
Who are you?
Just a friendly sort of girl.
You can call me Nanette.
Right, Nanette.
Maybe you know some of my old pals.
Oh, sure I do.
I know everybody in Juneau.
And everybody knows me.
Let's go sit down while we can talk.
That's a good idea.
Not now.
I just caught me a big fish.
Mike Trent.
Millionaire Playboy?
That's the guy.
I spot him from his picture in the papers.
Champagne, the best.
Of course I know old Matt Mitchell.
He always drops in around this time.
You just stay here with me.
We'll wait for good old Matt together.
Good old Matt, you said it.
You tell me the truth.
Everybody else lies, but good old Matt won't lie.
And tell me what goes.
What goes where?
Up there.
Way up there in the sky.
Hi, V. What are you doing here?
Looking for you.
Well, that's fine.
That's fine.
I want you to meet an old friend of mine.
What's your name, honey?
Honey, this is V.
Well, sit down, V. Have a little drink.
You've had enough.
Mike, why don't you do it?
Oh, you think I can't do it?
I can't do it.
Mike, why don't you do it?
Oh, you think I can't sit down for things, don't you?
And that's where you're going.
I'm here to find out things.
Very important things.
Mike, we're going back to the lodge right now.
No, no.
I've got to wait for a friend.
Old Matt, he'll know all the answers.
Where?
Near the bottle of wine.
You're not well, Mike.
So you need a nurse, do you, Mike?
Who said I need a nurse?
I do as I please, eh?
That a boy.
Better come along with us, Mr. Trent.
Won't take you long to find a boyfriend, did it?
Oh, Mike, don't be that way.
I'll be anywhere I want to be, see?
Listen.
I don't want this job in the first place.
And furthermore, let me tell you that I...
And furthermore...
Well, I'll be right here if you need me.
I won't be needing you anymore.
Goodbye.
Hey, V.
Hey, V, wait.
Hey, Mike.
Let's have some laughs together.
I better go pretty up.
No cigarette.
Mike!
Hey!
Mike, well, hey, my old friend.
Matt Mitchell, you old walrus, you, how are you?
Fine.
See, I heard about you.
You were up at your papi's lodge.
You know, I was going to look you up.
But you know, I've been so busy entertaining and...
Celebrate.
Yeah, that's it.
Why do you got to celebrate, you old walrus, you?
Oh, I'm getting rich, Mike.
I got to learn how to spend money.
You sure look like you're in the chips, all right.
Ah, plenty more where this comes from.
You got yourself a gold mine or something?
I'm better than that.
See, do you remember that old broken down trowel mine?
Sure, you taught me how to navigate when I was a kid.
Yeah, that's right.
Well, you know, the other day I was ready to junker.
And a couple of the foreigners come in and they write her.
And they're paying me $100 every day.
What are they using her for, Matt?
I don't know.
They ain't using her for fishing.
Well, at least not fishing her for fish.
Matt.
Yeah.
I got to go back to the lodge and find V.
Go on.
You still having that old fishing check up the river?
Yeah.
All right, I'll be up there first thing in the morning.
There's a lot of questions I got to ask you.
Very important questions, Matt.
So long, Matt.
So long, Mike.
Hello, Mitchell.
Let you and I have a little chat.
Sure, Mr.
I'd say I'd have a little drink.
Come on.
Perhaps we'll have better luck tomorrow.
We'll cover this area along the edge of the Taku glacier.
That's Alex.
Open the door.
Why have you brought him in here?
I had to, Colonel.
He was shooting off his mouth in the bar.
Don't push me.
I don't like to be pushed.
That drunken old fool is harmless.
He knows nothing of our plans.
Excuse me, Colonel, but he knows too much for our own good.
How can he have learned anything?
We hire as both, that is all.
If we let him keep on talking, even to a drunken playboy like Mike Trent,
someone may start guessing.
He will not talk anymore.
It's all right, Colonel.
He'll stay quiet for a while.
But he's got the thickest skull I ever cracked.
As long as you didn't overdo it.
He must be able to walk when we want him.
He can stay out under his own.
See that there are witnesses when he does.
We can dispose of him later from the trawler.
Why, please, won't you.
Your boyfriend took it on the lam.
He's gone.
on the land good riddance if you ask me. Turner Dr Lotton's mechanic at last he's
come to us bring him in. Mr Turner I've been expecting you for some time you've
been away I presume flying around here and there very exhilarating air travel it
ought to be two thousand miles an hour as much as that.
Sit down. So at last you've come to talk business with me.
Depends on how much you're willing to pay. Depends on how much you're prepared to deliver.
It works. Flying disc itself. Money's right.
I understood you were a believer in our cause.
So I wanted to give you a chance to bid on it before I took it to some other party.
You're a shrewd businessman. Are you dealing in Dr. Lotton's name Mr. Turner?
Dealing for myself. But the goods are in my hands. Dr. Lotton's gone to Seattle to make a deal with the Americans.
How fortunate. Then his experiments are finished?
Everything's perfect or he wouldn't be trying to sell it to the U.S.
And just where do you keep the flying ship Mr. Turner?
Let's talk money first.
Oh let us not quarrel over money. We will pay what is just and reasonable.
A million dollars cash? Agreed.
And now perhaps Mr. Turner you will tell us where Dr. Lotton has hidden his famous flying saucer.
Twin lakes. The other side of the ice cap.
Are you prepared to fly it to Russia?
He's gone out the window. Wait Alex.
We'll take care of him tomorrow.
Alex, we'll take care of him tomorrow on our way to Twin Lakes.
Thanks Matt. Saved my life.
Yeah all right young fella. Take it easy.
Matt.
Thanks Matt. Saved my life.
Come on there's a boat coming.
Come on there's a boat.
How do you feel old Thomas?
Fine Matt. Just fine.
It'll take more than one bullet to finish me off.
Sure. Sure you're too tough to die.
Sure you're too tough to die.
Why those fellas trying to kill you?
Cause they do what? They take us.
They take us.
the dinkus where the saucer was where is it to the side ice cap how do I get
there Matt I don't know unless you flew no one has ever flew over ice cap
deep dog gone dangerous I'll fly it where do I land face coat
put me I'll find it say Mike very much I got to tell you you'll be a lot of
trouble watch out who's so as our Matt Matt who are they Matt
I mean have you seen Mr Trent No I haven't
a friend I'm so so what's on your mind are you still interested in flying
saucers am I have you seen one better than that I've seen the fellow who claims he
invented it what is that
a how this group all called himself Dr Carl Lawton he said he flew down from
Alaska just to see me he offered to sell me the whole works for only ten million
dollars where is he now I'm fighting off the squirrels I suppose you actually let
him get away I'm running
an airplane company not in that house look Fred I've got to find that man you
really think he's got something I know he has and we've got to have it haven't you
any idea where he went to he was sorry when he left he said he was going to fly
right back to Juneau immediately and I'd be sorry well I am sorry Hank all right
so long
the
Poor old Matt said that no one had ever flown over the ice cap before.
I wasn't anxious to be the first one to try it,
but Twin Lakes was on the other side and I had to get there in a hurry.
I wasn't sure just what I expected to find when and if I got there,
but whatever it was, I had to find it.
Hey, what can I get a plane?
Inside the hangar.
Thanks.
I didn't outline my flight plan to the officer in charge.
His plane was more valuable to him than my neck,
so I kept it a secret that I was going to risk both of them.
Come on, let's keep moving.
Come on, let's go.
What made it to Twin Lakes?
From the air, I spotted a solitary cabin in the wilderness,
a place where someone who wanted to hide something might live in safety.
Perhaps I'd find there a place where I could hide my things.
I'll do it.
Perhaps I'd find there the secret I was looking for.
I decided to fly back to Juneau immediately and get in touch with Hank Thorn and the nearest
Air Force base.
It wouldn't take long to put the flying saucer in the bag with Uncle Sam pulling the strings.
But I soon found out that my gap was running low.
Yes sir, I'm going to Juneau.
Are you in a hurry, sir?
Yes, I've got to send a message to Washington right away.
Who were those fellows you were talking to?
What fellows, sir?
The ones you were talking to when I was landing.
Oh, they were just some fishermen, sir.
Asking directions.
Where's Miss Lang?
In the lodge, I believe.
I'll get the gas, sir.
Dr. Lawton, the Russians will stop at nothing to capture you and your flying saucer.
They'll never find the disc, young lady.
It's too well hidden underground.
Well, that may be true, but you're out in the open.
And if they get their hands on you, they may be able to persuade you to tell them where
the disc is.
Perhaps you're right.
They're quite skillful in such matters, I believe.
Now where was this place you suggest we stay until your chief arrives?
A hunting lodge up the river.
You'll be perfectly safe there.
V!
Hey, V!
Kick her over.
Put him in the chair.
Mr. Trench, you've given us a great deal of trouble.
Why didn't you stay in New York with your drunken friends of the night clubs?
I sobered up.
Mr. Thorn of Washington sent you up here on a mission, is it not so?
Never heard of the guy.
He came up here for my health.
A mistake, Mr. Trench.
Your health will not benefit, I assure you.
Where's the woman who called herself your nurse?
I sent her home.
I didn't need her anymore.
She'll be back soon, I'm sure.
Like you, she's curious about things that don't concern her.
There's a plane landing now.
Ah?
That must be Miss Langley.
Come in, my dear.
We've been expecting you.
And this is Dr. Lawton, I believe.
Always a pleasure to meet so eminent a scientist.
Turner, what are you doing here?
Mr. Turner is now my valued collaborator.
Oh, don't look so distressed, my dear doctor.
Instead of being used to further the imperialistic designs of America,
your invention will now be employed for the good of the entire human race.
Russia will never get it.
I don't see how you're going to prevent it, Dr. Lawton.
And now I think it's time for us all to go.
Where?
For a little trip underneath the glacier.
There's a most interesting passage goes through the ice.
We shall part company on the other side.
Even the so clever Mr. Thorne of Washington
will wonder what happened to his friends.
Turn to your left up there.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot.
It was only a small bomb, but Turner didn't know it was there.