Everything that we know and have learned about mankind and its place in the universe,
suggests that we are a part of the norm, we are not the exception.
Within the last month, a planet was identified that has water a mere 110 light years away from
Earth. We need to begin to prepare to accept and understand that we are not alone in the universe,
have not been at all throughout this time. The same year that life-giving water was discovered
on a distant planet, the US Navy made a startling announcement. Images captured by its pilots of
objects exhibiting a vastly superior technology were authentic. We can start to finally at long
last after all these decades begin to answer these questions about the origin of these vehicles,
where they're from, how they're made, how they function and why they're here.
People need to know there is something else out there.
To fully understand, we must examine a body of evidence long suppressed,
a parallel history to the one we think we know, stretching back at least 70 years.
On a clear sunny day in 1955, William Coleman, a decorated World War II pilot, took off from
Miami on a routine flight to deliver a B-25 bomber to an air base in Mississippi.
My co-pilot said, look at that bright spot up there. I think it's just a reflection of the
sun, a craze probably in the windshield. He and his passengers, two aviation engineers,
realized it was a strange object making a rapid descent right across their flight path.
My God, look at that thing. I opened it up to max continuous power. Here we're clipping right
along at over 300 miles an hour, right on the treetops. I'm right on the tail of this thing.
As we got closer, I said, it doesn't have a tail. It doesn't have any wings.
Look at the shadow on the ground. The shadow is perfectly round. That's not an airplane.
And I said, I'm overtaking it. So I said, hang on. So I'll make a hard turn. There it was, a disc,
going across the field with two big swirls.
What I didn't see was any exhaust, propulsion, no rivet lines, a rounded edge about that size
where it all came together. A true flying saucer.
Then it seemed to vanish until they spotted it thousands of feet above them.
Bright, yellow, sunish looking object. It went like a bat out of hell.
After they landed, the stunned witnesses were separately debriefed by Project Blue Book,
the Air Force investigation of the UFO phenomenon.
Ironically, a little over a decade later,
Colonel William T. Coleman became public spokesman for Project Blue Book.
Probably what we saw may have been from somewhere else.
Look, the Air Force is a very deadly being when it comes to intercepting an unknown.
If it proves hostile, we're going to shoot it down. Other than that, no problem.
In the late 1940s, America seemed impregnable to military threat.
It had just emerged from World War II, masters of the air, the only nuclear-armed superpower in
the world. But in 1947, something appeared in the sky and everything changed.
Every newscaster and every newspaper across the nation has made headlines out of it.
And this afternoon, we are honored indeed to have here in our studio, this man, Kenneth Arnold,
who we believe may be able to give us a firsthand account and give you the same on what happened.
I kept looking for their tails. They didn't have any tails. I thought, well, maybe something's wrong
with my eyes. They seemed to flip and flash in the sun just like a mirror. I'd be glad to confirm it
with my hands on a Bible because I did see it. And whether it has anything to do with our army
or our intelligence or whether it has to do with some foreign country, I don't know.
Arnold had sent this sketch to the Air Force following his sighting. He was later invited
to California's Hamilton Field Army Air Base. Where he was handed what he was told were authentic
photos of a similar craft. At the request of Lieutenant Colonel Donald Springer, commanding officer
of the 4th Air Force Intelligence and was given the above prints as a courtesy for the assistance
he had given military intelligence. The photo was taken in Arizona just two weeks after his own
encounter. They said that my father's sighting of flying saucers got more attention than the
ending of World War II. He was besieged by newspaper reporters from all over the world.
Mm-hmm. Reporters interviewed United Airlines pilot E.J. Smith who also flew the Northwest
route. He joked Arnold had likely been fooled by a cockpit reflection until he too became a witness
a few weeks later. He and his stunned crew had watched as nine disks maneuvered in formation
for a full 45 minutes. And from there it just exploded. The first few days in July of 1947 had
a very large level of exciting activity. These unknown objects barnstormed across the country,
sometimes in fleet-like formations that looked like a deliberate show of force.
Hundreds of people told Air Force investigators they'd seen the saucers with their own eyes.
Bright shiny things that wish through the air at incredible speeds. Even airline pilots who seldom
indulge in fantasy reported sighting them. And Air Force flyers told of chasing them
or something all over the sky. The Air Force called them unidentified flying objects
but people went right on calling them saucers and seeing there was something in the air.
Well the Air Force has the best brains in the country working on it.
But a then secret memorandum by the same general suggested that the highest military echelons
thought there was plenty to worry about.
The memo states quote the phenomenon reported is something real and not visionary or fictitious.
It described metallic disks circular in shape with domes on top often traveling in formations
of three to nine craft. It also listed aerodynamic capabilities with disturbing implications
for national defense, extreme rates of climb, dazzling maneuverability, and the superior
capacity for evasive action. A lot of people expected that the United States government was
about to confirm okay they're ours. This is an exciting new technological advance that we've
we were testing and now it's time to tell people about it. Occasionally eyewitness testimony
included compelling photographic evidence.
Evelyn Trent was feeding her rabbits when she spotted a metallic disc shaped object
floating over their farm. She alerted her husband Paul to grab his camera
and he managed to get two shots.
They described the object slowly hovering before it abruptly sped away. Life magazine
picked up the story and the McMinnville UFO became a global sensation. There's no chance
of this being weather. There's no chance of this being a star or an aircraft. This is either some
kind of structured object that we don't know what it is or it's a hoax. Paul Trent and his wife they
were honest, simple, hard-working people who never made a dime off the photographs that they took.
They never tried to make a dime off of it. It just come up like that and tipped and just
I mean really went. It went fast.
I've never seen anything go so fast in my life as that thing went. Yeah.
In 1951 future astronaut Gordon Cooper while training in Germany chased a large formation
with his squadron of fighter jets. Unlike fighters they would stop almost stop in their forward
velocity and change 90 degrees sometimes in their flight path and within the next two to three days
we'd had practically all the fighters we could muster on the base up climbing as high as they
would climb with guys with binoculars in them still trying to spot these strange devices flying
overhead and we never could get close enough really to pin them down but they were round and
shape and very metallic looking and they would come over and do the same maneuvers that we make
except everyone's while one of them goes to his hip and you just can't do that in a fighter.
Like two saucers one inverted over the other they seemed to be made of some kind of polished metal
when I first saw the objects they were almost overhead by the time I had the camera ready to
go they had moved to a considerably greater distance.
But the unknowns showed no signs of hostility
an otherworldly power on its own mysterious mission.
Commercial pilots William Nash and William Fortenberry former Navy aviators with thousands
of hours of flight experience saw eight huge disks fly in a stack formation over Chesapeake Bay,
Virginia just a stone's throw from Washington DC. When they came out over the blackness of the
bay they're distinct six red coins when they got closer we could see that you were it looked like
you were looking down into it like a hot coal. They reported the glowing red objects had approached
them head on at a speed they estimated at six to 12 000 miles per hour. They came in like this and
went out like this there would be no way of making complete reversal or a 90 degree turn
12 000 miles an hour or greater without making the occupants juice on the wall.
They kind of really shook us up looking at the things shook us up nothing could have gotten to
that degree of scientific progress without some of the intermediate steps
having become public knowledge. We just knew that they were not from this planet.
The next weekend the unthinkable happened the nation's capital was invaded from the skies.
Seven unknown blips suddenly appeared on radar at Washington National Airport.
Air traffic controllers at both Andrews and bowling air force bases confirmed the objects
as they danced through restricted airspace.
The Capitol building, the White House where the president lived, these were some of the most
important places in the country when it comes to national defense.
And there were ufos violating this airspace and there was nothing that the air force could do
about it. F-94 interceptors were scrambled.
Pentagon press liaison Al Chop was in the radar room that night. We could see the planes coming
in on this radar scope the minute we saw the beginning of these guys ufos disappeared.
Ufos disappeared they just left. Obviously whatever these things were had intelligence
enough to get out of the area when we had an intercept going in.
But the next weekend it began again. Pilot William Patterson pushed his starfire jet
to maximum speed to try to intercept one of the glowing objects.
It flew right into the middle of three or four of them. Al Chop recalls the pilot's panicky air to
ground transmission as he streaked at 600 miles per hour into a group of unknowns.
He actually said they're closing in on me. What do I do?
It was frightening.
The air force had just issued orders to shoot down the unknowns if quote they can't talk them down.
I'm not going to tell an air force pilot to fire at the damn thing or anything.
What? I didn't say anything. Nobody said anything.
And then all of a sudden things began to move away from here and he said they're gone.
I'm convinced they're solid objects. I'm convinced that they're probably from another planet
or from outer space somewhere. I've always felt that way since that night.
The very next day the air force's top brass hastily prepared the largest
Pentagon press conference since World War II.
Seen here in the last-minute huddle, General Roger Ramey, Air Force Director of Operations at the Pentagon.
Captain Edward Ruppelt of Project Blue Book, the Air Force's official UFO investigations arm
and Director of Air Force Intelligence General John Samford.
And Director of Air Force Intelligence General John Samford.
Since 1947 we have received and analyzed between one and two thousand reports
that have come to us from all kinds of sources. Of this great mass of reports we have been able
adequately to explain the great bulk of them. However there have been a certain percentage
of this volume of reports that have been made by credible observers of relatively
incredible things. We can say that the recent sightings are in no way connected
with any secret development by any department of the United States.
In the Q&A with reporters, Samford suggested a 50-50 chance it could have been radar waves
bouncing off temperature inversions. The point that Samford put across all too
effectively was that they were not real. They were just tricks of the atmosphere.
An atmospheric phenomena can't be a threat to national security. You don't shoot at clouds.
The public was pondering the implications of possible extraterrestrial contact.
Robert L. Farnsworth, President of the United States Rocket Society,
urged defense officials not to permit our planes to fire at any flying saucers. He says this might
alienate mankind from beings of far superior forces. Farnsworth feels that friendly contact
should be fought as long as possible. Behind the scenes, the CIA had other concerns.
A secret internal memo urged immediate attention to unexplained objects in the vicinity of major
U.S. defense installations. I would dare say if anything happened that we thought was a threat
to our national security, somebody out there, one of the services, would respond to it.
Remember, this is the height of the Cold War. There are bombers on both sides loaded with
nuclear bombs. Dr. Jacques Vallée was the inspiration for the French UFO researcher
in Steven Spielberg's Close Encounters of the Third Kind.
Have you recently had a close encounter? In real life, Dr. Vallée conducted sober scientific
research on the phenomenon. We know now that there is no simple answer. For decades, he met
with witnesses and traveled the globe gathering evidence, ultimately creating the first database
on the UFO subject. Mr. Chairman, all the great nations of the world are represented
on this committee. Let us keep in mind that the UFO phenomenon may represent an even greater
reality. Vallée also consulted with scientific, military, and government officials including
Project Blue Book's top science advisor, Dr. J. Allen Hynek.
I began my work as scientific consultant to the United States Air Force as an open skeptic.
Hynek was a university astronomer with a high security clearance when the Air Force recruited
him to investigate UFOs. And it so happened when the Air Force got the job of trying to figure out
what some of these strange flying saucer stories were about. Well, they needed an astronomer to see
how many of the reports could possibly be explained as meteors and twinkling stars and planets.
The two scientists became close colleagues, with Hynek entrusting Vallée to index the reams of
Blue Book files scattered throughout Hynek's home. It was there that Vallée made a chance discovery
of a letter so secret he had to appeal to the chief counsel of the Senate Defense Appropriations
Committee to get it declassified. That document changed my life. It taught me that the subject
had been taken much more seriously than anybody thought. The document revealed an ultra-secret,
highly funded scientific investigation working parallel to Blue Book, unknown to all,
but a select few. The letter was signed by H.C. Cross, director of exotic metallurgy
at Battelle National Laboratories. These were the people who had analyzed the files
with a large budget, with highly competent physicists and computer scientists.
Who are these people? What information did they have?
Good evening. Tonight we go after a fantastic story. The story that flying saucers from other
worlds are visiting our planet just as we are exploring outer space with our own rocket satellites.
Our guest is former Marine Air Corps Major Donald Keyhole in his campaign to prove that
flying saucers exist. My name is Mike Wallace. The cigarette is Parliament. Why will the United
States government withhold information from United States citizens? For what reason?
The Air Force is simply treating the American people like children. They don't trust them with
the facts. During the 50s and 60s, it wasn't just the Americans who were seeing flying saucers.
At the Westall School in Australia, several hundred students saw an object hovering over
this power line tower on their athletic field, an event they vividly recall 50 years later.
A student came into the classroom, you know, there's flying saucers in the in the oval,
there's flying saucers, and everybody ran out. And I remember the fear and the hysteria of all the
students. I couldn't believe it because what I was seeing wasn't possible. It was vertical,
horizontal, move away from us, back towards us, appear somewhere else, somewhere else.
My god, you know, but it was exciting. It was like that and then all of a sudden it just turned
on its side and I could see that it was a round disk. The children saw the disk begin to descend
into this wooded reserve at the end of the school's running path. I ran towards the corner of the
school, jumped the fence and ran towards where it looked as though it went down into the trees
and then stopped dead because it was right in front of me on the ground.
Like a disk with a slight rise in the middle,
I also heard a low sort of a humming noise and I felt a bit of a heat coming off it as well.
And it started to take off pretty well straight away. It had all bluey-purple lights around the
bottom. I don't remember seeing any windows and it took off to about probably four or five meters
in the air and then turned on its side and just went zoom straight up so fast that there's just
nothing, even now, day that could go that fast. Shortly after the object departed,
the authorities converged on the school. We had army, air force, police down there cordoning off
the area to prevent any of us entering the area or disturbing anything. We got called to assembly,
the headmaster said you have not seen this, you do not talk about it, you'll be in trouble if you do.
For the first time ever, the school science teacher agreed to describe what he saw that day,
providing we concealed his identity. It was not a mirage,
there was something physical in the sky. It was silver, it could hover, it could move slowly,
it could move very rapidly. Eventually it moved away to the other side of the oval and down behind
some pine trees. I was not then, nor ever have been, able to use my knowledge of the world,
nor my scientific training to provide a rational explanation. What he said next sheds light on why
the school staff have remained silent all these years. I was a knock on the door one night,
two older men, one in uniform, asked for my description of what I'd seen. I was then told
that I hadn't seen anything but I'd made it all up, possibly because I was drunk and that they
would have to report that fact to the education department and I would lose my job. After that I
was told that I would be prosecuted under the Official Secrets Act and I was told that there
wasn't anything there when I knew there was and that I had to keep quiet about it.
Why did I have to keep quiet?
The Westall landing may not have been an isolated incident.
Four days prior, a then young engineer in nearby Baldwin was taking photos in his mother's garden
when something caught his eye. This tremendous flash of light and I looked up and I saw this
object and I pulled, I had a Polaroid camera and I pulled this up, hit myself on my face
and I took the picture and I thought the photograph here. This is the original Polaroid.
It looked like it was made out of some form of metal and it was engineered and being an engineer
I was sure it was and this when I took the photograph and it tipped around I could see
the bottom and it looked like it was rotating to me and that was it and then after that it
sort of gave a bounce and it rocketed away to the north very high speed. Can you describe
the acceleration? It was like almost insane, it's like it had been shot out of a gun. Wham!
Air Force officers showed up at his doorstep asking for every detail of his experience.
And they also had some photographs of similar things and they also had a book
which had pictures of things in which they didn't leave with me but at least I had to look through
but they said it was an unidentified flying object so that was it.
What was the implication? That it didn't come from anywhere on earth.
Project Blue Book with a skeletal staff continued publicly collecting thousands of cases.
Despite efforts to explain them away hundreds were still filed as unknown.
Several reports of a strange egg-shaped object about 200 feet long landing on farms and highways
last night in the vicinity of Leveland. Sheriff Glenn says he even himself got a glimpse of the
thing which somehow turned off lights and auto engines when it came near.
Within 24 to 36 hours after these sightings in Leveland, Texas at the White Sands Proving
Ground, very close to the Trinity Test Site where they first detonated the first atomic bomb,
military personnel witnessed a glowing egg-shaped object that apparently landed.
Well, I was chasing a car up Park Street. It was reckless driving.
I saw this big cloud of smoke so I decided to let go of the car and go up there and investigate.
By the time I got there I could see a big white object sitting in the arroyo.
I couldn't tell what it was at first.
My radio was dead. It didn't work at all.
I could see some figures.
Looked like they were walking around the craft there.
They appeared to be dressed in white coveralls and were child-like, that is, small.
Zamora added that one of the two persons turned his head and looked straight at him.
When I got out of the car, about 50 feet from it,
I guess they saw me because they started their motor or whatever it is.
I could see a big blast of fire coming from right under it.
So I was behind some bushes there behind my car. I could see it and I could feel that heat.
That really got me scared, you know. A lot of people say why don't you take your gun out and
shoot at it, you know. They weren't doing nothing to me, so.
It just took a little while to get airborne.
Came up a little bit, about 20, 30 feet, and it stayed there a little while.
And it stayed just as quiet as it could be.
And then just flew away, that's it.
Lonnie was very, very scared. He was as white as a sheet from here.
Went directly to the church to talk to the priest, okay.
Pablo Lopez was among the first to arrive at the landing and takeoff site.
The ground was still smoldering, some of the weeds that were around it.
This rare footage gives us a glimpse of the scene shortly after the incident.
Patrolman Zamora stoops to point out one of the landing gear imprints
where officers had just placed rocks to protect the fresh ground traces.
And then there was a set, two sets of footprints, two sets of footprints like so.
That was about the approximate size of them.
And in comparison to the quarter, that's pretty small, okay.
That's about the size of them.
Within an hour and over the next several days, officials from the FBI,
military, and Project Blue Book documented the evidence at the scene.
Were there any prong marks on the ground or anything like that where
you can see where it had landed?
There were four.
Very unusual footprints.
How many were there?
Two footprints on one side and two footprints on the other side.
Of course, the burn area there.
I was behind my car.
I could see it and I could feel that heat.
They told me that all over the state they had been seeing some of those flying saucers,
whatever you call them.
They gave me a book on it, you know, and they told me to go ahead and read it.
Well, it says not to say nothing.
Keep away from it.
Don't say too much, you know.
It was the middle of the night by the time Lonnie came home.
Oh, he was real pale.
And I thought he was sick.
I said, are you sick or something?
He said, no.
He said, I was just working.
He was like, like he was angry.
What I knew about it was when I started reading the papers, you know,
started coming out and coming out and everything.
I said, well, what's this that you said?
I don't know.
He said, it's just a headache.
He said, everybody's after me and some believe me and some don't.
Dear Mr. Zamora,
I'm interested in UFOs.
Sure, I believe you saw an egg-shaped spacecraft that had passengers.
I saw a UFO myself in the summer of 1910.
I'd go on for a week telling you what I'd seen.
One in our school science fair had three pictures in that book,
just like the one that I saw in the spacecraft.
I thought I should write to you to tell you that you are not alone in your sighting of this object.
As I have pictures of a couple of egg-shaped ships taken when I was little.
I read about you seeing a flying saucer.
Well, you have a friend.
The saucer phenomenon has changed my life and ideas.
Mama said when it took off, he said his long teeth bite.
1960, a red bluff officers and dozens of people saw it.
Can you tell me how long it stayed on earth and other things like that?
And then people started making fun of him that he had seen little man from outer space or this and
that and all my sister's dirty stuff.
A lot of people ask me, is that the reason you quit the police force?
No, the reason I quit the police force because I was going into,
you know, a lot of publicity and stuff like that and I didn't want to hurt the town.
The level of inquiry went all the way to the office of the president.
To this day, the Socorro close encounter remains unexplained.
Socorro was very similar to the French cases that I had brought to Hynick's attention.
Checked by the police, checked by the French Air Force,
where there were also occupants who were seen short beings in connection with the object.
I think that's what convinced him that there were UFO landings in the United States.
It looked like a toy top, somewhat upside down.
So this is the diagram in which we've come up with.
It's more from the beginning.
This is the diagram in which we've come up with.
It's more flat here other than round, but it does have the hump up in here.
It seemed to move off the ground if it was down.
And then we saw three lights that went from yellow to red.
When you got right up to it, it lit up.
I mean, it needed to come bright and we could see it, the outline of it real good.
Blue Book's Dr. Alan Hynick investigated one of the alleged landing sites with the local sheriff.
At an overflow press conference later that day, the world held its breath
for an historic revelation about the landings in Michigan.
Hynick, by now privately convinced of the UFO reality,
struggled to follow the Air Force policy of tamping down public excitement.
Are you saying that the sightings of the Ann Arbor and Hillsdale areas
definitely were caused by marsh gases?
I'm saying that the two cases that I investigated most deeply were most likely.
I said in a statement that I couldn't prove it in a court of law.
Otherwise you're saying then that you don't know what caused it.
No, that's not quite right.
I think that a person can be pretty sure about something
without being able to convict somebody of a murder.
Can you say, can you say?
Yes, I do, honestly, in this case, in this case.
But you can't say without question that this is what happened.
Hynick's strained explanation, which he later called his greatest regret,
ignited a public furor.
Mr. Ford, what about flying saucers?
You've had some in Michigan in the past week.
Dave, we've had several incidents that many felt were sufficient to justify
some action by our government and not the kind of flippin' answer
that was given by the Air Force where they passed it off as a swamp gap.
It seems to me that this mystery does require
that the Congress take a good look at it.
Let them put their record on the line.
On April 5th, 1966, congressional hearings were held
with Dr. Hynick and Secretary of the Air Force Harold Brown both giving testimony.
Mr. Ford has come out.
He has a pretty good size stature in the Congress.
And so, Mr. Secretary, see if you can shed some light on these highly illuminated objects.
Mr. Secretary, there have been charges that the Air Force is hiding something in the UFO field.
We have not been hiding anything.
The investigations have been made public.
The hearing this morning was public for just that reason.
There has never been any evidence presented to the United States Air Force
or discovered by the United States Air Force,
which would indicate that the UFO phenomenon
represents any interplanetary space vehicle of any kind.
Amid growing pressure, the Air Force commissioned an outside panel of scientists
to analyze select cases and settle the matter once and for all.
It was headed by physicist Edward Condon.
Dr. Condon, do you hope to find people from outer space here on Earth?
Well, I don't know for sure, but we'll try to just study the reports
and get as much additional information as we can to see.
Would you like to have us being visited by these little or big things?
Well, that'd be fine with me if I hope they're friendly.
How do you propose to go about?
After the project was launched, Condon remarked to an audience
that he thought the UFO subject was nonsense,
but, quote, I'm not supposed to reach that conclusion for another year.
After a two-year investigation, the panel submitted a massive 1,400-page report
showing that many cases were radar and weather anomalies,
but confirming a number as truly unexplainable.
Among them were the famous McMinnville photos taken on the Trent family farm,
as well as film footage of UFOs in Great Falls, Montana.
As I looked up, I saw two silvery objects moving swiftly out of the northwest.
No sound, except I thought I heard a whooshing sound when I first saw them.
The disks appeared to be spinning like the top and were about 50 feet across.
Which was much slower than the jets which shot by shortly after I filmed the disks.
I could not see any exhaust, wings, or any kind of fuselage.
They appeared to be of a bright, shiny metal, like polished silver.
There are cases that are not explainable in conventional terms.
There is the assumption of intelligence or intelligent control,
but not necessarily the assumption of direct communication.
Why are they here? What are they doing? What do they want from us? What are their motivations?
But it was Dr. Condon who wrote the final word.
There appears to be no verified and fully satisfactory evidence of any case
that is clearly outside the framework of presently known science and technology.
I would kind of wally on that one. You'd have to conclude that what we were looking at
was beyond our current state of the knowledge.
But it began to hit me that Dr. Condon has apparently not read his own
material very carefully. You do an actual tabulation, which he doesn't seem to have done,
and you find his percentage of unexplained is five to six times larger than the Air Force.
And yet, what is his principal recommendation? The principal recommendation that Dr. Condon
has come through with is there's nothing of scientific interest that warrants further
attention on the part of the federal government here. In any major way,
he recommends dropping the whole problem. Nobody could get funded. Nobody would look at the data
seriously because of the prestige of the academy saying that the problem had been solved.
The Air Force closed their reporting system so that if the public wanted to report something,
they would report it to the local police, but it would never get to the attention
of scientists really examining the phenomenon.
In 1969, the Air Force officially ended its public investigations.
Which would suggest what? That they knew what it was?
Or didn't know what it was.
Also, the other way, they did know what it was.
That's why.
One aspect of the phenomenon that was swept under the rug
was the pervasive reporting of UFO intrusions
at the world's most sensitive military facilities.
Details did not come to light until decades later
at the National Press Club in Washington, D.C.
Declassified U.S. government documents
and witness testimony from former or retired
U.S. military personnel confirm, beyond any doubt,
the reality of ongoing UFO incursions
at nuclear weapons sites.
What you have heard here today is evidence of a phenomenon.
It sounds fantastic, and it is fantastic.
In 1967, I was a missile launch officer
stationed at Malmstrom Air Force Base, Montana.
Malmstrom was America's first line of nuclear defense.
Its silos packed with Minutemen missiles,
each one nearly a hundred times more powerful
than the bomb that devastated Hiroshima.
Launch officers could, within minutes of confirmation,
send their birds arcane 6,000 miles
to incinerate key Soviet cities,
triggering a war that would end our civilization.
The U.S. military is now in the hands of the Soviet Union.
I was the chief of party, I was the observer.
Basically, what I was doing was the star observation
to provide precise latitude and longitude
on our small three-man team.
Came from the north and stopped right over us.
And it had a white light from the center,
looking down into the silo.
I just said to myself, what if this thing beams us up
and takes us off to some distant place
and never returned to Earth again?
I mean, this is going through my head here
while this thing's above me.
And then from this dead stop, it shoots off to the east.
It's just like, now you see it, now you don't.
It just...
The strike team that went out claimed that they saw something.
How did they describe that?
He just had a large round object.
Directly over the LS?
Directly over the site.
Lieutenant Salas was stationed
in his underground launch control capsule
when he received a frantic call from one of his topside guards.
Screaming into the phone saying,
they're looking for a target,
they're looking for a red glowing object
hovering just above our front gate.
Our missiles began going into what's called
a no-go condition or unlaunchable.
Essentially, they were disabled.
In fact, 10 missiles began going offline
in a matter of seconds, one after the other.
Firstly, I'm never aware of any two missiles
going down at the same time, let alone 10.
I was a top secret control officer
and I passed out nuclear launch authenticators.
I can clearly recall a message
coming through my communication center,
which basically said that a UFO did in fact
shut down several missile silos in Montana.
I was on duty at Echo, which is our squadron command post.
We had strike teams respond to alarms from the missiles.
They were three to five miles away.
And they said, sir, lack of a better description,
there's a flying saucer hovering over that missile.
And there's a beam of reddish light going down to it.
It had to be a data collection thing.
I'm sure they scanned the warhead or something.
In 1980, I was reassigned from the Pentagon
to RAF Bentwaters as a deputy base commander.
At that time, Bentwaters was one of the largest
tactical fighter planes in the world.
It was also the largest American nuclear bomb storage depot
in Europe.
In December, 1980, early in the morning,
several of our security policemen discovered
strange lights in the forest.
Expecting to find a crashed aircraft,
they came upon an unrecognizable object
resting on the forest floor.
They observed it for a period of time
and it very quickly and silently vanished.
Two nights later, Colonel Halt received an urgent visit
from the base security commander.
He was white as a sheet.
He said, it's back.
He said, what's back?
He said, the UFO.
I took several security policemen with me.
I also had my small cassette recorder
I carried everywhere when I was on duty.
What is it?
We don't know, sir.
Do you have a tag or something?
Yeah, it's a strange, small red light.
And all the barnyard animals have gotten quiet now.
Definitely calm.
This is weird.
One object approached us at very high speed.
Here, here he comes from the south.
He's coming towards us now.
I'm sure everyone appears to be a beam
coming down to the ground.
We stood there in awe.
Was this a warning?
Was this an attempt to communicate?
Was this a weapon?
Or just a probe?
Just as suddenly as it appeared, click, disappeared.
We stood there.
About that time, we noticed the other object
to the south was sending down beams
about a mile, mile and a half away over Woodbridge base
when we had great difficulties communicating.
But we were able to discern that some of those beams
were either falling into or near the weapon storage area,
and there's a great deal of concern.
I also found out later that both the tower operators
at Bentwaters saw an object and picked it up
on their bright two radar and watched it.
I was just sitting there and I happened to see
a dot come on the scope, and it just went like
one dot at the beginning, then another dot,
and another dot, and it was gone.
And then it made the immediate right hand turn
towards the base, just absolutely phenomenal.
It's not like any radar target I've ever seen
traveling at an extremely high rate of speed.
It passed over the control tower, and then it stopped.
It was an orangish color, sort of popped into my mind
at the time that somebody's flying a basketball out here.
There were lights around the center of it.
It was more like portholes, and then you were seeing
the light from the inside, but it hovered momentarily,
reversed its course, and went back out
at a high rate of speed.
Even more alarming incidents took place
on both sides of the Cold War.
According to one secret Soviet documents,
a UFO hovered over a Ukrainian nuclear base
for nearly an hour.
Inexplicably, several missiles suddenly switched
to full combat readiness and began a launch sequence
without any authentication codes.
After 15 heart-stopping seconds, the countdown
to a potential Armageddon ceased as abruptly
as it had started.
As this object passed over the missile site,
we would start getting erratic indications on that missile.
The bad thing was we also got a launch indicator.
Does that mean that the launch sequence has been triggered?
That means that the missile has received a launch signal.
The countdown had to be manually aborted.
We have UFOs in the air.
These witnesses are some of the most highly vetted military
officers in charge of the world's most
devastating armaments.
If what they're reporting is accurate,
then the pattern is hard to avoid.
UFOs have been making incursions into top security nuclear
facilities decade after decade.
To me, it's pretty clear.
This is just we're shining a light on this.
We're pointing it out.
What are you people doing with nuclear weapons?
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
As the 90s dawned and the walls fell down,
it was as if humanity itself was demanding
to be seen as one people and one world.
The Soviet Union had dissolved, and history's spotlight
began to shine on long, darkened corners.
Different officials were looking for ways
to open dialogue with the West and embrace all the changes
that were underway in their country at the time.
This is George Knapp in Moscow, the city many are
Knapp's team was invited to Moscow
by government and military officials
who were willing to share decades worth of UFO files.
General Igor Molchev, for seven years commander
of the entire Soviet air defense system,
recalls a UFO flap over Moscow in 1990.
Hundreds of visual and radar observations
by military personnel.
Molchev confirmed his standing order was, don't fire on the UFOs.
March 1991, radar at the Leningrad Airport
detects first one, then two, then three unidentified objects
hovering over a nuclear plant.
From a dead stop, the UFO zipped away at 2,000 miles per hour.
Jacques Vallee was one of few Westerners
to personally investigate the case by meeting
with Russian sources firsthand.
An object hovered near a nuclear power plant in Voronezh
and a beam from that object melted the asphalt there.
The intention was maybe we would be able to find out
from the Russians more about what the American government
knows about UFOs than we will ever learn
from the American government itself.
Governor, are you ready to take the oath?
I am.
When a young open-minded president was sworn in,
one of America's most highly placed civilians
saw a chance for a new government transparency
on the phenomenon.
As a means of access to people, to the wonders of nature.
Heir to the power and influence of one of the world's
wealthiest families, Lawrence Rockefeller,
philanthropist and conservationist,
also had a passionate interest in UFOs.
His idea was to approach the president
with a plea for making available the data
that the government had on the subject.
The first inclination by particularly people in government
is, you gotta be kidding me, you want me to risk my career
by getting deeply into the rabbit hole
of talking about UFOs.
And so there's a tremendous resistance.
Rockefeller met with President Clinton's science advisor,
Jack Gibbons, at the White House
and persuaded him to take action.
Rockefeller was then asked to pick a case
that the White House should attempt to declassify.
He chose the 1947 Roswell incident,
noting, quote, many are convinced that Roswell
marks the beginning of government secrecy about UFOs.
Jack had actually gone to the Air Force,
asked then Secretary Widnall,
who was the secretary of the Air Force,
to take a look particularly at the records
around Roswell, New Mexico.
Dear Colonel Cavett, the General Accounting Office
seeks to fully explain the claim
that the U.S. government recovered an alien spacecraft
near Roswell, New Mexico in July, 1947,
and since that time has covered up that fact.
The Army Air Forces has announced
that a flying disc has been found
and is now in the possession of the Army.
According to my dad, there was a bad thunderstorm
the night before, and the next day he was out
on the ranch and he found this debris.
This landed at a ranch at Corona, New Mexico,
and the rancher turned it over to the Air Force.
Roswell was then home to the world's only nuclear air wing,
including the B-29 that had dropped
the first atomic bomb on Hiroshima.
The base's chief intelligence officer, Major Jesse Marcel,
was dispatched to the ranch to investigate.
We had to follow the rancher out there.
It was just verbal directions. We know where to find it.
Marcel and another officer were the first military
to arrive at the crash site.
They came upon an expanse of unrecognizable debris
strewn across an area the size of a dozen football fields.
There was so much of it.
It was scattered over such a vast area.
We found a piece of metal about a foot and a half
to two feet wide and about two or three feet long.
It felt like you had nothing in your hands.
It wasn't any thicker than the foil out of a pack of cigarettes.
The thing about that got me is that you couldn't even bend it.
You couldn't embed it.
Even with a sledgehammer, it would bounce off of it.
Marcel was ordered to immediately transport
the strange wreckage to Fort Worth Army Airfield.
There, Marcel was met by the commanding general
who told him to keep silent in the face of what was becoming
a media frenzy.
They had a whole flock of microphones there.
They wanted me to...
They wanted to stop comments from me,
but I wasn't that good, but they didn't do that.
Marcel was instead ordered to pose with wood, foil,
and rubber debris from a conventional weather balloon.
All I could do is keep a mouth shut.
And General Raimi is the one who told the newspapers
what it was and forget about it.
It was nothing more than a weather observation balloon.
Of course, which we both knew differently.
Colonel Thomas DeBose, who was also ordered to pose
with the fake debris, describes how an iron curtain
of secrecy slammed down.
This is the highest priority you can exhibit,
and you will say nothing.
More than top secret, he said.
Beyond that, this is the story we're gonna tell the public.
It was a cover story, the balloon part of it.
In order, we don't have any more inquiries
about what we picked up on the desert.
Congressman Schiff, what got you interested
in this subject per se?
I started receiving letters a little over two years ago
from constituents stating that they believed
the government was covering up what happened at Roswell.
Many of them clearly believed that it was, in fact,
an extraterrestrial crash.
The weather balloon story never made sense
because there was clearly an undisputed, in my mind,
extra military attention to this matter,
from extra security around the crash scene
to special handling of whatever the debris was.
That could fit a classified project.
It doesn't fit a weather balloon.
In September 1994, the Air Force issued its response,
the Roswell Report, Case Closed.
The Air Force claimed it was a secret project
of weather balloons hung with box kites and microphones
to spy on Soviet nuclear tests.
Please roll the video.
There's a famous box kite that became the famous flying disc.
Became the famous flying disc.
The weather balloons that were on the balloon train.
Same rubber balloon, same foil box kite
as the original cover story.
Only many of them strung together
with microphones dangling beneath.
That's the tinfoil paper, rubber, and sticks
that they recovered in the desert near New Mexico in 1947.
The Air Force, nearly 50 years later,
was basically telling the same tale,
that the top security personnel
of the world's only atomic bombing wing
really had mistaken this rubber, wood, and tinfoil
for a crashed flying saucer.
Being an intelligence officer,
I was familiar with just about all materials used
in aircraft and in our air travel.
This was nothing like that.
It was not anything from this earth
that I'm quite sure of.
My suspicion is that the Roswell incident did happen
and something maybe not from our universe went down there.
And we should allow the American people to make a judgment
on what that might've been by disclosing.
I mean, this is probably the most blatant case
of overreaction to what is national security.
The public has a right to know.
Rockefeller put together a briefing document
intended for world leaders with a sobering observation.
It is conceivable that even the president himself
is not fully briefed on matters classified
as above top secret.
I did attempt to find out
if there were any secret government documents
that reveal things and if there were,
they were concealed from me too.
I wouldn't be the first president
that underlings have lied to
or that career bureaucrats have waited out.
But there may be some career person
sitting around somewhere hiding these dark secrets
even from elected presidents.
But if so, they successfully eluded me
and I'm almost embarrassed to tell you
I did try to find out.
Ha ha ha.
Three feet per second contact now.
That was a beautiful one.
Apollo astronaut Edgar Mitchell,
who had grown up around Roswell,
was an aerospace insider with deep Pentagon connections.
He became convinced there were UFO secrets
concealed from normal government channels.
Well, if the accounts had been believed,
yes, there have been ET visitation,
there have been crashed craft,
there have been material and bodies recovered.
And there is some group of people somewhere
that may or may not be associated with government
at this point, but certainly were at one time,
that have this knowledge.
No one has proven there's nothing to it.
No one's had the opportunity to prove there's something to it.
And that's what I did.
And every passing day...
In 2007, the most powerful man in the Senate,
Majority Leader Harry Reid, persuaded two colleagues
to go to the United States to discuss the matter.
And they did.
Majority Leader Harry Reid persuaded two colleagues,
Senators Ted Stevens and Daniel Inouye,
to secretly allocate millions in Defense Department funds
to investigate UFOs.
The covert program operated from the tail end
of the Bush presidency through the Obama administration
and into Donald Trump's first year in office.
In December of 2017, the lid blew off.
At long last, the government was admitting
a modern day program to investigate UFOs
and released startling official evidence,
including videotapes from the cockpits of military aircraft.
One of the key authors of the Times' report,
One of the key authors of the Times' story
was investigative journalist
and bestselling author, Leslie Kane.
She went to Washington to meet with Luis Elizondo,
who had just resigned from his position
as head of the secret Pentagon UFO program.
I was invited to this meeting.
They wanted me to meet up Mr. Elizondo
to see what could happen.
Objects that are moving so fast,
and yet we don't see an ionization trail in the air,
and you don't hear a sonic boom.
How is that possible?
Another one is-
Elizondo's colleagues took her aside
to reveal some extraordinary documentation
related to the program.
I wasn't allowed to take anything with me.
I mean, the most important evidence
that was shared with me at the meeting
regarding the phenomenon itself were the videos.
Check on 6-1-10.
Roger, roger.
Yes!
Yeah!
Woo-hoo!
You got me!
I knew this was breaking news
for the front page of the New York Times.
The whole fleet of them are looking on the airspace.
My gosh!
Do you hear that thing?
It's hurting!
My co-author, Ralph Blumenthal and I,
set up a meeting with Mark Mazzetti
and said we have this explosive story.
Sat down with him in the New York Office
of the New York Times and we brought in all the documents.
These are the videos.
Here's other documents that show the existence
of the program and here's what they've studied
and here's what they've learned
and here's a letter from Harry Reid about the program.
Elizondo's colleague,
the former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense
for Intelligence, Christopher Mellon,
managed to obtain the tapes from the Pentagon
and chose the New York Times to break the story.
I received the videos, the now famous videos
in the Pentagon parking lot
from a Defense Department official.
I still have the originals and the packaging.
This is a case where somebody bent the rules a little bit
and they did so for the larger good
and we're absolutely all better off because of it.
In the end, I have to say,
I was still extraordinarily disappointed
with the New York Times
because they focused on this small ATIP program
and the real story in my mind, at least,
should have been these things are real,
they're here, this is happening now.
One of the Pentagon cases reported by the New York Times
was an encounter by naval aircraft
about 200 miles off the coast of San Diego, California.
5,500 people that were on the Nimitz in 2004
when this happened and I guarantee every single one of them
knows that this event happened.
That's a whole air wing, that's Mount Fuji, that's Japan.
Commander David Fravor was leading a training exercise
from the USS Nimitz Carrier Strike Group
when he was abruptly ordered to investigate
an unknown target that had appeared
on one of the ship's radar scopes.
We're gonna suspend the training,
we have real-world tasking, so we're like, okay, cool.
He and another F-18 Super Hornet,
each carrying two airmen, zoomed toward the coordinates.
That's myself and my whizzo and the other pilot
and the whizzo in the back seat of that airplane,
so there's four of us.
When they arrived, they first saw
what appeared to be a large object
slightly below the surface of the ocean
with a strange oval-shaped craft
darting around in the air just above it.
If you picture a tic-tac that's about 40 feet long,
you know, round on both ends, no rivets, no metal,
smooth white, it was white.
It was just smooth, no wings, no propulsion, no windows.
It didn't matter which way it was pointing
because as it was moving over the water, it would go,
you know, it never turned,
it never changed its longitudinal axis.
It went four, aft, left, right, it was just doing this.
And I said, hey, I'm gonna go check that out.
All of a sudden, you just see it turn its body and go whoop
and start coming up at you and you go,
that was rather interesting.
We're just looking at it, we're doing this,
we're looking at it, we're looking at it,
we're looking at it, we go around,
all the way around the outside was circle 180 degrees.
Well, I know where he's going, so I'll just go over there.
And this thing goes poof and it's gone.
I mean, literally that fast, gone.
You can think about what we're saying like,
holy shit, what the is that?
You know, and then there's a lot of, dude, what the?
Did you guys see that?
Do you guys see it?
And they're like, it's gone, we don't see shit.
Nothing accelerates that fast.
You're talking, you're talking, you know,
something that not only accelerated beyond anything
that we had seen, but it just was poof.
The controller comes up and says,
hey, you're not gonna believe this,
but that thing is back at your cap point.
Meaning the object had instantly reappeared
at the precise secret coordinates
of the fleet's critical aerial defense zone.
It obviously had some awareness,
see it knew where we were going.
Gotta make the hair on the back here next stand up.
And I actually told my back here,
I said, I don't know about you, I'm pretty weirded out.
More jets equipped with the Navy's
most advanced radar visual tracking systems were scrambled.
This time, capturing the object on video.
First thing he gets is a little blip on the radar.
He puts his cursors over it
and he tries to grab a lock on it.
Basically, when you take a lock,
you tell the radar, look at that location
and stare at it and put all your energy on that point.
Well, as soon as it does it,
the radar gets indications that it's being jammed
by the object it's trying to lock.
The infrared sees differing temperatures,
so the tic-tac is actually hotter than the air around it.
It doesn't have to be by much, but it's gonna appear white.
They're driving straight at it.
It's just kind of hovering there.
And then it goes, poof, and it takes off off the side.
I just don't know, I doubt that we
have developed that technology.
I interviewed three of the four aviators
who were with Dave during that encounter.
And it was readily apparent to everyone involved
that that vehicle had what they call
dominant battle space awareness.
It was in control of that engagement from the outset.
There was no question that it completely outmatched
our frontline fighters.
I served on the Special Access Program Oversight Committee,
so I had access to all of the black programs in those days.
We know perfectly well there's nothing like that
behind the scenes or even on the drawing boards.
Senator Harry Reid, who instigated the secret
Pentagon UFO program, confirmed what nuclear launch officers
have been reporting for decades.
There's more than one out there.
UFOs have interfered with our country's most powerful weapons.
If it had been called upon by the president to launch,
we couldn't have done it.
Did you have anybody in the Defense Department,
the Pentagon, pull you aside, bend your ear, and say,
why are you doing this?
They did everything they could to stop the program
from going forward.
They gave the person that came to me initially such a bad time.
He's fortunate to have hung onto his job
because people tried to get rid of him
because they wanted nothing to do with this.
The Defense Intelligence Agency was one of the worst.
They drugged their feet, even though there
was one of their senior scientists
thought they should look at this.
And remember, all we're saying, nobody
has to agree why it's there.
But shouldn't we at least be spending some money
to study all these phenomenon?
Shouldn't we study the stuff?
The answer is yes.
And that's all this was about and why the federal government
all these years has covered up, put brake pads on everything,
stopped it.
I think it's very, very bad for our country.
I interviewed Gordon Cooper, Mercury astronaut Gordon
Cooper back in the 90s.
Cooper said on camera that there was a landed
UFO at circa 1957 at Edwards Air Force Base.
His camera crew captured the filming of this object.
And he presented this to the higher ups.
And eventually, a courier jet came in from Washington.
He handed the footage over, which was good.
He viewed it.
That's the last he saw.
Exactly.
Did you know where that footage went of the flying
saucer that landed on the tournament?
Went to Washington.
That's all that I know.
Did you ever keep in touch with anybody about it or discuss it?
How would I keep in touch with anybody about it?
There's no way within the military
or within the government of keeping track of something
that is classified.
Did you try to go after stuff like this?
We did.
It's there.
Are you saying that there's some evidence that still
hasn't seen the light of day?
I'm saying most of it hasn't seen the light of day.
Astronaut Cooper had spoken with the president
at a cabinet meeting.
He raised this with Secretary Cohen.
And then Cohen's office called me
and asked me to pursue this and chase it down.
The Air Force colonel that I spoke with got very frustrated.
And when I asked him what happened
to all of these records, he said, well, that was all
cleaned up or thrown out to save space, something like that.
That sounded ludicrous, but that's what he told me.
If there is some recovered debris, say,
it is so deeply buried and squirreled away
that it's outside of those normal oversight processes.
And that's where there's a problem in this area.
Dr. Jacques Vallee has collected purported metal debris
from UFO cases dating as far back as 1947
that experts are analyzing in a state-of-the-art laboratory.
The breakthrough has come with the invention of a machine
that enables us to look at the atomic structure.
And at that point, the atomic structure
is impossible to fake.
This device is a multi-parameter ion beam imager.
Dr. Gary Nolan, a Stanford microbiologist,
is using a revolutionary three-dimensional imaging device
to analyze the samples right down to their individual atoms.
When Dr. Nolan placed some of the fragments
in the vacuum chamber of his instrument,
he was astonished to find their composition
was unlike any known metal.
Just one spot, and the isotopic composition all the way
across the
No matter where he looked in the sample's jumble of elements,
whether magnesium, iron, nickel, or titanium,
the ratio of isotopes didn't make any sense.
If you're talking about an advanced material
from an advanced civilization,
you're talking about something that I'll just call it an ultramaterial, right?
It's something which has properties
where somebody is putting it together, again, at the atomic scale.
So we're building our world with 80 elements.
Somebody else is building the world with 253 different isotopes.
I intend to use the information to try to build something,
to try to understand a physical principle that we don't know today.
This material was manufactured.
It's not natural.
It's not natural to the materials that we have around us
in the lab or on the Earth.
It does not mean that it was necessarily made some place in outer space.
It just means that it was manufactured specially for a particular purpose
that we don't understand, and we want to understand it.
There is an immense array of unanswered questions.
What we observe some of these craft doing,
think about the possibilities, what we may discover technologically,
how we might solve the energy crisis,
how we might raise our standards of living.
There is an urgent need, in my view, to get to the bottom of it.
We don't know the origin of these vehicles,
nor do we understand the intent of whoever is controlling them.
There are cases that seem to go beyond encounters with an advanced technology
to contact with an engaged intelligence.
Papua New Guinea, June 1959.
An Australian missionary spots a large disk
hovering just 200 feet off the ground,
while standing with 38 other people.
This solid-looking object,
and can you imagine what it's like to look up in the sky
and see some figures up there?
All were amazed to see four small occupants
dressed in what looked like black diving suits.
Figures walking about on top,
and not the slightest noise whatsoever.
And so we waved.
Wouldn't it be wonderful if we could get this object down onto the playing field?
And as we waved,
wondering whether we'd get some recognition
and whether perhaps they would understand what we wanted,
they waved back.
The encounter lasted several hours before the object abruptly departed.
There was this amazingly incredible speed
that the whole craft disappeared to nothing across the bay
in a matter of a second or so.
In 1994, three days of sightings across Zimbabwe
culminated in what some believe is the most significant close encounter
in modern history.
Hundreds of people today phoned the ZBC and the BBC
correspondent in Harare,
saying they sighted an unidentifying flying object last night
with some eyewitness reports.
It almost seemed to be under the clouds,
and it came past and notices no noise,
and that's when I thought, well, there's something very odd here.
It was quite amazing. It was beautiful.
They are saying that Jesus is passing through Africa.
That's what they are saying.
We interviewed about 64 children in front of the camera.
UFO story that happened.
Just say exactly what you want to say, OK?
Well, I was running and playing,
and then I saw this maroon colour in the sky.
Why don't we follow it?
We saw this, like, silver thing down there.
It was a silver oval thing that flew past us.
I saw the bigger one and the spaceship,
like, four or five of them.
It was red, green and yellow.
There was this big ship, it had these lights,
these petals, and it flew.
I thought, no, it's not a UFO,
and then I looked carefully at it,
and I thought, maybe.
Dozens of children said that one or more of the children
who saw the UFO,
dozens of children said that one or more of the disc-shaped objects
landed just beyond the far edge of their playground.
The next thing they knew,
something was standing next to it.
We saw him standing by the silver thing,
and he had big eyes.
He had a big head and big black eyes
and was dressed in a black bodysuit.
They were wearing pure black.
And I came down, and I saw the funny man with his eyes here,
and I saw a spaceship,
and there were a few little ones around him.
How far away were you when you saw him?
Not very far, not very far.
About a metre away.
A metre away, that close?
Yes.
And how big was the figure?
It was about as big as a grade 6.
I believe that the children did see something.
I believe them,
because normally children don't lie.
I've always taught my children seeing is believing.
Unfortunately, I didn't see, so...
It's a myth!
This alleged encounter caught the attention
of Pulitzer Prize-winning Harvard psychiatrist
Dr John Mack.
It seemed that he was looking at all of us.
What did it feel like when he was looking at you?
I felt scared.
It felt scary? What was scary about it?
I felt scared because I've never seen such a person like me.
I felt scared because I've never seen such a person like that before.
And I saw this person,
and it had big eyes.
That's all I saw about it, big eyes.
They had short legs and quite a long top.
With a big head and eyes that are bigger than ours.
How much bigger than ours?
Four or five times the size.
Four or five times the size of ours.
So then I was looking at him, right?
Then he was looking at me back.
How could I just keep on looking at him
so I had to stop and look aside?
But I was looking straight into his eyes.
Well, he never said anything.
It's just that the face is the eyes.
Maybe they're trying to communicate with us,
show us something which we don't know about.
I think they want people
to know that we're actually making harm on this world
and we mustn't get too technology.
We don't look after the planet.
All the trees will just go down
and there will be no air and people will be dying.
Is this an idea you have had before
or did this idea come to you
when you had this experience?
When I had this experience.
For the first time in nearly 20 years,
the Ariel School children gathered
from the four corners of the world
to talk to each other about the experience
they shared that September morning.
I remember something there.
One they all still struggle to understand.
You know that it's moving, but you...
I stand by what I saw.
There was no reason for any of us to make that up.
I've not spoken to anybody about it.
Not because I'm not proud of it,
but because I don't want the stigma.
So it's something that I've had to deal with
for 19 and a half years.
I don't want to say I felt like I knew it,
but I knew that I didn't have to be afraid of it.
They took us back to the moment of contact.
Exactly how I felt, exactly.
The details still seared into memory.
I was with one of the other girls
and saying to her, this is amazing.
We all were just stopped in our tracks.
A little man appeared on top of the actual craft,
and that moment for me was very distinct
because I was like, that's not human.
I was just completely engulfed in these eyes.
The eyes, and in that moment, however long it was,
because I have no idea of the time frame,
it was mesmerizing.
There was no talking.
It's all just images in the head.
Telepathic communication.
They were trying to communicate,
trying to tell us something
with something to do with the environment.
I kept getting these thoughts and ideas
in my mind of technology.
Technology is not helping, technology is bad.
And we're going down a wrong path,
and we have to start recognizing
that what we're doing is detrimental,
and we need to make changes,
and I don't know what to do with that.
They were reaching out to us.
It was as if they wanted us to go with them.
At that moment, that was kind of when
I snapped right out of the trance.
As soon as I broke contact,
all of those feelings, technology, the fact,
the horribleness that was happening
and going around my body at the time, went.
It's making me a bit anxious being back here.
I can feel it right now.
I was scared.
They came running up here in such a panic,
screaming, screaming,
and they were here, you know,
and a child can't make that up.
So I was there when they were interviewing them
and saw the way they were.
It was just a huge, big mess
and muddled up and just people everywhere.
Just ask them questions straight off
without explaining to the children
what they were doing and why they were doing it.
It was chaos in terms of the media frenzy
that was going on and us being so young
and not even being allowed time
to comprehend what we had seen.
Our teachers certainly didn't believe us,
so that was a big deal because we had to continue
going to school there.
We went back one last time to the aerial school
to meet with Judy Bates,
a teacher at the time of the incident
and now the headmistress.
Something was weighing on her
that she wanted to tell the children.
Yeah, I said I wanted to apologize.
I should have taken more notice,
but I didn't.
I was more concerned about me and not them
than what was going on in my own sort of experience.
And that's what, yeah.
And if you could summarize in just one sentence
what took place September 1994
here at aerial school, Rua Zimbabwe,
what would you say?
Aliens visited us.
And that's about it, yeah.
And that's where if you believe it,
you believe it if you don't.
We find ourselves confronted with something
that challenges our very understanding of reality.
We may be sharing this fragile blue-green oasis
with an unknown other,
one with a mysterious relationship to humanity
and its own interest in our world.
And if you saw him again, what would you do?
I'll ask him, what is he doing on Earth
and what does he want with us?
What do you think?
They were well-observed UFO cases
just like modern cases in the 18th century,
In the 17th century, there was science.
There were astronomers. They had telescopes.
And they were very good observers,
because their life depended on being good observers.
And these observations come from all over the world.
They just have been forgotten.
I like to think of anomalies, mysteries as opportunities.
And we'll go after those mysteries,
take the torch away from the campfire
and out of the cave into the darkness
and make some amazing discoveries.
And I think that's the way to do it.
I think that's the way to do it.
Well, I'd like to go out and do it.
I'd like to go out and do it.
and make some amazing discoveries.
The UFO phenomenon,
bespeaks the action of some form of intelligence.
These objects gave the impression that they wanted to be seen. With these enormous spotlights,
there was no way that they were trying to hide. So why? That is the main question. Why do these
objects want to be seen? Later on I was so sorry that why I did not call on the
radio, ask them, who are you? Please make communication with us. I figure if they're
smart enough and capable enough to come into our airspace, the technology that they have,
if they wanted to do us in, they could have done us in a long time ago. So I'm not fearful of this at all.
I think as long as we don't change the world, it will greatly promote the development of the
scientific and technological level of the world. It will be beneficial to human progress. This is a big
thing. I've never seen anything go so fast in my life as I think. Incredible speed disappeared
to nothing. And just went zoom straight up so fast. It's like it had been shot out of a gun.
Now you see it, now you don't. It just, but it just was.