So in the extraterrestrial research part of the archive, this is at the observatory,
because anything that has to do with space doesn't go to the Vatican archive,
it goes to the observatory, which is in Castle Gandolfo. And that's a space observatory.
So basically, they just had from back in the day, from like 1200 onward, what people have thought
about and published about extraterrestrials. But if you look at the history of Catholicism,
and you look at like, especially people in the Vatican, they know about Emanuel Swedenborg,
who's talking about angels and people on Venus and things like this in 1750.
Right? In 1750, there was a bestselling book called Life on Other Planets.
There was a bestselling book called Life on Other Planets.
Yeah. Welcome back to Blurry Creatures. This is your first episode. Welcome. Welcome to the show.
You might want to go back and start the beginning. This is kind of a journey podcast.
Exactly. We've been doing this for a couple of years now. We've heard a lot of weird stuff.
Our paradigms have been smashed and put back together several times.
Just when you think you know what you're talking about, you think you understand what's going on,
you hear a story or you hear another smart person come on and blow it up again. So
for those of you who have been around since episode one, thank you. Thanks for being on
the ride with us. We know how you feel because we're right there with you. Yeah. Right?
Just one is true. Yeah. Blows the whole paradigm.
Oh, look at you. Yeah, you know, you have to. I prefer just to quote Judd if I really want
to do it. But yeah, that's the most fun. But we were just talking, Luke and I were just
talking out there a little bit about just how blown away we are with the response of the podcast.
Just how it's been charting people, buying merch, people supporting the podcast and just
going places in the public and people stopping us and saying nice things. And it's a podcast.
You don't ever think you never know. We're just having conversations and we're putting it out
there. We don't realize like, oh, you know, this is, this is wild. This is, this is something that
seems to be needed. A lot of people need to have these weird conversations. So we're happy to have
have them for you. Right. And with you and sometimes with you as well. But I, you know,
I want to say this, Luke, there are a lot of people feel alone. A lot of people messages and
say, you know, I'm thankful for you guys because I felt alone my whole life. And it's, I'm just
thankful for your friendship, Luke, because we can have these conversations together and we don't
think each other is crazy. And I, sometimes I understand how they feel, but then other times
I'm like, I feel lucky that I have a lot of friends in my life who don't, who don't think
this stuff is crazy. And, and we can have conversations about it, but a lot of people,
they tune into the podcast, they have nobody to talk to. Maybe even their spouse doesn't even
believe in any of this stuff. And so grateful for you being here though. And you're welcome here.
And I truly believe there is a quickening. I think that people are waking up, you know,
we always say like this, this is, we're just a couple of guys that ask questions. We don't
have PhDs behind our names, but we were looking for better answers. Most of all,
we say this almost every episode, Nate, we want people to think for themselves. So
digest the things, the experts we bring on and have spent the research time and decide for
yourself, think for yourself. That's what makes free speech great. That's what this country is
founded on. So made this country, made this country great was that you had a free exchange of ideas
and you could let the cream rise to the top. And that's, you know, I think in some ways,
kind of what we're doing, we want to have platform where we can talk about things and,
and then ruminate and, and marinate. Age and the fine, the fine whiskey barrel. That's right. You,
but you believe he's out there now, huh? It's just one of those people's right. He's out there.
You know, it's, listen, I mean, we've come a long way since big foot, but we need to, we know our,
we know what our core competency is. And so we, we, we have to talk about the big guy.
We're grateful to our members. If you, if you want extra content, you can join,
join up, become a member. There are extra episodes, exclusive episodes.
There are exclusive groups, Facebook, discord, telegram groups. You can join and continue
discussion about episodes and everything blurry. We also have merchandise. If you like Nate's
pretty talented, creative dude. And we've got some fun t-shirts, all that goes to support the
podcast and us doing more of the more blurry things and more of this. So thank you to our members.
If you're interested, check out our webpage, where Nate blurry creatures.com slash members or
slash merch. Yeah. We also have a link to our official Spotify playlist on the show and,
and a guest suggestion sheet. And we're going to be doing more for, you know, all the members on
the show. We're coming out with ideas every day. We've got a lot of ideas, but you guys have been
awesome. Thank you for all the messages. Sorry, we don't get back to a lot of them. Um, lately,
it's just been a ton and we're trying to have a newborn, new dads, old dads, new dads, old dads.
We're flying by the seat of our pants. And I thank you guys for supporting the show, putting
food on the, putting food on my family's table and helping this show get produced.
And it's become so much bigger than we ever imagined. And we can't say thank you enough.
And I actually put a fusion six on my wall in here when I'm podcasting now, because how crazy
the show's gotten, I got to like stare at it, you know, put on the armor because it feels like this
stuff's just, it's not only is it real, but it's coming at you and in a way that I've never thought
possible. So we're praying for us. And, um, yeah, yeah, we're grateful for this community. And
let's, let's bring on Dr. Diana Pasolka. Yeah, we have Dr. Diana Pasolka today. She's coming
on the show. She wrote a book called America Cosmic Academic, who talks about the blurry things in our
world, which, you know, we always love those people who are bold in their field to talk,
talk about the truth and not be afraid to have a bunch of pushback.
Cause I mean, just the pushback we get sometimes I'm like, gosh, I can't imagine being in like an
academic field and all this stuff they get. It's bold. You got to be bold to speak out,
you know, and there's a lot of people getting put in jail these days if they speak out the truth.
So, you know, Facebook jail, Doug van Doren goes to Facebook, Doug, we love you. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. But I mean, literal jail, some of these doctors who speak out, they're going,
they're getting locked up, you know, and it's crazy just false accusations and all kinds of stuff. So
yeah, you guys are awesome. Thanks for supporting the podcast. Thanks for features.com. Thanks,
Matt Maher, Matt Maher for, for the suggestion and for recommending Diana. We need a show roller.
You're now entering the blurry bird.
The history of our earth is so different from what we can imagine.
The Smithsonian, and if they found out about a large skeleton somewhere was to go get it.
I'm going to assume at least one person is right, because if one person is right, it busts the
paradigm. It all goes back to the fallen cherub. And the problem with the modern day church,
they have a very truncated view of the supernatural. This backdrop that's just pregnant with all kinds
of meaning associated with this Mount Herman event.
And this guy defects from the kingdom. That's a big deal.
That's right. Well, Dr. Diana, we're glad to have you. So we'll do a proper introduction.
Dr. Diana Pasolka, you're an author and a professor of religious studies at the
University of North Carolina in Wilmington and chair of the department of philosophy and religion.
We wanted to have you on because you wrote a book called American Cosmic, which is UFOs,
religion and technology really picked our interest because, and in talking to you before we started
recording, you're, you're also a Christian and, and then we found out you didn't believe really in
any of this stuff when you started researching it, which I think is a, is a fascinating journey.
I think with all of that, I would love to ask you about that journey from, you know,
a religious studies professor to, you know, to this book, like, you know, how, how did,
how did that process happen and how did you end up writing a book on, on, on UFO?
Yeah. And you, you and my sister are both Davis alumni. So shout out.
Wow. That is so cool. Davis is one of my favorite places, riding around on bicycles. And there's a
great religious studies program there, which I had taken classes in and philosophy too. Okay.
And I'm a Chico State guy. So we were rivals at one point. Now you guys are D1.
Okay. Yeah, that's right. Wow.
I'm Cal Poly. I'm Bigfoot on the circle. All right. So
California educated kids. We're all brainwashed, right?
Yeah, that's right.
We got out of the brainwashing, I think. That's how it works.
Baby, hopefully.
Okay. The Southerners are going to say, oh no, this is too much, right?
Yeah, right.
There's too much North Cal here in the South.
Okay. So I had, I had an idea to do what I'm doing now when I was 11. So I wanted to, I was a,
a kid who was, who had a feeling of being religious, like being Christian when I was
young. And so what I did was I read the Bible basically when I was about 11. And it was the
King James version, which is not a Catholic version of the Bible, but it's a, it's a Protestant
version of the Bible with, it's a red letter edition. And so I would focus on Jesus's words
in the Bible. And I said, you know, the Bible, once you actually read it is quite strange
and it doesn't make a lot of sense. It's a lot of books put together. Now, if you're a kid,
you don't know this. So, but I w I knew enough to know that through reading this book,
there were, there's a history here and there were these original languages that this book was,
you know, translated from. And I wanted to learn those original languages.
And I wanted to know about the history of the Bible and religion in general. So that was kind
of like a goal that I had when I was very young and I ended up doing that. So I started off as a
born again Christian. My, my family, my dad was Catholic and my mother was Jewish. We came,
you know, from eclectic California, new agey culture, and they weren't particularly religious,
but I was. And so I asked them if I could attend a Catholic school that was actually run by
sisters, the sisters of mercy. And these were great role models because they were living the
gospel in terms of actually helping people and, you know, doing actual work of feeding people and
clothing people and getting them medical supplies and things like this. They were doing this in
Central America at the time. And so this, this was my early education. And so I decided to now,
I grew up, you know, what it was like in the nineties in California, it was the.com boom.
So it was really easy to get a job doing really anything tech related and make decent money.
So I did that and that kind of kept me off my route of going to, you know, school for religious
studies for a while. But I kept reading philosophy and religion and I knew that eventually I'd do
that. So I did. So in my twenties, I went back to graduate school and I was applied to the divinity
school in Berkeley. It's called the GTU, the graduate theological union. And it is a great
school because you've got everybody who wants to learn academic, you know, the field of academic
religious studies, but also they want to either be a priest or be a rabbi. And there are schools
there that teach people how to do that. So that's where I went. And so I took classes
at UC Berkeley and I took classes from the Jesuit school theology, and I took classes from all kinds
of different schools. And I learned a lot about religious studies, which is different than
theology. So people ask me, you know, are you a minister or what do you do? No, I teach academic,
I teach that basically that comparative religion or the history of religions. So we learned every,
I learned about every sort of religion. So I teach classes on
Hinduism, Buddhism, Islam, Muslim, you know, Christianity. I teach Christianity to people
who are Christians and have not ever read the Bible by the way. So, so these are the things I do.
I had never thought of UFOs before. So how did that happen? So what happened was that I've,
you know, when you start, when you're in an academic program, it kind of distances you
from things like miracles and the reality of, of religious people and how religious people have
experiences that are, that they could call miraculous. Supernatural stuff, right? Yeah.
Exactly. Totally supernatural stuff. So it teaches you to not believe in those and it teaches,
it distances you from those things. And so I was fully distanced from these things until 2011 and
2012 when I had the experience of finishing a book about a Catholic doctrine, a purgatory.
I'd been through a lot of the archives of, you know, Catholic culture and I did a lot of research,
you know, I was, I was a complete academic nerd, you know, this is what I was immersed in doing.
I had young kids and so I was, my life was basically taking care of my kids and doing
research and teaching nothing else. And then what happened was that I came across all these
sightings of UFOs. I didn't know they were that, like I didn't, I didn't think about it in that way,
but I, I saw from like 1100 onward to like up until the present that European and North American
and Canadian Catholics were basically identified these flying objects in the sky, but they were
interpreting them as different types of things. And so I had a kind of like a breakthrough weekend
where I had this and, and I was done with this one book and I said, I'm, I don't know what to do
with all this stuff. I had kept a log of these sightings, like here's an example of one of them,
a sighting that this nun had, it was this in the 1800s and she kept seeing these orbs come through
her cell, you know, basically she was in a cell, right? Like that's what nuns lived in, these
convents and it was a stone cell that she was in and these orbs would come in and she was afraid
of them and didn't know what to think of them. So she told the mother superior and the priest
of the convent, they didn't believe her, but she kept having this experience. So finally the mother
superior sat with her one night, saw the orbs herself and realized that she, they thought that
they were souls from purgatory that needed to be prayed away. And they got the whole community
together and they prayed, well, this is the type of thing that I kept coming across. And so I showed
the log to a friend of mine and I said, I can't, I really don't know what to think of this stuff.
And he said, it looks like Steven Spielberg, like, you know, UFO stuff. And I said, you are crazy,
but that weekend there was a UFO conference in Wilmington and I attended it. And when I attended
it, I realized that people were still having these experiences and then boom, my world changed.
I completely, the supernatural became real. And I had an experience, I would call it,
it was an experience that was frightening, terrifying, and also strangely familiar because
I recognized that those things that I'd been studying my whole life were actually real.
And how now do I think about them? Like, how do I deal with this now? And I frightened a lot of
my colleagues, you know, they were like, what's going on? What happened to you? Right.
But you know what, I developed a new way of, in my field of talking about this stuff. So I've,
you know, I was already the chair of my department back then. So I could do that.
I could write a book about UFOs without being maligned. And then the US government comes along
this last summer and basically says, yeah, they exist. We don't know what they are. And so,
you know, a lot of, you know, my book came out, the timing was perfect for it. So that's what
happened. That's wild. There's so many things I want to ask, but I think it's fascinating that
you wrote this book, taking these experiences and then contextualizing it in the context of
a religion. I think one of the things you talk about is that there's 75% of American adults
believe in extraterrestrial life, right? And this is the way that you teach academic religion,
you make an argument this is becoming a religion. Can you unwrap just a little bit of that for us?
Because I think that's a fascinating way to look at it. And that's what Nate and I,
we've talked about in the very beginning, Diana, when we started this podcast was to try to
contextualize the crazy things people experience and see stuff that's in the Bible that doesn't
make a lot of sense. And then to try to make it make sense through the lens of the biblical
narrative with the foundation of our faith. And you're taking this experience and saying,
this also looks like a religion, the way that people treat these experiences. What you think
is a really interesting juxtaposition on this. And I know you spent what, 60 years
doing an ethnographic study on all of this. So I would love just for just a little bit of insight
to why you see it like that, and maybe even why you called it American Cosmic with the idea that
this happens across the world as well. Sure. Yeah. So American Cosmic. So that references
to a book by Henry Young called The Russian Cosmists. And so this is how that happens. So
along the way of doing this study, it became known that I was doing a study like this. And I was
approached by people from who were affiliates and worked with NASA, and also were involved in our
US space program. And so they came to me to understand what they were seeing basically,
and what they were experiencing. And they wanted me to kind of explain it to them,
which I thought was so strange. And so what happened was that I learned, I started to do some
historical work about our space programs. And I recognized that at the basis for the Russian space
program, the two viable space programs back in the day, right? The Russian space program,
and our space program, the United States space program. And each of them were founded on very
odd ritualistic types of things going on. You had Jack Parsons with us, and I don't know if you know
anything about him, but he would do these kind of a cult, not kind of, that's what California
wave sang it. Crowley stuff, yeah. Yeah, full on a cult work in order to download or bring about
these technologies that would help him develop rocket technology. At the same time, or a little
bit earlier, the Russians were doing the same thing, but theirs was Christian. Theirs were
ritualistic, but they were Christian. They believed that they were getting in touch with angels
and beings that were godly, not demons and things like that. But the rituals were very similar,
okay? Although the Russians didn't involve the weirdness that Jack Parsons was involved with.
But for a person who studies religion, they were rituals. And most people don't ascribe science
with rituals. And they don't ascribe our space program in particular. They want it to be
completely nuts and bolts and no paranormal stuff. But I'm sorry, at the basis of both of those
developments were ritualistic paranormal activities that kept going on. And so one of
the people that I associated with and learned from was, I call him Tyler D in American Cosmic.
He was basically kind of in the tradition of Jack Parsons, but without the Crowley stuff,
because he was Christian. But the space program, I just did a talk on this actually,
the American space program is steeped, especially when it does these certain launches down in Cape
Canaveral. They have to do it at certain times. Certain people have to stand in certain places.
They have these patches that look, you know, in special clothing that they use. I mean, it's
ritualistic. And so that's why I called it American Cosmic, because I wanted to identify
this tradition that we are completely as Americans unfamiliar with. We don't even know about it.
And in fact, if you ask people in NASA today about Jack Parsons, they don't want to know.
They're like, let's not talk about that. That's what I got back when I was doing this research.
It's interesting too, Nate, because the other thing is von Braun, right, was a Nazi.
So you have these, you know how the Nazis were so very much focused on the occult and trying to
harness, I mean, they had, they built rooms and castles and they had, they were, I mean,
they were practicing black magic. I mean, they were doing satanic type things. And then you
have one of those people. That's really interesting to hear. I mean, because yeah.
Yeah. We hear it all the time on our show, because we have a lot of, we have a huge
following of flat earthers who listen to the show and they get really into NASA and the
deceptions and stuff. And it's not really what our show's about. I mean, we talk about creatures
specifically, but we've heard everything from there's orbs associated with Bigfoot to actual
abduction stories and encounters. I mean, there's nothing weird that we've, I mean,
we pretty much have heard it all now after doing this for a couple of years and everything's
strange, but it is, I do argue sometimes with the flat earthers on our show and say, look,
whatever you think, whatever we think we know, it's always 30 times more complicated.
Like NASA is not operating what it tells the public, what it's doing. That doesn't mean,
it doesn't mean everyone in NASA secretly knows the world is flat and they're hiding this from us.
And you're the only one who figured it out. Right. Right. Exactly. Yeah. And so it's, but I,
but I do think you're right that there, there's a lot of occult stuff that goes along with CERN.
It's science, but wait, what are they doing? What are they really doing here? They tell the public,
oh, we're just putting these particles together. No, no, no, you're doing something else.
And so we hear that all the time and it's always good to talk to someone who discusses with these
because these debates go on in our channels all the time. Like what is that? What is NASA really
up to? What do they know? And a lot of this stuff happened around the thirties around Roswell,
suddenly all these agencies sprung up out of the ground. And I think they do obviously know things
that we sort of, you know, debate on our show, like what's going on? Do they have alien tech?
Is, did they, did they go to the moon? Did they not go to the moon? What did they find there?
Where do these creatures come from? So it's all very blurry, but I just think it's complicated.
So it's good to hear you kind of put that to words because I've always kind of associated like
some people know in NASA, but some people don't. And it's just this complicated dance,
but hey, flat earthers, that's not a dig at you. Love having you listen to our show.
You just got to say that. That's exactly the case. So in fact, what I did was in my book,
I created a framework for us to understand what was going on. And the way I did that was I used
a reference to this movie called fight club, which was a book. Okay. So before, and it's a,
it's, it's a very, it's a very intense movie, but what it does have in it is this idea that
there's this underground movement that of men basically, and they, they have a club, but they
don't talk about first rule. And since right. Exactly. Yeah. First rule of fight club. Don't
talk about club. Yeah. So, so this is what's really interesting is that the main, one of the
main people of my book is Tyler and I named him after Brad Pitt's character. Yeah. Yeah.
Just a quick pause. We love movie references or at least I do especially. So this is just wheelhouse
movies too. Our show is 80s themed, but any movie reference. So we're tracking loving this too.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It was, so it's not just NASA, but it's also aerospace and the NRO.
So all of these organizations that are, you know, space oriented, they have the rule,
which is basically you don't talk about it. Not only do you not talk about it,
but your boss doesn't even know what you do. Okay. So Tyler's boss didn't even know what he did.
His, the friends that he worked with at the places where he works, they didn't even know
what he did. He couldn't talk about it. He also had these constraints. He couldn't go on the news.
He couldn't go online and look at the news. In fact, oftentimes he would ask me, can you look
at this website? I want to see what it says about so-and-so, right? And I would have to look for him
and tell him because he wasn't allowed, he was monitored that much that he wasn't allowed to do
that. So what I did was I unwittingly, not by my own choice, found myself amidst this culture of
people who were so incredibly compartmentalized that oftentimes they didn't even know what their
mission was. He never knew what his mission was. He had to figure it out. Okay. So this is the level
of secrecy that was created in order to keep people from not knowing, even the people that
were doing these missions from not even knowing what they were. There was a point when I believe
that, in fact, I stumbled upon names for programs. I didn't mean to, but I did. And then they would
change the names to numbers. That's crazy. Yeah. So I mean, that's how it works. Yeah. It's very
strange. Yeah. And then people get mad because like Bob Lazar basically said this and went public
with it. And they're all like, well, there's no record of him doing this and that. And I'm like,
you don't think they could make, they could easily make someone disappear because they barely
have any, you know, like you said, they have, they have this, it's just the shroud of secrecy
that kind of flows through it. I remember my, my ex father-in-law was telling me a story before,
you know, he, he passed away. He was saying that his dad worked in area 51. He said that his dad
came home and told him a story once that his father's in area 51 with clearance, with security.
And yet while he's in there, they had, they were moving something from one, one part of the
facility to the other part of the facility. And they had a bunch of armed guards there
protecting inside this high security clearance area, moving things. Like his dad is like,
I don't know what they're moving, but I'm not even allowed to see what they're moving. And it's,
it was just like, and then later on years later, you hear Bob Lazar story about this and you're
like, they, they didn't know. And he couldn't talk with his other coworkers because they didn't know
what they were doing. And everyone's sort of in the dark. And then skeptics will listen to our
show and be like, ah, these people are all liars and this isn't true. And I'm like,
well, it makes a lot of sense when you hear that, you know, a lot of people don't know
what's going on. And I wonder if that's because if, if they find someone that they don't like,
they can just get rid of them real quick and, and they don't have to deal with it or they're
just afraid of it. Yeah. I think, I think that it was a, it was a really genius plan to do this
because then if you want to keep a secret, also they don't write, you know, people, especially in
the communities of UFO people, people who are ufologists, they really focus on textual things
like things that are written down by clearance people and things like that. Well, I, I promise
you that they're not writing these things down. So they have communities of oral tradition and
we call it oral tradition where they pass their information to each other in word and they call
it, there's a word for it called pencils up where, you know, okay, this meeting is pencils up, which
means you don't nothing, right? There's no written record of it at all. And so, I mean, it's a genius
way to keep this type of thing quiet. Another strange thing though, that happened was that
the man who I called Tyler, I showed him everything I was going to write about him, by the way, it was
cleared with everybody in my book. They read their chapter and they wrote off on it and said, yeah,
it looks good. One thing that happened was that I found out that he identified with Tyler, Tyler
Durden in fight club. He even, he even had the soap, the fight club soap, and he also had, he had the
robe, you know, Tyler Durden wears like this purple robe. He had the purple robe that he, he would have
at home that his family would make fun of him for having. I mean, so I nailed his personality.
Yeah. And well, it's not even just UFOs. I mean, it's, it's, it's all the weird stuff. It's, we
talk about ancient history a lot on our show. It's all the, the, the architecture around the
megaliths that there's, you know, this Egyptian timeline that is inaccurate. Egyptologists are
always arguing big foot sightings. Oh, those aren't real. You know, it's every single, and we
constantly go through the archives on this show. We're talking about giant skeletons were discovered
when we, that gets covered up or UFO reports. And this isn't a, this isn't a modern thing.
You can go back in news archives and read about these things and big foot sightings go back
a long time too. So it's just constantly shrouded in conspiracy theory. Nobody wants to look at it,
but it is cool that a lot of, you know, doctors and educated people do come on our show. And every
once in a while, the right personality who's actually applying the scientific method will
come on and say, look at the evidence. It's right here. You have to apply it, but a lot of people
are afraid. I guess they're afraid of like Jeff Meldrum, who's like the big foot guy. You know,
he said all his colleagues would make fun of him all the time. He was constantly being ridiculed
because he's like, look, I have actual evidence. I know what a, I know what a real footprint
looks like. This is not a human footprint. I can, this is what, this is my life's work. I
can prove to you, this is not faked. And yet every, all of his colleagues still laugh at him. So
there's something strange going on in all these areas, whether it's aliens, UFOs or all the
cryptid science. So it's good to hear you kind of talk about this a little bit because we,
we do make that point a lot on our show that no matter what rock we turn over,
it's always this mysterious, the bones go missing or so, so we say on our show all the time. And
we even, we even make shirts about it because it's so, I'm actually writing an article right now
for a folklore edition for my field that talks about why, you know, why this stigmatized
knowledge, like it's called stigmatized knowledge in my field. Like, and so, you know, people who
seemingly are above suspicion in terms of their scholarship, like John Mack, who studied UFOs,
he was a Pulitzer prize winning research scientist at Harvard and you know, his own university
put him under investigation for studying UFOs in a way that was, that was, you know, he
conformed to the scientific method, you know? So, I mean, I was, you know, I, I was certain
things had changed by the time I started doing this work. And this was, you know, in 2012 on up,
and then my book was published in 2019. But when I would, when I would be asked by usually grad
students to speak at their universities, a lot of my colleagues would be horrified by what I was
talking about. And they were sure that I had been misled by people who were not actually who they
said they were. Well, I knew who they were was actually accurate, right? One of those people is
Gary Nolan from Stanford University. He's James in my book, but I couldn't say so at the time,
because the government hadn't yet come out. But then when the disclosures of UFOs started happening,
you know, now those people want to write about UFOs. And, you know, and so I just think that
that's disingenuous, you know, because they didn't follow the data then, how are they going to follow
the data now? Yeah, no, that actually has kind of piggybacks on the question I want to ask you about
all this, because your book, like you said, your book is timely, right? In 2019. And now we have,
we talked about before, we have the government, they're holding meetings now Congresses have is
holding, holding meetings about UAPs, they're now talking about it. And they even renamed the whole
thing to destigmatize it, right? But do you think that we are in the middle of another like
Copernican sort of revolution where, where we're sort of reorienting because because we have this
new, we have this thing that people have been talking about for a long time, but now it's being
talked about in the mainstream narrative, you think that we're in a bit of a revolution in the
same way that like Copernicus in his, in his revelations changed the way people thought about
earth and man and where we, where we said, do you think the things that happen right now,
and we're kind of in the midst of this? Yeah, so I do think that, okay, so first,
that Copernicus analogy is really good, right? And I actually did use that in a proposal that I was,
you know, putting together for a book that I'm writing right now. But after assessing it,
I also see that we're in a completely different era in terms of our infrastructure.
So, you know, when Protestantism and Catholicism split, there was, it was because of technology,
it was because of the Gutenberg press, right? So the printing press allowed people to read the
Bible on their own without it, you know, being in the hands of priests and such. Right now,
what's happening, this disclosure is not, is not on the timeframe of those who are disclosing,
it's on the timeframe of the people. Because right now you have other space programs,
you have a Chinese space program, and you have other countries that are putting things up into
space, and they're beginning to see what's up there. And so we can't, they're not going to
keep the lid on all these things that are flying around. And by the way, once people see these
things that are flying around, their worldview is open so that they can see other things too,
okay? So they see that reality is not what we've been told it is.
Now, when this happens, I think that, and will we have enough people? I think that we're at a
really interesting point in human history, frankly, and I can't predict what's going to happen.
But I can tell you that, that people have been here before. And if you look pre-Christian even
to like Plato and Plato's Republic and, you know, the cave, the allegory of the cave where people
are like, hey, you know, when Jesus was killed by Rome, a lot of his followers called him this,
called him Socrates. They said, you know, you're like Socrates from back in the day, you know,
you were killed by your government for trying to get people to see what is real, right? And so I
think that we're in that kind of place right now. And I think that we're getting a lot of narrative
framing and we need to be aware of that. And, but I don't think with that, honestly, I don't have a
lot of hope that I think that communities like yours and communities, you know, that I feel like
I might be a part of our, we can help each other to identify the BS, right? And the framing that,
you know, no, this is how it is kind of thing. And we're like, no, that's not how it is. We have
brains, you know, we can figure it out, but a lot of people will just go for the bread and circuses
instead. And we, and we can't fight that because technology, this is a good part of my book actually,
is physiologically addictive. So, you know, when you have like, you know, TikTok or something like
that, and I see this, the changes in students because I'm a professor. So the people I see
are 20 year olds and I see 20 year olds from 10 years ago, 20 year olds from 20 years ago
and 20 year olds today. And they're different. And the reason they're different is because they
have this thing that they're like sucked into and they're addicted to it and it is changing
their behaviors and everything. So, yeah, I think it's a scary time to tell you the truth.
Yeah. Yeah. And we hear that a lot. I mean, and it's, it's amazing how, you know, when you,
everyone seems to have some sort of experience, whether it's, you know, they see a Bigfoot
and you typically it's people that are the most skeptical who see something like this
or they see a UFO. We had several people come on our show and say these things fly right over their
head. 10, 15, 20 feet and they're silent and they're huge. They're like the size of buildings
and they're doctors. You know, we had a doctor come on and tell us his experience. And I think
that for the most part is that more and more of these things are happening. Bigfoot seems to be
the most cited of the creatures, but the UFO phenomenon is ramping up more and more and more
people are seeing this. And so eventually, you know, they've got to get on top of the story
is kind of the narrative that we hear a lot is that it the, because of the cell phones,
because of the tick tock videos, because of all these things, more and more is coming out
every single day. And eventually it's going to be undeniable. And sort of this fake history that
we've all been taught. Someone's got to tell us, you know, the new fake history, I guess you could
say like the aliens seated us on this planet, you know, and they're the ones who did it all. And
it kind of feels like we're, we're being built up to something like that, some sort of ultimate
reveal, some sort of close encounter where it finally happens and everyone can see it.
There are a lot of channels like us who just trying to tell Christians like, Hey,
this stuff's been going on in the Bible since Genesis, wake up. You know, it's, it's right
there in the pages. The weird stuff happened. We had encounters with, with angelic realms. They
came in, they messed with us, they gave us technology. And it's like, it's crazy how many
people just don't know this. They've been going to church their whole life and they're like, man,
you know, like we bring on a doctor, he talks about Genesis six and some of the weird,
weirder passages of scripture. And then all of a sudden they're like, I'm in, I get it.
It makes sense. You know, it's not hard. And so what do you think was the moment for you when you
were, you, you weren't a skeptic anymore. You, you believed you knew something was going on,
something changed. Like you sort of had your epiphany, I guess.
Yeah. Okay. So that's why I'm really always tolerant of people because of my own history.
Right? So as a child, I was, I had super, I had experiences of things and I was a believer,
right? Complete believer in the supernatural aspects of religion, which is by the way,
ironically, why I wanted to study religion. And then when I became a graduate student,
I mean, that's a very intense training that you go through. And I started to study it from
a distance, right? It was an evolution that I never acknowledged. It just literally happens
to a person because you're so immersed in communities of like-minded believers. Like
they believe what you're, you know, they're being taught what you're being taught. We all are on,
it's almost like you share their frequency. And so when something weird happens, you don't even see
it because you're not trained to see it. And then what happened was it was, it hit me so hard in one
weekend that what I had been studying my whole life from a distance was actually real because
I heard these people talking about it. And then I, then this happened to me and then this happened
to me. And I was like, Whoa, wait, wait. So I went back and I looked at some of the major,
what I call contact events in Catholic history, where literally people are being
absconded by angels. And I read the original sources. So I looked at them in their original
languages and they didn't look at all like how they'd been represented in art. So we tend to
look at the art and we're like, Oh yeah, that looks pretty, right? This angel encounter looks
really nice. Well, this angel is beating the heck out of this person, you know, it's like,
or this or that is happening. And I was like, wow, no way. And I just went back and said,
this all happened in 2012 during a whole weekend. And it, it, it stayed with me for a whole year,
this feeling of being disoriented because of this. Now, strangely enough,
I was working with these two screenwriters who were the, they're Christians, this Chad Hayes
and Carrie Hayes, and they were the screenwriters for the Conjuring. And I was, I was actually a
consultant on the first Conjuring, the movie. And so I was, and my expertise was in traditionalist
Catholicism, which is what Ed and Lorraine Warren were, you know, they were traditionalist Catholics
who believed in demons and they were helping people get rid of, you know, they were exercising
people, helping people. And so those guys who were from California, and I felt like,
kind of like akin to them, they were identical twins and they were like Christian and they really
wanted the Conjuring to come out with a very intense supernatural message. And in fact,
if you look at the last, you know, the quote that Ed Warren says in the last, in the Conjuring,
the first Conjuring, the last scene, you know, it's real, you know, it's real. The supernatural
is real and evil is real. Okay. So they were with me that whole time. They lived in Wilmington doing
the filming for the Conjuring. And so I had them to basically, they wanted to know, because they
could tell something was going on. And they said, what's going on with you? You know, are you going
through some kind of like research spiritual thing? And I said, yes, I am actually. And I told
them about the UFOs. And I said, I've become convinced about this and it's changed my whole
worldview. And so, so that's, they, some, they helped me through, you know, we helped each other
actually, because then I showed them what I was doing and I introduced them to some of the people.
And so this was my year. It wasn't a moment. It was a whole year in 2012 of waking back up
to the reason why I studied religion. That's basically what it was.
Was it, was there any, any moments where you getting outside of that? Like you felt like
maybe it challenged your conventional beliefs that were you, were your faith, were you like,
maybe question your faith and then how did you, how did you sort of traverse that?
Okay. So I never questioned my faith. It made me more faithful in fact, but what it did do is it
scared me a lot. And there was a point where I said, I'm not going to do this because I
perceived so much darkness, like so much darkness. I went to a, I went to a conference and this
conference now in retrospect was, it was a conference with CIA. It had some CIA affiliations.
Yeah. And the people there, you know, there were people who believed they were hybrids and things
like that and everything like that. I wasn't, it wasn't that it was the ideas in the conference
that were so challenging to me. And this sounds very strange, but I'm just going to tell you how
it felt. I felt the dark. I felt darkness. It wasn't that the ideas were dark. I literally felt
it. And after that, I said, I'm not going to do this anymore. This is very bad. It's very negative.
And then your amongst your amongst friends here that says that doesn't surprise us too.
Yeah, it was like harsh. It was like, this is really negative stuff and I'm,
I don't want to bring that into my life, but I was, so there were, there were enough good people
who to kind of are in my position who were doing kind of similar things that they kind of helped
me come back to why this is important to do right now and why, in fact, I get, I was harassed. I get
a lot of harassment. I've, you know, a lot of times I, Gary and I both were harassed and we
reported this to, he reported it to the Stanford police, you know, university police, and I reported
it to my university police. I'm meeting with a detective this week tomorrow, in fact, about it.
So it's not like you can just go out there and do this research and not and think that, oh yeah,
it's going to be all fun. It's not, it's, I don't know why people are doing this, but I do know that
if they're doing it, there's a reason for it. There's, you know, so I have a follow-up question
to that because something I wanted to, because I think this actually fits into that, but you talked
about all the aerospace stuff, right? And the space programs and the ritualistic basis on that
in your research, do you believe that those institutions or people within those institutions
believe that they are getting information from ETs or, you know, what we would assume to be maybe
like even demonic stuff, like they are, because there's that thought too that like, and I know
that something that you talked about with Tyler was that he believed that he had this extraterrestrial
knowledge downloaded to him. And when I hear that, to me, it sounds like you're kind of accessing
the spiritual realm. And of course, this is not a new thing. This is as old as Solomon said,
nothing's newer than the sun. But the fact that some of these things are based on ritual,
it just got me thinking, like, how much did you run into that where either the technology
or the ideas and the idea of technology as well was coming from somewhere else? Like, or,
I mean, I don't know. I'm just, that just was something that-
Yeah, yeah. Well, I think this is an ongoing question. Okay. Definitely many people that I
met who were within those programs that we talked about, believe that they were in touch with ET
presences, just like Konstantin, Konstantin Tchaikovsky from Russia believed that he was,
but he thought that they were angelic. Jack Parsons did, but he thought that they he didn't
know what the heck they were, frankly. And, but they looked pretty evil to me. Like, I thought
his whole program was pretty twisted. It was Babylon workings, right? It was all, it was really
like gnarly mystery school, satanic stuff. Oh, it definitely was, but it was efficacious in the sense
that it definitely got us off of earth into space. You know, it did work, I guess is, you know,
for better or worse, I suppose. But- Sounds a lot like, sounds a lot like Gen 6 though.
Sounds a lot like the trading of technology and ideas for, in that case, women, right? It's the
idea that there's this transfer of knowledge, you know, if you ascribe or you look into Enoch,
right? And you talk, which is, you know, just a big exposition on Genesis 6, there's the idea that
all of the Watchers taught humans how to cut roots and practice magic. It was all technology. It was
learning the father of animal husbandry and all, you know, all these things that all of a sudden
you have the explosion of technology. So that's what I hear in the space too, is like that they're
tapping, they're getting, they're getting knowledge from something else. Yes. So I mean, yeah,
in the introduction to my book, I basically said that there's a myth of Prometheus, right? Which
is the giver of technology to humans. And he's kind of an, he gets punished for it by the gods,
right? So he's not a god, he's a half god. And he's a Titan. And he's like this, you know, he's the
one who gives technology to humans. So it's not, it's a, it's a myth that's been around, but it's
no longer mythological. When we get into my book, you know, it appears to be a reality is what I was
trying to say was that how do I talk about this academically when the people that I'm interviewing
believe that they're getting technology literally from, you know, ET or some external source.
And I, there were various ways of doing that. One was to talk about creativity and what that does
and that possibly makes your brain think that you're actually getting it from an external
source, but you're actually in a certain state of vibration in your brain. So, you know, there's
lots of different, there are different frameworks, not lots, but there are different frameworks for
looking at this. And a lot of people go with the literal framework of, you know, this is a living
myth, this is not a myth, actually, this is real kind of thing, like Tyler does in my book. And a
lot of the scientists do, they're more literally minded than people in the humanities, I guess.
Okay, but let's get back to this idea of feeling that the darkness of this. So,
you know, when you look at Werner von Braun, right, and you look at his, how he created his
technologies, we have to acknowledge that he had a concentration camp, you know, where people,
there were more people who were killed in the creation of his technologies than actually by
the weapons that came out of his technologies. I mean, could anything good come from that kind of
creation, you know, where people are literally slaves?
Sounds like a ritual too, like you're, it's the letting of blood, it's a sacrifice.
In a macro form, it's a human sacrifice, right? It's, which is really crazy to think about.
It's absolutely true. Yeah. So again, in my field, we talk about ritual studies, and there is
Ren Girard is, I don't know if you know the work of Ren Girard, but he basically makes the case
that, you know, religion came up, especially he's Christians, he's Catholic, and he basically said
that Christianity is the religion that recognized that all human progression seemed to happen from
sacrifices, from, you know, ritual sacrifices. And he said Christianity was the one that basically
said, let's make this the last sacrifice, let's make Jesus the last sacrifice, and then acknowledge
our innate desire to kill each other over things, you know, over basically scarce resources.
Yeah, I mean, I, you know, did the space program, I don't know. That's a lot of stuff that you'd
have to like look into. Yeah. But I can say that all of that stuff is quite disturbing, you know,
and that these are the kinds of things that I worked with when I was writing that book.
And I ended in a pretty negative, like, I wouldn't say I was optimistic at the end of that book.
In fact, I ended it with Martin Heidegger's idea that only a god can save us now.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, yeah. Luke and I talk a lot of off show about how dark it gets on our show,
just people coming on and sharing their stories. And then it's funny, we were talking in the day
about, man, the last couple of episodes have been dark. And then we get an email from one of the,
our recurring guests who says that she has somebody who's been, came out of the occult,
was, was, was a satanic ritual abuse survivor and wants to come on the show, but we have to
disguise her voice and all this different stuff. And it's like, wow, we were just talking about
this loop. I was just telling Nate, I was like, I can't do any more heavy episodes for a while.
Cause it's just, it's a lot. I mean, it's a lot. It is. It's heavy. You know, in the art of war,
you need to know your enemy. And so part of, of us being Christians in, in, in understanding
the gospel is understanding that we're also at war. We are, we are caught up in a cosmic war.
You know, we're not fascinated by the darkness, but we want to expose it. We, people need to be
aware. It doesn't serve anyone to put your head in the sand or you're obviously there. You wrote
a whole book on, on traversing the space and yeah, it gets heavy. Nate's, Nate made a great point.
Like, and you, I can see it through, you know, six years of studying this, you ran in some,
as you say, very dark places.
Well, what I think is the one thing that I've learned a lot in the show is just how many people
have carried these burdens, these supernatural burdens, I would, I would say, or something
like that where they don't understand why would God flood the world? You know, they've carried
these, these they believed, but they haven't believed with their whole heart because they've
questioned the Old Testament, a lot of things in the Old Testament, which are very blurry,
like why, what was going on then? And then when you just, when you, when you work backwards from
like some of these creatures that people see today, and it goes all the way back to the
corruption of all creatures, you go, Oh, okay. So there's, there's been this occult stuff that's
been going on forever. It's not a new thing. The scientists in NASA are doing occult practices.
They were doing this all over the world. They were building the same pyramidal structures
everywhere. They were all worshiping their gods. What happened the last 300 years where we all
just put our heads in the sand and we're like, we were trying to analyze the world inside the
matrix and it doesn't make any sense. It's like, well, yeah, but then somebody will get pulled out
of the matrix and everyone gets pulled out in a different way. And they see something or they
have an experience and they come out of it and they go, wow, everybody is clueless. The hardest
part is the church is clueless, but then you plug in some of these, these things we've discovered
on our show, like Genesis six and such. And then you can, you, you let those burns go like, Oh,
now I get why God needed to flood the world. Human beings were almost went extinct. If you,
if you take it literal, you know, and, and we try to apply the scientific method on our show,
we don't, we like, when you say the myth of Prometheus, I almost wonder if like,
I, I, I, I'm going to the belief now that those people that those stories were real,
they just preserve them in a, in a way that we can understand them throughout time. But I,
it seems as though those demigods fits right into the Nephilim walks the earth at one point.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, that's what I was doing. I was trying to open it up from
what we consider to be a myth to, I am now in this Smith. That's what I say in my introduction.
I am now in this Smith and I'm going to write this book from being within it and deal with it.
Academics, you know, because this is it. You were, you said you were, you were reading about these,
these, these original Catholic miracles, right? The, or these, these. Yes. Yes. Did you find
anything crazy in, in, in the Vatican archives? Did you get, did you come? Yes. Yeah. Tell us
because this is. Yeah. I mean, you think. It's a whole, yeah, it's a whole treasure trove of
blurry creatures. Yeah. That's what we're talking about. Yeah. Miles and miles and miles. So I saw,
I mean, there were so many things I, we were there to do specific study of Joseph of Copertino,
who is a Saint who is said to have flown around, right? Levitated and a lot of UFO abductions have
levitation aspects to them, right? People are levitating up and doing this. I posted on my
Twitter account, a picture of people going into purgatory and it literally looks like a flying
saucer, beaming people up into it. Right. So I wanted people to see that these images were,
are so similar and these representations are similar. The interpretations are just different.
You know, they call them souls from purgatory. Then we call them UFOs now kinds of things like
that. Right. In the Vatican archive, we came across a lot of things. We came across a woman who's
called the woman in blue. She lived in the 1600s in Spain and she believes that she was being taken
by angels kind of flown up above earth into space where she could see the spinning earth. And she
described it and taken to what she called the new world, which was basically New Mexico and around
that, this, the Southwest, Arizona, all these areas. And she was put down and then she actually
interacted with indigenous tribes there. And in fact, one of the leaders, the chief of that
indigenous tribe just called me the other day and I have to return his phone call because he said,
come on, tell me about the lady in blue. Like we really want to know because they have statues of
her and their whole oral tradition goes back to this time period. So there were missionaries from
Spain who happened that they were evangelizing. Right. And so they happened upon this indigenous
tribe who already knew the gospel already knew that Jesus's name already knew all of these things.
They were like, how did you know, you know, and they said, this lady came, you know, and they were
like, what did she look like? And so it, so this is a, so we came upon her records and looked at
her records and then my whole episode itself. It was crazy. So I, I had already, I thought I'd
finished my book, but I turned it into my editor. And then once I saw this stuff, I realized I opened
my book with going to New Mexico to this specific place. And I recognized that this sister or none
believed that she had been at this place that I had been to too, with this guy, Tyler, who I was
now at the Vatican Observatory with reading this woman's documents. It was pretty weird.
And so, I mean, how much of that stuff is under lock and key though?
Oh yeah. You have to have special credentials to get in. It's not something you can't get.
Did you see anything about the Nephilim in there or any of that kind of stuff? Or was it?
There's a lot of stuff like that. Yeah. I mean, the thing is, is that you have to understand a
lot of people think that the Catholic, okay. So for one thing, I'm a, I'm a Catholic. I'm a
historian of Catholic thought. I'm Catholic. I was let in because that's what I do. And I
have a PhD. You have to go through a whole series of checkpoints in order to get in.
Okay. So yeah, it is under lock and key and barely anybody could get in there to read these
documents. These documents are really old. Some of them would disintegrate, right? If you touch
them. So you have to be careful with them. The thing is about it is this, and this is to stop
any kind of conspiracy theory about Catholicism and Catholics. Like the Vatican is trying to
hide the truth about them. They know what they have. They know that they're weird.
They look at it within their theological worldview that this, these beings existed
or exist. And that's okay. That God created everything, right? And that these beings are
just part of God's creation. And they don't view them as like, you know, that they're trying to
keep the world from knowing about, you know, these beings, these, you know, the thing is,
is that those, the Catholics right now at the Vatican are doing their hardest right now,
their darnedest to basically digitize those documents because those documents are basically
going away. Like they're disintegrating. Yeah, they really are. Yeah.
What do the Vatican think about, what do they, what do they think about your project?
Did you get any resistance talking about UFOs and then writing a book about you?
No, no, not at all. No, I have a lot of friends at the Vatican and a colleague is brother Guy
Consolwanyo, who's the director of the Vatican Observatory. In fact, we were given quarters at
the Vatican Observatory to stay. So we lived in those quarters for like a week to do our research.
We were given lattes and I mean, it's pretty awesome. I actually lost an original Kepler,
an original book by Kepler. Yeah. So they were, they basically look,
they probably changed the rules after I was there because I went there and I'm like,
they go, yeah, just look at whatever you want, you know? And I was like, are you sure? And they're
like, okay. So I did. I looked at everything. I'm like, okay, they have a whole wall of something
that's called extraterrestrial research, research into extraterrestrials. And I was like, I'm starting
here. And so, you know, you go through the whole thing, every single day we wake up and we go in
there and we wouldn't leave except for like a latte, right? Or like, you know, or lunch or
something like that. And we go right back. It was awesome. And we go right back and we do the study
again. And so I kept a lot of the books out. One of them was Kepler, you know? And for some reason,
this was really fascinating to me because he was talking about magnetism and a lot of these kinds
of things. And sadly, I misplaced that book. And so when I got back to the United States,
I got a frantic email from Brother Guy and he said, do you know where the Kepler is? You know,
it's priceless, right? And I'm like, oh gosh. Wow. No, I actually remembered, believe it or not,
where I put it. And I said, yes, I do. I do. And they probably, like I said, changed the rules
after that. I felt really bad about it. So what, I mean, what did you read in there?
Because, I mean, it's difficult because I feel like something that we talk about on our show a
lot and it gets heated in our channels. It's just like every institution is compromised somewhere,
every institution. It's not just like, oh, this institution is good. This institution is bad.
It's just like, there's, there's good cop, bad cop and everything. And so it's hard to identify
because like some of the things you said earlier in the episode, and that's a whole nother rabbit
hole. They're just like, when spiritual entities appear to you and tell you something, and there's
a lot of historical accounts, I mean, how do you know which team they're on? You know, and you don't
and you don't know. It's not that we don't believe it exists. It's just, how do you not be deceived?
And so, but in terms of the Vatican, we've never really talked to anybody who's been inside of it.
And we know they have answers, but there's got to be some people in there that are probably not
wanting certain things to get out. I mean, it can't be like a hundred percent across the board.
Everyone's, well, there's a lot of people who, who are angry at Catholics and the Vatican for
good reasons. You know, I mean, the, the, you know, the priestly pedophile thing, all that kind of
stuff, terrible, right? And the whole, you know, it's been around for a long time. The Vatican was
the Roman Empire. I mean, it became the, the, you know, Roman Catholic Empire. I mean, it's like,
when you go through Rome and you look at the, and you go into the Vatican and you go through
their museum and everything, you basically see a history of colonization and war. And that wasn't
pretty for me to watch or see, you know, it was a lot of carnage. Okay. And, you know, taking of
other culture stuff. So yeah, so we're talking about an empire, not just a religion. Okay. So
I talked to Peter Gumpel, who some of your listeners should check out. He's super interesting.
He is in his nineties and he was, he was supposed to be a Cardinal, but he didn't want to be because
he enjoyed being, he was a Jesuit and lives in the Vatican. And basically he is, he reminded me of
Tyler because he had several, he had rules that were very much like Tyler's where he couldn't go
online. He doesn't have email. He couldn't see the news. You know, he had to keep his, his own
worldview separate from the world's because you have to understand that they're taking their faith
seriously. Christians are in, but of, but not of the world. So, right. So that's where that's how
they live. They believe that they're in the world, but they're not part of the world, right? The world
lives with different values than like Father Gumpel. Now, does that mean that everyone at
the Vatican is like that? No, there's like such corrupt people there, but he wasn't one of them.
And so, you know, I, I did my best to find those people and to talk to them. And he was a papal
advisor to the last, how many popes, you know, as long as he's been 30 years old, he was almost
killed by Hitler. His nephew was killed by Hitler. His mother was almost killed by Hitler.
He intervened to, to save her. So, you know, he's like, he knows so much history. What does he think
about UFOs? What do they think about? There's a great book by brother Guy Consulmano and his
friend who's a Jesuit, who's a father Mueller, and it's called, would you baptize an extraterrestrial?
Would the Pope baptize an extraterrestrial? And that goes along and talks about the whole history
of extraterrestrial belief within the Catholic church, basically. So to them, it's not as big a
deal as it is to people in the United States, because people have been talking about extraterrestrials
in religions for a very long period of time, right? Just like you all say, you know, that it's back
there in the Bible. I mean, brother Guy says, look, you know, just look through the Bible and
you'll see reference to beings from other places in planetary intelligences and things like that.
So it's different terms now, right? Like, I mean, literally like angels,
extraterrestrials means not of earth. And so we can think of semantics, which I think is interesting
the way, but it's manipulated though, which is very interesting. That's how in most people's minds,
those are very different things. Yeah, in most people's minds, they're very different things.
But if you look at the history of Catholicism and you look at like, especially people in the Vatican,
they know about Emanuel Swedenborg, who's talking about angels and people on Venus and things like
this in 1750, right? In 1750, there was a bestselling book called Life on Other Planets.
Wow. Well, it's just like, it's like the whole, it's, I think it's why there's so much traction
with ancient alien theory is that it just takes all of that and puts it in an alien bucket and then
just says, oh yeah, aliens did this. Aliens came here. Aliens did that. And it's like,
if you described what people will do, that's not, that's not how you would interpret it.
Like it would be. No, no, no. So the Vatican doesn't, this is what they don't want.
They don't want, and this has happened in the ufology community a lot. A lot of people who are
what I would call UFO influencers, they're not necessarily researchers, but they're influencers.
And they, they like to talk about the Vatican a lot and they say, we're going to go to the Vatican
and we're going to bust open, you know, this thing. Well, guess what? They're not, they're on
the outskirts of the Vatican. Like anybody who's been in the Vatican knows you can't just go into
the Vatican. The guards are different. Like, you know how the guards look really nice on the outside?
The Swiss guards, right. They have special uniforms and everything. When you get in the Vatican,
they're actually scary as heck. I mean, these people have like machine guns and they're wearing
full fatigues and you don't go anywhere unless you have, you're with someone in the Vatican.
It's wild. Like I was like, you know, I was terrified of these guys.
Yeah. I was lucky to go there. I went there and went to St. Peter's and went around, went
to the Sistine Chapel and it was definitely, it was, no, I mean, it was, it was an experience.
I just remember being like, well, there was a lot of people there trying to,
trying to sell you something. They were trying to convince you, trying to sell you tickets to
something that was free. That's what I noticed right away is everyone's trying to like, wait a
minute, that's free. I know that's free, buddy. It's difficult. It was just, but everything's
so amazingly old. I think that is sometimes on our show, obviously, yeah, the Vatican does get,
it sort of gets just, everything's blamed on the Vatican. Why isn't here? It's, it's at the Vatican.
And I do think that, like I said earlier, there's just, there's so many people that have infiltrated
all these systems and they all have their own agenda and it's, you can't, it's not, there's,
nothing is easy. Nothing is as easy as a lot of the people listening to our show. It's this easy.
It's just this one deception. I'm like, no, it's not. It's very complicated. Satan's not going to
leave any crumb trail if he doesn't have to. And I just can't get, I just can't get past, Nate,
that there's a whole wall, Diana, that you said that was going to ask her that dude, this is insane.
Yeah. Give us a little rundown. What are some of the talking points to that? What was some of the
Yeah. Yeah. So in the extraterrestrial research part of the archive, this is at the observatory
because all the, anything that has to do with space doesn't go to the Vatican archive. It goes
to the observatory, which is in Castle Gandolfo. And that's a space observatory. And so, so basically
they just had from back in the day, you know, from like 1200 onward, what people have thought about
and published about extraterrestrials. And so when they get, when you get into the seventies
and when you get like the sixties and the seventies and eighties, it just took off and it got super
interesting. And I could, I didn't have enough time to go through everything, but what I noticed
was that the terminology changed. So when you, and this is another way to do archival research is
that you don't just look at what's in there. You look at how things are categorized. All right.
And if, and if there's a shift in the way things are categorized, you know that something happened.
So I wasn't there long enough to figure this out, but I did have Tyler with me and Tyler was part of
the U S space program. So he was able to fill in some of these blanks. But what I found was that
when they got to the eighties and certain space missions, they stopped, they were actually funding
programs that were in search of intelligent extraterrestrial life. Right. But yeah. But after
that, they stopped funding that and they started to search. They did microbiology. Like they wanted
to find like, you know, traces of biological things. Like bacteria meteors and stuff. Yeah.
Yeah. They weren't looking for it. They took out intelligence.
And I was like, why did they do that? That was after the Apollo, one of the Apollo missions.
And so that's what Tyler looked at me and said, think about that. Yeah.
Maybe they got the question answered. Yeah. Yeah. So the funding and the funding for the
research changed. Absolutely. Yeah. But they tell you, you know, these, these things you can't talk
about or you had free access to write about whatever you, you found. There were certain
times when I was told to not talk about certain things and in no uncertain terms, basically,
like sounds like fight club fight club thing going on here. Talk about it. Right. And I,
I didn't. And then what happened was that all of this stuff happened where the government started
talk about it and all of those things changed and nobody told me to not talk about it anymore. So
I'm talking about, except for referencing people who want to be anonymous, I'm talking about all
kinds of things that I was told not to talk about. And what do you think aliens and UFOs are? I mean,
what's your, what's your take if you had? Yeah, sure. So I think that people have been seeing
things in the sky for a very long period of time, as long as humans have existed, it appears that
they've been having these experiences. I don't discount these experiences. I believe that people
have them, what they are. I have a professorly view and then I have a personal view and I
separate those. So my university won't, you know, so I can say this has nothing to do with my
colleagues or my graduate student professors. Yeah. Yeah. I do think that there are,
which is very fight club. Yeah. I'm not in flight club. I'm not. Yeah. So I'm just a professor.
I'm not bound by those rules. So I think that there are a variety of these things.
And I do believe that we can like, you know, I do believe in these angelic presences and I also
believe in demonic presences. I feel like I felt these before. This is me not as a professor talking.
Okay. So this is just as a human being and being alive and having these experiences. I've always
wanted to know what they were about. I feel like I know I have a better understanding of what they're
about now. I feel like we make choices in our lives to open us up to various experiences.
And I think that I've, I know people who've had very bad experiences, either drinking a lot or
doing drugs and feeling these, feeling these things, you know, these presences or whatnot,
and even without those, you know, and I feel that I try not to go to places that where UFO activity
is identified. I do not call any type. I'm not a CE5 person, you know, a close encounters five
person. I don't want to be, I don't want to hook in with any other, you know, I, I just don't want
to do that. I don't want to advocate that to anyone. And I believe that, I believe that human
beings are made to, like we have kind of like a, some people would call it a God gene. I think we
have a predisposition to want to, to know about the spiritual component. You could call it God,
Jesus, whatever you're, you know, right. So I believe in that. And I believe that people,
if they want, can, can do that. I also have been studying the protocols that people have done,
like monastic communities, communities of monks and nuns, and, and the ways in which they've
cultivated having experiences of peace and love and goodness and things like that, what you would
call, you know, God and prayer and contemplative prayer and things like that. So I think that these
things are very real. I think some of them perhaps could be extraterrestrial. I do believe that some
of them are interdimensional. So yeah, I believe in a variety of different ones.
Yeah. It seems like it gets more complicated the more, the more we rocks we turn over and the more
things we find. And it's not easy. It's not an easy answer. You know, I think a lot of people want an
easy answer to a lot of these complicated topics. And it's, it's just not, I mean, it's just human
beings have been given a little bit of information, but we haven't given enough. We've almost been
given enough information just to carry on. And we're so, we're so curious. Yeah. The fact that
these sightings do go back and the alien, the alien encounters do go back. And I'm surprised as
that there have been more academics involved in this topic than I originally thought when we
started the show. It seems like when you go there, there, there are always a few outliers of people
who, you know, apply the scientific method to these blurry topics and, and found some interesting
stuff. And I didn't know that there was an archive in the, uh, the Vatican. I've got, I've got one
last question here because I'm curious, do you, having studied the UFO phenomena and then also
having sort of laid that over a religious infrastructure, because that's, that's where
that's where your expertise is and your study is. Most UFO people probably don't describe to
religious beliefs per se. Like you talked about, there's a lot of, like it or not, there's a lot of
spiritual supernatural element to this stuff. There's probably, there's a very physical aspect
to a lot of people's experiences and to, there's also a very supernatural. So do you think that
there is the UFO in, in this UFO religious space, as you might define it, do you think that they are,
there is a, like almost a come to Jesus moment that could be waiting at the end of that as
people dive deeper into, into this. And then the reason, the reason, yeah, okay. The reason I asked
this is we've, we've talked about this before, Nate, about how in certain communities, and this
is in different, not the UFO, but maybe in the Bigfoot community. And I believe this was Duke
and I brought this up on another episode, but I think it's fascinating that people that have
encounters, according to some of the people that are doing the research, Bigfoot encounters that
a very, a significant portion of those people get saved, which is a really interesting,
like reaction to having an encounter. And so my question then is, do you think that for a lot
of these people that could end up with, you know, finding their answers in sort of a come to Jesus
moment? Yeah. So my, one of the things that I do is I look at people like classic examples of UFO
events, right? And I think we could all agree that Kenneth Arnold's 1947, you know, where he's a
pilot and he's going over a mountain Rainier and he is the envy, we get the term flying saucer from
this encounter that he has. So he has, he's a pilot, he is a smart engineered guy. And his
identifying these things and people calling them flying saucers, he called them flying plates,
right? They look like flying plates. We all think that's a nuts and bolts kind of, you know,
spacecraft type thing, right? But if you actually go back and you look at what happens to him after
his encounter, you realize that he's, he describes these things as beings, as like living things.
He also says that he thinks that they're like Ezekiel's wheel. And he also begins to make these
prayer cards, like any Christian would know what a prayer card was, right? So he, he has the picture
of the flying saucer and on the back of it, he has his philosophy where he identifies this as
spiritual and he gives it to anybody who he, he meets. He says, have you heard of this? And he
gives it to them because he's become evangelical about his spiritual experience of having a UFO.
So my point is this, is that I'm not overlaying a religious framework on UFOs. What I'm doing
is I'm looking case by case at UFO events and I'm saying, this looks weirder than you think,
everyone. Like this is a paranormal event. This is not just a nuts and bolts craft. You know,
you can have all these, you know, pilots in the sky and like, you know, saying, oh, this and that's
happening and we take, and, but, you know, you go to the very first pilot in the sky and he's freaking
out because now he's had this experience that leads him back to the Bible. And I would, I'd
love to ask you, like, my last question is like, is there a story in your life where you've had
it like a skeptical colleague or someone in your life that has, you know, you've had a conversation
with and they've come full circle? Yes. Yeah. Yeah. Can you talk and tell about that a little bit?
Yes. So this was actually a colleague of mine who you would think shouldn't be skeptical because
he's at Rice University and his name is Jeff Kripal and he's a friend of mine. And at the
beginning, this was in 2012 when I had just written my book about purgatory and he was
blurbing it. I met him through my, he's in my field. He does religious studies
and his background is similar to mine. He was, he wanted to be a monk and then he kind of ended
up at University of Chicago in religious studies. Okay. So he's going to blurb my book on purgatory
and we both know people in the UFO scene, right? And I start to tell him about my experiences
and he thinks it's really interesting, but he doesn't buy, he buys that UFOs happen,
but he doesn't associate them with our tradition of Catholicism at all. He doesn't. And so I say,
wait a minute. He did his master's thesis on Teresa of Avila, who has had what looks like
a classic kind of abduction experience, right? That's made into, if you've been to Rome,
you may have seen the statue of Bernini statue of Teresa. It's called the ecstasy of St. Teresa.
And you see this angel kind of with a dart that's going like this to her. And it looks like a
chara, but if you read the original account, so when I had my experience of that weekend,
I looked back at hers and I reread her account of it cause she wrote it down in her diary and
I subsequently had published about it and I read it and I said, my goodness, like she's having this
experience that John Mack talks about in his book. So I wrote to Jeff and I said, Jeff, look,
you know, Teresa had this experience. He said, no, no, no, no. He said, she didn't Diana. He said,
that's Freudian. That's all like Freudian and clearly nothing to do with UFOs.
And so I, I did a translation where I, I kind of emphasized like that this being was, she really
saw it. It was short. It wasn't like a big angel. It didn't have wings. It had a dart, which she,
which, you know, did like the examination on her and everything like that. And I sent it back to
him and it freaked him out. He was like, Oh my gosh. He said, it's, it's like UFOs all the way
down. That's wild. Yeah. Yeah. It's hard. I mean, it's, it's, and it feels like that's to me,
some of the extent of the, the, the way that religions and the Bible is taught is, is it's
like all that stuff is edited out of the story. All those characters are omitted. So we're all
kind of confused. And then eventually if we take some of the like verses in Matthew 23, Jesus says,
you know, like the days of Noah, when I'm going to come back, I mean, what does that mean? It
feels like those realms that were once interacting with human beings. You know, we, we didn't have
this problem of disbelief. We didn't have this problem of, Oh, I don't believe in any of that
stuff. You know, I don't believe in creatures. I don't believe in UFOs. And it was, it was more
like, which side are you on, you know, in ancient history. And then, and then we've kind of gone to
this, this, this era where we spend all our time debating if these things are happening. And then,
right. And it's, it's such a waste of time because once you get out of that and you realize, man,
this phenomenon is not just in one of these camps, there's so many camps of weird stuff happening.
And we have to spend some time actually figuring out like, what is going on? Because
clearly there's going to be a deception. Like you said, you didn't end your book with like
positive note because it sounds like what you hear is what we hear is like, it's going to, to be such
a grin, a mine grenade on too many people at once where people aren't going to know what to think.
Because the church is in educating people as a whole. There are some churches that talk about
the weird stuff, but as a whole, most people have no idea that our government's trickling this out,
that there's this ancient history you don't know. And, you know, a lot of this stuff is undercover.
So I guess we try to be hope dealers on the show and say, you know, this is why you need,
this is why you need a savior. This is why the son of God came to save you, because this, this
kingdom of darkness is deceptive. It's big. It's, it's gnarly. So we try to talk about that a lot
on our show and it's really encouraged my faith. It's just like, yeah, you know, I do need a savior.
I do need someone to put my hope in. It sounds like some of your colleagues are coming around
when you're, when you're shooting them over some info. They've come around a lot of people. I was,
I honestly thought maybe 10 people would read my book, but it seems like it resonates with a lot
of people. And people do want to know, and they are wake, there are wake, you know, I hate to use
that term waking up, but yeah, they are waking up to the fact that just, that is supernatural.
And as much as the, and that the people who are most angry are the people who want it to be
spaceships, you know, with technology, they don't want the supernatural stuff because it's too weird
for them. But, you know, it's like, you have to go where the data takes you. Yeah. I mean,
that's the same thing. We thought 10 people will listen to our podcast. Yeah. I was going to say
the same thing. Nate and I are just going to do this because we like to have a good time and talk
to each other. Right. Yeah. But, and then, yeah, we, we, we hit some of these charts and I'm like,
oh no, this is crazy. I don't know if I want it to get any bigger. No, I know. I know that feeling.
It's like, whoa, we get trolled. Yeah. A lot of people troll us and a lot of people from different
camps and everyone has their, you know, like I was saying, I don't pick on the flat earthers,
but you know, they love our show and they listen to our show and they really, really want us to get
into these, these areas. And we're, we're talking creatures, you know, where that's the fences we
put up on this show. And sometimes we get out of those lanes, something like a big foot encounter
can bring you, can bring your faithful circle. You can, it's almost like it, it's not related,
but it is related. It gives you permission to believe all the strange stuff. Right. And,
and I love all the academics who are giving people permission in these spaces. Hey,
you can believe the weird stuff. It's everywhere. It's out there. And there's metrics for it. I think
that's the other thing. It's important, right? That's right. Yeah. Yeah. Well, Diana, it's been,
it's been a pleasure. Yeah. Do you want to? Yes, it has. Thank you so much. Thanks so much. And
do you want to tell people where they can, they can find your work or, and the stuff you're doing?
Well, I do have an, an Amazon author page and all my books are there. I have a lot of free stuff
that's on academia, edu, and people can look at that too. And it talks a lot about how technology
and us interface, you know, and what that means for the way that we believe stuff. But yeah. Oh,
and I have a Twitter account that's, um, I try to stay off of a lot of social media because of the,
the trolling that goes on, you know, it's just not good for anyone. Yeah. But I do have a Twitter
account, D W Pasolka. And, um, I post stuff there and there are a lot of supportive people there
too. So, yeah. Well, if you ever want to come back and do like a deep dive on the Vatican.
Oh, I will. Yeah, absolutely. That would be fun. Cause yeah, I feel like it's, it's shrouded in
mystery a lot. We're, we're trying to get someone who knows a lot about the Vatican and someone
who's been inside the Smithsonian knows a lot about that, that, that institution as well.
If you know anybody who's willing to spill the secrets on the Smithsonian, we'd love them.
Oh, that would be a good one. I'll get one of my colleagues who does that and I'll do the Vatican
and he or she could do the Smithsonian. That would be a cool show. Disguise your voices,
who you are so we can tell all the secrets. Yeah, exactly. We're always trying to figure out what's
going on in the, in the blurry, the blurry versus what we call it. Oh, that's cool. I like that.
We're grateful for your time and you know, you have, you have five teenagers. So, um,
we know you're Andrew, the chair, your, your academic chair of your department and you're
writing books. So grateful spending a couple, you know, spend some good time here with a couple
knuckleheads and just, just want to ask questions. Thank you. And so, yeah, everybody check,
go check out American Cosmic. Uh, big shout out to Matt Maher, uh, who recommended we reach out to
you and, uh, and actually did, did some show notes for this. So Matt, you're, you're appreciated.
Oh, cool. Yeah. But we, uh, now we're, and my sister, Jim Davis alumni, Davis alumni.
That's right. Yeah. So we got North Cal here. Yep. Yeah. And, and thank you for praying for us.
And I don't know if that'll end up on the episode, but you know, cause we started,
I don't know if we'd start recording already or not, but appreciate that. And, uh, thank you for,
just thank you for, thank you for taking time as value and time is, is valuable and we just
appreciate your time. So, oh, absolutely. Yeah, absolutely. Take care. Thanks so much. Thanks,
guys. You bet. Take care. Good to meet you.