The Joe Rogan Experience, trained by day, Joe Rogan podcast by night, all day.
What's up?
How are you, man?
Hey, good.
Good.
Thanks for coming here.
Appreciate it.
Yeah.
No, it's a pleasure.
You've been on a whirlwind sort of tour.
I guess we should start from the beginning.
Yeah.
Well, first of all, lay out to people what your job was with the military and how this
all started for you.
Yeah.
So I was an Intel officer in the Air Force for 14 years, seven active, seven reserve.
Then I kind of had like a parallel track in the civilian Intel world when I became a reservist.
And ultimately I got brought back in in civil service in a government way at the National
Geospatial Intelligence Agency.
A couple of years ago at a senior level, so I was a major in the Air Force in a GS-15
at NGA, which is like a full bird colonel equivalent civilian employee.
You know, I'm very humbled that I was able to kind of get that kind of job.
But my career mostly, I didn't even really think about this topic.
UFOs were not on my radar.
I wasn't really a believer.
I was agnostic about it.
Most of my career, I did a lot of behind the door, special access program, technical type
activities.
I was kind of a space intelligence expert, a cyber intel expert.
And like I said, this was not on my radar at all.
I would joke with my buddies because I used to handle the presidential daily brief for
the National Reconnaissance Office director in my military capacity as a reservist.
I was well clear to hundreds and hundreds of compartmented programs.
And, you know, the joke was like, when are we going to get the read on for the crazy
shit? And that never happens.
And I do remember that the day that I really can remember that I was like, huh, what's
with this UFO stuff?
I was briefing a senior person at the CIA into a couple hundred special access programs.
So I was at the headquarters at the agency.
And, you know, after the indoctrination, I was giving to the senior person, this person
who worked with Lou Elizondo previously was like, yeah, Dave, have you ever heard of this
guy, Lou Elizondo?
He's running some UFO program at the Pentagon.
We all think he's crazy.
And I'm like, I don't know who this guy, Lou Elizondo is.
And I don't know of any kind of UFO program.
So that sounds nuts to me.
But lo and behold, and that was like early 2017.
And lo and behold, in December 2017, that New York Times article came up with that named
the ATIP program and the OSAP program.
So Advanced Aerospace Weapons Systems Application Program and Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification
Program being the other acronym.
And I was like, holy shit.
Wait, that's that guy, Lou Elizondo that I heard about.
Oh, you know what?
I think I have heard of OSAP when I was a lieutenant.
I used to read these reports from the Defense Intelligence Agency on black holes and stuff.
And I was like, oh, that's like stupid.
Why is the DIA looking in the black holes?
Time warps.
It just didn't make any sense to me back in like 08, 09 when I was lieutenant.
And all of a sudden, I'm like, well, maybe there's something to this UFO thing.
I'm not saying I was like a believer either way on the subject, but this was a topic of
concern, apparently, for the Pentagon.
And in 2018, I started doing kind of what I call my open source literature review.
Like, let me spin myself up on this topic.
Watching Chris Mellon, Lou Elizondo, Leslie Keene, all these people talk about the subject.
And then, you know, just trying to understand.
So what is this with UFOs?
Has this been going on for a while?
The answer is yes.
Like Foo Fighters, sightings of weird stuff in antiquity, etc., which we can get into later.
But and so early 2019 comes along and my boss at the National Reconnaissance Office and kind
of my Air Force Major Capacity forwarded me an email from the what became stood up in
like, I guess it was 2018, which was the unidentified what was aerial now anonymous
Philometer Task Force, UAP Task Force.
So the UAP Task Force director sent my boss an email saying, hey, we're looking for a rep
to the task force.
And as like any good officer, I was like, well, I'll put it on my performance report.
Hey, I was on a task force and, you know, that would look good.
And I being well cleared and also bachelor's degree in physics, master's in intelligence
analysis, I'm like, you know, I'll figure out what the shit is.
It's either going to be weather shit.
Maybe it's an adversarial program.
Maybe it's like a U.S. program.
People are misidentifying on rare occasions.
So fuck it, I'll I'll go see where the data takes me.
And, you know, early 2019 or so, I joined the UAP Task Force.
And then. I started, you know, interviewing pilots, flag officers, you know, general officer
equivalent type Navy folks.
And, you know, they were seeing some really crazy shit and like a, you know, event that I
talked about previously publicly in a YouTube video on the Yes Theory channel.
You know, there was this one 30 year senior Navy officer that, you know, he was going to
work sober, no predisposition for fantasy, all that kind of stuff, because I interviewed the
individual for a couple of hours and he saw this, you know, crazy triangle hover over his
car going to work at a certain naval facility and it like blew his mind.
He was serious.
The paint on his car turned milky white after the incident.
So that's to me, that sounds like ionizing radiation.
So like ultraviolet, just like how your your headlights get all foggy over time.
If you park your car out in the sun, same phenomenon just happened, you know, within 24
hour period. And I'm like, whoa, if this is true and the oral testimony and, you know, crazy radar
data that I saw when I was on the task force, you know, stuff making turns, it didn't make any
sense. Well, holy shit.
What is this stuff that this anomaly with his paint is documented?
Is it photographs or?
Yes, I saw photographs. It was documented.
Yeah. And what is their conventional explanation?
I mean, based on what he described, something to rapidly ionize his paint like that within a day.
I don't I can't think of anything off the top of my head in terms of some conventional aerospace
technology. And and this was a certain facility in the continental U.S.
This is not overseas. So it's not like our adversaries flying some spooky thing in U.S.
airspace.
So this thing hovered over his car for how long?
Couple of minutes while he was traveling at about 60 miles an hour.
So it was pacing how far away from his vehicle.
It's probably a couple hundred feet in altitude.
It was less than a thousand feet, which is also bad because from an airspace perspective,
pilots would know this. Anything under a thousand feet?
No. Unless you get special clearance and you only do that over controlled airspace like a
military test ranges where people fly low and that kind of thing.
So is he on what kind of a highway is he on?
A conventional civilian civilian house.
So anyone could have been on it. Yes.
It just happened to be this guy.
Did he have any other experiences with this thing?
No, this was like a once in a lifetime thing.
He kept it to himself for a couple of years.
But then he asked for his name.
I don't know what he's OK.
That individual still on it's called Bob.
Yeah. But didn't we say to him, hey, Bob, what the fuck happened to your car?
You know, that's a good question.
I don't remember if people asked him about his car, so he took pride in his car.
So it actually was probably more upsetting to him personally.
What kind of car was it? It was like a Toyota or something.
OK. Yeah. So all of a sudden this Toyota is fucked.
Yeah. OK.
And so did he have to report this?
Is this something that he did not report it to my knowledge to anybody?
It wasn't until he reported it to us about five years later that it happened.
So are these kind of experiences
something that a lot of these pilots are embarrassed about discussing
or have apprehension about discussing because they could be ridiculed?
Yeah. A lot of people that are on flight status, they don't want to be sent to the site.
Right. You know, there's a whole aerospace physiology kind of empire in the military.
And if you're an operator or, you know, a guy,
missile missile key Turner, you're on what they call personal reliability program.
You're taking like, you know, Tylenol, you got to report it.
If you have a fever, you got to report it because you're, you know,
in control of nuclear weapons when you're on duty.
So. Right. Yeah.
And so this idea of being predisposed to fantasy,
that's also something that they
sort of talk to these people about or try to get a gauge of.
Yeah. Yeah. These are people that are very sober minded.
I mean, this individual was early in the morning going to work,
not under the influence of anything.
And that person had a similar clearance as mine, you know, TSSEI.
So, you know, we've gone through. Yes.
Was that top secret?
You know, since Department of Information Clearance and, you know,
just like myself, I've been through multiple polygraphs in my career.
So did this individual. So does he have any idea
or any theories about why this thing was following him?
No, that's what freaked him out the most, because
he didn't have any experience in his life like this.
It like totally blew his mind when he looked out his moon roof
and then looked out the side of his car door and saw this 300 foot triangle.
It was like pre-dawn sky, but it was darker than the pre-dawn sky.
And it had this like plasma edges, like it was like purplish glowing edges
in these three lights that had like these omnidirectional,
like almost like pull lights, you know, how there's
you can't really tell where the light source is.
And it was totally trippy.
And that's just one example of many anecdotal,
with some evidence, you know, pilot stories.
And that's what made me dig deeper.
And I started, you know, cultivating my network like.
Has the government studied this before?
This wasn't just OSAP and ATIP and Blue Book and all this shit in the past, right?
There's this seems serious.
So, like, certainly the government has looked at this.
And, you know, I went to search for that program
and that's what I ended up whistleblowing on. Right.
So when you what was how did you initially discover this program?
And like, what was your first encounter with the information?
A very senior individual in the Intel community came to me
when I guess I was asking a lot of questions because I'm a very inquisitive guy.
And it was like, hey, we I need to introduce you to somebody.
You know, he listed that certain person's academic credentials,
which were beyond reproach, you know, PhD level education clearance.
Resume was insane.
I'm like, well, OK, sure, I'll I'll talk to this person.
And and I ended up meeting that person in a, you know,
top secret facility.
And, you know, he started to discussing like, hey, there's a program.
I was on it.
And, you know, we were reverse engineering crash material
that we've recovered over the decades, you know.
And he's like, I'm not joking.
You know, you know what we're telling you, because you have
you guys have to report to the deputy secretary of defense in Congress
on this matter. Right.
And we were we were actively
briefing like Secretary Esper, Deputy Secretary Norquist, you know,
other cabinet level folks. Right.
And it's like there's a you know, there must there's an oversight issue
because you're the UAP task force.
You should be read into this stuff because like
why spend the taxpayers, you know, dollars looking at stuff
that we already have data on. Right.
So that's and that spooked me.
And that was like fall of 2019.
And, you know, I don't take a guy's word for it.
I'm like, you know what?
Myself and my trusted colleagues that had a lot, a lot of special accesses
like me, you know, we cultivated our network
and we ultimately interviewed about 40 people or so all the way up
to multistar generals,
directors of agencies, mid-level guys that literally touched it,
worked inside of it, all the stuff.
They brought intel reports for me to look at, you know, documents.
And in a lot of that, I could cross verify with other
oral sources that my high level colleagues or I talked to.
And, you know, it checked out, especially when I
had enough information on.
And I know who specifically to ask, like, hey, well, I went right into this.
Like, I'm on the task force.
And we went to those, I'll call them gatekeepers for the lack of a better term.
And they basically said, fuck you to me and my colleagues.
Hmm. So why were these other people willing to discuss this with you?
Well, they determined I didn't need to know I was already
cleared at such a high level handling presidential material and everything.
It's like Dave needs to know.
And they felt that coming to us, it was a form of a protected disclosure.
They felt that they weren't really violating anything because, you know, we were the
I'll call it the investigatory body for the Department of Defense
and the intelligence community and Congress at the time.
And they, you know, you are allowed to,
you know, disclose to a government official in an official capacity.
And I, you know, did that.
And, you know, of course, I protected those people.
And and do know I took those people, a lot of them,
and they brought them to the intelligence community inspector general
when I filed my complaint, because I don't want people to,
you know, hear it from a secondhand source.
You know, people call it hearsay, whatever.
Well, I have some firsthand knowledge.
I eventually talk about someday I'm trying to get it cleared.
But through through security processes.
So they could hear it and hear the details like,
you know, who, what, when, where, why, where the shit is,
who's in control of it, what are the cover programs, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
So and that's what deemed my my complaint credible and urgent in July 2022,
which is a so that my complaint, yes, was about reprisal, too.
I filed that separately eventually to the Department of Defense Inspector General.
That's an ongoing investigation.
But it was my congressional oversight
UAP crash retrieval allegations that was deemed credible and urgent.
It was sent to the director of national intelligence.
And then it was sent to the congressional intelligence committees
around that time, July of 2022.
And I eventually went to Congress in December of 2022.
And it's a crazy story why it took so long.
It's fucking nuts.
But I provided total about 11 and a half to 12 hours of,
you know, classified testimony to the congressional staffers and their lawyers
for both the House and the Senate.
And I I went full open kimono.
I mean, I told them as much as I could within my time slot, if you will. So. So.
This is obviously very compartmentalized.
Where there's only a few people that know about this information.
And they're not allowed to discuss it with other people.
When did this all start?
I mean, is this out of Roswell?
Is it predate that?
Like when when did they first realize that there are things
that cannot be explained or can't be explained through conventional means?
Yeah, I mean, the program goes back a ways the precise
beginning of it.
I can't talk about, but I did because security stuff.
But I did talk about publicly the 1933 retrieval.
And I did that tactically.
And I ran that through the security approval office
because I wanted to show that this is much older and it's international.
It's not like a U.S. thing.
I mean, this stuff is landing or crashing around the world.
And unexpected countries have had this happen.
And that's why I pick that because I thought that was an interesting case.
And then, of course, the Pope Pius XII and the Vatican were involved
backchanneling it through the OSS, which became the CIA later to FDR.
And that's how the U.S. knew something weird happened in Italy during.
Well, right before World War II.
But so this is 33 was the first like documented.
That is the earliest one I can talk about.
Yeah, there's something that predates that.
You could infer that you could infer that.
Yeah. So this 33 one, you said, was in Italy.
Yeah. Magenta.
So it's a bad geography.
I think that's like a Lombardy region.
It's like northern, northwest Italy.
And what's the story behind it?
So basically, it it looked like it crashed, right?
The original shape most likely was like a lenticular disk like craft,
you know, with like two dinner plates.
What does lenticular mean?
So like two dinner plates, you know, smushed together, right?
And there's like, you know, like a bubble on top of the classic classic
like like that, like that.
But it looks like when it hits, the edges broke off.
So it became this like bell or acorn shaped thing.
And there was nothing in it.
It was like just an artifact.
You know, there was no biological remnants, if you will.
So it's so funny because the Italians were so confused.
They actually called up the Germans and they were like,
is this one of your Wunderwaffe?
Like, what the hell just crashed in northern Italy?
Mussolini and this is all publicly available information
because some Italian researchers
found all these original documents
that some people were sitting on for years in Italy.
You know, they put a gag order on the press, et cetera.
And Mussolini asked the Germans to come down.
And of course, the Germans came down and they were like,
that is not ours, but let's look at it together.
So that's kind of perhaps a tertiary reason
the kind of Axis powers got together.
I'm not saying that's like the reason, but I think the Italians
and the Germans were so intrigued with what they found
from like an artifact perspective.
There was at least some scientific
and military collaboration during the war.
The details of which I'm not I'm not sure of,
but I know people that know that specific event
that are currently still intel officers
within this program in detail.
But so was there witnesses to the crash
or some sort of an understanding
that something had crash landed and then they discovered it?
Yeah, I forget the precise discovery.
I don't know if it was like local police officers
or local farmers found it in the field, something like that.
I don't want to misspeak.
I'm I assume some of the Italian researchers
might have some fact witnesses that can orally say,
oh, yeah, my my great grandfather found it
or something like that. But I don't remember.
And what was the scale of this vehicle?
It was probably like like 20 feet by 10 feet, something like that.
Not super huge, but kind of big.
Do they think that this was a drone?
Do they think that this was occupied?
There was nothing in it.
So if it if it was piloted, if you will, by some sentience,
I mean, your your guess is as good as mine.
So hmm.
So what happened to that vehicle?
So we knew where it was being stored at a particular location
after the crash.
And then the military came in and we we grabbed it
towards the end of the war, you know, 1944, 1945,
because, like I said, Pope Pius XII already kind of.
Let's FDR know why the pope get involved, because well, Italy.
Well, interestingly enough, there's like a whole history
of human intelligence prior to World War Two and old money.
The Vatican, the Italian mob, kind of the old country boys
did a lot of informal intelligence collection
for the US.
And there's probably some books you can read on it,
but it's really interesting.
You know, human intelligence collection wasn't really formalized
until the Office Office of Strategic Services, the OSS,
which became the CIA in 1947.
You had, you know, Paul Mellon and all these other
affluent guys of all these old money families
that basically created the CIA.
So that's probably the reason why.
So this thing that was recovered,
this was the first documented one that the United States had access to.
I can't get into if it was the first or not, but it was an early one.
Very early. Yeah. So it's almost 100 years ago. Yes.
And so they take this thing and then they bring it where?
Yeah, I can't. I can't get into that.
Can't get into that. No. OK.
So they bring it somewhere in the United States.
And was the attempt to try to back engineer this thing?
Was the attempt to try to understand what it was?
Yeah. I mean, first of it, obviously, it's understanding the situation, right?
What do we have our hands on?
And and like I've said in some other videos and stuff,
you know, that we took the Manhattan Project secrecy
and overlaid it on this issue because that secrecy worked well for atomic bomb
developments and whatnot.
And and certainly this whole program in a nutshell,
if I were to like summarize the 90 plus years of history,
it is a reverse engineering program to garner some kind of insight.
And of course, not a lot of the things that we've learned from it
are like directly, you know, ripped off the technology we found,
but it has inspired other innovations that made its way
into other US classified programs over the year for national defense reasons.
You know, it's a myriad of different things.
So the UFO folklore is that this is where fiber optics were discovered first.
Yeah, I'm not going to break the seal on anything we've discovered
or anything like that.
And yeah, it's a place I can't go to.
Are you and what you can discuss and what you can't discuss and why?
Why do they let you discuss any of this?
Yeah. So anything sensitive that I want to say as it relates
to like US government activity, whether it be intelligence stuff, military stuff,
et cetera, I have to submit it through what they call DOPS or DOD office
of pre publication and security review.
That is something anybody who's been an intel officer,
anybody with like a clearance has to submit that kind of stuff.
Now, obviously, if you're writing a book about gardening, you don't have to.
But if you're going to talk about anything military
and intelligence related, you have to submit.
So it's kind of a catch 22 for this office, right?
They're only looking at it from a security perspective.
They're not vouching for it or anything like that.
And that's like any author, right?
They could write a book about Navy SEALs and they're not vouching for the story.
They're vouching that you didn't say any nasty code words.
You didn't burn a specific ongoing classified program.
And for them, I mean, I'm not in their OODA loop, but certainly
it's a catch 22 for them where if they want to redact and they propose
a redaction, they're like, hey, Dave, you can't say these sentences.
You can rewrite it and resubmit.
You know, we can't necessarily tell you
what agency said to redact it, but you're not allowed to say this.
They would be basically self certifying there's a there there.
So in my opinion, probably the policy is like,
if it has to deal with the subject, we're not saying anything.
We're not proposing any redactions.
As long as he's not burning a conventional program,
we kind of have to allow him to exercise his First Amendment rights.
So I think it's like a catch 22 for that office is kind of the long
or the short of the long answer.
So this is essentially one of the very early ones, 1933.
How many crash retrieval
incidents have there been?
It is double digits.
These specific numbers, I do know.
However, I can't discuss that.
I know it sounds like, oh, I'm being coy or whatever.
But, you know, this show, any other interviews I do write, you know,
Ford intelligence services are watching.
And it's like, I'm not here to help Russia and China calibrate
their intelligence collection like, oh, Dave said it's this number.
We missed a couple.
Shit, let's put it out for the KGB.
SVR and GRU are now going to hit the streets to try to figure out
which ones they miss.
So I'm I'm here to protect national security.
And I'm just trying to put all the general topics out there
for public conversation to hold our government accountable, really.
So because I'm I'm here as a fact witness
because we have a, you know, a constitutional oversight issue
because this program has not been,
you know, reported to Congress in the appropriate way, you know,
and I can get into a senator I talked to that has died recently.
So I can, you know, explain to you why I'm so sure.
Besides what I read, which we can get into that, what Intel reports I read.
I did get some stuff cleared.
So during my investigation, I'm like, you know what?
I need to talk to somebody at the highest levels. Right.
So and this will give you an idea of the kind of people we talk to.
And this is the only one I'm going to talk about using their name
because they died two years ago.
So in spring 2021, I actually flew with a couple of colleagues of mine
to Las Vegas, and I met with Senator Harry Reid
about nine months before he died.
And of course, he's a private citizen now, and I wanted to brief him on.
The topic, and I wanted to get his kind of thought leadership on it,
because, you know, he was a gang of eight member, right?
You know, which is the top most cleared senators and congressmen.
He was the majority leader, for God's sake.
So the Senate and I knew, you know, he helped sponsor
the OSAP program that I mentioned
and where they looked at Skinwalker Ranch and some other things.
And I wanted to understand, like, what does Harry Reid actually know?
Like, why did he, you know, give 21 million dollars
to DIA and Bigelow Aerospace for this?
So I'm sitting there in Harry Reid's living room,
you know, right next to him with some other witnesses that were there with me.
And he straight up says he's like, yeah, I knew we had UFO material.
I was denied access for decades.
I tried to get access.
And then he explained some of his efforts during OSAP.
And I was like, holy shit, the former majority leader
just say that he just confirmed this to me as well.
You know, I was already talking to these amazing high level people.
But I have Harry Reid literally saying, yes, we have material.
And, you know, he knew it was non-human.
Did Harry Reid have personal experience with this?
I don't know if he's had any personal stuff in his personal life.
I mean, did he see it? Did he he said this?
In terms of seeing the material himself, he said he was denied access
for years, decades was his term.
And he actually told me on behalf of me, he was going.
So he had like a weekly call with President Joe Biden at the time.
And he straight up said to me
he was going to talk to President Biden about this issue, literally.
And then what he was telling me about OSAP,
I was like, holy shit, I have like 20 other people that told me this, dude.
So the real history, what fucking OSAP was,
because I think there's a lot of people out there
to think when they were looking at ghosts, skinwalker ranch.
Yes, they went to the ranch as a secondary and tertiary objective.
But the real reason.
So like there's a document that came out a couple of years ago
through FOIA from the Defense Intelligence Agency.
There was this special access program request that Harry Reid,
you might have seen this, I think, like George Knapp and company
have reported on this
that he sent to the deputy secretary of defense, William Lynn.
And it was asking for one of the most serious saps you can ask for,
what they call a bigoted, waived special access program.
So waived means it's limited congressional reporting
that is a class of special access programs.
And bigoted means it's like by name.
And it's like it was like you can read the FOIA document.
It was like, you know, Harry Reid, James Inhofe, Luella Zondo, etc.
And I'm like, why are you asking for the most serious sap to be created
for a program that ostensibly is looking at skinwalker ranch and stuff?
And it doesn't make any sense.
So what really happened there?
And, you know, Harry Reid,
God bless his soul, made this disclosure
a couple of weeks after we met in the New Yorker.
And you can look this up.
I think it was like a May 2021 New Yorker story where he says,
I knew for decades and he made this disclosure, not me.
So I'm going to say the name of the contractor.
Harry Reid said this, you know, we knew that Lockheed Martin
had this material for decades.
I tried to get access and I was denied.
And specifically with the Lockheed Martin stuff,
he was talking about during the ASAP program.
And for the people who are on this program,
I submitted the shit to the officer, got this cleared.
So don't freak out.
But I'm telling the truth here.
So Lockheed Martin wanted to divest itself from this material
at a specific facility that's known to me, that I provided to the inspector general
like street address, all that shit, right.
And the idea was if they made a catcher's mitt, a security catcher's mitt
for this shit, you know, most serious sap possible,
the contractor and the other government customer,
which was the Central Intelligence Agency for that specific Lockheed material.
And it was shit that they recovered from like the 50s and stuff.
And it was like bits and pieces of of of of like hall structure, shit like that.
And so they were going to tech transfer it.
And the 21 or 22 million dollars was actually for Bigelow Aerospace
to build out, you know, facilities in Las Vegas and material analysis equipment.
And I've seen I have I saw the staff meeting slides.
I saw the paperwork like there's a paperwork trail I've seen on this shit.
And I talked to the people involved in this program.
And, you know, even Jim Lakatsky, who ran the program,
whose retired DIA officer, PhD in engineering, even made this disclosure in his book
Skinwalkers at the Pentagon, page 152 to 153.
And he also made a disclosure a couple of weeks ago.
I think it was on weaponized podcast with Jeremy Corbell and George Knapp, where
he's like, yeah, we had a whole craft and we broke into the hall and we gained access.
And he ran that through the same, you know, security process as I did.
And so Jim Lakatsky, who ran this program, is also going on the record
that he is aware, personally aware of intact vehicles and everything.
But so they gained access.
What does that mean? And by what method did they gain access?
The way he wrote it in his book, I can only infer it sounded forcible.
So through some kind of, you know, means, I don't know if it was like CO2 laser or something.
I don't actually know how they gained access, but imagine it was not permissive access.
They like broke into the damn thing.
So this thing is essentially sealed and it's some sort of what was the shape of this thing?
Lakatsky didn't disclose the shape on this particular vehicle, as far as I recollect.
What about the dimensions?
I don't believe he did in his book.
But I think it's like Chapter 11 in his new book or something like land status.
But he did make that disclosure on video as well.
And I do encourage both the Aero Office, which is the DOD's UAP task force successor,
and Congress to ask Dr. James Lakatsky to come in for classified testimony,
because the disclosure in his one book that he wrote with Colm Kelleher, George Knapp,
and then the second book.
Well, the guy saying he has close personal knowledge, he needs to go to Congress.
So, you know, I don't know James Lakatsky, but I do encourage him to be a fact witness.
But going back to that transfer with Lockheed, long story short,
can't get in all the nuanced details, but basically the CIA said fuck you to DIA and Lockheed.
And it was totally killed.
So Harry Reid's request to get the material transferred to the OSAP program was totally killed
because of bureaucracy and kind of fiefdom stuff.
So they used that money, and then they, you know, they wrote those Defense Intelligence Reference Documents,
the DIRDs, as a lot of people who's familiar with it listening will know about.
And then they did look at Skinwalker Ranch because they thought that studying kind of the more woo-woo phenomenon
aspects of this, and I've never been to the ranch, so I've never experienced the ranch for myself.
But, you know, obviously, I think we both know a bunch of people that have been to the ranch
and have seen some trippy stuff, or at least allege that.
They thought that they would be able to gain currency with the program, you know,
and in this case, CIA, to unlock the key for the Lockheed Martin stuff,
which actually, I'll tell you right now, it's so weird to say that, but I ran that shit through security.
Yeah, to me, it's like an out-of-body experience to talk about that kind of detailed sensitivity, stuff like that.
But basically, they studied the ranch to gain favor, to be like,
hey, look at all this stuff we're figuring out, this paranormal stuff that's somehow connected to the phenomenon on the ranch.
But ultimately, they never gained favor with the government customer.
And then the program kind of died a slow death because of a lot of politics in the Pentagon.
So that's kind of the long but short of it with the OSAP program that, you know,
I wanted to make sure the public knew it's not what you think it was.
There was some other stuff behind the scenes that, you know, I wanted to speak truth to power on.
So this particular vehicle that they had recovered from the 1950s, what was the source of it?
Where did they find it?
Those details, I did not get cleared.
So they have in possession this thing, they gain access to this thing.
And what do they report once they've gained access to it?
Oh, those details, I do not know.
That's probably a question for Dr. Lakatsky.
I presume he knows those details. I don't know.
So this thing is housed somewhere?
It is, yes. Currently.
It may still be in the same location that I know about, yes.
And how many people have access to this and how did they prevent this information from being released?
I mean, you know, it goes back to the compartmentation and kind of the ecosystem of secrecy in this community, right?
You know, only a limited amount of people, you know, at least at the time, you know, on Lockheed Martin's side.
And Lockheed Martin was complaining basically like, look, like the secrecy is ridiculous.
We can't even bring the right engineers.
Imagine you're like a hot engineer, a hot engineer, a hot shot engineer.
It might be hot, too. I don't know.
But that you're fresh out of grad school.
Maybe you're like the best PhD electrical engineer.
You want to do cool shit. You want to publish an IEEE.
You want to like, you know, climb the ladder corporately, you know, and that kind of thing.
A Lockheed Martin executive comes to you.
Yeah, dude, you're going to I can reach into something really crazy,
but you're never going to publish papers on it.
You're never going to be able to tell people what you worked on.
And it's probably not the most career enhancing.
But if you want to work on something cool, but I can't tell you because it's unacknowledged
until you sign this piece of paper, non-disclosure agreement.
You know, sorry, but here's the raw deal.
And, you know, a lot of people are like, fuck you, no.
And it's not like Lockheed Martin could broadcast this to universities like,
come work for us. You'll work on crazy shit.
But that is very akin to a lot of other black programs in the government
that are adding knowledge in nature.
You don't know what you're signing up for until you get bred in.
And I've, you know, I've been briefed to a lot of that kind of conventional stuff in my career.
So that's one of the problems that Bob Lazar, and I'd love to get your take on Bob Lazar,
one of the things that he talked about was that science can't really operate in a vacuum.
When you separate the metallurgists from the propulsion's experts, from the biological
experts, like, and they're not allowed to communicate with each other and they're not
allowed to bring in other experts to have different.
Well, that was the frustration that I had some friends that I've known my entire career,
like almost 14 years, right?
I literally know them personally.
I had a relationship with them, but they ended up, you know,
spilling the beans where, you know, look, we're on the program.
I'm an engineer for X, Y, and Z.
We can't even cross talk across like the cubicles for God's sakes.
Like I can't, I'm looking at material X doing some X-ray diffraction testing on it,
which is like shooting a stream of electrons and seeing how it bends and looking at the
atomic arrangements.
I can't even like cross talk that with another aspect of the program.
This is like ridiculous.
And that's kind of their frustration.
Yeah, I knew you were probably going to ask me about Bulbasaur.
I know, I figured as much.
Why did they do that though?
If everybody was already sworn to secrecy, everybody already has NDAs.
It seems the most effective way of reverse engineering or at least gaining an understanding
of how these things are structured.
Well, that's exactly how Manhattan was, right?
People working on the fuses for the bomb didn't necessarily know it was going to a nuclear
weapon.
And I've seen this kind of compartmentationist up to secrecy in other programs and it is
debilitating for progress.
And honestly, as a former fiduciary of the taxpayer dollars, it's not the best modus
operandus to do it that way.
And very few people kind of had that top down, could look across the silos and see what was
going on.
It just became very dysfunctional and they were afraid of people being too cross briefed into
the different silos for counter espionage, counter intelligence.
They were going to remember a bulk of this program was done during the Cold War and we
were afraid of Russian spies, Soviet moles.
And so we made it ultra locked down, but to the detriment of national security.
And that was one of the crazy things that got me that I wanted to whistle blow on because
I'm like, this is so stupid.
We should be making more progress on this.
Were there any breaches that you're aware of?
Were foreign agents were able to gain access to materials or an understanding of what we
know?
So I'll tell you about some intel documents I read that kind of obliquely answers that
question.
So there was sense of human derived foreign intelligence that I read.
So I had access to kind of the ATIP OSAP classified archives and I was like thumbing through
everything and there's some other people were bringing me documents to evaluate.
And I'll never forget I had to say stolen by the US intelligence assessment from a certain
foreign adversary discussing the US reverse engineering program.
And I was like, and that was actually another like, what the fuck?
And so I had an adversary also confirm this program literally because of exfiltrated
intelligence.
And so they certainly had a limited knowledge, at least fact of that the US had a program
like this, a particular adversary.
And actually I was like, well, I want more.
Like I know who wrote this literal or who got it right on behalf of the United States
government.
So I went to that certain agency through the approved and official way.
And this is kind of part of the myriads reprisals against me.
The agency was like, oh, yes, we have what you're looking for, Dave, you're going to
need to sign a one time read into something, you know, come visit us to, you know, go to
the vault and read it, right?
You know, hard copy, but yes, we have what you're looking for.
And ultimately, from what I was told by friends in higher places, my request kind of went
up the flagpole at that agency.
And all of a sudden, the agency ghosted my boss and I for like two months.
And then when I really pressed them hard to gain access, because I'm like, I have a
need to know I need to evaluate this intelligence for fucking Congress.
And they debriefed me from all my accesses over in that other sister agency and made
up some bogus excuse.
Like I shouldn't have been briefed anything in the first place, literally, and basically
gave me an administrative middle finger like persona non grata.
Don't ever fucking ask us about that shit again.
And I'm sure the person who made the oops that told me they had what I was looking for
probably got admonished and slapped on the wrist because I never heard from that person
again, even though it was somebody I actually used to work on occasion with.
So that was also another way I knew I was you know, there was a lot of smoke and fire
because I, you know, had stuff like that happen to me.
So this knowing that our adversaries were aware of this reverse engineering program,
are we aware of their reverse engineering programs?
Yeah.
Which countries?
You could you could probably guess and you wouldn't be, it won't be too shocking.
Okay.
But I won't acknowledge what the US may know.
Right. So are we aware of numbers in terms of like at least a rough estimate of how many
are available to these other?
Yeah.
How many?
That's like super sensitive.
But there's more than one.
Yeah, you can read into that.
You can read into that.
And has anyone made any progress?
Yeah, I can't get into if we've made progress, if they've made progress,
because that's like straight up some national security stuff.
But like, I want the just to be clear, I want the US populace to learn a lot of this.
And this is why, you know, another reason why I went public is like,
I need to call everybody out.
I'm not here to admonish the entire government, mind you.
But there is an element of the US government and its clear defense contractor base that,
you know, we have a three branch of government oversight issue like going back to Harry Reid.
Harry Reid didn't even get access.
I fucking talked to myself to confirm that.
And he said he was going to talk to Biden.
Because I think there needs to be a disclosure plan.
And this goes back to what's currently in legislation right now.
That's super fucking important.
Because 90 some odd percent of this should be open for public discovery,
public analysis and academia.
This should be like, at very least true nuclear programs such as nuclear physics,
you study in the university, nuclear weapons classified,
because that makes people in the pink mist.
That's really sensitive.
We don't need everybody to know how to do that.
So I think the stuff that is like legit weapons related stuff,
that's like straight up national superiority stuff, sure.
Reasonably classify that, but these programs, we need a change.
And that's why you saw the Schumer Amendment, right?
And I think you might have read that on air or something in a previous episode,
if I remember correctly.
You know, Chuck Schumer, and I knew about the amendment a couple months before I went public.
And that's kind of another reason why I did what I did.
I'm like, fuck.
I'm like the only guy that kind of has the opportunity to do this.
I know what's in the chute, so to speak, that Chuck Schumer and his staff had
with the Schumer Amendment, which is 67 pages of literal, we want to disclose.
And I'm like, I have to spike the football by going public because,
you know, I can read the tea leaves on the hill.
And I think that they were hesitant to do anything
without being able to point to something publicly.
And I'm like, I'll be that fucking guy and just send it.
And then, of course, a month after I went public, I guess I pushed Chuck Schumer over the ledge.
And I do know he talked to the White House about the amendment, too,
because not like Chuck Schumer is going to propose groundbreaking legislation like that
without talking to the national security advisor or president.
Like, I imagine he did so.
And, you know, so you have the 67 page amendments, right?
It's called the UAP Disclosure Act of 2023, known as the Schumer Amendment.
Co-sponsors were Young, Gillibrand, Rubio, Rounds.
Yeah, and Young.
And, you know, kudos for those senators for stepping up to the plate
because they know this is real.
I know what meetings they've had with certain other individuals
that are, you know, even more credible than myself.
And so this act, which is like super important, is currently in conference.
As we speak in Capitol Hill.
So the amendment is wrapped in something called the Fiscal Year 2024
National Defense Authorization Act.
So that is the act that funds the military basically every year, right?
So it's an amendment within this bill.
And the act is really long, but the main meat of it is about halfway through the act.
It talks about a presidential panel or agency, which is nine person,
and a controlled UAP disclosure plan that's six years in length,
conceivably from 2024 to 2030 in this panel.
And you can read this is public law.
Anybody can read this.
They want a scientist, economists, you know, you know, sociologists, etc.
It's kind of like who you would want to help craft the plan for the president.
And this whole bill was actually built off the JFK Records Act,
which I know like they're like, well, they never released all the records.
Well, we put some teeth in the bill, some eminent domains, some other stuff,
the, you know, kind of force the issue.
Now, granted, the chief executive, the president has the final say.
The panel can't compel the executive to do it.
But like, I hope the president does and I support that.
But so the Senate already passed it.
They're chill with this.
This is like, we're good to go.
And and but there's pushback in the House right now that is,
you know, pardon my language, fucking ridiculous.
So they're saying, for one, it's duplicating the DOD arrows office activities.
They're doing good things.
They're looking at UAP reports, trying to figure out what's balloons and air trash
and what's weird stuff.
And of course, they are doing an historical review to try to understand the US's history on this,
too.
But the problem is with that agency, it's within the DOD and IC, not above.
So you have an issue reaching into Department of Energy, other, you know,
cabinet level agencies.
You need a presidential level panel that can declassify stuff, reach into other agencies
and tell certain secretaries, we're coming in.
We want your stuff under presidential authority.
So what's happening in the House?
From what I'm told from people on the Hill that are working the issue right now,
you have the chair of the House Intel Committee, Mike Turner, who's blocking this
from Ohio, Dayton, Ohio area.
Right, Pat.
Weird.
Right, Pat, meaning Wright Patterson.
Yes.
Yeah.
And Mike Rogers, which I'm kind of surprised from Alabama, who's the chair of the House
Armed Services Committee.
So I have a problem with Mike and Mike right now.
So Mike Turner, now remember, I went to his committee in December of last year.
He wasn't there, but his staff and lawyers were.
And of course, he goes on Fox Business after the hearing, doesn't use my names like this
whistleblower.
He has no idea what he's talking about.
I'm like, really?
Tell me, Mike, have you ever been an Intel officer or served in the military?
Oh, wait, you've been the mayor of Dayton, Ohio.
You were voted most corrupt person in Congress a couple years ago and pull up his PAC donors.
Who are his biggest donors?
Lockheed, Raytheon, Boeing.
Okay, so and first of all, if you thought you need more information or wanted to talk
to me personally, why didn't you call me back when I reported to your committee?
So and furthermore, besides blocking the bill, I'm sure you're familiar with like
Representative Tim Bershett of Alabama, and he's been very outspoken on the issue.
We may not agree with everything Tim says about conventional stuff.
That's, you know, here, no there.
But, you know, he's been a champion on the Oversight Committee and he was, you know,
one of the members that I testified in public under oath regarding this.
So like, and Mike Turner is looking to fund, according to staffers I've talked to last
two weeks, an opposition candidate for Tim's reelection in 2024.
So why is Mike Turner going out of his way to destroy the career of a courageous Tennessee
representative on the Oversight Committee?
And why are you blocking a bill?
And it's not going to cost much, a couple million a year max, you know, for the panel,
which is like vaporware and US government speak, right?
If there's nothing to see here, why are Mike Rogers and Mike Turner in the House
blocking this bill that is, in my opinion, the most important legislation for transparency
in American history?
If there's nothing to see here, if I'm fucking crazy, multi-star generals I talked to are crazy,
the Intel docs that I read are incorrect, they're fucking forgeries or passage material
or something like that.
Good friends of mine that worked on the program are bullshitting me in some consorted
operation against me and my colleagues that it would be totally crazy to even conduct
that because I took precautions, then why don't we just pass this and see what happens?
And what do you think the answer to that is?
Special interests want to keep the genie in the bottle, even though the toothpaste is
coming out of the tube, and I think it's like a death rattle in this industrial complex
that doesn't want change.
And I'm not here to be some total adversary.
I think there needs to be a truth and reconciliation process on this issue.
I'm not here to throw people in jail.
I'm not here for big contractors involved to lose money.
I think this would be a boon.
And I think the leadership in these companies need to think about this, where if we're more
open with this, you can hire people, you can push the subject into undergraduate,
and postdoctoral programs of research to study this in an unclassified, just like nuclear
physics.
And this answers a fundamental question for humanity.
Are we alone or what happens when we die?
Well, I don't know about that, but are we alone?
Well, the answer is we're not alone.
And I know that with 100% certainty, which as an Intel officer, you never say 100%, but
all things pointed towards based on the people I talked to, like Harry Reid, and I use him
as an example, but I talked to the highest of the high people you could possibly talk
to, if you catch my drift.
So unless all them are lying and they're covering up something else, which I don't
even know what it would be at this point, because the phenomenon is real.
It's been going on for thousands of years.
People have been seeing strange things and not everybody's mass hallucinating.
So that's kind of my long diatribe about what's happening.
What do they think these things are?
The people that you talk to?
So they specifically, the people on the program that handled the material that were in executive
level briefings with Intel community leaders and other folks over the years, last 20 years or so,
they did use the term extraterrestrial ET or whatever.
Okay, that isn't a possible origin.
But the Schumer Amendment, if you read it, it specifically uses non-human intelligence,
NHI, very deliberately because we want to catch everything, because what if some of
this stuff is not ET and they're going to use that as an escape clause?
Well, this stuff that we don't even know if it's extraterrestrial, so this doesn't apply.
So that's why we want it to be as broad as possible.
Besides ET, a lot of it would be my own personal opinion.
I think we have a couple conceivable buckets and I'm using the work of Jacques Vallee,
other people that have thought deeply on the issue on how the phenomenon has changed since
antiquity, it showed itself in a different way.
Like a good example is like witches sitting on your chest phenomenon with
a paralysis and medieval and enlightenment era became this alien abduction phenomenon
in the modern era and is it the recipient and their analytical overlay cognitively
seeing the phenomenon based on a modern interpretation, inside out, or is the
phenomenon, this is like Jacques Vallee's book, Passport to Magnolia, Magnolia,
I can pronounce it right, 1969, where he talks about the phenomenon seems to like
masquerade itself as different stuff over the years, but we've seen roughly the same stuff.
If you look at the Foo Fighters of World War II, there are declassified Air Force OSI reports
from the 50s, people can Google the talk about flying butane tanks with the same measurements,
approximately what we saw in the 2004 Tic-Tac incident, but they called it flying propane or
butane tanks in the 50s. So from a morphology or in the Air Force Intel, we call it vis-rec-y,
visual reconnaissance, they basically look the same and we can back-asmith that decades, if not
hundreds of years in the past, wheels of Ezekiel, they're seeing these like disk type objects.
Unless Ezekiel is tripping or this is an allegory or fable in the Bible, let's say the event happens,
just like in the Vedic text, you have the battles, the blue people and the battles in the sky that
sound like nuclear and directed energy weapons, like what's going on there? Maybe that's a
Graham Hancock or Randall Carlson type thing they know more than I. So there is a real phenomenon
that origin undetermined but it's trippy and sometimes it presents itself in like a non-corporeal
form too, you know, orbs, balls of energy, they don't appear as like some kind of bipedal hominid
like some people have expoused. So I think that might be, call it interdimensional, call it shadow
biome, I mean there's a lot of different theories. What are the primary theories? The
primary theories are from another planet or from another dimension. I think those are the primary,
I mean there's certainly origins that we probably can't conceptualize as humans because we're just,
our meat is stuck in 3D and we don't understand and our IQs are only so high so there might be
some origins that we don't understand. In terms of like interdimensional travel.
Yeah, I mean obviously if you talk to mainstream physicists they say like crossing dimensions
physically is kind of a trope of sci-fi and that's why I used an example and I know some
physicists don't like me talking about this theory but it is a theory. So the holographic principle
which was originally conceived to explain how information is encoded on an event horizon of a
black hole which is a distance away from the singularity of a black hole where if you cross
it you're fucked because you're going to get ripped to shreds or you're not coming back
and that principle talks about how information basically from higher dimensional space can be
encoded in lower dimensional space and the easiest example is like us casting a shadow on a sidewalk
right? Three-dimensional object, 2D shadow on a sidewalk. If you lived in two-dimensional space,
flatland you'd be tripped out. What the fuck am I seeing? But they just don't know that it's really
just a person in higher dimensional space. So is some of the, I mean obviously we have physical
material that's in three-dimensional space that we've recovered but at least maybe some of the
phenomenon is really operating in higher spatial dimensions but is either being projected or quasi
projected into our 3D plus time space which is really trippy to think about but we literally do
it on a day-to-day basis like casting shadows. So and that might be some of what we're seeing too
but I mean I presume we know more. The people I talked to did not espouse, they had full knowledge
either. Like I said the normal colloquialism was to say ET or extraterrestrial. Could you dumb down
this concept of interdimensional? I know in physics they have theorized that there are
multiple dimensions other than those that we can currently detect. Yeah and a lot of that is based
off of like, this is my bachelor's degree talking, I know there's going to be like some physicists
who has a PhD who's like oh Dave you fucked that up. But basically from high energy particle
collisions and based on the deflection angles and all the stuff what happens when the particles
collide confirms certain theoretical frameworks about extra spatial dimensions and I can't speak
with any real authority on precisely how that works but a lot of whether it be string theory
or quantum mechanics are based off of higher spatial dimensions and so that is a mainstream
physics theoretical framework that's not like wacky or loony or anything like that.
But that's basically a possibility but like I said like we don't really have a good theory
if you lived in like 5D space for example. It's almost like remember the ending of the movie
Interstellar right? Where he's pushing the books, he's like in a tesseract you know which is like a
4 to 5D structure but he's trying to interact with 3D space and of course he like leaves that
space to come back to his daughter many years later at the ending of the movie, great movie.
But so that's a way to conceptualize it in something you may have watched in film.
It's kind of like the ending of Interstellar. Oh yeah. Yeah there you go.
Yeah. Which is based on what? Like what theory? So the physicist Kip Thorne was the very famous
guy. He was a big black hole and wormhole guy. I think it's Caltech or somewhere in California.
Kip Thorne actually did all the physics equations and everything for Christopher Nolan
to make sure that they were conceptualizing and visualizing black holes and wormholes and all
that stuff correctly in the movie. We saw like the halo around the black hole when they were
coming in with the ship and everything. That's actually based off of real physics models that
Kip Thorne did the calculations for which is pretty cool actually that Christopher
Nolan took it to that level you know. So this idea that these beings or whatever you want to
call them exist in some other dimension. Do we have, I mean I don't know what you can say about
this, do we have an understanding? Do we have any sort of communication with these beings
that give us some sort of an understanding or a map of this? Yeah the interaction stuff
it's a sensitive area. There were multiple very senior people that were concerned about talking
about that kind of stuff with me. I mean that is certainly as nuts as it sounds that was a real
subject of conversation even it sounds like something out of like Star Trek First Contact.
But it doesn't if you have vehicles. Yeah so it's like once you realize the phenomenon's real
then you realize we've recovered artifacts and you know biologics or you know dead pilots if you
will even though it's you know kind of creepy to even think about that in your world view
you don't think they were ever you know alive sometimes too right and I'll you know leave it
at that only because you know that is something you know the president and his cabinet need to
disclose this in a controlled manner going back to that amendment you know I'm not here
to you know push the subject in an improper way and that sounds like why don't you just do it
Dave like there's a lot of secondary and tertiary ramifications socioeconomically, theologically,
our relationship geopolitically with our allies and adversaries this is not rip off the band-aid
and it's simple there's a lot of complex stuff behind the scenes that need to happen and that's
why I'm laying out all the general stuff that needs to be talked about during the disclosure
process but I should not be the one disclosing and it would be highly inappropriate because I
care about the health of the United States and its people and national security for me to do so
so I know there's people that are like oh why doesn't Dave say x y and z it's like this is
serious this is not like haha let me tell you a good story I'm a serious guy I ruined my fucking
career doing this I was going to make lieutenant colonel in the air force and this winter I was on
track to be you know a flag officer equivalent civilian in my career I spent 18 years in uniform
if you count the cadet time right my whole adult life was serving as an intel officer but
I wanted to see and I'm 36 right older millennial I wanted to see change so I'm throwing the flag
out and I'm here to hold the government accountable to do the right thing in a manner that is mature
and thorough because I don't begin to say that I know everything all the different ramifications
of saying certain things publicly I don't know all the answers to that and that's why I have to
be careful because I don't even know I'll call it you know collateral damage effects to use kind
of a military term what may happen of certain things in detail that are revealed that I might
not know the ramifications thereof because there's something that I'm not privy to so this is like a
serious this is not like a fun situation this is like humanity changing hopefully in a good way
but this is like you know quite serious and I you know risked my personal and professional life
and personal life because things have happened to me to be public like this and you know I
swore an oath but you know myself and my generation you know want to see it change
Can you discuss the things that have happened to you personally?
Yeah so a lot of the stuff I have to be purposely vague because there's an open
inspector general reprisal investigation on my behalf and I'm not here to compromise
the investigation by tipping off my antibodies that may be watching right now but
you know when I really started looking into this I mean they came after me
so hard to try to revoke my clearance ruin my career kicked me out of my agency
and they accused me of everything you could possibly think of with like no evidence for
example at first they they wanted to say oh Dave you have mental health stuff you didn't report
to us we're concerned because we think you might have an ongoing mental health issue I'm like what
are you talking about I reported that I had PTSD from Afghanistan in my military service several
years ago and I sought help for that like I'm not ashamed of that you know I'm high functioning
autistic and and I didn't know that until my early 30s and and how I processed trauma I didn't
really understand until many years later and you know I sought help for that and they were trying
to say that like I had some secret mental health problem that I haven't been reporting to so I had
to go through this whole process three agencies at the same time investigated me for that's which I
don't even know if that's like legal they tried to say that I like mishandled classified all this
other stuff it was insane apparently I was under criminal investigation for a couple months and I
didn't even know that and nor did they interview me but they made a finding with no evidence they
tried to use against me that I had to spend money to basically litigate and maintain my employment
my clearance which I did for the record I maintained my clearance I resigned with full
accesses you know I'm just debriefed now but I maintained my top secret eligibility
and I left with my own accord and and so and of course uh they ruined one of my boss's careers
in another agency they walked him out of the building and revoked his clearance and terminated
him as a show of force after they were going after me and I feel sorry for that certain
individual and they came after co-workers of mine I can't get into who what when where and why to
protect their identities and their own process but so that's what happened to me professionally
and then what happened to me personally was very disturbing so I had to be very vague about this
because ongoing investigation but I think you'll understand what I'm saying is
they showed my wife and I they can touch me at any time two times and it was very disturbing
it was in conjunction with some other people getting a message like that that are let's say
publicly well known some that are aren't publicly well known and of course I immediately reported
that to you know counterintelligence federal law enforcement local to me because it you know wasn't
criminal but it was like a fuck you to me like and this was right before I filed my whistleblower
complaint now I don't know who did this you know an entity who did x y and z to my wife and I
identity unknown but it fucking happens and I you know provided that documentation to
a couple special agents and I just knew that it was getting serious and you know as
first of all I'm the kind of person I'm from Pittsburgh you know like steel town I don't take
shit from people and I decided fuck it I'm gonna file an inspector general complaint to protect
myself I don't I'm in fear for my safety you know my wife's an air force veteran too and you know
very strong individual but you know as a man you don't want to put your family at risk
and you know did certain other measures which I won't talk about to protect myself you know
physically and I could not believe that that was happening to me no kidding and I knew
I needed to do something internally and then when I saw the writing on the wall
earlier this year and of course I knew about the Schumer amendment like I mentioned earlier
and I knew I'm like you know I gotta do this for my own protection because me leaving the
federal service because I resigned my air force commission I totally threw that career away
to do what I thought was the right and patriotic thing to whistle blow on this you know and I
swore my oath 18 years ago and that sounds hokey but I believe you know integrity first
service before self and excellence all we do that's the air force motto and I'm like I
this is not going to help me personally like love talking to you I like spreading this message
because it's the right and ethical thing to do but this is a nightmare for me I don't want to
be public I've served the country in clandestine and covert operations for 14 years I've done
technical intelligence for some of the most high profile takedowns in US history I shouldn't even
be here but I am because I want to see change I saw something unethical and unmoral I want to
make sure I hold that element of the government accountable and it was the right fucking thing to
do and and I get kind of emotional about that because you know my career has been service and
sacrifice and you know I had two friends of mine die and I've talked about this publicly before
and I you know I'm segueing a little bit but the the suffering of the American intelligence officer
is something that for their service of their country and when I'm talking about this subject
obviously people don't realize the kind of trauma intel professionals go through so first of all I
had a friend six months after I got back from Afghanistan his name is Captain Dave Lyon there's
a park in Peterson Space Force Base named after him I remember seeing his coffin come off the
plane stuff so you know I saw him die that that fucked me up for a number of years and that's
what you know gave me a lot of my my problems that I ended up dealing with but then I had
I remarried and then my best man Captain Ben Heine Air Force intelligence officer Air Force
Special Operations Command I've known him for years he's my closest friend you know best man
at my wedding and then 28 days later unfortunately he suffered from depression and it was you know
as his best friend he didn't even confide in me you know I remember chit chatting him chit chatting
with him on the phone one day about 28 days after he was my best man and I he didn't tell me anything
was wrong with him and a few hours later he walked in his backyard and shot himself and you know I
gave his eulogy at his at his funeral and that really you know really affected me and and and
with what Ben experienced which I can't get into all the stuff he did obviously but imagine
being the guy that decides that that person is bad fire the hell fire that person is now pink
mist that they're dead you just played god let's go back to you know the wife and kids at the end
of your shift and a lot of that I you know I did the same kind of thing I did a lot of stuff
overseas involved interrogations and you know ops that were you had to decide if a target is bad
enough where you're going to affect their life forever and their family's life forever and and
that's the silent suffering of intel professionals especially during the global war and terror which
was you know 21 years or so and you know the the trauma and the mental health problems that people
get from being an intel professional and operational environment people think like special
operators pilots etc you know ground army marines ground pounders and they certainly have their own
trauma but it's this weird insidious am i in a video game is this real trauma that intelligence
professionals and i just wanted to highlight that during the show because that was just a
near and dear to myself so people are aware of the service of military intelligence and
civilian intelligence professionals so that's have to make really tough decisions for the country that
affect people's lives on the receiving end you know so was there a concern while you're going
through all this that if you didn't come out with this that we would be stuck in the same sort of
loop for a long long period of time and no one would ever have access to this stuff that they
would continue yep yeah and that you nailed it on the head is you know i think my generation once
it changed the under 40 generation their parents went to war their older brothers went to war
were fighting two dangerous proxy wars right now which is extremely
stupid i don't know the better way of saying it be quite frank and i give you my own assessment
on that if you want but i like we're in this loop we're not progressing in a healthy way
as a civilization you know it's becoming more divisive whether on the left or the right
you know people aren't even looking up all they care about is tiktok you know we're creating
potentially dangerous artificial intelligence you know i even saw that in my government service
and i think humanity's kind of stuck right now and we need to change and this subject is like
one of the only unifying ontologically shocking but i would think generally unifying topics were
where if announced by you know the us and other you know major powers that have knowledge in a
controlled manner that this could change humanity for the better make us look inside ourselves
become less divisive and care maybe a little less about superficial things so so that's kind of my
philosophical motivation to do what i did and and you're confronted with one of the biggest
mysteries in in human history yeah which is are we alone and it seems like at least some people
have the answer to that 100 i mean the people i talked to certainly did and they had close personal
knowledge and the intel reports i read you know literally indicated that as well like i talked
about earlier and it just so it's like this caste system i call dudes with sci clearances do not
have an embargo on reality so it's a caste system of you know people in government and outside of
government in the industrial complex that run this stuff under little oversight and you know
i remember some of the people who denied us access they were like you know you know i don't know what
you're talking about but if i did why would you have a need to know and i'm like well why did you
have a need to know you're just some multi-star general where you're a human being you're a human
being you're not better than me i mean who determines need to know on a humanistic question
um it's like basic fact of life why do you why are we classifying fact of life
at this day and age in 2023 it's insane and the answer to that would be national security
yeah it's obtuse national security right so like why we classify stuff it's called executive order
13 526 right section 1.4 sections e and f are why we classify science stuff why we classify nuclear
stuff it's like a one-liner it's very vague and and are you saying this is these basic
facts should be classified are you saying that this fits in this bill and you know and and you
notice the schumer amendment if anybody reads it awkwardly calls out the atomic energy act in 1954
right and they're basically treating this as nuclear secrets because it gives off
a you know nuclear radiation because if you look at the ultra vague definition
of special nuclear material which is section 51 of the atomic energy act in 1954 it says anything
that gives off a sizable amount of atomic energy literally that's what it says well what's sizable
and what legal gymnastics are you saying this stuff which is obviously not a well who knows
maybe it is a nuclear weapon and you're saying this is a u.s. nuclear secret you're trans
classifying it into a nuclear secret which i understand maybe at first why they did that
and i'm not admonishing the hard decisions that presidents and other folks did many years ago when
this was more of an enigma and we wanted to like lock it down figure it out and then see what we're
gonna do but there's never been a disclosure plan i always ask that like to these super senior
people i've talked to was there a plan any kind of plan at all and they're like no never we tried
the muddy to waters back and then you know tried to put it out there and test the populace but
you know there was never any cogent plan i mean people think the government
is like this fine oiled machine they have plans for everything well i guess sort of but like
it's not i mean look at the war and terrorism we left afghanistan no general officer mattis
betrayus mccrystal i call them the failed generals people loud them but really themselves in the
obama administration bush administration except you know trump whatever nobody had a cogent plan
for success and we were fighting people who are much less of an adversary than like our one of
our peers or near peers and we couldn't even win that war like what the fuck are we doing
but these protracted endless wars let's be real it's good for the industrial complex right so and
i'm not like admonishing the whole industrial complex for the record you know we need national
lethality we need weapons to kill bad guys because there's evil people in the world
but you've got to control you know some of it though well that's a part of the problem with
people that have secrets it's like once you have secrets and part of your identity is the holder
of those secrets yeah and part of the culture of these these industries is that they they are
the ones that have the access to that yeah and i saw that in conventional really black programs
i was a part of in my career it was almost like um you got that secret society vibe where it's like
if you're a career government servant uh your salary is not that great but knowledge is your
currency and what makes you special what rice bowl do you control and i remember getting
read into some stuff that like it was like the president and very limited number of people
getting read into and i was one of them because i was operating a certain thing for a certain op
and oh you're part of the club you know like only 30 people are cleared or whatever and i'm like
who the fuck i don't get off on this shit it's like it's so weird but like these like lifers
and i hate to you know talk so matter of fact about it but like it just it's kind of disgusting
to me because it's like this like uh it's weird it's like a weird like gnostic cultish thing
and you know i live that community for 14 years of my career and people really do enjoy having
information that other people don't have access to i was like i got a secret and like that's why i
whistle-blowed okay so i know this shit's real i know there we're not alone we have stuff no shit
am i gonna sit on my ass for 30 40 years i'm an old man i look back like ah i had that secret i
knew about it but i didn't do anything i didn't change so i couldn't just keep that secret because
i thought it was just perverse and wrong that the people don't even at least get to know the basics
it's insane so when it comes to these i'm gonna bring it back to these these actual entities
yeah do we know or we do have an understanding of how many of them we're talking about and the
variety of them well yeah there is a variety and we have a certain number of different things
but the like total numbers of like what's interacting with us on earth i mean nobody
knows that and i mean that there's an understanding of some that they do believe are interacting
with us and there's a variety in terms of there's there's variables yeah i talked to people who are
familiar with uh the biological analysis and everything so we have some idea not a complete
picture because it's like you know you know you're looking at it's like well i don't even understand
the physio physiology at all it's like what the heck it's like way different right so
um we have at least a description of this physiology yeah no i was in i was in the room
when uh
hey be careful i don't want to i was in washington dc with a very uh number of senior people that
work for members of congress put it that way um when i was still in government and
i brought the people who worked on that stuff to the hill i mean this is why the members were so
confident to put out the schumer amendment and stuff and i was like please explain and
they went into all those details and stuff and i remember you know some some of the professional
staff members were like whoa like like they were like in g-lock right because i mean it like a total
world bubble got burst right there for a lot of people and so we have some idea it's not a
complete picture i mean it's just like but you're not even bringing in the right the right people
like i think about my friend and colleague dr gary nolan which i started the sole foundation
non-profit with i mean he's like you know nobel level biologist virologist like he's the guy that
you would want on it but he's not on it so i think we can make a lot of progress in our
understanding once again if if this is more broadly studied um in an open environment
you aware of the nixon jackie gleason story vaguely i i stayed away from ufology because
i had these contemporary people that were inside i could check all their credentials where they
worked etc but i i'm vaguely familiar where what was it like nixon brought jackie gleason
to some facility and showed him some stuff or something like that yeah supposedly that's the
story and it's very it's very hard to determine the origin of the story or whether or not it's
real it came from there's a story about one article that was supposedly public was it vanity fair
don't make that and uh you can't find the story but jackie gleason by all accounts was obsessed
with ufos and uh even built a home in upstate new york that looked like a flying saucer oh really
yeah that's cool this is the house he had this house constructed supposedly after he had this
meeting with uh nixon so nixon supposedly they were drinking
jackie gleason and nixon are tying one on and nixon's like you want to see some shit
and uh they fly uh to wherever this base is yeah and he shows them these frozen biological entities
and this retrieved vehicle and then jackie gleason becomes a fanatic obviously that's crazy
yeah i mean not crazy but but uh that's interesting that a president would do that to
like an uncleared celebrity friend of his like oh let me just show you the most sensitive
shit our country has i don't know it's kind of crazy to me people are obsessed with celebrity
you know there's even world leaders you know kings and queens of you know they've always
been obsessed with famous people and jackie gleason at the time was incredibly famous and
also beloved right yeah so this is my pal and uh i'm drunk you want to see some shit you know i
get it i want to hang out with nixon if that's how it was like man well i said he was probably
wild i bet he was like that in a lot of ways you know i mean hunter s thompson famously recalled
his uh yeah there's the two of them meeting together uh famously recalled sitting in the
backseat of a limo with nixon talking about football and he was like god if i didn't think
he was a piece of shit i actually kind of like him oh that's funny yeah we're just talking
football yeah you know um look nobody in that job nobody as a president is going to be loved by
everyone and i'm sure nixon has positive qualities and you know if jackie gleason liked them i'm a
giant jackie gleason fan it's probably probably fun to hang out with yeah yeah if you're drunk
and you know you're the president also we're talking about the 1970s right so this is a
different world you know like even if you tell anybody who the fuck is going to believe you
you don't have you can't get on tiktok like what are you going to do how are you going to get this
information out oh exactly and that's kind of how you know in my personal opinion you know how the
program was protected right forever make make it crazy right so if anybody leaks anything um or
you know that has an unauthorized disclosure yeah people are gonna think you're fucking nuts of
course yeah yeah um but there are actual reports that we have biological remains
yes oh yes yes how many it's up there uh as well just like with the and they vary
there's different kinds do we have an understanding that you don't have to answer where of where they
came from nobody i talked to espoused any specific origin to me we may know that but
i'm not aware of anything so i don't know are there reports of some kind of interaction with
these things where they're giving information or discussing the the problems of humanity and
possible solutions or explaining why they're here interactions was a sensitive subject
that my interview subjects did not want to get into uh i suppose that there's probably detailed
documentation of those interactions that goes into a lot of the stuff you're asking i truly
don't even know the answer to a lot of that so but is there discussions amongst these people
that there have been these sort of there was water cooler talk with some people i talked to
on the program i love water cool yeah they're like hey bro guess what i overheard in some weird
meeting you know right and but that is the problem with that is it's like secondary information
right and i'm so anal retentive unless that person told me i had close personal i touched it whatever
like cool well you're coming to the inspector general or i'm gonna at least give them your
name because that's what you told me and then obviously i did that so those people who physically
were there were on the program did the thing i brought to the inspector general um are there
discussions of interactions with live beings uh there was some water cooler talk about that kind
of thing but that's it but you know i i don't even want to get into it because it's like
there were some details provided to me but it's like it's secondary and i i don't know if that's
like the telephone game and i don't know if it was hyperbolized in any way um you know in
the break room so to speak so i just i'm so anal about making sure what i say is accurate i don't
you know i don't know so yeah do we have an understanding i mean if if there have been
these discussions do we have an understanding of when they first took place
yeah some specific events were mentioned to me and i provided that information in a classified
setting and how far back did they go pretty far back it's pretty weird yeah so well one of the
stories from roswell that's fascinating to me is that eisenhower had the wreckage flown to
right paterson air force base in two separate jets in case one of them crashed there has been
some public testimony um so general debose there were some old timers that at least uh you know
did some videos in like the 90s like i'm i'm brigadier general exxon here's what i heard
whatever i mean that's out there in the the open source so yeah yeah and there was always a
discussion of hanger 18 right if you're a hanger 18 there's a lot of hangers that's the for whatever
reason i think it was maybe a movie was there a movie well you know you know it's funny speaking
of uh senators being denied there's a video in the late 80s of senator barry goldwater of goldwater
nickle zack famed right he was a two-star general in the air force reserve and uh like literally
this video is like on youtube it's like hard to find though but um jesse michaels on american
alchemy put together i think a short video yesterday and there's like a section there
where he actually has that goldwater interview but general goldwater is like yeah one day i called
curtis lame who's a very famous air force general and was like general i heard that there's this
room that you you know have ufo material and barry goldwater exposes in this interview like yeah and
lame got madder madder than hell at me and told me never to fucking ask ask about that again i
might have added the f word in there just for um for fun for fun but uh yeah it's bad the military
too long um my wife tells me to be careful with my language all the time around my niece and nephew
so but but even barry goldwater knew that we had ufo material he asked general lamay when he was
in the air force and general may basically told him to fuck off and that is a literal interview
you can google so a lot of this like people um disclosing fact of has really been out in the
vernacular for a long time but nobody really cared because well everybody was just kind of
like desensitized from the whole subject and thought it was wacky and i'm not the first
former government official to confirm that you have goldwater and all these other harry reid
who made the same disclosure to the new yorker a month after i talked to him in person melon
yeah melon has said stuff uh lou ellisando said uh you know he believes we have material on i
think it was tucker carlson a couple years ago um so there's certainly been other officials now i'm
just trying to spike the football and take it all the way to the end zone here and and luckily
we have a congress that's mostly motivated minus mike rogers and mike turner you're on you're
getting cool in your stockings i'm going to make sure your office gets cool and um uh you know they
they want change too and they realize it's time for a change and uh presumably you know chuck
schumer's talked to you know jake sullivan and president biden and you know who's in the white
house right now is john podesta he is the uh green energy czar or something like that in the
white house but you know john podesta uh um shout out to john podesta in the white house he
has an axe to grind on this issue too because remember he tweeted at the end of obama's second
term you know my biggest failure was not to have obama release the ufo file and made the same kind
of statement with clinton so certainly if mr podesta is listening in the white house you know
i'm here to help i you know i hope that you're championing this within the executive office of
the president and um you know the other speaking of people like goldwater who who've made some
weird non-sequitur kind of admissions there's a john stossel interview of mike pompeo the former
cia director about two years ago or so you can find it online where pompeo talks about
the jfk file and like dismisses it or something about like there's no boogeyman here but then
he he quickly says oh i've seen the ufo file too and we have bigger problems
but at least the way it was edited john stossel didn't even follow up uh at least the way the
final cut was i'm like dude if i was john stossel i've been like right what does that mean what do
you mean mike pompeo you've seen the ufo file and we have bigger problems and ufo file the way i
interpret that is a uh long existing file or briefing document or something that he
had access to so i think i think the former cia director mike pompeo should probably clarify what
he said two years ago next uh if anybody interviews him next ask mike that question what did he mean
yeah yeah we have bigger problems well we certainly have bigger problems in terms of our
current existence specifically with what you were talking about earlier the proxy wars and
collapse of society as we know it which it seems yeah i mean the i mean i feel for the ukrainian
and the israeli people you know i'm not taking any particular side but certainly people forget
us aid in these wars what's the like most expensive thing if you've studied phases of
conflict it's the reconstruction costs after the conflict so are we in it for like
triple digit billions like the war and terror i mean certainly the israeli conflict is a great
distraction because you know like russia is very tight with iran right and personal opinion you
know this is my own personal opinion but i you know i'm sure they commiserated and was like can
you start a two-front war because we would like to win in ukraine and uh this will distract the
u.s because israel is a long-time you know middle east ally so it's brilliant it's brilliant public
opinion i mean the the virtue signalers on social media have essentially completely forgotten about
ukraine it's it's all about israel and palestine yeah you don't even see it and um and i understand
you know what the national security council determination was that they've discussed publicly
where there's kind of like trying to drain the russia's you know military capability and
and annexation of ukrainian territory because they don't want russia sphere sphere of influence
to further enter that caucus region and stuff but yeah it's funny like you said it's like you don't
even talk about ukraine it's all about israel now and which is a horrible conflict on both sides like
it's just it's unfortunate so without a doubt yeah um it's that it was a very interesting
statement though that we have bigger problems so even if we do this seems to be like a
this is such a human question because it's one of the biggest mysteries
obviously you know there's the fermi paradox where are they right if you look out and if you look
out into the cosmos yeah if you've ever gone a clear night and you look out and you realize
those are all stars and those stars are all surrounded by planets and there's literally
hundreds of billions of them in the drake equation you can calculate what probable sentient
life yeah and i've been an amateur astronomer since i've been a kid and i've never
crazy enough i've never seen anything remarkable i've seen some stuff that could have been ball
lightning and some satellite passes that weren't registered uh online um what you can you could
actually check to see if there's gonna be like an iridium flare or something like that and that
maybe that was a satellite pass maybe not but i've never seen in my personal life
never seen anything weird uh and it's funny you mentioned the fermi paradox and it's like
well where are they and okay well you know if you're sentient life you're certainly going to have
sophisticated cover concealment and deception techniques it goes back to like what Jacques
Vallee's work is where you know the phenomenon presenting itself in different ways but also
i live in the mountains of colorado right so there is a mountain lion den about 10 miles from my house
in colorado literally um you know i am there are lower predatory sentience i'm higher
predatory sentience and i'm using this as a device or an analogy for nhi and us well
i don't on a day-to-day basis i don't care what a mountain lion is doing
i may hike in that area to explore but day to day i'm afraid of it and i don't care and think
about what humans might be unfortunately to some of these higher sentience where this monkey has
a nuke holy shit keep them in the cage we don't want to go anywhere near them and so people think
that there would be some kind of open contact with some higher sentience that is either visiting
earth or from another dimension or whatever the origin is but they probably don't care
they're probably neutral at best and maybe actually fearful of us in some sense
or we're the progeny of you know personal opinion progeny of some experiment and the
it's almost like living in the matrix but it's not like an actual simulation it's like we want
the simulation to go we don't want to intercede because we want to see what you know homo sapien
sapien 2.0 is going to do after the great flood or something like that right yeah yeah that's one of
the more fascinating ideas is that we're some sort of a product of genetic engineering i honestly
would not be surprised i don't know that to be true but we're so different than everything else
so different so beyond different i mean there's not another primate that is even reasonably
close i mean if you there's speculation amongst primatologists and there's a
not even speculation they believe that chimpanzees in particular have entered into the stone age
so they're at the beginning of the stone age they're using tools you know and this is obviously
some learned behavior like there's some footage of orangutans using spears to hunt fish with
oh interesting yeah have you ever seen that no i'm not it's cool shit there's an orangutan that's
hanging on a branch over a river or a body of water and stabbing at fish with spear huh which
is incredible i mean they're using tools i mean we know they use tools to extract
um you know termites and the like look at that i mean oh that's crazy how crazy is that i mean
he's clearly hunting i mean he's going fishing in borneo i mean that that is you know at the very
least a distant cousin of us some you know intelligent primate that is to figure out a
way to use tools how long would it take an orangutan to become a human being how many
millions of years are we talking about of evolution but it seems to be that process has started
interesting but why are we so fucking different than yeah like are we a product of darwinian
evolution or what is a punctuated equilibrium is obviously another theory and i'm not a
anthropologist by any means you know i watched some netflix episodes but yeah me too a lot of
youtube but yeah we we seem to be oddly advanced advanced and we seem to just possess other skills
i mean it goes back to like the stargate program right you know with the declassified by clinton
and sensibly cancelled i guess in 96 you know where you had people trained in remote viewing
and and like there was feedback loops to confirm what they saw was real and either satellite
imagery or human sources where they sketched out a room of where there's hostages and
they got a hostage out and they're like and this is a real story actually and they're and they're
like did you have a source in that room how do you know where all the corridors were and everything
i was like no actually uh pat price remote viewed you and he's like what the fuck so
there's something going on there and and that's like uh gary nolan you know has studied a lot of
this stuff very famously he's pointed out the caudate patanum in the brain right this horseshoe
shaped thing in the middle of your brain that if uh he's done mri's and cat scans and i hope i'm
not butchering his work gary might you know slap me later but uh it lights up with people who have
those kind of skills they have like an overactive caudate patanum in the brain and it's like okay
well is it a transceiver of some sort i'm guessing that's the case is it an emerging
property of human beings as we have exactly and we're seeing just a few human beings that have
this stuff and then if if it is a transceiver where's the information is it in a higher
spatial dimension or how are they extracting how are they able to basically be um uh non-locality
right they're able to like project themselves somehow their consciousness to a and this is a
declassified example from stargate a russian missile base sketch the crane and where the
silos are what the status is you know satellite comes over takes a picture and it's exactly the
way they sketched it how did they do that like it's certainly real real because there is a
feedback loop now there's a lot of charlatans in the psychic space and all that but like at
least that government program and i've talked to you know how put off and people who actually ran
that program at sri for the cia then dia in the army and that seems to be the men who's
staring at goats right the george clooney movies the famous movie based on the stargate program
seems to be legit as far as we can measure from a feedback perspective what was the explanation
for the discontinuation of that program oh gosh i'm not a scholar on that that something
russell targ or hal putov or one of those guys could explain if it was just like i got caught
up in the bureaucracy or or what i don't remember yeah yeah so the idea of that being an emergent
property of uh of human beings as we evolve has always been fascinating to me because there's
there's certainly something that goes on with human communication other than we make sounds
that represent objects and physical things and that the other person interprets those sounds
and understands it there's communication between human beings that's oh acoustic communication
like the symbol rate if you will is really slow like if you were able to consciously communicate
aka you know the hokey term like telepathy right and it's funny because that's what a lot of
people espouse that have had you know alleged contacts right a lot of the people that
dr john mack at harvard studied over the years where they felt like they were getting hit with
like a qr code it was like instant knowledge or they heard like somebody speaking to them
non-verbally in some way that they couldn't even conceptualize through you know acoustic
communication or talk if you will and it's the same thing like um book proof of heaven by dr
ebb and alexander md i remember reading it when i was in afghanistan and i was like this is a
crazy experience this medical doctor has necrotizing fatty fasciitis of the brain
is a near-death experience and he gets this like crazy like the feelings of love other stuff it's
a really interesting book it's like a scientific take on a doctor's own near-death experience
but when he came back and somehow the fasciitis didn't eat away his brain and he was cognitively
normal he tried to write down what information or facts of the universe he learned during his nde and
he couldn't even put it in english it was like crazy he didn't know how to translate it
into our language it was just there was no like adjectives if you were adverbs etc
that could describe the knowledge that he knew like natively when he had that near-death experience
it's a really fascinating book um and he talks about the disease he had and his
physiological condition at the time really interesting what was he able to discern from
that like what was what was the overall message yeah it was like this like the you know there's
the message of love which so that's that's positive but it was like this interconnectedness
everybody is kind of connected in a way that um they don't really realize i mean you think about
this is getting really trippy uh a lot of thoughts with people who are smarter than me i like to talk
to them about this kind of stuff where if you're say you know higher dimensional sentience right
the act of creation so act of creation for 3d beings is having a baby right it's producing
another three-dimensional object well if you're in five-dimensional space or even i guess four
dimensional physical space what if act of creation is creating other conscious realities in other
universes and the act of creation is creating the universe where you me jamie whatever we might be
connected to the same um i'll call it universal consciousness or a higher dimensional sentient
life force or life form i know that sounds like really out there but when you think about it
there's a lot of other theologies out there that basically expels that i have a very good friend
of mine who's a phd level kind of higher up in the mormon church and basically the mormon theology
is kind of like that the mormons say you were once with god or like god but then you were sent
down to like a lower plane of existence and that's literally what i'm talking about right now but just
in a secular sense so maybe uh you're all created beings from and this you know this doesn't like
hurt christian theology whatever it's actually kind of enforcing the fact there's a creator and
we're literally created in the image of a creator literally and that's kind of what life really is
it's like think about it's like a weird 3d plus time temporal sensory experience for a higher
dimensional sentience you're here to experience time in this weird linear fashion and to experience
yourself divorced from yourself to gain knowledge and to report back is maybe what life is and that's
just kind of my own personal theology as a summation of just during covid i was really
bored and then and that's what i was looking at well i yeah i extrapolate that to the creation
of ai and i think if you think about human beings as something that creates things um i think
ultimately we create a new life exactly what if higher sentience is creating some kind of
artificial intelligence you know call it like a commander data from star trek next gen right
not even really it's made in the image of the creator in some sense but it's not even and
that's what might get sent into these like uh long endurance you know missions and of course you know
people are like well why would they you know come here so far uh to crash etc or are they crashing
on purpose do you know that for a fact or are they crashing by accident and what if they're like um
like von neumann replicating probes right you can google that but you know what if they're just
throw away which von neumann probes are just like throw away spacecraft like yeah they're just
we send it out we don't really care what the mission success is or they're seeding us
or as jock valet says it's like you know here's the key can you unlock the cage kind of thing
right yeah so and it seems that it would be a long i mean if you think about biological evolution
so long lengthy process and if ultimately that led us to the creation of a technology that's far
superior in terms of its capabilities of understanding and thinking that seems to be what's happening
and that's one of the reasons why so many people are concerned about the term artificial
intelligence is a very strange term because it's not artificial it's intelligence it's silicon
based at a carbon base yeah it's just it doesn't have blood and tissue and cells but it has
something that's superior but also something that's much more scalable right we're we have a very
obvious biological limitation in terms of evolution you know if you look at evolution
when we turn back to the orang tans that are fishing they're obviously learning new things
and those new properties from those new things we assume will be encoded in their genetics
and then pass to their children do you have children no i have three dogs we went the fluffy
i'm a fluffy dad the problem is dogs don't learn from what they do but one of the most bizarre
things about children is that they have properties that are clearly uh it's hard to say right um
because my children obviously have the example of my wife myself and they obviously see
a lot of how we live our life and you know uh discipline and hard work and creativity and all
those things but there's also they seem to have gifts that are they seem to be clearly genetic
yeah and uh artistic gifts that just seem extraordinary that are unusual that i had
when i was younger that i was an illustrator i have a young daughter that's just extraordinarily
good at art really used to illustrate yeah yeah that's what i wanted to do i want to be a comic
book illustrator oh interesting interesting yeah um but then i have this other daughter that's
super gifted athletically like she can learn things really quickly it's extraordinary it's
and it's weird and and also this drive that she has i had a drive from poverty and from you know
a lot of like stuff that was wrong with my childhood that seemed to be i had this need
to prove myself she doesn't have any of those problems but she also has this insane drive
it's weird it's a weird discipline it's extraordinary that seems to be very different
than most kids and i i just think that's an emerging genetic i think there's something encoded
in whatever you are as a human that as you replicate and as you have children they have
that they have some of that yeah you know and i think that is this process this biological
evolutionary process with humans but it's there's so much chaos there's so much i mean you could
breed with a dumb person you can find a hot dumb person have a baby with them now your kid's
fucked yeah and then we see that this is like this obviously some people are just born with
brains that just don't work that well it's just like i'm sure you've met some dull-minded people
and try to talk to them about things and there's no one there you right so okay good luck and good
luck with whatever children you have and whatever what what what are they gonna have well they weren't
genetically yeah we're genetically encoding artificial intelligence now kind of i think
that's where you were going yeah what i'm going with it like these biological limitations that
we have it's it's very clear that we're essentially dealing with a model t as opposed to a tesla which
is just insanely superior to these ancient vehicles yeah we we create technology i've always said this
if you looked at the human race if you were some sort of an outside observer and you stumbled upon
this this thing that occupies this planet this this apex predator of this planet you would say
what is this thing doing what's making technology all the other things that it does it does all
these other things that also but what do these things generally motivate what do they move
towards they move towards the advancement of technology and innovation that is a constant
aspect of human beings if you trace us back to the earliest civilizations to what we have today
things constantly improve unless something goes horribly wrong unless there's some sort of a
natural disaster or some sort of a you know genocide if something doesn't happen to these
creatures what do they do they consistently make better things well that if you extrapolate if you
follow that to its natural progression well what is that going to get to well once they've invented
computers and once they've invented devices and once they've invented things that enhance their
personal understanding of the world around them which we already have now with phones we already
have with the internet we already have with our ability to communicate with each other we are
the the newest latest android phones that are coming out will translate natively on your phone
in real time in conversation so you could be speaking portuguese to me i would hear it in
english on a phone call which is fucking wild it's crazy it's like universal translators star trek
literally yes literally literally well that that is a real thing now without having to use google
translate it's native to the latest android operating system you you could autumn if you
just sit down and said well where's that going well it's going to something way more sophisticated
and way more capable than we are biologically with our limitations the our monkey bodies we are the
ancestors or the the the the people that emerged from that distant cousin that orangutan that's
using a stick to hunt fish we're we're going in this direction yeah what would be the most logical
way we would completely accelerate that we create something that does what we do but does it way
better yeah it's almost like to permanently harbor our consciousness eventually right right and that
kind of makes sense right it does make sense and there's a sort of an understanding of that
that leads to this fear of our demise that everyone you know elon's openly discussed this
sam altman and i were talking about it what open ai is doing what chat gbt4 versus chat gbt5
which is going to be insanely superior well what is chat gbt15 going to do you know is that going
to be the president of the world you know like what are we going to bypass government and just
say you know it's it's obviously like this administration is incredibly corrupt and flawed
and influenced by the military industrial complex it's not good for the world it's not good for the
environment we need something that is far superior that doesn't have all these motivations
what would that be that would be an artificial intelligent creator that we or a creation rather
that we use to govern life yeah i mean that sounds nuts but i think that's probably a better solution
than humans with all of our fucking flaws and issues and greed and envy and all the things
that we have that that would be a better version of it but what are we saying then are we saying
that we're we're programming like empathy into it though you know probably not probably not which
is terrifying but we will become obsolete and or we will merge and if we merge it will completely
change what we are and i think that's very likely what's going to take place i think the initial
stages will be some sort of a merging with technology and then from that merging it will
essentially we'll realize well why are we even fucking around like this this new thing is so
superior and it doesn't have all the pitfalls it doesn't have all the problems it's not short-sighted
it's not going to drain the ocean of fish so that we we can make sushi it's going to do something
it's going to be far more far more aware of all of the different effects of each individual act
and how we affect everything around us and what is net positive and what is net negative
and how to avoid all these things i i really firmly believe that we are this biological
caterpillar that is making a cocoon to create the electronic butterfly and we don't even know
what we're doing while we're doing it we're just doing it and i think materialism is also baked
into that one of the main problems with human beings in terms of like the ridiculousness of
our actions we're so materialistic people are constantly wanting to get the newest latest
greatest thing what's the motivation behind that other than social status well the motivation is
that that's what that's what fuels innovation if you do like if we all just stopped right now
and said hey you know what iphone 15 is pretty fucking dope we don't need to make new iphones
let's just keep fixing those and just like exist the way we are right now and let's clean up the
air let's clean up the ocean let's clean up the sea and clean up the rivers and clean up the
forests like let's just fix the earth yeah and then no we don't do that we know i want iphone
16 you know when when is the iphone going to be able to communicate completely just with satellites
we don't have to worry about cell phones it's almost like a drug addiction right they did
studies where people receiving in text messages is the dopamine rush too yeah so it's almost like
an artificial drug addiction you're fueling because you want the more responsive tech more
integrating with your make easier so you can get your fix quicker and more efficiently or something
like that i don't know and why yeah well i mean why would fucking staring at a stupid cell phone
give you a dopamine rush well it does it does it does yeah i'm not a biologist and you get addicted
to your goddamn phones and then why would it be that we would innovate and create things like
instagram and tiktok that are insanely addictive to the point where you look down and you've spent
three hours staring at nothing nonsense like what what why is that well that ensures continual use
of this device until it lures you into this ultimate integration well it's right well they
there's people at meta i guess now or facebook you know where they actually have a whole team
of scientists on how to make their apps more addictive right so demons yeah fucking yeah i
don't use social media i have never tweeted in my life really that's amazing i mean i have like
i used facebook back in the day when it first first came out when i was going to college
yeah i don't have instagram i've never tweeted in my life i don't intend to because you don't
want to get sucked into that mind virus which is like people responding you and you have to feel
like you have to respond back i don't even yeah i don't even touch it well i'm very aware of those
traps so i don't i don't do that yeah i don't i used to but many years ago i stopped interacting
with people because i just realized like overall it's negative yeah like there's positive aspects
to it it's great for people that like you and their fans it's great too that you're an actual
human that you interact occasionally a comment on a post like that's really awesome congratulations
that kind of stuff then i get the fuck out of there and i don't read any responses and i found
that that's the very best way to mitigate all the negative aspects of social media but then you're
also dealing with algorithms you're dealing with things that recognize what makes you more likely
to engage and so those things are constantly showing you the things that you engage and
you know it's not necessarily even positive it's just it's just whatever you engage with
what's coming your way whether it could be cool stuff like maybe you're just like really into
muscle cars and shows you a lot of muscle cars or it could be like murder like i see a lot of
murder on instagram yeah fucking crazy yeah i'm a car guy so like my feed is like oh do you ever
think about this mod for your ford bronco oh those lights look nice i'm gonna wire that shit up next
week you know so yeah i get those too yeah it's bad yeah i have a problem with that i have a car
problem yeah my wife doesn't allow me to have the good stuff anymore so i have to you know keep it
under a certain price that's good that's good i i'm more actually interested in old stuff than
i am in new stuff you like uh like rat rod stuff right well i like muscle cars like this very
specifically 1960s muscle cars those are my favorite because what they are to me is it's a
toy that you could drive yeah it's like a ride that gives me immense pleasure to just drive around
and it's really fun i don't even have to go fast it's just going around in a 1970 cheval just
driving it it just it's hard to describe for someone who has never experienced it but it's
just uh it's just so engaging and it's like you're on this drug yeah it's like everything
you feel all of it and you're engaging all of these senses yeah very tactile very mechanical
i under yeah i totally understand that i mean the only kind of old cars i like are like uh
black lincoln lincoln continental suicide doors from the matrix i remember seeing that when i
was a teen when the matrix came out i'm like that car is badass yeah it's like totally i want like
have whatever morpheus drove there are yeah they're essentially art it's it's it's functional art
like you could it's a piece of art that you could actually drive around it yeah and it gives you
this very bizarre sensation but the point is like that's not most people most people want the newest
latest greatest thing and this there's a motivation to get the newest latest greatest thing that i
think if you just follow that up to its logical conclusion it's going to create life it's going
to create i mean how many films have been made about this you know x machina and all these
different films that's right yeah that's what we're gonna do we're gonna i mean there's no way
we're not gonna do that it's it's if if i had a bet on one thing if the human race doesn't get
wiped out by a media or a nuclear war we're gonna fucking do that we're gonna make a life form
100 and it's going to be almost instantaneously able to figure out all the flaws in its own
personal programming and make a much better version of itself if it if it's sentient if it
has the ability to make decisions well i think we're close i mean i think i saw some stuff there's
like a open ai fiasco going on right now and there's rumor that they might have cracked
artificial general intelligence right a gi and that's oh jeez that's frightening i mean
it was like was it sam altman i think we're talking about i think there's like a the board
of open ai there's some shuffle i was just they just removed when i woke up this morning yeah
well they removed him but then apparently the shareholders like what the fuck are you doing
and there was so much outrage that they're trying to bring him back like instantly so but but elon
had a very good point like what was the motivation behind that and when you think about the
implications for humanity as a whole because this is such an emerging technology that's so
overwhelmingly powerful what happened like what's going on like i think this is one of those things
where like we need to know like what was the motivation behind your decision and if it was
that he was holding back information about the actual creation of artificial general
intelligence that it's already it's already happened and that he's like hesitant because
he's a little cagey in how he talks about stuff when i was talking to him about you could tell
it's like a little bit like he kind of knows yeah that he is at the forefront of this technology
that worst case scenario replaces us yeah and you know going back to is a program with any kind of
empathy etc depending on if it handles critical i guess the thing i saw in the government because
i did a lot of cyber stuff in my career is as ai gets more advanced you you know you create say
offensive cyber tools that literally have a mind of their own and if say theoretically you release
that on some target and you might not be able to touch that target again say it's a one-time
whoop you put it in there well how do you control it's almost like skynet and the terminator hate
to use that analogy but like that was my fear when i was working at certain agencies working
on offensive cyber tools i'm like oh my god this is not good and then of course with cyber right
it's the attribution actor attribution is the biggest thing how do you know it was you know
hypothetically russia that used the cyber weapon to attack you it could have been another actor
masquerading as that foreign power using tactics techniques procedures ip proxy operations to
hide where it was coming from right so it's like you have uh non-kinetic fires that can
potentially create mutually assured destruction because you could take out critical infrastructure
blow up the power grid etc no radiation but potentially no attribution or can you know
confuse the attribution such that you don't even know who to go to war with it's like really scary
so it is scary yeah that's just my own it's already happening with social media yeah i mean
think about how many troll farms there are on social media that are just stirring up discontinue
i mean it's an active program that we know that russia uses that is trying to undermine democracy
and try to keep people fighting with each other and it's been very effective and if you look at
social media it's just fucking chaos it's just people yelling at you particularly twitter or x
you know that's and facebook it's like a lot of what's going on one of the studies showed that
out of the top 20 christian sites that are on facebook 19 of them are run by russian troll farms
so if we know that that on a like relatively rudimentary scare scale if you look at the
impact of social media versus the impact of artificial intelligence they're already doing
that they're already hiding who's responsible and what's the what's the goal and how to manipulate
consciousness and how to manipulate uh influence and how people think about things and what what
the public opinion on things are it's already very effective um you would imagine that a creation of
artificial intelligence would radically accelerate that 100 then i remember the deep fake stuff was
a real problem for my old community because we're like holy shit you could really fake some stuff
and you got to develop algorithms to make sure you can analyze oh hey that that is fake because
you've seen some of the deep fakes where it's like obama or arnold schwarzenegger yes you know the
tom cruise guy holy shit that is crazy like you're going to be able to bring actors from the dead back
at this point you're going to have like carrie grant uh you know doing a musical or whatever
whatever you know well bruce willis who has uh some sort of degenerate degenerative neurological
condition sold his likeness for the ability to make commercials and all sorts of other things
like he's essentially saying he's fading unfortunately and now he will give this thing
which is this property which is bruce willis this famous person and they will be able to create
versions of him starring in films oh and certainly if you train an ai model just like chat gpt
you could actually get almost like what they would normally say what their knowledge 100
and it's almost like uh having a permanent historian too you could like you know if you
want to talk to clenice wood about his films in the 60s after clenice wood you know passes you
know may live forever but like that would be it'd be crazy i mean really interesting but i mean he
might actually be able to give you advice he might be your personal advisor i know that'd be cool i
mean that's probably one of the things that's going to come out of this but when we think about
empathy we we also think about just human beings and the way we communicate and interact with each
other empathy is very important and also compassion and forgiveness all these things are very
important qualities because we recognize that we're very flawed but when you create something
that is not flawed yeah then the need for empathy the need for all these things that we attach to
human emotions and human reward systems they will they'll no longer be a significant issue
because you're going to be dealing with something that operates on a higher plane
it might be the answer to all that ails us which is so terrifying for us because we recognize that
what we derive the joy that we derive from love from companionship from friendship from community
it's like a key component to life on earth for us but it's also because we recognize that without
that we are the mongols without that we're nazi germany without that you know we're hamas we're
whatever the fuck we are that's that we recognize as being like evil or dangerous or horrible
about humans that when we think about the worst case scenario for human beings we always think
about things like the holocaust we think about what is the worst the worst acts that human beings
are capable of with our current programming and our biological flaws like what are the worst things
we can do to terrible awful things well if we don't have those problems if we no longer have
envy we no longer have greed we no longer have evil we don't have any of those properties they
don't they don't exist anymore we just have this new form of consciousness that's far superior
that's an interesting parallel because you have you know you're no longer maybe apex sentience
if you have artificial intelligence you know governing certain things right and i think
that's also kind of this psychological issue with this uap issue where we might not be the apex
predator we have we may be that mountain lion and yes and we're going to have to be comfortable
knowing that we're going to be vulnerable there's people far superior that may have malevolent
intentions maybe not i don't know and almost be humbled the fact that like sorry we're not the
smartest of god's creation and yeah and that might be really hard for a lot of people to process and
i think that's probably certainly i would imagine one of the deliberations they must have done years
ago we're like oh we can't disclose because you know people are not going to feel comfortable
in that world view 100 percent and they're not and then i wonder if these things that we're
experiencing are the natural progression of what happens when you do seed life on planet or you do
accelerate biological life you do have some sort of a genetic intervention where you take this thing
that it has emerging intelligence and you accelerate it and that that thing will in turn with all of
its desire for innovation and creativity and also all of its desire to control resources and
and have power and have influence that it will eventually lead to the creation of what we're
seeing that these things are the next stage of this process and that maybe we're dealing with
one form of that next stage but there's another stage that's a million years more advanced than
that that's far superior that doesn't even have a biological limitation in terms of physical space
that it exists completely in some other undetectable realm yeah that is not no longer
no longer thinks about biological limitations of life and death and and communication it exists
completely in some other space that that's what these things are and then i always wonder when
there's a crash or when there's a body or when there's a this and that like and people saying
well what if they're so advanced why are they crashing well hold on what what which which
version are we looking at we're not saying there's one thing that's visiting us if there's one thing
that's visiting us and we know where this one thing is we could say oh well that thing it deals
with a completely different solar system that's not as vulnerable it doesn't have asteroid clouds
it doesn't have all these different things where it's like it doesn't have a planet that has super
volcanoes maybe life evolved in a more stable environment and it allowed it to get to a far
greater technological level but not the ultimate yeah we might be testing the extent of their
adaptability and like i said are they crashing by accident right mission failure or on purpose
right so and then of course with the far distances and everything i mean if they're traveling here
through some kind of space time metric engineering construct you know the distances are not as vast
as you think right it could be going through some kind of you know traversable wormhole or
something like that where it's like a walk down the street for them it's not you know a thousand
light years well just think about communication just our communication used to be you had to get
in front of someone and they had to talk to them so you had to know their language you had to
either non-verbal or verbal communication you had to figure out a way to say things to them yeah
that's no longer the case obviously with this new android operating system it translates but
also the fact that you could have a fucking face time call with someone in japan right now
and you instantaneously can communicate back and forth which is insane that's a vast distance but
for us it's like stupid it's like yeah easy vast distance and we're tunneling yeah yeah i mean uh
i was just in scotland and i was facetiming my daughter back home yeah fucking crazy you're
nine hours by plane and you're having instantaneous communication which is wild
shit but that's just that's fucking that that's like pong you know that's uh that's morse code
that's like it's very primitive in terms of what if you physically can be in these places
instantaneous yeah and why why would we assume that that's not eventually going to be on the menu
yeah it's just like the conventional propulsion stuff we're not using an ilama starship to get
here it's like they're doing something else we talked to someone from the 1800s and he said
you're going to go to nevada jesus christ you know how far that is on a wagon you know that's months
man right no you fly to vegas it's two hours yeah it's fucking easy you know like we know that now
so why would we assume that there's a limitation to that advancement i don't think yeah and of
course a friend of mine eric weinstein certainly exposes we don't even have the right theoretical
frameworks right now he's you know he get he he has his own geometric unity theory and yeah he's
way smarter than he's too smart but uh he's confusing yeah he starts talking to you like
i so funny if he calls me i'm like you got to call me in the morning after my 24 ounce monster
energy drink or or i can't even keep up man it's like uh so yeah he's he's on another level he has
he's got some unique theories himself about where all this stuff is coming from and uh it's it's all
very very very interesting and intriguing but also makes sense all of it makes sense including
being visited you know i had this conversation with neil degrasse tyson like why would they be
interested in us i'm like what the fuck are you talking we're super interested yeah neil i mean
obviously he's a fine science communicator kind of the success and of successor of kind of the
uh carl sagan kind of i think carl sagan was a little bit more open-minded yeah i like carl
better yeah i'm more of a fan yeah i wish he was still alive i'd love to smoke weed with that guy
he was really into weed oh really yeah really really into it i remember my my aunt gave me
cosmos by carl sagan when i was in middle school and it was that book was from the 80s but that
book tripped me out yeah and i was like i want to study science and i read it was brief history of
time by steven hawking and i read those two books when i was like in eighth grade and i was like
this is trippy i want to study astronomy this is insane but i ultimately use kind of my technical
background to be a spook you know for the government but i still observe i have a big
telescope and i live like super dark skies in colorado and i still have that boyhood fascination
of the cosmos now ironically i found out something else that kind of confirms that the cosmos is
not lifeless and you know god paints with a broad brush as like the vatican has expoused a couple
years ago when they said this is okay with their theology i have a theory that the universe itself
is god i think that's like what i was talking about with the you know multi-dimensional creator
creating universes yeah i think we have a very limited idea of when we say god when god created
the heavens and they're like right right but what is what are we saying i think it's the universe
itself i think it's one thing and that this one thing it seeks to create these things that
continually push the envelope and maybe gods themselves eventually i think if you extrapolate
from our ability versus the ability of an amoeba and you continue to move that along what does that
do well it's going to be able to create universes there's already been like theoretical papers that
have been written about the creation of other things like black holes other things like a
universe so the like what what is involved in the creation of a universe what is involved in the
big bang can that be replicated well not now but if ai becomes sentient and ai eventually makes
far greater versions of itself if it keeps doing that like what what what are the limits of its
potential create creates the matrix literally literally literally creates a simulated environment
that's in detect indiscernible you you can't tell the difference between that and regular life
well maybe because there is no difference maybe that is what i mean that's the theory of simulation
theater yeah simulation theory yeah familiar and that that is a possibility because uh the universe
seems like a little too perfect it's a little strange very created to me so just like we're in
the goldilocks zone right perfect temperature like it's just real how about the big bang itself
yeah what what happened something smaller than the head of a pin for for no known reason becomes
everything yeah okay and what's the universe expanding into right it's like a quantum foam
or whatever the heck the latest theory is that's like beyond me and then it perhaps just retracts
back down to that infinitely small thing and then expands again yeah and that this is an endless
cycle and that we're just so limited because of our biological limitations or our life and death
is such a small little tiny blip it's so minuscule in terms of just the overall known life of the
universe and then you have the james webb telescope that's you know there's people that question the
actual length of time that occurred between the big bang and now that maybe it might be far longer
and there's people like brian keating they say that's not that's not correct it's just a
a lack of understanding of what we understand currently about the creation of galaxies yeah
because i mean obviously the length of the age of the universe keeps on getting older and older and
a lot of that's because of the the doppler fit doppler shift right the red shift as the galaxies
are accelerating away you know we can calculate what the what their origin point probably was
and how long it took for them to speed up like that right so it only based on our current
understanding yes which is obviously at least fairly limited in terms of what its potential is
well yeah like we still don't quite understand the origin of the moon the moon is at the right
location that causes solar and lunar eclipses it's like the right apparent size to block out the sun
it's like super weird same thing with like mars we're not sure like what happened near where mars
you know had some probable life on it either a proto planet hit it or there was some kind of
impact that vaporized stuff and like who knows yeah who knows and this is just this little tiny
neighborhood that we're looking at it's like we are in our backyard looking for evidence of like
life in africa you know i mean like you're not going to figure it out here there's so there's
just we're just looking at it such a small scale in terms of what we could potentially discover or
potentially observe yeah yeah i i often wonder you know when we're seeing especially with the idea of
uaps ufo crafts if we're seeing a version of what we will become or something like us becomes if
given enough time well that that is i mean there's like a dr mike masters at montana state he
literally postulates you know he says time travelers we could debate time travel but
like he thinks it might be like a advanced form of homo sapien is what we're seeing coming back
yeah like a breakaway civilization or coming back to see an older version of ourselves that was left
on earth or something like well the way we would visit like north sentinel island and and visit
those people that are trapped on that island that are yeah uncontacted yeah yeah exactly and
then a lot of uh you know there's also like cargo cult religions and stuff you know the
south pacific and world war ii they worshiped the p51 and stuff like they thought those were ufos
but really they were just us you know yeah and i think we were probably alien to them i mean oh
yeah i mean just look at how cortez looked uh to the the people that you know had no idea that
people could ride horses like what the fuck is going on these guys are riding horses yeah like
these are gods these white guys coming in what the heck they come on a ship in the ocean and
they ride horses yeah yeah exactly yeah it's it's all based on our limited understanding and
for someone whether it's the federal government or whether it's military contractors for someone
to have key elements that could give us a better understanding of this whole picture
it's it's really inexcusable to not relay that to all of humanity so this is too much information
to be secret it's too important if it is real it's too important for someone to have access to
just because they have power and money and influence yeah it seems insane i mean that's
the whole primer for what i did i mean it's uh i i you know i think i'm a pretty more unethical
person i just could not live with myself if i didn't try to like make a difference even though
it was very uncomfortable personal privacy and you know professional and personal health was at
risk you know so it also seems like the public understanding and appreciation of these things
particularly after the 2017 article in the new york times has changed there's been a shift
whereas before if you would talk about ufos or the idea of extraterrestrial life you are
automatically lumped into this group of people that believes in bigfoot you know it's like you're in
you're in the Loch Ness monster you're kind of a loon who likes fringe things because
probably got problems in your own life you're not addressing and so you're distracted it's like
a gambler or something like that you're just like distracting yourself with this craziness
in order to ignore the the reality of existence itself which is so complicated and difficult to
manage and then i think that if we had a better understanding of the the overall scale of the
potential of life in the universe based on what we know like physical evidence undeniable physical
evidence that shows us that we're not alone that would be a massive change in just the overall
shift of consciousness on earth if we could understand that these territorial disputes
that we have which are almost always over resources or over land or over religions and
ideologies if we could understand that these are nonsense in the vast scope of the universe itself
and this is the uh the what's that effect that the people that get into the space station have
oh the uh overview effect yes the William Shatner had that when he went up in the uh blue origin
yeah i'm sure i'm sure everybody has it i mean i'm sure it's just like you go like oh my god like
what are we doing like this is one and that's how i felt i mean like after i found all this stuff i
could have continued my career you know made lieutenant colonel here this winter made senior
executive service in a year or two did national security stuff but i'm like sitting in my office
and i'm like there's better things for me to care about than russian troop movements like
we're not alone right this is insane like i i have to like blow the whistle on this is insane
because certainly the people who we talked to are not lying and the documents i meticulously went
through they were not forgeries they were not deception material so it's just like i have to
do something i'm sure you've seen those uh freedom of information act disclosure
papers from the cia from god it was like the 1950s where they're detailing all the various forms of
life and that that we know are currently that currently exist and you remember that jamie we
pulled up that document do you think you can find it jamie will find it but it's like 1950 something
where they were discussing these things interesting yeah i'm not sure which ones you're talking about
i'd have to see them so it's pretty weird stuff because like if they knew about this in the 1950s
like how do they know well there was like cia docs about consciousness and like weird remote
viewing stuff i mean besides the stargate program uh that were released in the foya reading room on
cia's website too that are pretty trippy we're like wow cia is looking into some really interesting
stuff i mean they're a hardcore intel agency uh what's going on there but it makes sense that
they would kind of have to find out if that's bullshit or not like you can't ignore that if
you're really doing your job if your job is intelligence like okay like let's look at this
it's an aspect of the phenomenon because it's like a reach out from the crash retrieval program
like hey i need you to look into some weird stuff because it might be the key unlock for
something that we got in a warehouse you know so whoa yeah yeah so as it stands right now
what what's the future for this stuff what's the future for these disclosures and and what yeah
what are the bottlenecks well i mean certainly from the governmental process you know as long
as the house doesn't kill the schumer amendment and i'm you know that's why i'm discussing it here
with you because if they they don't pass it it's going to be the greatest setback to humankind
in u.s history literally that so the presidential panel gets and paneled about 90 days or so after
the passage of the bill so by by christmas as long as it doesn't get killed will be in the national
defense authorization act panel will be formed um say february march then they have a 300 day
process to develop a initial plan for the president and i don't know if uh chuck schumer
and his staff are being kind of as crafty or whatever but the 300 days if you actually do it
out it's like the election so so i don't know if they want to make it an election issue which
certainly if this act doesn't pass i think it needs to be an election issue because the senior
executive needs to rule on this if congress can't get their shit together to be quite honest
and we have a plan out the 2030 where this stuff starts getting rolled out knock on wood perfect
storm things could get delayed but then in parallel and that's kind of why i helped found
the soul foundation with gary nolan and dr peter scafe who's an anthropologist uh as well
is we wanted to figure out the stem outreach we wanted to figure out the public policy national
policy to advise the u.s and its allies on this issue you know and we're happy like i said i'm
not here to slap the government in its entirety and admonish everybody like i think there needs
to be a truth and reconciliation process but i think our foundation we want to be like okay well
bring us in as a think tank if you know based on my experience and experience of my colleagues
like you have an issue with x well let's figure out how to rule this out and how to you know
incentivize the national science foundation to look in this make this like you know it's dual
use right you might um develop a unique uh scientific uh process that actually works well
with nanobiology or something like that but also has dual use with uap so there's parallel tracks
i mean there's public discovery there's like the galileo project with avi lobe right that they're
trying to uh on their own collect techno signatures which is i applaud that i mean obviously the
government knows a lot about that but we don't want to obviously rely on the u.s government to
do all the work for us and also to be honest so i think having a parallel track and you know
galileo project soul foundation ryan graves has his own foundation as well for pilots and people
who've seen unique things to provide that data to people so i think you got to have those dual
tracks and you know hopefully we can create a tsunami event where the u.s government its allies
and maybe the our adversaries but really if the u.s government doesn't get their house in order
here i mean you could have a uncontrolled disclosure events such that either maybe the
non-human intelligence is like yeah let's do it or what if one of our adversaries decides to
disclose and they become the messiah figure on this and we lose sovereignty or national supremacy
and then that regard from an open and honest civil society perspective so i but i think the
governments were getting close i think as long as closer than we've ever been before yeah just the
fact that they brought you in to have these conversations yeah no i'm i'm still advising
the u.s government on this and and and i'm trying to carefully message this put all the broad
things on the table and i'm not trying to be coy i'm not trying to be conceal anything but it's
like there's real national security and collateral damage with just releasing this willy nilly and
i'm just trying to get the government to get a plan together here and and just be open and
honest with the people of the world really so and there's still the bottleneck with these military
contractors that allegedly have access to these things yeah and like to to those guys and i know
some of them and the individuals that hold the keys like this is a boon like this is don't look
at it like um you're going to lose money you this is a recruiting opportunity yes you're going to
have to let other people in the cookie jar that's how a fair and free society works and they should
be able to compete for work and because that was one of the main i talked to some individuals that
were in an informal session for a previous administration on should we disclose or not
for a certain former president and really insightful what they told me and one of the biggest
impasses to disclosure wasn't the ontological shock from a socioeconomic or theological
perspective it was well there's some white collar crime we violated the federal acquisition
regulations we sole source this work to some big companies for decades contractors are going to
litigate this to the supreme court saying they lost billions of projected income because they
didn't get the bid on the work and it's going to be this like liability disaster for the u.s
government and the problem with that is is like i understand that but like that's why you need
to have a truth and reconciliation process it's almost like uh the truth and reconciliation
commission and post-apartheid south africa where people who committed like murder came in and was
like this is what happened here you go and you know they don't get convicted of those crimes and
i'm not saying i mean people who've committed murder as it relates to the subject okay we should
probably hold them accountable but for some of this stuff there needs to be a process where we
kind of mitigate some of those unfortunate legal issues but that was one of the main
issues a certain group for a reasonably recent administration came up with and advised that
president hey look there's going to be a lot of supreme court stuff let's not be that makes me
that guy so it's like the like that's the barrier that's the reason come on well it's so ridiculous
it makes sense though that they would think that way because i do believe that lawsuits would
emerge from something like that oh certainly and it's and also it's like the government admitting
that we can't protect its citizenry you know uh you know these non-human intelligences you know
want to do something to you sorry we don't have any countermeasures to that you know it's like this
you know there's a social contract between the citizens and the government right we can protect
you etc and like in this case it's like it's an enigma but i think this is almost like uh you
remember like after 9-eleven i was in high school and 9-eleven happened and you know people were
afraid of dirty bombs terrorists we didn't we didn't know what was going to happen next we lived
in fear but like you know we banded together in the presence of fear and apprehension and
unknowing what the world was going to be and we made made it through it now i mean that's a
coarse analogy to this but i uh people just have to think in that mindset like it's going to be a
little scary it's not going to be like kumbaya let's let's uh move the shit to the masonian and
check it out it's going to be this you know awkward and uh things we're going to have to address
sociologically i guess are you optimistic about how all this lays out i am i mean it's kind of
like when i was testifying in the public hearing oddly bipartisan in a good way i had aoc and matt
gates like agreeing on something and they were like smiling at each other that's crazy this is
crazy you know i'm like look at there's aoc there's matt gates there's timber shat i mean
there's like people uh garcia like people that wouldn't see eye to eye on most subjects such a
human issue because they they want to know the truth too and i don't think the the leaders in
congress want to be told that they're second-class citizens i mean a lot of presidents weren't briefed
to everything some presidents knew a lot more than others and i have a pretty good beat on that
and it's like wait the chief executive that also forms foreign policy you don't tell them about a
ostensibly a foreign element so how do they as chief of state how do they form foreign policy
when you don't fully brief them on a foreign elements like classifying the existence of russia
right right so you're actually you know non-constitutional by not allowing our
commander in chief all information sometimes you know and i don't know what harry reid talked to
joe biden i mean it was certainly the substance that i mentioned here uh and i i hope that joe
biden has been briefed on the program so to speak uh at least i'm i'm giving him an oral
unclassified briefing right now i guess if he hasn't been and you know i'm happy to you know
talk to jake sullivan or avril haines and avril haines if she's not briefed like she's supposed
to be briefed all intelligence in the country it's 50 us code section 3024 the director now
national intelligence has allowed everything from all federal agencies that's intel related well
ma'am if you don't know what i'm talking about we have a problem because you're not being briefed
by cia director and some other agencies so well listen david i really appreciate what you've done
i think you've done a great service to humanity just by taking a stand and communicating these
ideas and and letting people know how much of this is real and you know you've opened up
a world of discourse that probably would not have existed if you hadn't done that thanks yeah i mean
this was not easy i'm sure so i appreciate it thank you very much for being here and uh good
luck in the future thank you thank you all right bye everybody