It's a very good time to have a UFO expert in.
A lot has been going on.
This is, you know, I had, I know you ran into him.
I had Ryan Graves on yesterday.
Oh my God.
I'll tell you the funniest story about how I ran into him.
You ran into him in the lobby of the hotel, right?
The lobby told me, they were all, don't use this one elevator.
It's really rickety and it makes a lot of noise and it's just, it's not very reliable
and just don't use it.
So I didn't.
And then I was leaving 24 hours later to come down and get some coffee.
And I was like, ah, fine.
Let me take the rickety elevator.
I was like, they told me not to take it, but I'm going to take it anyway.
So I pushed the button.
I'm standing there.
I hear this, the door's open.
I look, I see this shadowy figure in the corner.
I'm like, Ryan Graves, what are you doing?
He goes, I don't know.
What are you doing?
I was like, are you doing what I think you're doing?
He goes, yeah.
Did he tell you that?
Yes, he did.
He told me he ran into you.
He didn't tell me the whole story about the rickety elevator.
Yeah, yeah.
And he was like this shadowy figure up against the corner, like kind of just, you know, looking
at it.
He was looking at me.
It was really funny.
We had a lot of, we talked a lot of nonsense about aliens, but we also talked about the
technology that he knows is state of the art when it comes to drones.
And that some of these ones in New Jersey, they're doing things that you can't really
do yet.
Yes.
Yeah.
Which is really fascinating.
Because it's like, okay.
And they're the size of SUVs.
Right.
So is it ours?
And we somehow or another have some stuff that the mainstream drone manufacturers at
the highest level aren't aware of yet?
Is it ours?
Is it like some crazy military stuff?
Because if it's not, and it's coming from the ocean, like, what do you mean it's coming?
What the fuck do you-
Fifty of them.
What do you mean?
What do you mean 50 suburban sized?
So check this out.
UFOs are coming out of the ocean.
This is really funny.
I've been working with this guy.
We've been communicating on the signal for a long time.
Actually he was through Proton.
He was emailing me stuff about Virginia, the UFO crash in Virginia.
And but he was anonymous.
One day I was like, he's really knowledgeable.
And he was sending me stuff that was really helpful.
Like you should track down this flight.
If it happened, it was going to this airport, go to this base.
And I was like, finally one day I was like, who are you?
And how do you know what you know?
He goes, I'm a retired United States Air Force colonel.
I was like, oh, and he goes, and I'm also an experiencer.
I had an experience back in 1980, blah, blah, blah.
So what happened to him?
He had a UFO encounter.
It's in the movie towards the end.
But anyway, he texted me yesterday and he goes, James, I really want you to explain
to me how the hell you orchestrated a UAP invasion right around the time your film's
coming out.
I was like, I really like to know how you did that.
I was like, I know I could.
Do you know what kind of a budget you would have to have to have drones running in the
sky all over?
How many different cities are reporting it now?
Like what's the numbers?
It's exploding all over all over the place and it's getting better.
I've heard California, I've heard Europe now bases in England, New York, New Jersey.
I've heard San Diego.
I definitely wasn't there something in Ohio, right?
Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.
They had to shut that place down.
Yeah, that's Ohio.
So I've heard New Jersey.
I think Florida, right?
That was the one that Ryan Graves showed us a photo of that was from Florida.
So like, who fucking what's going on?
Who fucking knows?
I was super busy.
You know, I had the release of the film going on.
And so I was like trying to focus on that and getting everything lined up.
It was a huge push and all these text messages from all around the world are
pouring in like, what the hell's going on with these drones?
And I was like, it's probably something conventional.
I'm not going to worry about it right now.
I'm trying to keep on focusing what I got what I got at hand here.
And then I started getting more information coming in, more information
that a buddy of mine called me.
And he actually went to Brazil with me a couple of years ago.
And he's like, bro, I live here.
I'm seeing these things in the sky.
I've seen them seven times now.
They're the size of an SUV.
I was like, well, what do they look like?
What do they behave like?
He's like, well, they're making noise.
I was like, OK, well, that quickly kind of eliminates
something non-conventional in terms of propulsion.
But then I got reports of objects that didn't make any noise.
And it would go silent.
What kind of noise it was making?
Like propellers drones would make, but loud.
And they have a loiter.
But they're big.
And they have a loiter time of hours.
The average drone, like I fly drones for my films,
is like you're lucky to get 25 minutes.
These things are there for hours.
Yeah, five hours at a time.
They go dark when they're approached by other objects.
They're not getting picked up on FLIR at times.
And then some of them have no noise.
I've heard crescent-shaped.
And then I heard about the ones that really got me,
because I contacted Christopher Mellon.
I was like, Chris, what is going on, buddy?
I really rely on him for good information.
And he's like, I really don't know, man.
It's a real shit show.
And the US government seems to be clueless right now.
He goes, some of them are conventional.
Some of them are misidentified conventional craft.
But there are other ones coming in off the ocean that are up
to 50, the Coast Guard and Police Department are reporting
that truly remain a mystery.
And then you had Schumer at a press conference,
just like it was yesterday.
And then he's going, and he's like,
we don't know what they are.
We don't know what they are.
And the guy goes, yeah, so it's a UAP.
He goes, well, they're drones.
He goes, well, you wrote the legislation.
It's a UAP.
It's Unidentified Anomalous Phenomenon.
Why don't you just use UAP?
I think they're using the word drone
because UAP is almost too scary.
Like some kind of invasion's happening.
That's what, UAP is Unidentified Anomalous Phenomenon?
Couldn't that be kind of anything?
It doesn't even mean flying.
Well, that's the thing,
because it used to be Unidentified Aerial,
well, it was UFO, Unidentified Flying Object.
Then it was UAP, Unidentified Aerial Phenomenon.
But then they're coming out of the water, right?
I feel like this is nonsense.
So they said anomalous.
Why don't they just keep using UFO?
Because it has, because people associate UFO
with otherworldly and they wanted to take that,
remove that baggage and make it a little less scary.
That's my personal opinion.
I kind of get that.
But also, it's just an Unidentified Flying Object.
If we find out what it is,
then it becomes an identified flying object.
It doesn't necessarily mean it's alien.
True, right?
Like think of the stealth bomber.
People probably jumping out of their windows right now
if they said UFOs are invading the East Coast.
You remember World of Worlds?
Right, that's true.
People were like jumping out of their windows.
That's a good point.
That's actually a very good point.
So I think they touted it out.
I think they're using the word drone,
even though they're unidentified,
just because of the fear factor.
I think the fear factor's real.
Yeah, I can't help but cringe when I hear that word.
Oh, sorry.
The fear element.
It's so funny.
Sorry.
It was too much of a part of my life.
Too close to home.
So when did they start?
When was it acknowledged that this was an issue
that was reoccurring recently?
Like, obviously there's always been something in the sky.
People have always seen things.
Who knows what they are, whether or not they're,
a lot of people see Starlink
and they think it's UFOs, right?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
But when did this drone thing
that we're currently experiencing basically every day,
when did it start?
Couple weeks ago.
Maybe a month ago.
That's when I started really hearing about it.
Jamie, is there any sort of official answer to that?
I have something that-
20th, 19th, something like that.
Mid-November.
This episode is brought to you by GoPuff.
Does grocery shopping drive you nuts?
The lines and the chaos and the inflated prices.
Then you have all these third-party delivery apps
with their ridiculous fees, markups,
and you still have to wait hours for delivery.
Well, enter GoPuff, the game changer.
They deliver snacks, groceries, alcohol, essentials,
whatever you need straight to your door in just 15 minutes.
And get this, it's cheaper than the store
because GoPuff uses their own fulfillment centers.
No middleman, no crazy markups.
It's like Amazon, but for everyday essentials and way faster.
GoPuff also just launched cheapest on the planet pricing.
Think $2 organic eggs, $2 milk, $5 diapers, $10 Tide Pods.
It's insane.
They're beating big grocery stores at their own game.
So do yourself a favor, download the GoPuff app
on your phone, use the code ROGUE20 for $20 off your order
and experience faster, cheaper, better shopping.
Trust me, you'll thank me later.
I have something that this is about an air base
in Vandenberg Air Force Base in 2003.
And this is not an anonymous,
but this is about incursions over, listen to this.
I promised this individual that I met at Seoul Conference.
He's a witness, he's a military guy.
My name is Jeffrey Nusatelli.
I served 16 years in the United States Air Force
as a technical sergeant and a military police officer.
In October 2003, my coworkers and I witnessed a series
of extraordinary UAP incursions
at Vandenberg Air Force Base in California.
The initial event is known as the Vandenberg Red Square.
And it was first mentioned during the historic UAP hearing,
UAP hearing held in 2023.
The case involved Boeing contractors
who witnessed a huge red square shaped object,
roughly the size of a football field,
hovering over a missile defense system.
The object was silent
and had no visible means of propulsion.
The contractors watched in amazement
as the massive object slowly drifted east
and vanished over the hills.
I retained official Air Force records of the event,
including the blotter form entry,
which includes the names and contact information
of all the witnesses and provided it
to select members of Congress, Aero and the FBI.
Aero is a new UAP task force,
All Domain Anomalous Resolution Office.
After the initial event,
several other UAP incursions took place at Vandenberg.
I was on duty during many of the encounters
and I investigated the incidents as they unfolded.
Now remember, this is not anonymous reporting here.
They include a football field sized craft
that terrified security guards
as it silently hovered over a launch facility
before flying off at an unbelievable rate of speed.
A brightly illuminated silent object
that landed on the base flight line
before accelerating instantaneously
and disappearing into space.
A huge triangular shaped craft larger than a C-130
that hovered 50 feet over a police officer
before it drifted slowly over the base.
A blue-white liquid orb roughly the size of his house
that hovered over his house on the base.
The object stayed no sound
and had zero obvious means of propulsion.
And he says, my experiences with UAP
were awe-inspiring, exciting and terrifying.
I don't know why UAP are flying over our bases
and our neighborhoods,
but I do know the UAP phenomenon
is of the utmost importance to all of humanity.
I currently have five other military witnesses
to the Vandenberg incursions
that are all willing to testify tomorrow under oath
that these statements are true.
We need answers to this mystery
and better government transparency.
Thank you for the opportunity to share my story,
former United States Air Force technical sergeant
and witness, Jeff Nusitelli.
Whoa. Crazy, right?
I mean, we're talking object the size of a football field?
That's bananas.
And then they take off in insanely fast,
just like the tic-tac.
Straight up into space.
So, what was the exact date of this?
This was 2003.
There was a number of incursions during that year
up all the way into 2005.
And he has the names and they submitted it
to the new head of arrow.
That's interesting because that coincides with the tic-tac.
It does coincide with the tic-tac.
I wonder if it's like vacation season.
It's like every few years.
Let's go check out what those guys are up to.
You know what I mean?
Maybe it's like a real pain in the ass to get here.
Maybe it's one of those things like,
you can go to Australia, but it's a pain in the ass.
It's 16 fucking hours on a plane.
It's a long flight.
Oh my gosh.
I went to South Africa one time and that was like 22 hours.
I was like, the plane's gonna run out of gas.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
It's like one of those things.
It's like, you can do it, but it's a pain in the ass.
So, maybe they only travel to Earth every now and again.
How could these incursions have been taking place
and like, here we are 20 years later
and we're only now really starting to talk about them?
I think the reason being is if you don't understand it
and you can't protect people from it
because it's so beyond our capabilities
that if just describing it accurately
removes all confidence that our government
has everything under control.
That's one reason why.
And also, if you have no answers,
you don't know what the hell it is.
That's a very good point, yes.
If you don't know what the hell it is,
what are you even gonna say?
Hey, there's something that came.
We don't know what the fuck it is.
It's as big as a football field,
shot off into the sky.
We have no idea.
They'd be like, what do you mean we have no idea?
Hire someone who understands this
and then they'd be like, fire him.
Get him out of hospice.
I remember, like 20 years ago,
bright-eyed bushy-tailed, totally naive,
still naive, but I was meeting with a general
and I said, God, it'd be so amazing.
This story is so unifying
and we had this kumbaya moment
and we discovered that we're not alone in the universe
and wouldn't that be amazing?
And blah, blah, blah, the implications for all of humanity.
And he sat there almost chuckling at me.
And he looked at me and he goes,
you got it all wrong, man.
You gotta see this through our lens.
I was like, through your lens?
He goes, yeah, the military's perspective.
I was like, okay, tell me.
And I never thought about this before.
You just mentioned it.
He goes, okay, imagine this scenario.
We sit there and we say, my fellow Americans,
it has been brought to our attention
that there are craft of unknown origin
whizzing around with impunity in our airspace.
They exhibit a technology that's light years advanced
from anything that we have.
We don't know who they are, where they come from,
what they want.
Shall they turn to be hostile?
We have no visible means of defense against them.
Thank you and good night.
You're fired.
And someone like Trump will come along.
I'll make a deal with the aliens.
But you see that predicament.
People always go, why the secrecy, duh.
Yeah, you have to have secrecy
because you gotta imagine the job of a politician
in general, right?
You have to pretend that you're gonna be able
to handle situations that you well know
you're not gonna be able to handle.
If you're running for president,
you know that you're not gonna fix this economy.
All right, stop.
Just stop.
I'm gonna wave the magic wand
and it's all gonna be taken care of.
You know you're not gonna implement electric cars
over the, stop, stop.
Shut the fuck up.
There's not enough batteries.
So if you're lying about all that,
you're probably gonna lie about whether or not
you can handle the alien threat.
I will unite us.
I will unite us as a planet
so we can deal together with the aliens.
Yeah, let's do that.
Let's do that.
That's all you have to do
is just say some bullshit like that.
And then someone probably bends his ear
when he gets into office and is like, yeah.
A good speaker.
About that disclosure.
Like a J.D. Vance, like a guy like that.
Very bright, young, energetic speaker.
He can convince people he can talk to the aliens.
He can convince people that he can unite us all.
Have you seen the program?
No, I have not.
Okay, so there is-
Explain it to everybody.
Okay, so the program, basically,
it's funny because the last time I was on the show,
we were talking about an alleged crash retrieval case
that took place in Virginia, Brazil in 1996.
And your documentary on it, which is-
Yeah, Moment of Contact.
Amazing, amazing documentary.
So we're talking about that,
and I came off the heels of doing The Phenomenon,
which touched a little bit
on a potential crash retrieval program,
but then it was like,
then it was the crash retrieval over in Virginia, Brazil,
and then I got hyper-focused on that,
and then I had sort of, it was a personal journey for me,
was, okay, the elected officials, what do they know,
and when do they know it?
Do we have a crash retrieval program?
That's what I set out to do.
And then three months after I was on your show,
in April of 2023, the highest level intel officer,
David Grush, testifies under oath
that there is a crash retrieval program,
and that the government does have definitive proof
that we're not alone.
So he kind of opened the door for me,
and a lot had happened since the release of The Phenomenon
and Moment of Contact.
There was all this legislation,
there was the first congressional hearing,
there was behind closed doors meetings
with a number of intel officers and witnesses,
and then you had the second congressional hearing,
which was David Grush, which was absolutely phenomenal.
I'm sure you saw that, right?
And then just recently, just a couple of months ago,
we had the third congressional hearing,
which I actually, funny enough, got to attend.
So it was the first time in my 30 years investigating.
I was actually sitting behind people
while they were testifying under oath
about legitimacy of The Phenomenon,
as well as there's a crash retrieval program.
I mean, people have to understand
that feel like maybe things aren't happening fast enough.
Just a couple years ago,
they didn't even admit that The Phenomenon is real.
Now there's people testifying under oath
that we have a crash retrieval program.
So drip, drip, drip, things are happening,
they're not putting the genie back in the bottle.
Do you wonder at all that you're being mind-fucked?
Do you wonder at all that this is a massive PSYOP
and this is all just to cover up
some very advanced American weapons technology?
I think it's a very good question,
and here's why I don't believe that,
because I have done 30 years of field research, right?
So I've gone to China, I've been to Russia,
I've been to Australia and Africa and South America,
Canada, Alaska, all across Europe, United States,
and I've investigated close encounters of the third kind.
Ask your audience, don't take it from me,
but the United States Air Force investigated and categorized
close encounters of the first, second, and third kind,
during their official capacity, Project Blue,
Project Sign, Project Grudge, Project Blue Book.
Great fucking movie, by the way,
if you haven't seen it, folks,
Close Encounters of the Third Kind,
probably the best alien invasion movie of all time.
Dr. Heineck has a cameo appearance in that film,
did you know that?
I had heard that.
I don't remember who he was, though,
but wasn't the French guy, didn't he?
Jacques Follet.
Jacques Follet has a cameo,
well, there's a guy acting his part,
but actually, Dr. Jalen Heineck,
who's a scientific advisor to Project Blue Book
all those years for the Air Force,
actually has a cameo appearance,
smoking a cigar during the encounter.
And that's him.
Oh, that's right, that's right.
That's Dr. Heineck.
That's right, smoking a pipe.
Smoking a pipe, and a lot of the cases right down
to Richard Dreyfuss's face being burned by the UFO,
those came directly out of Project Blue Book files,
even the description of what the entities looked like.
Close Encounters, again,
Close Encounters of the Third Kind,
this is the United States Air Force documenting this stuff.
And he took it directly out of Project Blue Book files
and made a movie out of it.
And as a little wink, wink, nudge, nudge,
he has Dr. Heineck have a cameo appearance in the movie.
You know what?
Most people don't know that.
It's a fantastic movie, too.
It's a great movie.
Because it's a movie that's filled with,
it's not like standard UFOs land.
There's some play going on.
There's some weirdness to the way they interact with us
that sort of is much more realistic
in terms of the things that people experience.
They experience interactions, very strange interactions.
And when they had those little orb-like things
that were flying around in the movie,
that's all straight out of like, yeah.
Oh, 100%.
I remember I had a buddy of mine,
he was a pilot over in Europe in the 70s,
and he used to come for family dinners
and he was always talking about it,
and I was like, yeah, yeah, yeah, whatever.
And then later we're all in the life of it.
Foo fighters.
When I started getting interested in UFOs,
I was like, Michael, tell me about that UFO
and kind of you had that red orb.
He goes, it was just like it was in The Close Encounters
of the Third Kind, Steven Spielberg's movie.
And I was like, ah, they took those files directly
out of project movie files and right onto the big screen.
That's what the foo fighters were, right?
Yeah, foo fighters, too.
They had little orbs.
Yeah, these fighter pilots are flying around.
They're seeing these things with them.
Well, let me ask you,
and this is why that I don't think it's a Psy-Op thing.
I don't think it's a Psy-Op either.
Well, the reason why I don't is because, okay,
I don't just believe Grush
because he testified under oath
and he is a high level intelligence officer.
That's very impressive.
I believe Grush because his claims align
with my personal research in the field.
Remember, I've investigated crash retrieval programs,
crash retrieval cases, right?
And so I was, I mean, when I put out Moment of Contact,
well, actually, when I went in to put out Moment of Contact,
people were going, James, you just dropped
one of the biggest, most successful UFO films
in terms of transcending the UFO community
and penetrating a much broader, more mainstream audience.
Are you sure you want to put out a documentary
that deals with an alleged crash and live aliens
walking around the town of Virginia, Brazil?
Like, seriously, that's what you want to put out there?
You got access to like Harry Reid
and all these intel insiders, and now you want to do that?
You're going to tarnish your reputation.
It's a bad-
Who gave you that advice?
A lot of people did.
I wish you called me.
Well, you-
I was like, James, you can handle it.
You probably heard about Moment of Contact,
and then you thought, oh, this sounds too crazy,
then eventually you watched it.
No, I thought, well, I always think a crash
and contact sounds crazy.
I know, and it does.
I always think that,
but I would have never told you not to do it.
Oh, okay.
I would have never told you not to do it.
You're really good at this.
You know how to, like,
you're really good at explaining-
But you look half the town talking about it,
including the mayor.
Well, that's an incredible story.
It's an incredible story.
It's a phenomenal story.
It's one of those stories where you're like,
if everybody's in on this, this is crazy.
If everybody's telling it,
and no one, there's not one contrarian that comes out
and goes, they all told me to lie.
I'm not fucking lying.
This is stupid.
They're doing it for tourism.
Oh, yeah.
Not one person?
Come on.
There's always some hater.
There's always some hater who wants to ruin your gag.
I remember-
You know what I mean?
Oh, yeah, no, I totally do.
I remember when I was making Moment of Contact
and I wasn't done with it yet,
Lou Elizondo was like, he's like, James, he called me up.
He goes, I need a copy.
I was like, the film's not done.
I don't care.
I need a copy.
Give me a rough cut.
I don't care.
And he's like, okay, what's the urgency?
And he's like, you don't understand
who's watching this right now.
So I was like, okay, so I'm giving him copies.
And I had absolutely no idea ever in a hundred million years
that I think we're gonna be having months
after the release of Moment of Contact,
a congressional hearing under oath
that was a crash retrieval program.
What year did Moment of Contact come out?
It came out at the end of 2022.
Do you think Biden watched it?
Do you think he sat down with Biden?
That would have been wild.
He's been so dismissive at all.
Like, Obama said a lot more about it.
You know why?
Because he's already in space.
He's in space right now.
He's like, go talk to Obama.
He's in orbit right now around Saturn.
I was like, really, that's the best you can do?
He's like Dr. Manhattan.
He's on the moon in a glass house.
Okay, let's say, if Biden, if you're listening right now,
you have nothing to lose.
You're the president of the United States, sir.
Release the hounds.
He's never running ever again.
Exactly.
He's not running for a second term.
Come on, we're done.
He's already part in more human beings
than any president ever, other than Carter.
Listen to the advice at the end of the program
by Senator Harry Reid,
who's now the late Senator Harry Reid.
And I said to him,
what advice would you give the president?
It could have been any president at the time.
And he said, don't be afraid of tarnishing your legacy
by addressing this issue head on.
And I hope that Biden gets to see that.
And I really hope that president-elect Donald Trump
gets to see that.
People are ready for the truth.
They've had enough of the line.
I think we're way beyond that at this point.
I agree with you.
However, when I confronted Mr. Trump, he was very cagey.
Was he really?
Very cagey.
I've seen some things.
They told me some things.
He didn't tell me shit.
He basically, it was basically like
neither confirmed nor denied.
No, there was no eyes.
I don't do that shit.
Especially to a pro like Donald Trump.
Like you're not, yeah, yeah.
You're gonna do it to an actor, so shut up.
You're not gonna know what the fuck they think.
Daniel Day-Lewis told you that he just ate a baby.
You'd fucking believe him.
You know what I mean?
Like this idea that what did his eyes tell you?
What did his eyes tell you?
It depends on the person.
Depends on the person.
If it's your regular crackpot and they tell you a lie,
like something's up.
But there's people that can hide things.
They can hide things behind their eyes.
I think he knows something.
I don't think he's that interested.
I think he's more interested.
I think he's sort of a no-nonsense type of guy
This is why.
You kind of have to be to be managing
multiple businesses simultaneously.
He's always done that his whole career.
Managed being on The Apprentice
while running these golf courses,
while having these buildings, apartment buildings, hotels.
He's constantly doing something.
So while he's doing all that, and he's playing golf,
while he's doing all that,
there's no time for fucking aliens, man.
There's no time for nonsense.
There's no time for sitting around with your buddies,
smoking a cigar going, what do you think, man?
I mean, if they fucking, if I was them, man,
I would do what they're doing.
You know, I wouldn't even,
there's no time for that nonsense talk.
That guy's got businesses.
But we got objects of unknown origin,
flying over residential areas,
flying over military bases,
flying over nuclear silos.
Well, now I think he's much more interested because.
That's a matter of national security.
I mean, people are freaking out.
Like, what the hell are we seeing?
And they're going, we don't know what they are,
but everything's fine.
Well, he's totally safe.
There's no national security issue here.
We don't know what they are, but you're fine.
Don't worry about it.
You remember, what was the Steven Spielberg movie
with the shark, the great white shark?
Yeah, Jaws.
Jaws, you remember when they're like, everything's fine.
The mayor.
The mayor is like, keep swimming.
Yeah, keep swimming.
The water's fine.
Everyone's saying people are getting bitten halfway.
That's the perfect analogy.
Dude, that is the perfect analogy.
That is it.
Everything's fine.
Go about your lives.
They're definitely not nuke sniffing drones.
Come on, nuke sniffing drones.
So what if some nuclear material was just stolen
off a cargo ship?
Whatever, whatever.
Guys.
All the online conspiracy stuff is crazy,
and I get a lot of it,
because obviously what I do,
and people send me all kinds of stuff.
I was like, well, hang on a second.
I wish I could put poods on the ground,
but no, there's something really weird going on,
and the fact that they don't know
or they're claiming that they don't know what it is,
and here's another really funny thing.
I actually, in the program that I did now,
and I hope you get a chance to watch it,
because it's crazy.
It's got.
Tell people what it is.
Okay, so basically I was talking about earlier.
Tell people the title the whole time.
It's called the program.
It's gonna be on, it just came out.
It's at number one right now.
It's on Amazon.
When did it come out?
Yesterday.
Oh, beautiful.
I know.
So it came out yesterday.
It's on Amazon.
It's on Apple TV,
and you can Google the,
because the algorithms are just starting to catch up
with it on Google right now,
because everyone's like,
I can't find it.
Look up the program,
and then Google James Fox UFO documentary, the program.
You will 100% find it.
It's being also made available internationally.
They're working as fast as they can to get it up.
It just went up yesterday.
It's the most independent film from start to finish
that I've ever made,
and it covers what happened,
because everybody thinks the government
suddenly had this epiphany
to decide to be more transparent with the general public.
That's not what happened.
What happened is there were a couple of intel insiders
in the Pentagon reviewing some of this classified data
or so-called classified data,
and resigned in protest of excessive secrecy.
They found a loophole.
This is Lou, probably Jay Stratton.
I don't know for sure.
Definitely Chris Mellon,
and they walked these evidence tapes
out of the Pentagon through this loophole.
They bent the rules a little bit,
and onto the front page of the New York Times, right?
So that happened,
and it got, it was just,
it was exploded.
You remember that.
Since then, there has been this unprecedented push
by a bipartisan group of lawmakers
to find out what the intelligence agencies know
and when they knew it.
So that started happening behind the scenes, right?
So it was 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021,
and then in 2022, they were like,
we're having a congressional hearing.
Congressman Andre Carson,
I think he's of Wisconsin, but I'm not positive.
He spearheaded the first open congressional hearing,
public open congressional hearing,
and in that congressional hearing,
they acknowledged the fact that the phenomenon was real.
It was slowly introduced
that we were not getting told the facts.
There was a document that came out
called the Wilson Davis Memo,
and that was about the discovery by a former DIA guy,
Admiral Wilson, of the crash retrieval program
that was like maybe 20, 20 plus years ago,
and none of the names or anything
in that document were redacted.
I covered that memo in the film.
And then 2023, another congressional hearing.
This time it was David Grush
talking about the crash retrieval program.
It's been a steady progression,
and so a lot has gone on between 2017 and 2024,
and that is what this film does,
is it covers behind the scenes effort,
bipartisan, a group of lawmakers effort
to find out what the intelligence agencies really know.
Whew.
Yeah, and people that were,
and in one of them, there was an encounter,
and I think I remember you hearing about it,
because you wanted to get ahold of David Grush,
and so you contacted me,
and I actually had a drone up in the air in England,
and I was, I know,
and I had my phone attached to my drone thing,
because that's what it was using
as a controller for the screen,
and I'm flying the drone,
and there was a huge windmill,
and I saw this windmill,
and I was like,
oh, that's gonna make a beautiful shot for the movie,
and it is in the movie.
So I'm up there flying it,
and the wind, the turbines are going round and round,
and I can't quite tell how close my drone is to him,
so I'm paying really good attention,
and I'm getting close to these big turbines,
and all of a sudden my phone's ringing,
and it's you.
I'm like, oh my God, I can't not answer this,
I gotta answer, so I answered it
while my drone was up there,
and we talked briefly,
and you said, hey, can you get me in touch
with David Grush?
I said, yeah, I got a guy that can put you in touch with,
that was Jason Sands,
and I guess you and Jason Sands talked about
this alleged encounter in 1994
with this entity, alien,
whatever you wanna call him, in the desert.
Yes.
So that was a crazy story.
Crazy story.
But in any case,
so when you watch the movie and the program,
you'll see the drone flying dangerously close to these,
and that's funny, a little inside thing.
So it didn't crash.
It didn't crash,
but I was on the phone with you when it happened.
But when you watch the footage,
it's like, wow, that's really close.
Is that guy public with that story?
He, well, so.
Because otherwise I would discuss it.
Yeah, yeah.
Because it sounded so nutty.
No, no, yeah.
Okay, so here's what happened.
This is funny because
when I was in Washington, D.C. with Mellon
and this gentleman, Jason Sands,
I'm using his name now,
and Mellon looked at me and he goes,
this guy's story's pretty wild.
I was like, what do you mean?
He goes, really wild.
And we're sitting down having dinner
and Chris Mellon orders,
he orders a drink.
He had a tequila, so whatever.
Anyway, and we were all having dinner,
and Jason Sands starts telling the story
about this alleged encounter in 1994.
And it's one of the craziest stories,
and I've been doing this for 30 years,
and this story is nuts, okay?
You remember it.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I went like this to my phone.
He was telling me like there was one.
Yeah, me too.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, me too.
So I'll get it.
It was one of those, wait, wait,
what the fuck did you just say?
Insane, okay.
Tell everybody what we said.
I will.
I'll get to that in one second.
This is the reason why I can.
Well, the reason why I can discuss it publicly, I know.
The reason why I can discuss it publicly
is because he was gonna appear anonymously in the movie,
and I was debating on exactly how to go about doing this
because I was torn,
because you got a statement from an individual,
you don't have his identity,
but I was in DC, I put the whole thing down,
and I said, look, if he was worried about his security,
he was a whistleblower,
he'd already testified to a number of Senate Intel communities,
Senate Armed Service community, and.
All about the UFO phenomenon?
Yeah, about the UFO phenomenon.
They're part of the UOP task force.
They found him, and he was giving them information
and reporting on things.
And so he goes, I'm really fearful.
I don't know if this witness protection program
is gonna be that helpful.
I'm just, I'm worried.
I said, look, if you're concerned
about the story getting out or not getting out,
if you want, I'm here.
You can come to our studio,
we could film you on camera,
and if anything happens to you, it could be released,
and it could be a little insurance policy for yourself.
He goes, that sounds great, let's do it.
So I did a whole film about it.
And then I'm periodically posting clips,
or just still frames and updates on the movie
as I'm making it, as I do on social media.
And I posted this one scene,
and it had a clipboard in the scene.
And on that clipboard, if you zoomed right in,
it had his name.
So I posted the, by accident, I posted the damn thing,
and my phone starts blowing up 10 minutes later.
You just revealed this guy.
What are you doing?
Take it down, take it down, take it down.
Too late, too late.
So it was out there, and he's getting all kinds of heat.
So as a result of it, I'm giving the truncated version,
he basically had to go through the Dobser process,
which is basically pre-publication of authorization
of what you can and cannot say.
Excuse me.
So he basically could talk about a number of cases
that were in the film.
We had to blurp out one particular word,
which in the movie, it's blurred out.
We had to do that, that was Dobser.
So it was the winter of 1994.
There was a unidentified flying object
that was picked up on the base.
Old school, UFO.
Oh, yes, sir, old school, it was a UFO.
It was picked up on the base,
and it was recorded by sensory data,
and it was picked up on camera.
It had camera footage of it from different locations.
What did it look like?
It looked like, it was a weird shape,
it was like an unusual shape,
and there's people talking about it, it's in the movie.
And.
The film is in the movie?
The film footage that leaked from the base is in the movie.
So you can see what it looks like flying around.
Kind of, yeah, it's kind of blurry in some spots,
and yeah, you'll see it.
So.
It's in the program.
It's in the program, yeah.
And then you hear all the voices.
I actually had the voices cleaned up.
You can hear people talking about, what the hell is it?
Is there a clip we could see online?
Just so I could show people what it looks like?
Damn, I'm sorry.
Could you maybe just say the actual name of the incident?
Maybe Jamie can find it?
Yeah, try and find it.
It's Nellis Test Range UFO 1994.
See if you can find it.
People put stuff up so quick.
It's long and it's really bad, yeah, true, good point.
Cause it's on Amazon right now,
people put clips up so fast.
Yeah, it's true, yeah, and there's other things on there.
So in any case, so that, that, that video.
Bam, there it is.
Oh, that's terrible, there's much better footage of it.
Yeah, there's much better footage of it.
It's in my movie, I had it cleaned up.
But yeah, that's it, basically.
Can I see it again?
So that's what it looked like?
The footage I have is way better than this.
Yeah, sometimes it's, so.
So what did it look, Jesus Christ,
you know what that looks like, Jamie?
It's a very weird shape.
Jamie, you know what that looks like?
It looks like, looks like Terrence Howard's creation.
Doesn't it?
It's weird.
What is it, what did he call that again?
But it was.
Those things that lock together?
Those, you know, the flying drone thing that he created?
Linchpins.
Yeah.
Terrence Howard created this fascinating concept
for like a drone, where it's like propellers
going all these different directions
and they sync up and they link together,
and it looks like that.
Oh yeah, so it's, anyway, so it's footage,
people talking about it, what is it, we don't know,
it's not identified, and it flies around the base,
and that leaked, and the names of the witnesses leaked.
Three days later.
I'm sorry to keep cutting you off,
but can you just say what it did, like how it moved?
It just, it was like, it didn't have any visible means
of propulsion, it didn't have any wings,
it didn't have propellers, it just looked like an object,
a round sort of object, weird shape,
almost like a helmet or something,
with things coming off of it,
and it was just moving around the base.
How fast?
Nobody, slowly at time.
Oh, there it is.
Okay.
That's it, that's exactly it, yep.
It's definitely not a big balloon.
And you hear, no, you hear everybody talking about it,
the audio that goes along with it,
and I had it cleaned up, is, they're all talking,
nobody knows what it is.
So this is Zoom, is this why it's moved around like that,
they're trying to keep it in focus,
and they're zooming on it?
It's all, Mr. Sands explains all of that in the film,
the program, he talks about it.
So anyway, so this leaks, people's names,
the witnesses leaks, and three days later,
he's in a convoy,
Gesundheit, he's in a convoy,
and it's early in the morning,
and there's three jeeps, trucks, jeeps, in convoy,
on a dirt road, heading out in Ellis Test Range,
and they see what looks like,
maybe somebody was involved in a plane crash,
somebody that was struggling out in the middle of the desert,
it was early in the morning, wintertime,
and they're looking at this individual,
and they're like, oh my God, is that a person,
that individual needs some help,
that individual looks like they need some help,
they look cold, their skin had a slight blue tint to it,
and they're looking at this gentleman,
and they're like, hey, stop the convoy,
this person needs help, medical attention,
maybe they had a plane crash,
and so we're gonna help this person out,
and they pull the convoy over,
and this individual comes up to the car,
Jason Sands gets out the right side of the door,
and as he's getting out, somebody in the truck screams,
he's got no effing ears,
and Jason says, he turns around, and he looks at this guy,
and he had the same kind of uniform that they had had on,
but the uniform was just immaculate,
like there wasn't any dust on it, no dust on the boots,
and he was thinking to himself, well, that's weird,
this guy's got no ears, is this guy some kind of mutant?
And he looks at him, and he said his eyes were a lot bigger,
it's all illustrated in the movie,
and then he starts talking like,
he said it was like a snake bite him,
and he was just paralyzed with fear,
it was really scary, what am I looking at?
Is this a human, is this a mutant, is this an alien,
what is this?
And he starts talking to him in gibberish,
but he said he started to understand, like telepathically,
everything this person or entity being, creature, alien,
whatever you wanna call it, was saying to him,
and he was looking for some kind of metal,
and he didn't know tantillium,
and Jason Sands is like, I don't know,
I don't have any, you mean titanium?
He's like, no, tantillium or something,
and this conversation goes on for a bit,
and then the guy just wanders back off,
and gets into that little craft
that looked very similar to what you just saw there,
and flies away, and he sort of stair stepped away,
and everybody sort of came out of this comatose state,
and off they went,
and we have the names of the other military witnesses
that were on duty during the encounter,
the alleged encounter.
People are gonna criticize me,
because I'm reporting on a close encounter
with a third guy,
but this, Jason Sands says he's willing to do
a lie detector test, like public.
He's willing to testify under oath
that everything he's saying is true.
We have a date, we have a location,
and we have the names of the other on duty officers.
So what I'm hoping is,
despite the level of criticism I'm gonna receive
for reporting on this,
is that other individuals that have more information on this
are gonna be inclined to come forward.
I also met with people in the Senate Armed Service Committee,
Senate Select Committee on Intelligence,
sorry, in the House,
and they said, Jason Sands is who he says he is,
he checks out, he is named previously classified,
or classified programs, he's identified,
the guy's legit, his credentials check out,
and so I opted to go ahead and report on it,
with the hope that more information will come out on it.
Listen, man, there's nothing wrong
with reporting on a story like that.
There's been a bunch of them.
It's not a small number of these things
where people have experienced these things.
And imagine if it's true.
If it's true, yeah.
They're not all liars.
I can't believe they're all liars.
Oh yeah, it's hard to imagine.
Imagine being that person who had that experience
and not have anybody believe you.
Not only that, but it can actually ruin your reputation
and your career to talk about this experience,
which is the reality of it.
And it's one of the things that stifled discourse on this
until I think the New York Times really broke the ice.
I think in 2017 when they published that,
all of a sudden serious people who were unwilling
to talk about UFOs before just for the ridicule.
Now you've got the gimbal video, the go fast video,
you've got fighter pilots, Commander David Fravor,
you've got these people discussing these things openly
and like, okay, this seems like something
that a serious person can discuss now.
And so then it's open, but actually meeting one
and talking to, it's like the Virginia story.
Like when I told people the cop picked it up
and carried it in the car and the cop died.
Manhandled it.
Some horrible bacterial infection that they couldn't cure.
He was rubbing himself down with rubbing alcohol,
according to his family.
Like he was like, it's greasy stuff on my skin.
And he was rubbing himself down
and he had to stench, smell, grease.
And then I interviewed the doctors,
there's a couple of actually going back
to Brazil next month.
There were a couple of forensic pathologists
that are willing to come forward that we're gonna cover,
kind of update the movie and re-release it.
So it's an ongoing investigation.
Wouldn't that be the best protection
from an alien planet's bacteria
if you had the most vicious bacteria
on the surface of your skin, right?
Like imagine, like if you go to another planet
and the way to mitigate the effects of viruses
and bacteria on that planet is to have skin fluid
that's like unbelievably toxic.
Anything that comes near you just gets cooked.
Yeah, like a skunk.
Right.
Have you ever had a skunk?
Oh yeah, I had a skunk, got my dog once.
I took out this guy's garbage one time
and he's like, hey, it's in my garage.
He flipped up the thing and dropped it in there.
So I was kind of hung over.
We had a party the night before
and I went out to the garbage can
and I kind of heard some rustling in the garbage can
but I didn't really think anything of it
and I lifted up the thing
and then I heard some rustling again.
So I reached over and I put my head down inside
and the skunk just turned and got me right in the face.
Now, I held my breath, I held my breath
and I closed my eyes at the last second
and it went right through me.
It penetrated my molecules.
It was so powerful that it was paralyzing.
Absolutely paralyzing.
Can you imagine?
Just a smell, that's their way of defense.
It's just this stench that just goes through your body
like just paralyzes you.
That's crazy.
Anyway, it was really-
You got it in the mug, huh?
I got it right in the face.
Wow, how long did it take before you didn't stink?
Cause you smoked normal now.
Probably two weeks.
Ah!
I was wondering like how long did that wait?
It was several weeks.
Yeah, and I tried the tomato
and I tried the baking soda and I tried-
I think they have the special soap now
just for skunks.
When my dog got zapped, she got zapped in like 1980.
I think it was 1980 cause I was living in Jamaica Plain
and she went out in the backyard
and I think she thought that it was our cat
cause we had a cat that was black and white
and she just ran right up to that skunk
and it took her right in the side of her body.
She tried to turn away but it got her all over her body.
She was wet with skunk spit.
Oh, God.
It was so nasty.
I had to take her inside and I had to do it
cause she was my dog.
I was 13.
I had to like cover her with tomato juice
and wash her down and she still stunk.
The whole house stunk.
It's so funny because I was getting ready for a road trip
this couple of years ago and I looked over
and I was like, did we walk Duke?
It was like nine o'clock at night.
We were exhausted.
We packed everything up.
They had the car ready to go for the next morning.
We walked Duke.
You don't walk Duke.
Take Duke, our dog.
So we died, I was like, ah, it's nine o'clock.
I gotta slide him outside.
And I hear him like,
Ruh-ruh-ruh-ruh-ruh-ruh-ruh-ruh.
Then he goes, Ruh-ruh.
And I thought, oh, my God, he just got eaten.
Somebody just ate him.
I was like, oh, my gosh.
I ran out there to look for him
and he comes running in and he jumps in bed
covered in skunk.
The whole house.
Like it was so, so strong.
It's unbelievable.
That smell is just like.
It's so incredible.
The way someone explains to me, you know, like animals like bloodhounds and bears
They have the insane sense of smell god like a hundred thousand times stronger than ours, right?
But they can pick up parts per million the way we pick up skunk
Really? Yeah. Oh my god think about that. So if a skunk gets hit by a car like a mile away, you can smell it
Have you ever driven in your car? It's a mile drive over it and then my car smells like yeah
If you're in the but if you're in the neighborhood where a skunk got something you could smell it. Yeah
For some strange reason it permeates it like it carries more than any other smell with dogs. That's how they smell everything
They're like, oh Ross goes home, you know
like they can smell things that you can't even imagine they could smell especially like a bloodhound and then a bear can smell like
What is a bear's like?
Ability to smell above a bloodhound. It's some something something crazy
My friend was sharks in the in the ocean can sense blood from miles away miles miles incredible insane miles away
They could smell blood miles away
God something I remember look at this
300 times but look at this
This is crazy bears are sent the best sense of smell of any animal on earth
for example average dog sense of smells 100 times better than humans a
Bloodhounds is 300 times better a bear sense of smell is seven times then a bloodhound or
2,100 times better than a humans
Unbelievable, that's why they say when you go camping and put your food up in a tree or something
100% you have to you can't have the tent at all. Oh when I was a kid
We went camping and the bear broke open our cooler. Wow
Yeah, people just had regular coolers back you'd have like a little cookie in your pocket and be in bed
I mean, yeah, you're gonna have you're gonna have an issue. Oh a hundred percent. Yeah. Wow a hundred percent
I remember when I was a kid I went camping and they were like don't have any food
I was like, yeah, whatever like that. No, no, no put that stuff. They were really adamant
I was like why these guys making such a fault and bears not gonna smell a cookie in my pocket like yeah, of course
They'll look at that like a wanton like look at that soft outer layer and there's meat inside of it
They're gonna look at that tent like look it's trapped in there. The meat is trapped in the tent. This is crazy
What was that one movie called where they got the the grizzly man or something? Yeah grizzly man
That's when they came and got him. Remember they well
One with the Grizzlies and then he got eaten. It's a very complicated movie. That's a Werner Herzog film. Yeah, Werner Herzog
Yes, it's a really funny camera was rolling and they played it sort of the camera was rolling but all the lens cap was on
So there was an audio. So it's just audio. Yeah, that's even worse
Audio you hear on the internet. That's fake. Oh, that's not the real one the real audio Werner Herzog told the lady to destroy it
Destroy it. No one should hear. So he heard it. Yeah, he heard it. It's long, you know, because bears don't kill you
You know like a salmon they don't kill salmon they just put their paw down and start pulling chunks off of it
That's what they do with people too. That's terrifying. Is that well, they don't have any predators
So they don't have to kill things and then you know worry about someone taking it from them
You know shit from a bear, especially a grizzly bear. You're not taking shit from a bear unless you're a bigger bear
So like all the other animals have to worry like mountain lions kill quick because wolves will steal from mountain lions
And apparently in the areas where wolves have been introduced
It's actually become a problem because mountain lions are killing much more than they normally do
Because mountain lions will kill like a deer or two deer a week something like that and eat the day. Yeah
That's a lot of meat. Well, they're big, you know a big mountain lions, you know 150 pounds
It's a big cat their cats are just their obligate predators. All they eat is meat, you know bears lead a little berries
They'll eat a bunch of shit not cats. So the cats are
Killing more because the wolves scare the cats off of the kill
So if the cat's on a kill and a bunch of wolves show up the cat will just get the fuck out of there
Like fuck cuz he feels I didn't want to have to fend himself against the wolves exactly because wolves hunting packs
So there might be 13 14 wolves and one cat the cat will just get the fuck out of there cats run from dogs
Right, like they have a fear of like canines and I think it's from wolves stealing their food
So like that's how they hunt cats the way they hunt them
You have to tree them because otherwise you're not gonna find if you find a mountain lion
But tree them you have to get the dogs to bark them up a tree
Oh, they run a tree and they shoot them when they're in a tree
Yeah, and they it sounds cruel. But listen, they have to do that to manage the populations if they don't they start eating dogs
They start that's what you get in San Francisco
California still kills mountain lions
They kill as many mountain lions as they would if they gave tags out to people to kill them
Because you have to kill certain numbers of them for depredation because they'll start killing livestock
They start killing dogs in the Bay Area
They were the problem cats that they wound up killing in like San Francisco
Half their diet was pets
Really half their diet half their diet was house house dogs dogs and cats
That's half their diet half of their diet
So you manage, you know a hundred plus pound cat and he's running around just eating dogs
You leave your dog in your backyard gone
Happens all the time. Wow, it happened to my dog. Really? Yeah, my dog in Colorado got eaten by a mountain lion
That happens. Oh god. I feel so bad for my little guy. It's terrible. I'm not there to protect my little feller
You know one time I was I was hiking up this mountain
And I had my son with me at the time and he was in that little pouch
You know that little pouch
Oh, yeah put him in the front like he was like probably like maybe two two and a half
And I was hiking this mountain pretty daily. It's funny actually cuz when I went up there without him
I was like, well, this is why people hike with weights on this feels amazing. I could run up this mountain
But anyway, I was going to the mountain and I had my dog my little little Duke and I had my son
Walking up this mountain and I come around this like good left hand
It's a pretty exposed not too many trees some bushes and it's a hot sunny day
And I see this leg of a deer like just fresh kill with blood in the ground. I was like god damn
What the hell's the hell looked? Wow, that's fresh. It's like, huh? I kind of keep going and come around the corner
There's a long straightaway. The hill goes up like this
And I see what looks like a big
like greyhound dog
Kind of like brown light brown kind of walking kind of back and forth like this with a tail and I was like man
Who the hell's greyhound is doing out of here? Like what the hell is that's a mountain lion?
I was like, holy shit and the mountain lion turns around and looked at me and I had my kid
I was like shit
I so I grabbed my dog and I turned around and I started running and I knew that I shouldn't be running
So I'm running going I shouldn't be running. I shouldn't be running
I know he should be running but I wanted to get around the corner and get it out of its light sign of
Line of sight and then I go I go well if he comes up on me, I'm gonna have to throw my dog
I was like I look at Duke and if it comes down to it, you're gonna have to take one for the team
Horrible choice, but I had my son
But I remember my dog too and I was like looking at my dog going
Oh man, this is a horrible decision to make but if it comes down to it, I'm gonna have to sacrifice you buddy
I love you, you know, but it didn't come down to it. But I remember running going you're an idiot James
Why are you running not supposed to be running? You can't run. Well, that's the problem with mountain bikers
They get got because when they pass by a cat, it's almost like rolling a ball of yarn past a kitten
They're predators and they will they'll catch bikes, huh? Oh, yeah, they get people on bikes. Yeah, that's happened a few times
They get people on bikes. They get joggers people on bikes. They think you're running away from them
Could you tell me what it was like to be running for your life having something like that chase you yeah, I can I mean
It hasn't happened to me, but I've seen them
I've seen three of them in my lifetime only one of them that scared the shit out of me. I saw one in Colorado
I saw one in
Montecito like the Santa Barbara area. It was small. Those are small ones
They were like 50 60 pounds and then I saw one with a buddy of mine my friend Colton and I we spotted one under
A tree that was 30 yards away. We were in a truck and it made me shit my pants
Wow, it was so big. This one was really big
This was a mature male with a big pumpkin head and huge forearms like a fucking bodybuilder. It was freaky
It was freaky to see because you know, it was first of all, it was dusk
So the the Sun was going down and the lights of the truck even though it wasn't quite dark yet
The lights of the truck were making his eyes glow
Oh my god, and you can see him with the naked eye
But then I put my binoculars on and so I've got these 10-power binoculars and I'm zoomed in on this thing's face
I'm like, holy looks like he belongs in Africa. Well, he belonged right where he was and we didn't belong there
Let me tell you a really cool story that's a UFO the best UFO picture I think it's ever taken
Okay, so can you find the program trailer on on here at all or yeah for sure right find the program trailer
I'm gonna tell you about this. So yeah, just watch the trailer. Let's watch it story exposing a secret government program
investigating UFOs
That story was kind of a catalyst for a lot of things that have happened since
Members of Congress started to ask questions instruments report. There is something there
There are flight characteristics that we can't explain
UAPs are unexplained. It's true. They need to be investigated
Here we are having a hearing where just a few years ago we didn't even acknowledge that these things were real
Do you believe that our government is in possession of UAPs? Absolutely based on interviewing over 40 witnesses over four years
You're telling me people have come forward claiming firsthand knowledge of craft of non-human origin
That's correct
We have sources who have asserted not only that there have been crashes
But there have been crash retrievals. Do we have the bodies of the pilots who piloted this craft?
Biologics came with some of these recoveries. Yeah
Were they human or non-human?
non-human
I'm sitting here today because the American people are being lied to
We are the American government and we are open and we're gonna be open about this
What has been revealed non-human intelligence exists non-human intelligence has been interacting with humanity
There's only part of the story the pressures on Pentagon CIA. They're gonna have to answer the man
Some are risking everything. Have you had incidences that have caused you to be in fear for your life?
Yes personally to uncover the rest
What is being done to verify the assertion that the US government has spaceships of non-human intelligence in their possession?
That kind of revelation unearth people's beliefs
I would go to jail to say things that I've been exposed to
in the program
Bro, is that Mick Jagger?
Was that other guy Mick Jagger? Isn't he amazing? That's Hal put off. Hal put off. Oh, yeah
I know doesn't look like Mick Jagger. That's not Gary McKinnon
He's the biggest computer hacker in history. Let me see what he looks like. He almost went to jail for life
Because he was like, I'm gonna find out what the government knows about UFOs. So he hacked into the systems
NSA CIA DIA like
Where is he? Yeah, you want to see that really cool picture the foot no in the film. Oh, yeah
Yeah, you gotta go towards the end. Yeah. No, he's totally looks like
You should say that because I totally thought I saw it. I'm like, wait a minute. That does look like a rock star
He is a rock star in the UFO community. It's coming up
You'll have to pause it quickly when it when it hits but Gary McKinnon took it upon himself a computer hacker
to find out if the government had
Proof of alien visitation and he spent a couple years hacking systems and he found and he got pay dirt
Yes, that was it
You should just like only show that clip, you know, like they do in horror movies where the mask is not that good
Yeah, but so well I was gonna tell you there's a photograph of a jet circulating
Can I can I go in a little bit of detail because everyone's always worried about like where's the good evidence?
Where's the good photograph? Yeah, so it's yeah. There we go
This was a lost photograph that was recovered. Yeah. Yeah, you know about this. Yeah, I know about this
Okay, so I heard about this in the late 90s
Okay
So there was a guy Nick Pope who investigated he was part of the UFO desk at the Ministry of Defense of England in the late
90s mid to late 90s
Maybe in as late as early 2000s
But in any case and I was in fact I was interviewing him for a number of my films. I did a film called out of the blue
I know what I saw before I did the phenomenon and I I asked him like hey man
You were part of the UFO desk at the MOT. What was the best case you ever saw and he goes? Oh man
1990 he didn't give me this the town it was calvine, but he said Scotland there were two poachers
They called them hikers, but they were actually poaching and that's what made me think about this
We were talking about animals earlier and he said uh, it was it was late in the afternoon
They were in a place. I now know it's called calvine and
they
came upon
In this relatively remote area
I know because I hiked out to the exact spot and it's in the movie but and they came upon this diamond shaped or disc shaped
Object that was quite large that was hovering silently
Really close I mean close and they were scared to death and they were kind of
Hiding out underneath this tree and they're looking at this thing
What the are we looking at and there's looking at this thing as it silently hovering remember. This is 1990. Okay, and
one of them had a camera and
Just as he was considering taking his camera out a military jet came in turns out
It was one of those Harrier jet
they think it was a Harrier jet and it came out into the scene and it flew all the way around the disc and
As it did so the guy mustered up the courage came out from under the tree and he snapped five or six photographs of
This object suspended in the air and it went
so the disc is here and the plane is flying around us click click click click click click and
the reason why I know this is because
The individual who kept one of the prints. Thank you very much
Craig Lindsay RAF press officer and thank you David Clark for uncovering this because it's the most amazing picture ever and
The two hotel workers in just outside the town of calvine Scotland came back and they were like telling their co-workers
Oh my god, we encountered this thing. We don't know it was so they go to the local newspaper and they were like, hey, man
We just filmed something in the sky. We got six prints of it
it was I was it was 35 millimeter film footage, right and
And they're gonna go public with their story two witnesses broad daylight
I know a UFO points of reference with a military jet flying around five or six prints. That's pretty solid evidence, right?
so
the local newspaper was like
They're about to go public with it print print the story and they were like well
We need a statement from the RAF. So they contact the press officer Craig Lindsay and they were like, hey
What do you make of this?
UFO these guys took and the guy and Craig Lindsay goes I don't know what you're talking about
I I haven't seen the picture. You haven't seen it. Well, let me send you a print. This is the new the newspaper
sends him a print big big print like this the one you see today and
He's like, holy shit. The hell is this? He's already a press officer Craig Lindsay and he's good. So he
starts getting in touch with the MOD and he goes out and he
Investigate this go talk to the witness talk to the witnesses and they were telling him and he goes well
They tell him what happened and he goes well, what kind of noise did it make they say it didn't make any noise
No, he goes no noise. That's impossible
You know an object that can hover like that in the sky for that period of time. They're talking 34 years ago
didn't make any noise and
the witness said no
So he was like, holy shit. This is crazy
So he takes a color Xerox a machine and he sends it to the MOD in London and he says hey
There's a case that you might want to check, you know, you might want to look into and here's a Xerox, which is really crappy
It's just a it's just a scanned Xerox like a fax machine over to MOD
He said he went from the office where the Xerox machine was and before he can get back to his office
His phone was ringing off the hook MOD and the MOD basically stepped in took over the investigation
They said you can step down to Craig Lindsay. He steps down. He keeps the print, right?
He steps down they take over
Witnesses gone five or six prints gone
story killed, right
so
30 and we rumored about it because Nick Pope had talked about this case in a book he wrote called
Open skies closed mines and then I talked to him about it in late late 90s
Then I talked to him about it again in the early 2000s and I was like Nick, especially in 2007
I was like tell me about this photograph. He's like, I was incredible
We had a big poster of it on the wall the MOD and I was like, well, where is it?
He goes well, I don't know. I stepped down
I'm no longer that at the UFO desk and I said well
They didn't just throw that away once you get in touch with the people that were there and find out he's like
Oh, you know James I can't just make those inquiries that we we killed the story
It was like, you know, so I was incredibly frustrated. So so discreetly for over a 20-year period
I was making inquiries because I don't like letting things go
Right. It was like this picture exists and bloody hell. Let's get this one out there, but the story went dark
so David Clarke found Craig Lindsay and the way he found Craig Lindsay the guy that kept one of the prints is that he got
a he got a
Declassified government document out of the MOD's office that had redactions on it. And one of the things it said was
It was 1990 and they said RAF press officer in Scotland
Blacked out, you know said that blah blah blah blah blah and he's like, huh
Who was the RAF press officer in 1990 in Scotland Craig Lindsay boom contacts great Lindsay
They started communication going and then after like so much for redaction
Yeah, so much for redactions, right? And so this whole dialogue starts going and there's you know developing a and and then um,
He goes well gosh, I might I guess I might have when it turns out he ended up keeping one of those prints
Which he had and that story broke probably two years ago David Clarke again
I can't thank you enough you deserve accolades for this and so I flew to England
I met with David Clarke and his crew that people that did the analysis work. Then I went up to Scotland
I met with Craig Lindsay the art press officer gave me the first and only on-camera interview about it
What astonished him about it the analysis work that did on it what the witnesses said?
But we didn't have the witnesses the people that took the photograph
We didn't have them but I was gonna report on this anyway just because wow
This is the picture that we've all been waiting for this picture is phenomenal
But if you don't have provenance and you don't have the background story on it, it could be AI
It could be right could be a hoax. Some people call it a reflection not a reflection not a hoax. So
I'm ending production of the program and
I get a text from David Clarke and he goes something big is about to happen and I said what he goes just sit tight
I can't go public right now, but something big's gonna happen. There's a there's a new development and this is just teases
Well, I'm coming out with that. I promise so he did he did he did tease me
But I was like, well, I'm almost done with the movie
And if this is something I conclude in the movie about the case, please let me know
So long story short this guy Richard Greaves who was one of the hotel cooks worked in the kitchen with the
Photographers with the two witnesses that took the photograph and Richard Greaves
Came forward on print but I contacted David Clarke. I was like, hey, can this can I can you get me an interview with this guy?
so
He kept putting it off putting it off putting it off
And then finally I was like didn't want to be I wanted to be persistent
But I didn't want to annoy the guy to the point where he's been like, hey, you know what you like, right?
You're being annoying, you know, yeah, but I got it right up to that point
Right when I was like I was rapping the movie the movie's done
I want to get this movie out all the people that participated wanted it out
And then I finally sent him one final text
I was like, look, I'm really sorry to pastor you and I know you're probably really busy and I really appreciate the fact that
You even said that you'll meet with me, but that you'll give me an interview and then probably about 10 o'clock that night
I'm in the editor room buttoning the film up and all of a sudden I get a phone call and he's like
I'm just come out the pub. I'm ready to go. I was like, okay grab a camera roll it. Let's record this and
he
reveals that
He knew the the witnesses. He worked with them in the kitchen. He gave all the specifics
He provided their names and then he said that two or three nights after
Two or three nights four nights after they took that photograph. They were all on a cigarette break at the hotel early evening
Pissing rain. He said a car rolled up
There were three guys in it a driver and two men in suits in the back. They roll up they come out
They say cigarette breaks over they pull the two witnesses aside and they
Grill him and you got to hear it directly from the horseman Richard Grieve said that when they were all
The people that were not involved with the incident were told to go back inside the hotel which they did but they looked through the window
And they saw in the pissing rain. He said they're out there for 10 or 15 minutes in the pissing rain and that these guys
They came back inside and they were white as he said he's he literally goes
They they came back inside they were white as a fucking ghost and
Which we all get a good laugh out of but and then they started drinking heavily and within a couple of weeks
They vanished without a trace and they've been gone ever since so we report on this and yeah, that's a that's a replica
That's a replica. I say it's way too clear
I was like that's a replica from Nick Pope that he did it for some series talking about it and that was before
The real photograph was found and print. Let's see the real photograph
Let's see the real photograph. Yeah, show the real photograph again. I got it in there. It is. Yep
Okay, so what was he doing? Show the fake one one more time?
Yeah, that's what the recreation before it leaked out. So was he just recreating what he remembered? Yes. Let me see the real one again
It's pretty damn good. Isn't it that he remembered that not bad. Not bad miss the barbed wire fence
But not mad that put in a bunch of bullshit back. I went to the exact location that bullshit
He put in there put in beautiful hills. I know and and that fence is still there. There was a back throw
Yeah, that fence is still there. I took an actual I took a model
What is that jet in the back Harrier jump a Harrier jet is what I'm told
They're 99% sure and was that Harrier jet trying to figure out what this was
Well, like I said in the other prints according to to Craig Lindsay the RAF press officer
He said the other six prints or five prints had that Harrier jet in a different position
So he said it was if the Harrier jet flew around checking that out now, where are those other prints?
We have other MoD just ever gone they killed the story
I mean the guy at the mo do work there Nick Pope told me that they did everything they could to squash it because don't you
Think they probably have it filed away somewhere. Oh, of course. They do throw it away. Of course
They didn't throw those pictures away. They do zoom in on this January, please. Yeah, that's a really crap copy
You're looking at a really bad break
I've got a much better
I've got a much better version of it. You got it on your phone. I do text it to a homie. There's some this image is
It's weird. Yeah, it's a it's it's a it's hard to see what you're looking at, you know
It's a yeah. Well, let me show you a much better copy of it. Hang on
Let me just scroll up here because I've got a really good I got the original print
Of this copy, but you know people talk about you know, the more compelling data and the links so this is
This is the photograph that I took at the site. You can get an idea of that. Okay
See how right how similar right look exactly the same. Yep, and then here is
Here's the here's the print
And I could take a I could text that to you guys if you want
Yeah, text that to me. I'll text it. I'll text it to you guys
It's very interesting very interesting case. I mean it's again. I think it's one of the
Best photographic cases because you're not dealing with just a UFO
You've got a military jet in the background and if you have a date and a location guess what that pilot's still out there
That pilot can probably got it on radar and probably got gun camp for if he's still alive
If well, he would have been probably young right pilots are young sure
He would have been in his 30s or maybe early 40s and that was 34 years ago. So chances are he's still alive
They're pretty fit, right? Yeah, maybe he's in the 70s. Okay, I'm gonna I'm gonna text this to you right now
Here we go
Boom, you should have that
Did I get you all did I get all of them to you and here is a picture of Craig Lindsay, this is great
You're gonna love this
Okay, this is this is the guy that kept it I didn't get it yet you didn't know
I wonder if it's because I have my phone on airplane mode. Yeah, take it off airplane. Oh, bro. I told you
Okay. Oh you did explain to you. Oh, sorry. Okay. It's off now. I'm sorry. Otherwise, it won't actually send it
Oh, it won't. Okay. All right. Here we go. Here we go
Like I know I'm so bad. I know you were telling me how to do it. I was like, I haven't done that before
It's funny people that don't understand how to use their tell me if that goes through
Okay
Great great sure need me to send it here you do it
There's that one and there's flipped it left to right on it
but you know, it just goes to show the links that the Intel community the
Ministry of Defense the DOD go to hide the more compelling
Photographic data because it's so easy to complain like oh, well if they were real there would be good
Well, there are some really good
I found drones that you can I don't know that they're commercially available
But you can have a drone up for 24 plus that didn't send it to me either. Are you serious?
Am I sending to the wrong telephone number let me see your number the number you have
Okay, well, I have it. I definitely have it on signal. Yeah, you do it. Yeah, fuck it. You take over you drive
Because I'm clearly failing at this one
Oh, I can totally imagine that this is a separate I found some drones that this these companies say that you can take off anywhere
They're showing them taking off from like small platforms in the ocean. They can stay up in the air for 14 plus hours
They're small and they do have propellers. I will say that. Mm-hmm. Yeah, and like I said, I mean
It's not the question is and are all these drones, you know explainable by aliens and the question
Obviously the answer obviously is no the question is are any of these bona fide UAP and there's definitely some evidence to suggest
That's the case. But again, there's always misidentification of more conventional stuff, right?
And there's always
And then there's a stubborn core percent like I give you an example
This is something that I've discussed a little bit recently. Did you find it? Okay? Yes. Okay good. Finally
We've got that that enigma worked out. Yeah, it's just your 5g is very slow. Oh, really? Yeah, you're using AT&T
Oh, I use in Verizon Verizon. Yeah, really? Yeah, it's just real slow
Do I have do I have what's gonna call it on actually accidentally sent myself these are the ones of the guy holding it up
Too. Oh cool. Yeah, that's cool. That's that's Craig Lindsey. So
I'll send this to you Jamie. So let me tell you a little a little story. That's pretty cool
Which I never thought that this would happen. I
There's a guy Kirk McConnell who Senate Armed Service Committee and he participated the very last minute in my in my film
He's in the trailer and he in an official capacity with a high-level clearance
He had been investigating UFOs ever since the New York Times article in 2017. So he was behind the scenes
2017 2018 telling the 2017 2018 2019 2020 2021 22 23 24 and then he stepped down and he came
Through some Intel folks. We got in touch and I said hey, man
My films almost done if you want I could squeeze in one final interview. He decided to participate up
He went we became friends. We've been talking and he said hey
I could probably arrange a meeting because there's some mutual interest in some UFO cases and evidence that I've been going after as a
Civilian but he goes hey on the inside if you want I can cook up with it with the heads of arrow the new heads of
Arrow John Koskowski and this other guy Ryan it was Air Force Office special investigations. This is just a couple weeks ago
So I went to the congressional hearings, which was incredible and people say always big nothing burger
But you know what? It was very exciting seeing people testifying to oath
There's a there's a crash retrieval program seen at a rear Admiral Tim guy at Gallaudet saying that they're under the water
I mean, it's pretty fascinating stuff. Yeah, so I
had to I had to apply for a
Security background on me which about 48 hours and then I got approval for that and then I showed up
And a wing across the street from the Pentagon and I had to go through the metal detector and then there are these
Kind of exciting for me because I had never had this kind of experience before there are these like glass
Tube type things that were lined up like in a row and I only one person go in at a time the doors open
Just like in Star Trek and you walk in and that door closes the other one opens you go to the other side
Then I had to get rid of my phone and everything and leave it outside and then I go into a skiff
Which is a sensitive compartmented information facility
As gifts all super top-secret whatever and
And I got to meet with the new head of arrow John Kostelowski
I was like, I can't believe I'm in the belly of the beast. This is crazy. I got how could I I'm a civilian
I don't I don't belong here, but we started talking. They're just very nonchalant. You know, I said hey
You guys got to throw us a bone I said, you know, we're not going away
The story is not going away and I said, you know, and you know what we're ultimately dealing with
I mean obviously the vast majority of UAP or UFOs can be and have been explained away in down-to-earth conventional terms
Right, but there's a stubborn core 15 20 percent that really defy conventional explanation
Not because of a lack of data because they truly can't explain what these things do and you know
Well, you've had many people on these objects exhibited technology
That's just light years advance from anything that we have
I mean this is and it's been well documented since the 1940s and possibly some people say way before that but modern-day UFO wave
No question. So there's two, you know two stories
One is someone's been in possession of this revolutionary technology for 85 plus years and kept it secret or two
We're not alone, right? Right and a chai. So I said I said to the gentleman very candidly
You know, we're probably dealing with a small percentage of of NHI and what's the plan to tell the general public?
And this is just a couple weeks ago and he looked at me and he goes James
I can't part my hair without approval from the DOD and you can quote me on that and
That was him in my opinion telling me. Hey, this is structured in a way that's that I'm my hands are tied
I can I can uncover all the things in the world
But I can't tell the general public or even Congress without the DOD approving it first
Yeah
so that's what's kind of happening right now and one of the reasons why we were so fortunate to get the number of of
I say whistleblowers or potential whistleblowers or people to come forward in the program is because they were super frustrated with the previous head of
Head of error which is guy named Sean Kirkpatrick, which basically just kind of blanket
You know denied pretty much almost almost everything and people were extremely disappointed with that. But just like blue book
Yeah, I kind of like blue book. Yeah, they've always done that right? Yeah, but but again, he brought everybody's doing it
Not everybody's right. There's a bunch of well, I think now also with the internet
There's there's ways to get information out. That's much quicker and cleaner. No question then trusting a reporter
Yeah, you know and then your life's in danger. Yeah reporter get threatened and yeah
Yeah, now things just kind of get out. So so well, I've thought about this like, you know
I'm going back to Brazil and I thought you know, I'm obviously going after you know
Additional eyewitness testimony. I'm going out to the photographic stuff and those of you out there that are like tired of hearing about it
Well, I spent
20 plus years in search of the photograph that I featured just now that one with the background story on it provenance that sort of
Thing Jamie go look at the one that I sent you it's a better version
Yeah
and and so I saw I just because you've you know, you can't after a year or two haven't
Successfully obtained stuff. So this is a better. Yeah
Better version that you can see the granular of the film footage weird
It's almost looks like there's something in the back
It does look a little bit like that propeller or something like a Jetsons type thing
But but let's just say nothing was silent
Silent according to the witnesses that didn't make any sound hover there for an extended period of time
But when it took off it took off straight vertical like this
Straight up fast. It started going fast faster faster faster and then was gone
Yep, that was that was Craig Leslie who interviewed the witnesses who told me that
And it's so weird though according to Richard Greaves in Scotland the Americans got involved of course we get involved in everything
Yep
they showed up and they
Intimidated the shit out of the witnesses and I I know people can criticize me for reporting on these alleged men in black
But it's not me saying it
it's the witnesses that are saying it and I did it full bore for the first time full bore for the first time in moment of
Contact because I remember hearing these stories for decades and I finally was like everyone's gonna think I'm crazy if I report on this
but this lady who was the mother of the two daughters that saw they had these visits and
Intimidation and I was like screw it
I'm just gonna report on this and I'll just take the criticism, you know
And then I wasn't expecting this for the to be the case with this photograph, but it lo and behold it was but
Anyway, it's it's a huge story
It in my opinion they can't put the genie back in the bottle it's coming out and it's drip drip drip
But I have to remind your audience people that are feeling impatient that we've had three open congressional hearings in the last three years
Yeah, we hadn't had any in over 50 years prior to that
It's definitely even though it's still difficult to get information and figure out what's actually going on
There's way more open mainstream discussion of it. And it's frustrating at times. I get it, you know people are like
Well, why all these people why can't they just say why can't David Grush just tell us, you know
Well, I can remind people that the DOD has stripped David Grush of his clearances and won't allow him to get into a skip
This is one of the things that I talked to this guy Brian Benner appears in the movie at Politico
And he goes he goes if Congress finds out about it one thing we know on the hill is that you're gonna find out about
It they can't keep a secret. It's gonna leak. So they've been doing everything they can imagine
It's the DOD to prevent
Grush from going into a skip with members of Congress to release and reveal
the
Classified details necessary to verify his claims
Okay, if you've been keeping this under wraps for 60 plus years or whatever they've been doing
Yeah, would you really tell AOC would you really pull her aside and tell her?
Well, I mean any members of Congress with the proper clearances and feel like they want to have that information
I mean you got not making wrong with her. Yeah, I'm just saying let's pick a young one
Well, you're gonna give them all that information. Are you they're exactly they don't want them to have that information
There's no question about it. I mean I would that's what I would imagine
That's probably why they won't let brush get into a skim
So here's another thing I'd like to mention is that David Grush claims that he gave even a street address to the IC IG
Which is Thomas Monheim. That's the intelligence community inspector general
So I'm asking members of Congress to support all their efforts, you know
Burchette who's been amazing regardless of what your politics the guy's phenomenon
He's been really pushing for transparency. He's super solid guy. You got mace you got
Muscovsky what's this from from Florida Garcia from California AOC New York
Luna and
Then of course, you got the Senate side. You got Rubio. I totally knows where this stuff is rounds Schumer
and if you look at the
NDAA you can see the language in plain sight. I mean, it's it's phenomenal what's going on and I and I I
Think that our elected officials that are really pushing for transparency need to hear from us need to hear from the citizens and know
That we support their efforts and that we have their backs and continuing to push for transparency to push to find out
What the hell is going on? I mean imagine if it's true
Imagine if we have spaceships and we have biologics bodies, okay
That is not just
Implications for the United States that's global
Implications, I mean the impacts the ripple effect that would have around the world for that confirmation to happen. No doubt. It would be
Huge. Well, the human race deserves to know it shouldn't be
Unelected officials and Defense Department people that know about this stuff. That's crazy. I totally agree unless
unless
This is what I had a conversation with Ryan Graves yesterday the way I would argue it if I was a military person
I would say this is a national security interest and
We are trying to back engineer this stuff
We're not successful if China steals our data if Russia can back engineer one before if Iran gets one before us
We're fucked because these things are insanely we was indicated. We would obviously weaponize the technology. That's obvious
Yeah, it's like 101 right we not the basics I mean if you could put a nuke on one of those things
I mean the exhibited technology that people say
People that have witnessed this stuff say it goes from a standstill to out of sight in the blink of an eye
I mean these objects what was it?
David Fravor said that it went from space 50,000 feet above sea level to sea level in one second in one second. Yeah, that's
It's insane. We talked about it yesterday. Oh you did. Yeah insane amount of speed and
the way
Ryan explained it in terms of like the amount of force you would need is equivalent to how many nuclear bombs that he say?
Something insane like the entire nuclear arsenal has to be
To generate that kind of power whatever it is
It's if these stories are true. It's doing something that we don't understand. So if it's ours I
Kind of get why they wouldn't want to spill the beans
My thought once was what if this is not weaponizable with our current technology like what if these are
These things are our drones, but they don't know how to put a weapon on it yet
Like because whatever you do I have a problem with that a speed
I have a problem with that theory and the problem I have is that the United States government has
Documented close encounters of the third kind that's a beans connected right? That's their own files, right? That's not me saying it
Right, so it's not just these objects exhibiting revolutionary technology for at least 80 years, right?
No wings, no tail
No visible means of propulsion the ability to hover accelerate at a site the blink of an eye right angle turns at high speed
No wake no sonic boom that kind of stuff, but you also have reports credible reports of beans
Connected to some of the craft and that's documented all around the world. So that eliminates
Right if it's true
So well, yeah the whole thing like just because something's written down somewhere
It doesn't mean that someone didn't write it down as a Psy op
So don't someone did write down to discredit other people with a ridiculous story
One way to discredit a credible story is to attach it to a bunch of ridiculous stories, right?
So if I was gonna hide some sort of technology
One thing I would do is connect it to a bunch of kooky stuff
What's a psychic stuff and remote viewing just a bunch of things that people like very easily dismissed UFO abductions
UFO encounters encounters with an actual being right but put a bunch of stuff in there that like makes people go what is this real?
And just enough just enough so that you can hide the real stuff in there
Well, I think I'm again. I'm not I'm playing devil's advocate
And again, I've said this earlier on the show and I'll say it again is like the reason why I believe David Grush
Who testified not just I believe David, but David doesn't have firsthand experience
I know talked about but the reason I know I know but the reason why I believe
Him is because it aligns with my research in the field
I remember I spent over 12 years investigating on and off with my buddy Marco Leal and in in Virginia, Brazil
That UFO crash case and only found out last minute the last time I was there is that the Americans were involved
So I was like, oh my god, the rumors are are true
Like, you know, the Americans really are do you see like I obviously looked into Roswell for years
I went to Roswell the 50th anniversary. This is how the deal works, bro. You want the aid we get the UFO
We give you the aid but if a crash UFO you fucking call us. Yeah, stay out of there
Don't be carrying that dude to the hospital
Leave it to us and then we'll just scoop that up and shut the fuck up
What do you think about that that the one of the craziest stories is that there's a building somewhere?
That's an enormous building that was actually built around the UFO UFO was too big to move. Have you heard this story?
Yeah, it was reported on used News Nation with Ross call hard to be real and well Ross cold heart is a credible
He's got a great accent
Not quite British we believe
What it's close more credible than a New York accent there's something about a British accent that just adds credibility to anything
It was some guy from New York. So we got this fucking car right for the story
This spaceship so fucking big
Build a building around it, but they talked about it now. Here's what is this building and where is it supposed to be?
I I don't know. Oh, you're holding them back. No, no
Nope, I have a little bit but I don't have the same connections on that
But I'll tell you a case that I do think needs to get looked into oh, you see, you know
You're gonna move us around. Yeah, yeah, because this is what this is. No, but this is a craft
Government agent this guy so trying to so there's a there's a memo in the program
That was through the dobson process was released. Unfortunately, some of the names are redacted
Christopher Mellon obtained it. It was from correspondence. He had with a high-level government official
Back in 2020 it just got approved for release. I don't know maybe a year ago
it's featured in the in the in the dock and
In it has the names of not just the gatekeeper
But other people that names who found the gatekeeper to the crash retrieval program
I'm told that unredacted versions that had been handed to select members of Congress and people that are investigated in an official capacity for the government
But in it, they specifically mentioned a case not crash a landed case. It happened in
1953 it came in, Arizona
So I've made some inquiries with aerospace folks that I've been meeting with quietly and I'm like, what's this case?
So you guys keep talking about with the King in Arizona. They're like, oh, it was like they just landed and left
I was like, well, how do you know they like what do you mean landed and left and they're like
Well, the doors are open and nobody home and they walked off
I said you mean somebody just flew this thing down
It landed on the ground in the desert and came in Arizona in 1953 and they left the doors open and laughing
They're like, yep, that's pretty much what happened
So I'm so they left the craft there somebody just they flew it down and left a craft on the ground
I was told that and I I wouldn't be repeating this if I didn't think there was some serious credibility to it
But apparently is and well doesn't that align with how Diana Pesolka and Gary Nolan have started describing these things as donations
The individual that I talked to was so funny because this individual was like not a scratch
And I go not a scrap what not a screw not a scratch not a scratch on the no
It was perfect didn't have a scratch. I was like, oh my gosh
This sounds like somebody who's more than just heard about this but that one of the aspects of it didn't have a scratch on it
So I think that's that's a case that I think that so the first hand
Witness said it didn't have a scratch. I don't know if it was the way they describe the way the problem
The way the problem I have with all this stuff, but here's the thing if you were Travis Walton. Yes. Okay. Love that guy
I love that guy too fascinating. I really enjoyed there's we got a bobblehead. That's a Travis Walton bobblehead. Oh
No way. Yes way. I got it from Travis. That's him staring at the sky. Oh my gosh when he's a young man
I went to the location. So that is I'm interested in that because that's a first-hand witness. Yes, right? That's a guy
Yes explaining his bizarre experience. He told the same story. No question for whatever's 56 forever's whatever the hell
It's 1975 whatever it was since he got abducted 50 almost 50 years. So this guy
Was there that was his story that I'm interested in that when I hear a guy told a guy
That this is what happened and this is how he described it. I'm like super frustrated. So talking to Jay Sands
Yes, first-hand again first hand was like
Yeah, yeah face-to-face yes, tell me what it was doing what it looked like yeah
That's it. He thought it was an adolescent too. He didn't think that it was a full-grown one. He thought it was young
Well, he's got an illustration of it in the documentary and I tell you it's it's one of the crazy
I remember after imagine I know I was like if this is true. I was like
Crazy
Person now, this is something that we didn't reveal in the documentary was really funny
He thought that this individual was suffering from frostbite or
That when you get really cold hypothermia
Skin had a blue tint to it
so he was take he took his jacket off and he
Very insistently put the jacket on this individual because he was thinking this person's really really cold
He's been out in the desert probably had a plane crash or whatever
Right, and so he's putting his dad and the person was kind of resistant
But Jason said I insisted I took one layer of my jacket and I put around this
Individual and that individual left with the jacket on so we jokingly I jokingly say where do you think your jacket is now?
Probably out there it helps Atari or god. Holy knows or right here. Yeah. Yeah, or yeah, or this is the thing that gets right here
Logistically, yes. Okay, if these things are coming from the ocean just logistically you would have to have a large ship
So we were talking about this with Ryan yesterday and I was saying like if they had a battleship
We'd be able to see that right like 100% he said so it would have to be a submarine
So Mike Jesus Christ, what if there really is some sort of a civilization?
Underwater that that has existed co-existed with us forever. Did you hear about the
Testimony by rear Admiral Tim Gallaudet just recently in Congress. Is this the one where the things moving underwater 500 knots?
Yes, he's reporting. He's
I don't have all that you can remember. Yeah, what I can remember is basically is confirming that we have
Objects that are exhibiting a technology underwater that defies any conventional explanation things that are just virtually impossible
Like so much faster than the fastest submarine or anything like that just and they're really big
Yeah, it's moving as if there's no resistance underwater. Yeah, then they moving like a fighter jet would in the air
It's moving like that. Yeah, they call the transmedium or something. Yeah, but there's but confirmation
I mean that's and I actually spoke to to to rear Admiral Tim Gallaudet
On a couple of occasions recently and I thanked him for coming forward to testify and he said, you know
I felt an obligation to do so because a lot of my men
The pilots were coming forward and I wanted to back them up and so that's why that's why he stepped forward and
You're if you're coming here from somewhere else and you wanted to hide in plain sight
You would hide in the ocean
Especially if you have the technology to like completely negate any of the effects of the the water and the pressure least explored
Place on earth. Yeah, we can't get to it. We don't have the technology to get they know we don't they know
It's really hard to get a submarine out to wherever the fuck they went to the bottom of the Mariana Trench
Cameron Cameron by himself. I would never do that. He's a wild boy
Like 35,000 feet down. How far is it bizarre like that?
I mean, that's those poor would you go down in a submarine by yourself? No, definitely not
Homemade one like the one those people died in yeah
but that was there's another thing about that case when the people went down that submarine apparently I
Guess it's the Navy has some sort of very sophisticated underwater
Audio sensors and they heard the implosion and they knew about it like immediately and didn't report on it
Well, I mean I think the problem with reporting on is that you have to report on your technology now
Yes, I don't even know if this has been confirmed, but this is what I had heard methods and means or well
It's also
It's got to be top-secret
Like it's got to be one of those things where if you're gonna reveal that you heard that you have to have clearance to do
You probably have to run it up the ladder
One of the reasons why we know about overhead
Satellite imagery of UAP is because of Ratcliffe who was former head of ODNI
and he came forward and I remember it's funny actually it was classified and
Christopher Mellon participated in this latest production with me because of Ratcliffe revealing it on Fox News and Ratcliffe basically says
Yeah, we have overhead collection satellite data of UAP that are pretty fucking far out and that yeah that that happened
So they're talking about this but getting back to your point because I know you said you were frustrated
You're like, oh, yeah, it's just another anecdotal piece of evidence a piece of testimony third-party not firsthand
No, I know I what I'm saying is I totally agree with you
I'm frustrated as somebody who's been chasing the story for 30 years
I too want access to the better more compelling data
Yeah
Why chase after that photograph I just shared with you earlier on for as long as I did because I hear about something
I go after it, but I want to remind your audience
You can't go after something without knowing that it exists
So you get the leads you find you start we're learning more about the programs
We're learning how these programs are hidden these who saps
They're waved unacknowledged special access programs probably hidden somewhere in the deal
I know it sounds crazy
But but least guiding giving some guidance to where are these things and how these things are hidden where they might be found
We reveal there's a gentleman in the film called Navy X and people are like, ah, it's just another person
Testifying anonymously. Well, yes true
But he gives us specifics on telling members of Congress where to look to find this specifics
Jwix, what is it? And this is where to find the more compelling data
I'm gonna read this because it's important that people know that he's saying look I've seen it and this is where it is
It's called the official UAP data is kept either in sipper secret internet protocol router network or jwix joint worldwide
Intelligence communication system that's used by the DOD and only available in a skiff and a skiff is a sensitive
Compartmented information facility. So is it frustrating to hear that and people criticize? Oh, it's it's another person
But he's saying I've seen it
It's phenomenal. He gives descriptions of some of the stuff he saw and he's telling members of Congress
If you have the clearances, this is where it's being kept. So those are very good specifics
And again, I remind you guys like okay, just be patient. This is not a hundred-yard dash
We're running a marathon right now
We are we're trying to get back to what I was talking about earlier
Logistically, I'm kidding. If you're letting something go from the ocean. Yes, if you're flying it out of the ocean logistically
You would have to have some sort of a large craft out there
That's going to house these things or it's gonna launch from yeah, if it is actually coming from the ocean
Oh, you see the drones you're talking about right now, right? Yes, so either they're ours and if there are ours
Yeah, how do they hide the fact there's a battleship out there if is that possible? And if if it's from a submarine
How do they develop a submarine that can launch 50 car sized or SUV sized drones from yeah
That's one of the things that Christopher Mellon said to me this morning. He goes that's just that's the one
element or aspect that that really is a head-scratcher because but this is the question 50
50 of these things coming in off the ocean that's just confirmed right, right? No one said no
Here's the question. Yes, is it possible to classify the location of a US battleship?
That's capable of having these things so big. How could you like what how big would it have to be to launch 50 drones?
God, you're not talking you're talking. I don't know man
But that's a question a lot of drones, especially the size they're reporting they're talking about drones the size of an SUV, right?
So let's uh on loiter time, let's imagine let's imagine you
So when you take a ferry, how many cars can a ferry fit on it?
I take a ferry all the time in Vermont like a legit one like a European 50 cars
I put well the one that's medium legit I put
25 30 maybe 40 25. Yeah
So could you think couldn't you do that with drones and couldn't you have something that's a little larger than the average ferry?
So you wouldn't need a battleship? Why would they do that? Why would they do that?
Residential areas. Well, I don't know have everybody scratching their heads all these press conferences
You're talking about the head of the gang of eight. Okay
but if they're if they need to
You're gonna tell the if they are really looking for a nuke
Okay, let's imagine that this story about you know a Ukrainian nuke from the time when they they disarmed them
There's one that's unaccounted for this is one of those stories that's been on the internet. I don't know if it's true
Yeah, that it's unaccounted for that
They think it's headed to the United States if you were trying to find that thing like a dirty bomb
Yeah, or like a just a regular nuke that if you're looking for gamma rays
like the you could devise a drone that could search for that and you'd fly it over an area and you wouldn't care whether people
Freaked out because it's more important to find this goddamn thing. Mm-hmm, right?
So if you have this technology, it's some skunk works
No, I don't think so. I think you have to be there certain proximity within I think to pick up whatever
Did you bring this up with Ryan Graves? Yes. What did he say? You mean he doesn't know either, you know
He doesn't think so everybody that I trust that's the issue people in the FBI people that I'm I communicate with often
I'm like what is going on?
it almost seems too sexy that the United States has that kind of ability and they're just flying these things around and that
They're doing it for that specific reason to find a nuke
It's like that we have this kind of technology that we didn't none of us are aware of that
We have these these drones that can shut off when you come close to them. The lights shut off. They disappear
They that go dark avoid tracking the RF signal doesn't show up
They they're cool. There's some they have some sort of cooling mechanism in them. So it's difficult to see with infrared
I don't understand any of that. He was saying that's above what we can do right now
And saying they but they're not moving in a way necessarily
That's not possible with drone technology that is mainstream
But there's some aspects of the way they move and what they're doing that doesn't lead them to believe that this is
Current state-of-the-art technology. There's no yeah
They even even I had some and tell people tell me like even if it's conventional, it's highly advanced conventional, right?
But let's look at China like China has highly advanced drones. Yeah, they're drunk. They're
We're talking about this as well that the bottleneck in America was the FAA
The FAA put a lot of restrictions on the manufacturer of drones and how you can do them what you can do
China doesn't have any of that
So they're full steam ahead with innovation if you look at what drone manufacturers in the United States have been able to do and then
Imagine untethered if they weren't fucked over by all these regulations that got in the way of innovation
Who just come obviously you have to have one because if you have some
Commercial drone that someone can buy that can move
500 miles an hour and fly through the air and stay up there for six hours at a time and film video of everything and anything
Well, and you can't control it. You can't block the the radar screen. You can't find it with infrared. That's pretty nuts
So I would imagine that would not be a thing that they would want in the hands of the average American person
But why did it just start happening fairly recently when I say this I'm saying if it's Chinese
If it's Chinese if they if they're unburdened by our regulations and that not only do they have the help of the government they have
Financing behind them. They have an imperative there. They're told what to do
They're flying it over Langley. They're flying it over wouldn't you do that bet just to fuck with these people
What's the golf course that Trump has? Yeah, it's golf course. Yeah, what's that called? I don't know Westminster
They're flying over that yeah the president-elect
So it's Langley Air Force Base did experience incursions of unauthorized unbanned aerial systems in last year December
2023 says Sabrina Singh Pentagon spokeswoman the number of those UAS incursions did fluctuate
But they didn't appear to exhibit any hostile intent. It's something that we have kept our eye on
Well, thank God you're keeping your eye on it. Yeah, we have no idea what they are, but they they're fine
That's been happy this is the third year in a row this has been happening right around Christmas time
One of the reasons why I wanted you guys to hear that account by the guy at Vandenberg Air Force Base
This is not anonymous reporting the guy's giving his name right and he's talking about objects that are the size of a football field
Yeah, hovering over a silo launch control area. That's also the Phoenix lights
They described them as size of a football field or larger. Oh, yeah
Well, I interviewed a guy there was a case that happened in right here in Texas Stephen Ville
Ricky Sorrell is one of the best witnesses. I love the guy. He's a he was a hunter and
He's like he's like James. He's like you could have landed an airplane on this. I said you gotta be kidding me
He goes no man. I goes I stood under this thing. He goes it was so big I was
Standing under it and he had his rifle and he's standing under it and he's looking up and he's looking to the left
He's looking to the left right back forward can't see the edge of it in any direction
So he grabs his hunting rifles. He was he was hunting dear. This is 2008
Gives his honey shot it. No. Well, so he holds his honey, right his rifle up and he's looking through the scope and he goes
James I'm a metal worker. I work with metal. I know what metal looks like and he's looking through the scope and he goes man
There's no rivets. There's no seams. There's no weld marks. He's like there are these on the belly of it
There were these reverse like recessed
Cones it's like bigger and then they got smaller as it went up in the belly of the craft
He's looking up at it and his fingers on the trigger and he's like man
I wonder wasn't that how I go I wonder what happened if I just pulled the trigger here and I bet it would ricochet off
Or hit the belly or something
So he's looking at it and he's just about to pull the trigger to check it out and he goes
Hmm, maybe this isn't such a good idea. I
Interviewed him in 2008 when this is going down and then about a year later
I was doing some follow-up interviews for a film I did
I know what I saw and I had this gentleman walk up to me and I was filming in the downtown square in
Stephenville or it might have been Dublin and
This gentleman looks at me and he goes you mr. Fox
Yes, and he pulls out a badge and he shows me as his badge and he's like, can I talk to you for a minute?
I'm officer so-and-so and I was like Jesus Christ. What the hell did I do and I say yeah
We walk off to a cafe and he goes
He's looking at the head is back. He had his back to the wall and the cafe so you can see everybody coming in
He was really paranoid and he says, you know, Ricky Sorrell's I said, yeah, he goes that guy's telling the truth
I said, how do you know he goes because the whole police department saw it
I can't remember if it was Dublin Police Department of Stephenville. I think it was Dublin Stephen Police Department. He goes we have and we he said we
We were sitting over there patrol cars and this object was like a floating
Department store me it was absolutely colossus colossal like a city took out my radar gun pointed at it and it was doing
22 miles an hour and then he said it drifted off and they one of the officers
I don't remember the name of the gentleman took his his gun his sorry his dashcam and he flipped it up and he filmed it
And apparently with one of the biggest mistakes he this individual made this police officer made was it
He didn't make a copy of it because the local Air Force base
Requested that film footage and got it
And so I've been telling people to go after that stuff exists
But my point is this object was so big people claimed the witnesses the first-hand witnesses that you had landed an airplane on it
Yeah, I mean what is what is that?
See that that's the thing like if you see that do you even tell people you sound like a kook
Yeah, like if I saw it if I was outside in the desert. Yeah, I was just chilling
And something so big that I couldn't see the edges of it. Yeah flew overhead. I don't know what I'd say
He said when it took off it was like this
He goes James and Ricky didn't want to give me an on-camera interview for the longest time. He said I'm not coming forward
I'm not gonna do it. I'm not going public. I worked on him for eight months. Finally. I got the green light
I flew back out to Texas got him on camera put him in the movie
But he said when it took off it went from this a complete standstill and it went
Straight up like a slight angle, but straight up and gone. He goes James. I said describe the acceleration
He goes hell I'll tell you the best way I can describe is it had I blinked I would have I would have missed it
That's how fast it took off. So it went from here like that. He had um, he had helicopters hovering over his I know
This sounds crazy. People are gonna be like, oh this big, you know, but he had helicopters flying over his property for a while
Right around the time that I was trying to get him to go on camera
He came out in his underwear and his shotgun late at night with his helicopter spotlighting him up
and he ended up calling the local Air Force base and said stop flying over my house at night and they said we
suggest you stop talking about what you saw and
So he was kind of spooked and about eight months later
He finally he finally decided that he was gonna go public with the story
But you know everything to lose nothing to gain you get this countless reports of these cases
You know and they're around the world, right? It's not just the United States
I've demonstrated that time and time again
But there's more of them in the United States than anywhere else, right?
Well, I mean one of my favorite cases Ruiz and Bobway. That's an amazing right right
But there's more sightings in the United States
There seems to be an attraction almost like a moth to a flame with with nukes
Somehow they're interested in our new nuclear capabilities and and I remember interviewing that Robert Salas
Who was a launch control officer who described this whole event at Maelstrom Air Force base in the 60s where these UFOs were witness
on the base and then all their
Minutemen missiles started getting shut down and I remember saying to him like well what what?
What's what's your take on that?
Like what kind of you know, he goes and I could realize I realize why this individual was a launch control officer because he was
So measured and so calm and so cool
And he goes well James
The message I got was kind of clear. It's almost like taking matches out of the hands of a baby
About the news. Yeah. Yeah, so, you know with the phenomenon you look at what they do
Right and then that says some things
They've done some pretty brazen events right over the around over the decades, but you also look at what they don't do
Because if the phenomenon
Wanted to end this like, you know secrecy once and for all all they'd have to do is hover over the Macy's Day parade or
Of or the next big Super Bowl and it's game over they don't do that. They've done some pretty brazen things, right?
I mean case in point March 13th 97 over the state of Arizona including the governor 5 Simon witnessed that
Massive there were a number of UFOs witnessed but that the main one
You know was this big boomerang shaped craft and even the governor said it must have been at least a mile across from wing
Tip that floated and I actually interviewed people that worked at Luke Air Force Base at the time
And they said that they scrambled jets to intercept this thing and I interviewed a number of people that saw that craft
I mean that stood on their that light down in their lawns and watched it float over the top of them and
Apparently according to this individual that I met in the in the late 90s at Luke Air Force Base
They scrambled a military jet to intercept this thing. He came up on it could have landed on the damn thing
It was so big and it went from moving very very slowly to accelerating like warp drive boom just gone
when the jet came back to the base Luke Air Force Base, they had to carry him out of
The plane I'm told because he was so shaken by what he saw
Yeah, I could imagine you wouldn't handle that. Well, can you imagine having to keep that secret?
No, imagine like could you imagine taking the governor?
We had to lie right the government had to like stand up with a rope or a guy in a just an alien suit
Yeah, and the alien costume. Yeah, and I hammered him on that one
Well, then afterwards once he left office, then he talked about it. Yes, he talked about seeing it. Yes
Yeah, I got why he had to do that though. I got oh well
so I interviewed I was the one that got him to break his silence after ten years and
He told me and I don't necessarily know that I fully believe it
But he told because initially when it happened in March and now remember the vast majority of people were out of the night's guy
You get a glimpse of the hell bob comment
so it was witnessed all the way across the state of Arizona and even in Nevada, Southern Nevada and
Yes, there he is five told me that it was growing hysteria
But initially he had set out and he said we're gonna find out I'm contacting Luke Air Force Base
We shot to the Pentagon and all these various services and we're gonna we're gonna get to the bottom of it
And then I don't know how much longer it was. Was it later that day?
The next day he held an unscheduled press conference and that's when he had his aides dressed up in an alien suit and made a
Mockery of it all and I can assure you pissed the hell off his constituents and the witnesses all across the state of Arizona
they were furious and I
Confronted him on that ten years after the fact because I was pissed off
I was investigating that case when it happened in the 90s and I interviewed a lot of really good witnesses really good witnesses and
He said the reason why he did it was because of growing hysteria that he wanted to
quiet calm down the the hysteria, but
Did he get a phone call just saying hey kill this story? I?
Lean in that direction, but he's never even when we're having cocktails together
He's never confessed that that happened, but it was awfully suspicious the way it all went down
It's a little weird especially considering he actually saw it that could have been a turning point in the UFO phenomenon reporting
You know
Era right like suddenly you get this massive sighting which would happen today
We would have been covered by you know everybody's phones and I whatever but but if the governor had come forward and said yeah
We need to figure out that thing is I'm a former captain in the Air Force on a pilot
And I don't I saw it. I don't know what the hell that thing was
Is there any footage of the actual thing that the triangle boomerang there are there's some footage floating around and I featured some
And I know what I saw you got an object in the night sky with lights that and I at the time in
2009 I did some kind of enhancement. I'm sure the software is a lot better nowadays of
It looks like
Like a big I can draw it like a boomerang yeah, yeah, but more angular. It was like
like this
Am I drawing my drawings are terrible look up at the screen
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah kind of like that. Yeah, mm-hmm. Yep, and so that image in the far left
That's but that's yeah, and there was that's it right there, right? Yeah, and here's something that kind of throws off the trail here because
Excuse me the object came down of the state of Arizona it went from north to south is that legit
on the right there yeah, I
Honestly, I can't say
I'd have to really do a deep dive into it
But let me tell you what happened because this is brilliant
So what happened was you got this massive object from around 530 at night in the southern?
Nevada and then it drifts down very slowly over across the entire from north to south across the entire state of Arizona and right around
738 830 the Gary the Barry Goldwater Mountain Range, which is the direction it was heading in
The military decides to drop a bunch of flares and
So people were like, oh there it is. There's some you know, and they and a bunch of people film the flares
So in my opinion, it was a diversionary tactic
That was brilliantly done because why the military suddenly decided to drop flares and the shape of somewhat of the shape
So I think that some of the footage that you've seen out there is military flares, but there's and there was an effort
I don't know if you want to get into it right now, but there was there was an effort
By the so-called M&B, which the MIB these men in black or the whatever unknown government agency they come from
to
That took that took some footage that I was
learning about
During my investigations in the 90s and then you're looking at me looking crazy
No, no
So the first time I really heard a really credible report of the MIB and I decided not to report on it
Was when I was in touch with a woman who was councilwoman Frances Barwood who was one of the few officials
in
Phoenix area that was saying hey, let's investigate what these people are claiming they've seen
She's not saying aliens have landed. All she's saying is hey these people have a right to know what's going on
Let's launch an investigation. She was lambasted over the media made fun of ridiculed
But as a result of her inquiry public inquiry and putting it out there
one of these individuals reached out to her and I know this because I know her Frances Barwood and I heard the whole story and
he was a
He was a Vietnam vet and he was on the roof of his house with a tripod and a camera and he was trying to
Get a glimpse
He was trying to film the pale Bob comment and he had walkie talkies and he was monitoring the truck drivers driving up interstate 10
from Tucson to Phoenix and so he's
Monitoring this and he hears these truckers talking about a massive UFO and he's like shit
That's heading right towards my house
Who was like I'll film it
So he had a camera all ready to go and the object went right over his house according to him and he filmed the whole
Thing and he goes. Yeah, I filmed the whole thing. It's pretty spectacular
And I know that you're launching an investigation Frances Barwood. Would you like to see it?
And she said yeah, so they made arrangements where he was gonna drop it off at her office
Either later that day or first thing the next morning two representatives and it was July at this point
It was very hot two men in dark suits showed up at his house and they said hey
He was apparently relieved. That's all they wanted. He said they were quite menacing looking didn't really say a lot
They said we're from Francis Barwood's office. We're here to pick up that footage
So he gives him the footage and he said the only question they asked him is did they make any copies and he said no
And so they take the footage off. They go when he doesn't hear from Francis Barwood
He's like what the hell so a couple days go by I think possibly up to a week
He calls her up and he says and Francis will tell you this she'll validate what I'm telling you. He says hey
What do you think of the footage?
She goes well, what do you mean? What I think of the footage?
I never got it. You were gonna drop it off at my office and you didn't show up
He goes well didn't have to you had two men from your office show up and pick up
She goes I didn't send anybody around to your office and I know at the time in the late 90s
I'd heard a couple of stories prior to that. I thought this is too out there. This is too outlandish
No one's gonna believe this. I have no proof of this other than her testimony screw it and I didn't report on it
But hearing those cases over and over and over it's like there we go
Once again the so-called evidence that could prove or disprove one way or the other the something truly
Extraordinary took place in the skies over Phoenix back in 1997 vanished
But there is some that's that slip between the cracks that's out there
You just have to do due diligence and there's I don't have the time to sip through those images that we're looking at
They look too clean. Yeah, I don't know what's AI generated or whatever. But what could have been in a documentary like a recreation?
I know what I saw features some of the footage. I covered that case extensively
So if anyone's interested in the Phoenix lights case that but I can tell you how many cited how many people saw it?
Oh thousands. Yeah thousands
I talked to another woman Stacey Rhodes and her daughter Emily and they said they were driving on Interstate 10 and she goes look James
I'm gonna tell you how big this thing was
I said how big is she goes first of all, there were people stopped on the freeway just like stopped as this thing
It was like close encounters. They're floating over the she goes
I could have held up a newspaper like this and look to the left look to the right look that and she said I couldn't block
This thing out. That's how big it was and it didn't make a sound. It was gunmetal black
It was witnessed by a lot of people
That's why I say there's some some events that have happened over the decades that are pretty brazen
And that's one of Hudson Valley's pretty brazen as well
knew if it was true
When you get thousands of people seeing the same thing if you see thousands of people saying the same thing including the governor
The governor invested in it and you go what happened the governor?
Yeah, the governor same guy who came out with a fucking guy dressed up like yeah
I know but I got him to come clean ten years later, but so he's well not credible. Well, he already bullshits
He does he bullshits. He definitely bullshit. He definitely bullshits
You're right. Yeah, but when someone bullshits about that, they may bullshit about anything, but well I
True. Yeah, but I mean I again. I'm just playing devil's out. No, I hear you. I hear I hear what you're saying and I
He has been a limelight a while. It's good thing to talk about now. There's no smoke without fire. There is so much
evidence in terms of
eyewitness testimony and
radar some photographic not as much as we'd like that something truly inexplicable is
Taking place in our aerospace right for sure something that
after careful examination something that
Not because of a lack of data in some instances
But that after careful analysis and research investigation that comes out the other end and says I can't explain this
This is gonna have to be one of those
unknowns or you know falls into that 15% category of
Cannot provide a terrestrial or conventional explanation for and those are the cases that I've so desperately have been going after for a long time
So is all this disclosure and those discussions on television now and all these meetings and hearings does it
So are you think we're on an accelerated path? Do you think this is like this is all good, right?
I'm convinced of it. Yes, but do you think that there's a real possibility like within the next few years that they just completely drop
All the bullshit and come clean about this stuff
Or would it take some sort of extraordinary event where they had to admit it something much bigger than this drone thing?
Well in some respects there has been I
Remember I interviewed this guy Nick Pope at the MOD years ago
And I was like this is the time when we were pushing for
Transparency there France was was releasing previously classified documents on UFOs
Liz O'Neill as they'd say in the MOD followed suit
They're releasing previously classified documents slowly putting it out there and at the time was rather exciting
I just did a big event at the National Press Club with Leslie Kane and and it was like this whole move and it was
Like oh my god, it's happening, right?
But it it kind of petered out a little bit and I remember asking this guy that used to work the UFO desk at
The MOD Nick Pope and I said Nick do you anticipate this any type of disclosure?
This is like 2009 or something 2008 2009 and he goes
James no, he goes it's gonna be disclosed with a small D. Not a big D
It's gonna trickle out slowly the condition people get people prepared test the waters
You know one of the things that we explore in the program and I'd never done that is the politics of disclosure
It's a far more complex. Let's just suspend judgment for a moment and assume that it's real
Okay, that there really is an NHI or non-human intelligence aspect to the phenomenon, right?
Let's just suggest that's real. Now. How do you disclose that to the general public? What about the impacts on organized religion?
What about the impacts on financial institutions? What about the fact that we'd have to confess that we don't have full control over this
I mean
Those are real considerations and it's not just the United States, right? This involves the planet. This involves all the humanity
I wanted to ask you about this. You see I'm saying like yeah
Oh, I do I totally understand more complex than you think. Oh, I totally get that
What do you how does Russia handle these things? How does China handle these things?
Well, I there was a case in China that happened in 1994 right around the time of Rua Zimbabwe
also in 1994 called Meng Zhao Gua and
Happened in the Black Mountains and it was a landing alleged contact close to kind of the third kind
It's funny because it happened around the same time of Africa similar message that was conveyed. I went to China
I met with an active general in uniform talked openly about the UFO phenomenon. They were pretty open. I went to
Russia in the late 90s and that was right before Putin
It was right around the time when Putin was coming in and that was a period of openness
And I went to Star City, Russia. I interviewed a cosmonaut Pavel Popovich
A number of generals and they were very open about it. In fact, they said to me at the time if you're here
To discuss whether or not the UFO phenomenon is real the doors right over there
We're here to create an international coalition an international exchange of information and to talk about the implications of the phenomenon
Which I thought was amazing. This is like 25 years ago, right?
So now I don't know things have changed since Putin's been in office, but that was back in the late 90s
I mean, they've been congressional hearings in Brazil. There's been there's been an effort
I mean shit they had they had hearings back in 1978 at United Nations at least Beagle put on, you know
So there's been an ongoing effort for this stuff to come out. I just think it's different this time to me
It feels like they're not gonna
There's too much. There's too much momentum behind it at this point and there's so much legislation that's written
It's too much that's come out and it's too important
Look, whether you believe it or you don't believe it if you can just imagine for a moment if it is true
And if the US government does in fact have
Irrefutable evidence that we're not alone in the universe
That's so significant that we all have a right to that information and that we should continue to support this
Unprecedented push for transparency with our elected officials and get to the fucking bottom of it. Why not everybody agrees, right?
I think the general public no one's gonna disagree with you about yeah, and then new administrations coming in
There's I you know, there's Ratcliffe and Rubio. I'm telling you Rubio knows a lot. I know that how do you know?
He knows because I've talked to people that have debriefed him and been in the room with him during the first haven't talked to him
No, I have not. No, I have not but I talked to people that were in the room when he was being briefed from first-handers
I'm told that there were
I'm gonna say right around 12
First hand people that have that have had behind closed doors meetings firsthand
people that are concerned concerned about their secrecy concerned about their safety concerned about the implications and the of them coming forward and
You know going going public that they're not quite they don't quite have this comes from very good source of information
That the witness protection program and the legislation that they've created around that is not quite there yet. It's getting closer
They need to continue to work on that. You don't mean like witness protections program like whistleblowers. They have whistleblower protection
I'm sorry. I meant to say that. Excuse me. Yeah, whistleblower protection. It's not quite in place
One of the things I really wanted to mention is that there is a gentleman a young man who's 30 and he feels like he's old
His name is Jesse Michaels and he's got this new show called American Alchemy new a couple years old
Why does it feel like he's old because you know when you're 30 you feel like you're old really well
I did when I turned 30. I was like, I'm 30 because just 10 years earlier
I was almost 19 right or 11 years earlier. I was 19, right?
You go for a teenager to suddenly you're 30
You always stick like 30 and I was talking to him not too long ago Jesse and I said he's like, yeah
I feel a little old. I was like dude. You are just getting into your prime, baby
This is rock and roll tub, but I really wanted to this is a guy who's young
Julian Dory is also doing some amazing work on this and podcasts, but he was young and he's doing a deep dive into the implications and
Into he meets with aerospace engineers the guys he's a Jesse
Phenomenon keep rocking and rolling. I want to cut tip my hat to you
I don't know if you've seen this guy or not or no, he's doing deep dives into what's happening
Yeah, he's documented it with these podcasts and he's doing a fantastic job
and I just got a tip my hat to the guy because
He's ten times smarter than I'll ever be and he's young and he's a force to be reckoned with and he's really doing he's
Answering all the questions that you and are exploring all these issues that you and I are talking about
Well, I'm glad there's people out there pushing it and I'm glad there's guys like brush that are sticking their neck out and guys
Like you who are making documentaries about it
It's the the subject is much more open to discussion like I was saying amongst serious people
Yes, where it didn't used to be before and now I think with this drone thing
I think there's so many people are going okay
Okay, even if they're ours or they're China's or who what's going on? Yeah, why are there so many of them?
What are the answers and why can't you tell us is it because they're searching for a new Jesus Christ?
Maybe you should warn people and get the fuck out of here
Is that really what's going on like
If it's not what is going on and if it's not ours, what are they and how come you can't track them?
How come like what kind of very bizarre? It doesn't even make sense
It's very doesn't make sense when you think of the capabilities of the United States military
It doesn't make any sense. They can't figure out what's going on
I think what Trump said is probably correct that the government knows they know what's happening and they don't want to tell people
He could tell us why wouldn't he I don't think he knows yet
Until he gets in the office. He was he gave a speech about it at Mar-a-Lago. I saw that I saw that but did he say
Well, let's watch it. We'll watch it. We'll watch it. Yeah, pull the speech up because I'm wondering if he yeah
Well, we're about to find out. Yeah, essentially he was saying that he knows that the government knows what's going on and
They're not telling us so that means they're not telling him. So they're not telling him
No, I don't I'll think until you get in the office. You're not the president, right? So he's the president elect
I don't know what kind of clearances that he has. Yeah, I don't understand how that works
I'd be very curious to know what he knows right especially with this like who to even ask
Who is the person that can lay out the information like which department which which agents? Yeah, right?
It seems like they're so compartmentalized
Thank you, good to see you good to see you
The government the government knows what is happening
Look
Our military knows where they took off from
If it's a garage, they can go right into that garage. They know where it came from and where it went
and for some reason they don't want to comment and
I think they'd be better off saying what it is our military knows and our our president knows our president
And for some reason they want to keep people in suspense
I can't imagine it's the enemy because it was the enemy that blasted out even if they were late that blasted
something
Strange is going on for some reason they don't want to tell the people and they should because the people are really I mean
They happen to be over Bedminster
Very they're very close to Bedminster. I think maybe I won't spend the weekend in Bedminster. I've decided to cancel my trip
Yeah, I think I won't spend the weekend in Bedminster. Yeah
Wow, I bet someone told him mr. President, it's pretty important that you don't go to the golf course. Yeah
God, that's so crazy. Yeah. Um, so what does that mean? I gotta I gotta if you don't mind
There I was contacted what is this?
Well, no, no, no, no, no, no, this is all about exactly what we're talking about
I just this is something that that I really need to put out there because it's very important
Okay, and it's an unprecedented effort spearheaded by this woman Andrea who runs a number of communities on reddit
And she said that they're banding together for the first time ever
It's the biggest grassroots campaign for government transparency
This is happening on Friday the 20th of December at 3 p.m
Eastern time and this has the potential to reach millions and millions of people. It's the most
Unprecedented event on reddit in history and I'll post all of the necessary information on X
Because this is a very grassroots effort and I'm reach and what are they doing at James C Fox on X formerly known as Twitter
It's there the reddit community is banding together for a huge grassroots campaign for government transparency
So basically all the various platforms on reddit like paranormal UFO. They're all they don't usually get along too well, but they're all
Combining their resources and they're getting together for the first time ever and to push for government transparency
There's a couple of government insiders that appear in my film that will be appearing on this to answer questions
And what steps that need to be happening? What's going on today? And and this is happening on the 20th of December
3 p.m. And I'll be posting more information the very specific details on X at James C Fox
I just wanted to get that out there before because well the more of this stuff that happens the better the more people demand it the
Better the more politicians hear from the people and want to I mean
Especially politicians that are up for re-election and they want to show that they're doing what the people want them to do. Yeah
I'd like to know more but obviously I'm very happy that we're hearing much more about the subject in a serious way
Yeah, you know whatever the hell's going on. Yeah. Well, I
Really encourage you to watch the program
I will 100% I went bent over backwards to put together in and explain everything in layman terms
What's happened from 2017 to today because it's it's unprecedented. We're living in an unprecedented moment in history
There's an unprecedented push for government transparency and I want to continue supporting our elected officials
Bipartisan effort to get to the bottom of this and I especially want to throw a shot out to representative
Burchette because you're you're killing it buddy. Thank you. Hey, Jamie, why don't you use chat GPT and ask chat GPT?
What's going on with the drones in New Jersey? That'd be very curious to hear about that
Yeah, it's a damn good idea and maybe then ask rock but uh
Ask chat GPT what is really happening with the drones in New Jersey
Let's just see what tell me how that works
It's AI right and
What is really happening with the drones in New Jersey, let's see
So what does chat GPT say?
Chat GPT is gonna search the web. Oh
Numerous Jones side had been reported across New Jersey and other East Coast. It's incredible. How fast is this? Look how fast?
Look at this. This is incredible
They found no evidence suggesting threat to national security or public safety despite these assurances
Some local officials and residents remain concerned for instance Belleville Mayor Michael Melham
Speculated the increased drone activity might be related to a search for missing radioactive material from the medical facility in New Jersey
Additionally the public figures like Bethany Frankel have shared unverified theories about the drones purposes
Further fueling speculation the situation is evolving and authorities continue to monitor investigate new reports
Residents are advised to report any suspicious drone activity to local law enforcement
Avoid taking matters into their own hands like shooting them down people are shooting them down
So they shoot them down they're eating the dogs
It's anything to shoot down drones as it could pose safety risks and violate laws
Now ask chat GPT
Oh, let's just keep going with chat GPT for a little bit because you're asking it again
Ask chat GPT if I live in New Jersey, should I get out of town?
Yeah, if I live in New Jersey, should I get out of town
Should I evacuate? Yeah, should I evacuate? You'll say evacuate because get out of town is like a colloquialism
Should I evacuate?
Okay, this is amazing at this time there's no official recommendation for residents in New Jersey
Uh-huh follow official updates. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay
As a precautionary measure, are you sure are you sure?
No federal evacuation orders, okay, it knows that there's no fat federal evacuation orders if you were gonna give me advice
Would you tell me to leave the East Coast
Advice is fucked up
There we go
Based on the current information provided by trusted authorities. There's no evidence of an imminent threat
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah
Could you imagine?
Put this in
Could you imagine a scenario?
Where these drones are actually looking for a nuclear bomb and
If so
Would you advise me as a preemptive measure
To evacuate
I type so much worse when people are watching
I'm so impressed at how well he's typing actually I
Really am while it's possible to imagine scenarios involving drone searching for dangerous materials such as a nuclear bomb
There's no verified information suggesting such an extreme situation. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah
so I
How about this? I think
Type this in I said if I put it in grok and fun mode
We might get but hold on a second, but try this is there a non-human intelligence behind it. I think
The drones are looking for a nuclear bomb and I am going to leave New Jersey
Where should I go
To Montana how far away should I go? Oh, that's okay. If you leave New Jersey is a precautionary measure
Here are some suggestions for place to relocate temporarily. You're doing good head west. Okay, so now we're getting better
So now it's saying go further away
Wow
Colorado consider scroll back to up so I can read that where it's a Colorado
Consider Durango Grand Junction or areas outside of Denver. These are safe and equipped with modern infrastructure
Almost telling you to move this is telling you to get away from big cities to Rango, Tennessee
The Smoky Mountain region and Gatlin Burger, Knoxville provides natural beauty lower cost of living and a sense of isolation
They're telling you how to rebuild civilization
Okay, if a nuke goes off
Where to go if an if a nuke goes off on the East Coast type this in Jamie if a nuke goes off on the East Coast
Where should I be to be safe
Oh my gosh, if you're concerned about potential nuclear incident
Here's a list of safest options based on geographic environmental and strategic factors, Montana, Colorado
Wyoming, Idaho sparsely populated vast distances for major cities and military targets
Towns like Bozeman Jackson Hole Sandpoint are beautiful remote and away from the fallout paths
Jesus Christ. I'm curious. What would happen if you asked chat?
GBT is it GPT GPT if
What percentage of UAP represent a non-human intelligence, okay, that's a good one
what percentage of
UAP
Represent a non-human intelligence
Really curious
I know
Could represent non-human intelligence remains unknown and speculative current investigations by UAP organizations like the US government
And it did it emphasize the following most UAPs have conventional explanations as project blue-blue bullshit
It's all percent of five or ten percent of UAP cases remain undefined even after thorough analysis these cases
I was like 15 to 20, but yeah, five to ten percent
Evidence inconsistent with known human technology
No conclusive evidence for non-human intelligence while some UAP cases are public puzzling the government as not officially, okay
Commander would type this in
Commander David Fravor
Encountered a tick-tock a tick tack. Yeah tick tack shaped
craft in
But 2004 2003 2003. Okay 2003 that defied
our understanding of
Of known physics
Period what do you think he saw?
Wow
2004 I'm sorry with tic-tac shape craft remains one of the most compelling and well-documented UAP cases in modern history key deal
Details the encounter craft describes smooth white oblong resembling a tic-tac no visible propulsion wings or exhausts play extraordinary flight characteristics
Accelerated instantly from a hovering position descended from 80,000 feet to near sea level in seconds
Fravor reported the object mimicked his movements during their engagement and then vanished at extreme speed
It's possible. The craft was an ultra-secret military project either US based experimental aircraft aerospace technology or developed by another nation
However, the extreme flight performance raises doubts such advanced technology would suggest a significant leap beyond publicly known capabilities
Which is inconsistent with current engineering limits
sensor anomaly or perception issues then yeah, I asked the heads of arrow if they could explain that one and they said no if
Don't type this in
Really good case if all
Accounts of the capabilities of the tic-tac craft
Are true
What are the possibilities that it came from another planet
If
The accounts of the craft capabilities are accurate instantaneous acceleration hypersonic speeds without the propulsion no heat say it loud
So people can hear you. Okay
So if the accounts of the tic-tacs crafts capabilities are accurate instantaneous acceleration hypersonic speeds without visible propulsion
No heat signatures and defiance of inertia then the possibly the possibilities of origin
Origin being extraterrestrial or from another planet become a viable hypothesis
Here's why the physics of the tic-tac craft reported behavior
The craft suggests technology that operates beyond our current understanding of physics and propulsion systems
No visible propulsion and implies propulsion system unrelated to conventional jets or rockets
Instantaneous acceleration defies inertia in Newtonian physics achieving this would require manipulating gravity or space-time itself
Silent operation no sonic booms despite hypersonic speeds points to a technology that likely emanates
Eliminates air resistance such as surrounding itself in an electromagnetic field or bubble this level of
Technological advancement far surpasses anything developed on earth if true such capabilities would suggest a highly advanced civilization perfect
Perhaps thousands or millions of years ahead of us scientifically if true. Where do you think it came from?
This was 20 years ago
I know but if true, where do you think it came from if how about this?
It's still typing
Final thoughts look at this writing a whole turnpaper. Yeah, it's amazing how fast it does. It's amazing. How fast it does. Wow
Tic-tac if the tic-tac UAP is real and the accounts are accurate then its origin may very well be
extraterrestrial or involve unknown physics and technology that we haven't begun to comprehend the extraordinary nature of the case suggests an equally
extraordinary explanation
What do you think? Why are you asking me bitch? You're chat GPT. What do you this?
Extra-terrestrial visitation seem plausible or is there another explanation that resonates more with you? So type this I believe
It seems plausible that they are extraterrestrial in nature
Good luck, I was gonna say if true comma if true
Where do you think they came from
Let's see
All right
Identifying where they might come from involves exploring nearby stellar systems known exoplanets and
Plausible scientific ideas about interstellar travel here are the most likely possibilities nearby star systems with habitable zones
Alpha Centauri system four point three seven light-years away the closest star system to Earth Proxima Centauri
Potentially habitable planet exoplanet
orbiting Proxima Centauri within the habitable zone if life developed there might be
Technologically advanced enough for interstellar exploration Bernard
So it's giving me a list of all the potential possibilities possible star systems. This one's only 39 light-years away
What was the closest one office office and Terry was that was that four light-years or something?
I don't know scroll back up scroll back up a little bit
Three point nine million point three four point three alpha Centauri four point three light-years away
Wow, but here's the crazy part pretty close. Remember the number the twin paradox theory
They say that if you get like two twins
Right as kids say one's ten
They're both ten right and you put one in a spaceship that travels the speed of light for one year
Mm-hmm. He would come back with an atomic clock on board that spacecraft a year old or CB 11 and his brother would be an old
Man. Mm-hmm. I
Can't wrap my mind around that right, but that's they say it's pretty much fact, but that's speed, right?
I think what we're talking about is different than speed. I think it's instantaneous instantaneous relocation, right?
So I think in state yeah, I think instead of like if you like the space time between the two points, right?
So I think the idea is that instead of a rocket that goes
You know five million miles an hour just shoots off of Earth and keeps going until it, you know
Five million years from now. Yeah, it runs into this planet. I think it's different than that
I think what if I had to guess
Where something can manipulate gravity and space what it would do is
instantaneously
appear in these new places
Like you've talked to a lot of physicists about this kind of stuff, huh?
I have and the way they explained it is baffling and
Bob Lazar's version of it is baffling because Bob Lazar's version of it that he told in 1989
Kind of makes sense
When you talk to people that are trying to develop some sort of a gravity or a warp drive, right?
And the way Bob Lazar explained it is that this element when bombarded with radiation creates this
I'm really butchering it for sure creates some sort of a
Gravity field that allows it the way described it like if you took a mattress a very soft mattress
They put a very heavy bowling ball in the middle of the mattress
It pushes the mattress down to that area and that this like folds time, right?
So you go from here here, but when you stretch it down suddenly those two points connect it folds it
Yeah, right. And so wherever it is, it's here. So it's not like it's going a million light-years
So it's million light-years an hour. Yeah space is malleable. Exactly. It's just well it makes sense
If if you think about how technology scales
Yeah, and if we do I mean Ryan brought up this yesterday as well that there was research and there was papers written about
The idea of having some sort of a gravity drive or having some sort of a gravity propulsion system something that doesn't rely on
Conventional, you know rockets
That's for sure exactly and he said that this was something that was discussed a long time ago
But then it just stopped and you know, we brought it up along quite a while ago
There was an episode that we brought up a paper that was written in the 1960s about gravity drives
Was that by hell put off? I do not know because he's like a propulsion
Expert in terms of the propulsion behind the physics behind UFOs
Yeah
And he tried to I tried to get him to explain it to me in sort of conventional layman terms
And of course my tiny little brain but he I felt like I almost grasped it for a moment
But the attire the amount of power that it would take to create that gravitational field around the object and he said that's why
You see them doing these maneuvers that look like it defy physics, right and then everything inside the craft would just splatter
It that that you're immune from that on the inside according which also would make sense
Right, but that would also make sense if you had something like that that you could go in the ocean as well
Right. Yeah, so because whatever's around you wouldn't matter because you're not affected by it, right?
You're somehow creating a field around it. It's it's that that's immune to whatever
That would be the only thing that would make sense where how it could move so fast underwater
Atmosphere space water and how it would be transmedium. Yeah and go from space into the water. It's unaffected by gravity
It's unaffected by all the things around it creates its own gravity field and allows it to just pass through things. I remember
Kirk McConnell who Senate Armed Service Committee who investigated UFOs from 2017?
I talked about him earlier, but he said that they were picking up
Aegis radar systems were picking these objects up from basically from space and they were shooting down from space all the way down
They'd loiter for as long as they wanted to go in the water
come back out again shoot back up into space and they would just do it like
You know all day long and there was nothing well, we can't see that right and
Know what someone does have I mean if there's someone in the military that does have some like super advanced satellite
reconnaissance imagery of these things
I
Could see why they would hold that back. I could see why they would think that people aren't ready for that
I could see it. Do you think Elon knows?
He's real cagey about it. He is cagey about it. He's got deals with the DOD and he's
Everything it's probably why I'd be cagey about it, too
He knows more than what he's saying, this is what he said if aliens are real, they're very subtle
That's what he was saying. I was like, I don't know if they're subtle man. The Phoenix lights wasn't that subtle
That's aliens
I heard from some people around him that that because of his contracts with DOD that he kind of keeps quiet about it because I'm
Sure, everybody talks about I mean even Ratcliffe talked about the satellite imagery for a view AP
I mean if they're picking it up, why wouldn't his systems pick it up?
He hasn't said a peep about the drone thing and you haven't asked him about it
Nope, if he wants to tell me he'll tell me I'm not gonna be that guy. I'm not gonna be annoying but
Publicly like on X has he said anything about the drones?
Something a couple weeks ago, I believe they think it was a couple weeks ago
I'll check right now
But is that there's a big drone storm or a big drone fight coming and people are taking that as like he knew this was
Happening. Hmm a big drone fight coming
well, you know, he's
Been real public about the idea that building manned fighter jets at this point kind of foolish, you know
And he's I think he's correct. You know, so unpiloted only. Yeah, I mean I think the fun out of it
Well, it takes the biological mistakes out of it is what it does
It takes the human mind out the human mind is very fallible
You know, we already know that AI systems like Mike Baker explained to us that AI systems with fighter jets beat actual fighter jet pilots
100% of the time so when they have a simulated yes when they have these simulated dogfights
Wow, they take AI fighter jets that we have right now
They beat our fighter jet pilots the best of the best 100% of the time
So they don't have any biological limitations in terms of what what they deal with things
Yes. Yeah, don't you have that right? So all you have to do is make the equipment and the materials
Robust enough so they can take insane speeds and not blow apart
But it certainly would be way easier to do that than it would be to get a human being to be safe in it
So much less badass though recently. So what does he say? Oh, so he clicked on it future wars are all about drones and hypersonic jets
So this is us talking about that. This is us talking about fighter jet pilots by humans will be destroyed very quickly
So he talked about it. So he put a clip up of us talking about it on the podcast. This was in November
November 28th and so neither side is air superiority and tanks are easily destroyed by missiles
So that leaves infantry and artillery basically World War one drones are not yet available in sufficient numbers to matter much like aircraft in World War one
A defense in-depth trench war means and then some modern example
So did you get the impression when you spoke to Elon about UFOs that he knew more than he was telling you?
Yeah, he doesn't he doesn't even entertain the idea of UFOs
So if you bring up the flavors incident, he'll just say no it didn't happen or that's doesn't seem interested
I don't know. I mean I would imagine what you're saying is true that it's not wise for him to discuss it
That's what I would imagine
Yeah
If he wants to tell me he'll tell me and if he wants me to tell no one I'll tell no one
Yeah, if he wants to tell me and say don't tell anybody I'll I won't tell anybody but I'm not gonna ask him
I think his position as you know being the guy at SpaceX. Yeah, why would you fuck around with that?
He's got too much at stake. Yeah, there's way too much at stake
Yeah, also like if anybody's gonna find out he's gonna find out if there's something going on if something legitimately going on
The guy who can catch rockets with a crane. That's the guy he's gonna know
I thought the first time I saw that I was like AI generator
I was watching the thing come down and I just thought that's the ones that land before that those insane
And now you can catch them. They don't even have to land
It's nuts like what he's done is just
Accelerate what we are capable of doing far beyond what NASA was able to do just a few years ago
So I used I used to have a neighbor that worked for Elon Musk and he drove a Tesla way early way early on when
Teslas weren't that many out there and I was like well you got a Tesla as a gas you work for Elon Musk
I saw him a couple years later and I was like, hey, you're not driving Tesla anymore. He goes no
He goes I I don't work for Elon anymore as a couple months sorry to hear that what happened he goes
He goes well, he's he works so hard and his expectations are so high
He goes I was at the hospital with my wife giving as she was giving birth to our first child and Elon's like
I need you in the office
He goes I cut I you know, a guy's got an incredible worth ethic work ethic, but it was too much
He goes I'm at the hospitals. I don't care where you were. Yeah
Like pretty brittle that's brutal wasn't he sleeping in there he was sleeping in the sure
Yeah, he was sleeping in working 16 hours a day and sleeping on the floor. Yeah, that's commitment
Well, he demands out of other people too. And you know, maybe you want that maybe you don't and if you don't you can't work there
It's simple. Like if you want that hop on in if you're a single guy and you don't have a wife
You have children. Yeah, but if you do boy, that's not a life for that's not a life for me. I don't want that job
I think the closest thing to a spaceship on wheels is a Tesla. Oh, they're amazing pretty remarkable
I've had three of them. This is my third the acceleration is incredible. It's like a gut punch. Yeah, they're getting better
They're getting the the autonomous driving is incredible now
I remember once somebody said to me they were like, you know step on it, you know
Show me the acceleration and I I stepped on it a model three performance
And it seems fake. I got nauseous. Yeah, I wasn't quite ready
I was like I turned myself a little sideways or something. I I felt no
I was like wow, I'm all right motorcycles. I would do all this I was like, you know, but I was like now
I prepare myself for that. That's really fast. It's super bike fast
It's crazy fast and it can actually the beautiful thing is you can merge on the highway
You don't seem like a douchebag cuz you're not like
It's not like really loud just super quiet
Stealthy. Yeah, it's all sons going a hundred miles an hour. What happened? Yeah
I remember I got a ticket years ago on a motorcycle and the guy I bought the bike was we had a loud exhaust pipe
I ended up getting rid of I didn't like the loud exhaust pipe
It's too loud and I got pulled over and the cop never even saw me
He just heard me and he wrote me up exactly how fast I was going. He's like you're doing 90 to 35
I'm like I was he's like, oh, yeah, I could hear you
I was like I went up to the gears and I put a quiet. So yeah, that's
Quiet is nice. Quiet has its benefits. Well, it doesn't in a motorcycle though. You want to be
That's true, but I drive like the invisible man when I'm on a motorcycle you have to yeah
I've had people look me right in the eyes and I've they pulled right out in front of me people want to
Side-swiped and also people are like they don't how many people are medicated. I don't think they see you as a threat
I think they see is like you're almost like a gnat or something
I've learned and I tell people that ride motors
I've been riding bikes for 50 years as soon as you get on that bike. You become the invisible man, right?
Right pretend no one can tend that no one can see you live a lot longer
Yeah, you can make eye contact with somebody doesn't mean they see you right? I've had people pull out in front of me
Like I said, I've been t-boned and all kinds of crazy accidents over the years
I wish they weren't so dangerous because I would love to drive. Oh, they're amazing
I know you just had to be like I said, you just you know, yeah until you're not I had three friends
I was I was getting my motorcycle license. Yeah, I was doing it was a while ago
Ten years. So it was a couple of us that worked on fear factor a couple of guys that worked on set
we all decided to go and take lessons together and
shout out to Peter Hershko and
He wound up getting his motorcycle he kept driving it and but one of the guys we worked with he crashed his bike and fucked
Up his shoulder and then one of the guys who was fighting for the UFC Frank Mir he got hit by a car
he got t-boned and
Ran into his femur snapped his femur and he almost lost his leg
His leg was and it fucked up his career for years
So there was that and then I saw a guy on the highway that was covered in a blanket
Oh
Yeah, he was alive
You can see but his his leg was so fucked up that they covered in a blanket so that passerby's wouldn't rubberneck it
There's three of those and then another friend of mine saw someone get hit saw someone get rear-ended someone not paying attention in their car
Rear-ended a bike and had the guy flying through the air at a red light
So that was enough for me. Yeah
I know I became a dad and I had two motorcycles right before I became a dad and I sold them and then after ten years
I was like, maybe I get just like a dirt bike because I really enjoy riding
Nothing like it being on a motorcycle. So I should be getting a dirt bag that a mountain lion takes you out
Damn it. I have a dirt bike with a motor. Yeah, even with a motor. I
Don't know if a mountain lion would be scared of a motor. Yeah
I'd be able to outrun it, but I think most of the time they were
Bicyclers. Yeah, most of the time they kill bicyclers. This is nuts. Yeah
So so let me ask your honest opinion. I know we're wrapping up here. Okay
If you had to say whether you believed or you didn't believe
Look, you can't make any definitive statements. I get that but you're a very influential individual
Who's done more for the push for disclosure? I hate use the word disclosure
It's got a bit of a buzz a bit of a connection to it a push for government transparency on this topic, right?
If you had to say something truly inexplicable that most likely would lead to NHI or non-human intelligence or not
conventional
What would you pick?
Ultimately that you think there is possibly a non-human intelligence behind this or that there is not I wish I could be definitive like that
I know you can't be definitive. I don't
I just try to stay as open-minded on this as possible
Which means I fluctuate back and forth to fully believe from fully believing to fully believing. It's some military
Experiment and that it's a bunch of our stuff
But then there's stories like the things like the tic-tac and where you go, okay
2004 how how do they how could they do that in 2004? Is there a propulsion system available in 2004?
That's that far advanced and if so, how come there's so little evidence of it in like in
A practical use like how come that technology you would think that technology would take so much money to develop
That you would do something with it in 20 years
You wouldn't just have it and just be flying it around like a drone every now and again
Yeah, it would seem like there would be some sort of a practical application for something like that
Yeah, and it seemed like like the Manhattan Project and like the stealth bomber
Eventually you find out that it's a real thing, right?
So 20 years is a long time to not find out that something's real
Well, how about if we take it up to a lot longer than that? What about the?
1952 two consecutive weekends in July over the White House in the Capitol
Yeah, and that was we had a press conference about that
Sure, a guy in general that basically admit that they're real Kenneth Arnold, you know
That was phenomenal. Yeah, and then you got to go to the Bhagavad Gita, you know
Oh, like there's there's stories of things the historical stuff is incredible
Isn't it like think of the guy that showed up with the blue skin? Is that an angel?
Is that a devil like what if if you were living four thousand years ago?
You're one of the people that wrote the Dead Sea Scrolls. He'd be a god. Yeah, what is that?
What is what is that visitation that you've experienced with a craft? It would be right connected with a god, right?
Right and also the story when you tell the story like what is this and then someone illustrates it?
What does even how does it even relay in words, especially you're using the words of four thousand years ago
What what are you describing and if they really have always been here and they've always been visiting us
That's probably how you would describe it you would describe it like Ezekiel did in the Bible
Yeah
Well, you know I was in Africa investigating the the alleged landing and close encounter of the third kind at Rua Zimbabwe aerial school in
1994 I wasn't there in 94. I was there much later and the teacher Judy Bates who's now they had principal and
She was sharing with me these drawings that children did of the alleged creatures and they were amazing these drawings big eyes and
Big heads almond shaped eyes blah blah blah, and I'm looking at these drawings one after the other from all these schoolchildren
it was phenomenal and
She gave no I took photographs of them and then a month later
I went to Australia and I was investigating an alleged landing that happened at Westall primary school in
1966 and
That was that was incredible
I was there investigating and I was showing some of the drawings of the aliens that I the alleged aliens and I just had
investigated in Africa and
Some of the people were like, oh wow, these drawings are amazing. They look like the one Gina cave art
I was like the what the one Gina cave art the aboriginals drew these things and so they pulled it up one Gina and
the parallel of their thousands of years old right these cave paintings in Australia the parallels the
consistencies the
It was the comparison of the two was like let's take a look at those real quick
Yeah, look at one one before we leave cave painting
UFO or alien was one most likely something there. I just don't know and if it's a thing
So let's say if it's a real thing. Is it from another planet or is it more complicated than that?
It's more complicated than that. Yeah. Well, that's how you see that. Yes. Yeah, very bizarre, right?
Look at the three of them and that the one in the center Jamie. Yeah that one look how weird that is, man
That's so fucking weird look at the one with the dark black eyes right there and pale they are too
It's like yeah, it's very weird. And then there's that one with the big with the big dark eyes, right?
Look down just go straight down up down. Yeah, right to the right right there. Look at that. Very weird. Very weird
Isn't that it's also very weird how this is four thousand years old and then close encounters of the third kind the 1970s
4,000 years old and I'm telling you I could show you the drawings
One of the witnesses
Very weird. Yeah, it's just it's just phenomenal. Listen, man. Thank you for everything. Thanks. Thanks for what you do
Thank you so much for having me on my pleasure. But I mean you you're
Fucking dogged determination to get this stuff out there. It's very important. You promise you'll watch the program
I will 100% watch it comment. I will I will. Thank you, sir. Awesome, brother
Awesome, brother James. Thank you so much. Thank you. It's on Amazon the program
And then moment of contact is probably available everywhere and the phenomenon. Yeah, I know what I saw out of the blue
Okay, 50 years of denial. Oh my god. It goes back. Yeah, you've been
You've been deep in this rabbit hole for a long time, sir
You