Joe Rogan podcast, check it out!
The Joe Rogan Experience.
Trained by day, Joe Rogan podcast by night, all day!
Very nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you as well.
I really loved your series, the telepathy tapes.
I had long suspected that there was some sort of a way to prove that there's something going on.
But there's no way that that would be a thing for so long that people would talk about certain moments where people could read people's minds
or certain moments where there was something that was being exchanged that wasn't verbal, it wasn't facial expressions, it wasn't body language, there was something going on.
And the telepathy tapes, excuse me, the telepathy tapes essentially proved it.
But has there been pushback about this?
I know there's a lot of hardcore skeptics that never want to believe.
Yeah. I think anytime you're pushing the status quo, there's going to be pushback, of course.
But I think the overwhelming amount of emails that we've gotten from families and others that have a non-speaking child have been so excited that this news is finally out there.
Same thing with teachers that have been witnessing, like you said, for witnessing this in classrooms and in their homes for decades.
And when facilitated communication first came to America, it was the 90s.
What does that mean, facilitated communication?
Okay, maybe we should back up.
I mean, so I wonder, okay, so what the podcast is about are non-speaking individuals who tend to have apraxia, which is a mind-body disconnect.
And those individuals cannot speak with, you know, using their voice.
Speaking is a fine motor skill, whereas pointing to letters is a gross motor skill.
So spelling to communicate is how many of these individuals communicate, right?
And when the first and well, and with that in mind, I just want to say one quick thing that often people historically have looked at people with apraxia or non-speakers,
and they think that because they can't speak, they can't think that they're not in there.
They don't presume competence.
And none of that is true.
These individuals have a hard time controlling their body, right?
And so if you can't control your body, people make all sorts of assumptions, you know, and that's been really difficult.
And so I think that the subjects in this project who are non-speakers with autism have been up against all sorts of different battles from people not presuming they're competent,
from people doubting their way of communication through spelling to communicate.
And then, of course, it comes out in many cases that these individuals can read minds, have a plethora of other, for lack of better words, spiritual gifts.
And then the parents and teachers often aren't believed about that either.
So it's like there's stigma every which way.
And the podcast is kind of a collision of all these stigmas and really trying to break down those stigmas and be like, here's the truth.
These people are in there, spelling is a valid form of communication.
And yes, many of them say they have spiritual gifts, which I think we can pretty much validate at this point.
When you say spiritual gifts, what do you mean by that?
Yeah. So when I first stumbled into this, which we can talk about later if you want, when I first kind of stumbled into this, I thought this was just about telepathy, right?
And that there were these individuals and their parents and teachers are claiming they could read minds.
And as I start meeting more and more and more of these families, and again, like I said, teachers is not limited to just families.
One thing that they started telling me was telepathy is the tip of the iceberg.
And I didn't know what that meant. You know, what do you mean, telepathy is the tip of the iceberg?
And it's true, because I think whether or not its ability to see disease or illness in someone and be able to diagnose it before this person knows that there's something wrong, reading an aura and, you know, saying that they can see a color around not just animals and humans, but plants.
Being able to speak multiple languages, even though you haven't been taught them, or playing instruments and knowing music or being able to access almost any song and having perfect pitch, being able to visit people in dreams.
And then, I mean, I think some of the more just like mind-altering, shocking things for me was how many non-speaking individuals have said that they are able to speak with people from the other side.
And yeah, so it didn't just start with telepathy or end with telepathy. It's a plethora of things.
So do you think that this is an emerging aspect of human consciousness, or do you think perhaps this is something maybe we had before we were verbal that we've lost but that lays dormant, like that we don't need it so like a muscle it atrophies?
Yeah, I think that's exactly right. I mean, I think we all have these abilities. I think this is all part of us. And in the telepathy tapes in episode five in particular, we get into animal communication through telepathy.
And a story of elephants that knew when someone who was like in charge of their big game preserve had died, and they'd walk days to his house and did kind of stay there for grieving and then would come back every year on the day of his death.
I mean, just unbelievably beautiful stuff. Rupert Sheldrake has talked, has written at length, a brilliant Cambridge biologist about dogs, experiments he's done that kind of show the dogs know when their owners are coming home, and sometimes cats.
So, so this seems to be part and parcel of the animal kingdom right and many of us have had that experience of phone telepathy, where I was just thinking of someone and they call.
People like to dismiss that as being just coincidence but just why do people want to dismiss everything. Like that's the problem. It's like, I think, I think they're the real fear is being full.
That's the fear, which is why the problem with any sort of telepathy or any sort of psychic ability. The problem is there's so many charlatans, and so many people get duped.
Yeah, and it's really common. I mean, it's, it's so common. It's, it's everywhere you see these psychic palm reading signs everywhere you go.
And because of that, it's in the realm forever of nonsense. And if you believe in nonsense, you're not a person to be taken seriously.
So if you're a scientist and you're studying human neurochemistry and you're studying neuroscience, there's no way you're, you're going to support this unless it's just beating you over the head with overwhelming evidence and then perhaps you say maybe there's something here.
I think that's changing, actually. And one of the things that we look at in the telepathy tapes in episode six, which we call our science episode, is this idea of materialism, which I'm sure you've heard of.
You know, this idea that, at least for the past few hundred years, that the reigning philosophy around how we interpret the world is only true if we can measure it and observe it, right?
And that makes you seem foolish if you believe in something that can't be measured or observed, like a siphon on telepathy or precognition or dreams being able to communicate with someone or any of that stuff would be thrown out as being silly.
And I think there's been a massive effort to make that true, right? That if you believe this or you're a scientist and you want to publish this, we're going to dismiss you or ridicule you just for even daring to ask that question.
Research about this type of stuff has been dismissed because it's materialist, you know, scientists who for a long time run the journals.
But there is something interesting here, which is that consciousness, we don't know where it comes from, you know?
And so what a brilliant scientist, Dean Radin, talks about in the telepathy tapes is that if you think of materialism as a pyramid, right, and the base of the pyramid and all the things that have built up our world,
which are biology and physics and chemistry and all those things, those have rules and properties, and we shouldn't throw those out.
Those are pretty much true. But currently at the top of the pyramid is consciousness, and we can't explain where that comes from and why it's there.
But if you just take consciousness from the top and put it on the bottom so that consciousness is the basis of all reality, right?
That consciousness is fundamental, that all of everything is the product of our thoughts first, then we can account for all this stuff.
Then we can account for precognition or telepathy. And it's not that big of a change.
It's just flipping kind of the order of the pyramid. And I think that makes a lot of sense.
And so there's been a lot of scientists who have looked into near-death experience research, who've looked into the research on telepathy, who've looked into the research around precognition and said, we can't dismiss this.
This is happening. There's a lot of anecdotal evidence here. There's a lot of things that add up.
So we're going to start the Academy of Post-Materialist Sciences, where we will take this stuff seriously and we will look at the research and we will advance science.
And I tend to believe that there needs to be quite a few funerals.
But I think in like 50 to 100 years, the scientists that we're gripping onto the materialist paradigm, I really believe that that's going to be kind of like the flat earthers in the future.
Like, I think the scientists doing this are on the right side of history because you have to account for it.
Right. You know?
Who's scoring big in the NBA this year? You are, with all new ways to get in on the action at DraftKings Sportsbook, an official sports betting partner of the NBA.
From monster slams to dishing the rock to cleaning the glass, get behind your favorite players and the prop bets you can make on DraftKings, the home of NBA player props.
Plus, for new DraftKings customers, bet $5 to get $150 in bonus bets instantly.
Take it to the rack with DraftKings Sportsbook. Every point counts.
Download the DraftKings Sportsbook app and use the code ROGIN.
That's code ROGIN for new customers to get $150 in bonus bets when you bet just five bucks.
Only on DraftKings. The crown is yours.
We have to account for it. We don't exactly know where it comes from.
And there's a lot of people that think that the universe is formed through consciousness.
This is Thomas Campbell's take on things. He was a mind bender when I had him in here.
I was like, what are you saying exactly? You have to listen to it three or four times.
Then you have to, I told him, listen, let's stop here. We'll do it again because I'm going to have to absorb this.
But the concept is that essentially the universe is formulated through consciousness in some way.
And that we're interacting with it through consciousness and that it's not as real as we want to believe it is.
Yeah. I mean, and even if you just basic it down, right? Like this room, what came first, the room or the thought of the room?
Everything in this room. It was a thought first. Right. Everything. Right. Everything. Everything on our planet was a thought first.
Well, everything except the planet itself. Right. Yeah. I've always said that that I think that ideas might be a life form that they get into people's heads
and then people manufacture physical objects out of these ideas, whether it's art.
And I think that's one of the reasons why we like art so much. Yeah. I mean, that's how this whole podcast started, I think.
Sure. You know, I was reading that book, Big Magic. I don't know if you've read that book. It's wonderful.
Well, I guess I should back. You know, I was doing a lot of documentary work that was on social issues. Right.
That was all like fixing broken things in our great country.
And then I had a few deaths in my own life. And I thought, my gosh, whatever I do next, I want to fix what's broken in humans
because I was in a complete topsy turvy thing of how do these great people that are heroes, you know, a police officer going in and saving someone.
My other friend was taking care of the unhoused in Kansas City and how do they die?
So I was going through my own just like kind of grief process and thinking, whatever I do next, I don't want to look any more.
I was humbled to do that work of broken social systems. I want to fix what's broken in humanity and figure out what that is.
But anyway, I was reading Big Magic and this is a book about how ideas by Elizabeth Gilbert, how ideas are outside of us, the creative process is it comes to you.
And they're you know, it's wonderful. In the book, they talk about songwriters who heard her song.
And if you don't grab it, you'll hear that same song on the radio or or just how a story will come to you fully formed.
And one of the kind of topics that comes up in that book, too, is you don't ask the creative whatever this God muse, either right to to to give this to you.
Tell it I'm going to do this with you. It's going to be great. And so I said that out loud.
I was reading this book. I was in this moment of just major shift in my life.
And I said, whatever I do next, I want to solve the question of where we're going and why we're here and what it all means.
And do we have a consciousness and does it survive?
And then and no, I actually didn't ask it. I said, yeah, I said, I'm going to do this next.
And I didn't know what it was going to look like. But then started reading, you know, all the things I got in consciousness, tree communication and about near-death experiences and Ian Stevenson's work and all sorts of things.
And then I heard a podcast with Dr. Diane Hennessy Powell, who was a Harvard, you know, Johns Hopkins educated, you know, taught at Harvard scientist who was saying that non-speakers that she'd tested had demonstrated a remarkable ability.
For telepathy and reading minds. And that was like, boom, like lightning just kind of hit like this is the thing.
And I really believe if something's intended for you, it won't miss you, you know.
But I think that concept of big magic was a bit of that of asking, telling the muse, you know, to to guide you.
Yeah. Yeah.
Guide you towards something that can illuminate this issue.
So did you have a preconceived notion of telepathy or spiritual gifts or anything before this?
No, I mean, I think like a lot of people like the idea of mediums and psychics.
It felt like people that are often trying to just make money off of people in really vulnerable situations.
And I've always believed certainly there's got to be people who have certain gifts like that, you know, but that the vast majority couldn't be trusted or, you know, I didn't think telepathy could be real.
That seems impossible. It just seems impossible.
Even things like plant communication felt impossible.
Or I mean, I mean, none of that was something that was was like my worldview.
You know, I was working on, you know, solving problems around paid family medical leave and making health insurance more affordable and accessible.
Like it was not my cup of tea, really.
And so which was kind of great because as I tumbled into this world, I mean, I was really wide eyed as like, wait a second.
Have I been wrong about everything?
And that's kind of where it ended up was like I had to go revisit everything I ever thought about the world because I started realizing our entire paradigm is wrong.
I mean, or a lot of it is.
That was my experience.
So let's let's talk about what you saw first.
Like, what was the first example where it was like an aha moment for you?
Yeah. So after I heard the interview with Dr. Diane Hennessey Powell, I, you know, I zoomed with her and then I asked if I could go see her and meet her and talk about this a bit, you know, because I thought this could be the next project.
And I just knew it was going to be the next project.
Right.
So one of the first things I had to do was I was like, can you just tell me about some of the emails that come in from parents?
I had to just kind of go through reading some emails from parents.
And it was one after the other.
Like, I didn't believe this and I didn't believe my wife.
I didn't believe my husband that this could be possible.
But we've tested it. We've tested it.
People were sending tests.
And I thought, OK, whatever is going on here, these parents don't know that any other parents are going through this.
They think a singular miracle is happening in their home that this child can read their thoughts and that this is where the story is, that there's so many parents who haven't been listened to.
And so I really thought this was about parents at first and then discovered, no, there's been teachers writing about this for 30 years, capturing it, videotaping this phenomenon going on and scared to come out about it.
And I think same with the families. Right.
I mean, what a weird thing to say this child can read my mind or this child seems to be able to do X, Y, Z, things that seem impossible.
And so, you know, my first thought was, OK, I need to see if this is my own eyes.
And so I, Dr. Powell had just been reached out to by a family in Mexico who discovered that their 13 year old daughter was inside.
They didn't think she was. And she was able to communicate.
And the reason they discovered that was during COVID, you know, they were in charge of homeschooling and started being like, OK, let's see what you know.
She started spelling. She knew an awful lot. And I think they were shocked.
And pretty soon thereafter, she said, I can read your mind.
And they thought, what? And they would do tests. What did I just draw?
And she'd say what they just drew. You know, what are we thinking?
And she would write it. And so do they say what they see or how they see it?
Like if someone writes something down, do they see the word or do they know it?
Well, I think that's a really good question.
And, you know, we've done a few experiments that, you know, again, I'm not a scientist.
Like the experiments I was doing for the film, I mean, which is going to be now a film.
But the podcast was kind of me just trying to understand like proof of concept what is going on here.
Right. And I can only say what spellers have told me.
And there's been quite a few spellers who say I can see through someone's eyes or I can hear through their ears.
And others who seem to have a merged consciousness with someone that they're very close to,
whether it be a father or a teacher or a communication partner, father or whatever,
where we did some experiments with one mom where we'd show an image to her.
Her son, who was sitting across the room, would all of a sudden start writing what the image was.
But what was so fascinating is sometimes the mom wouldn't even know what the image was.
So at one point, she thought it was paint. No, no, she thought there was a food fight.
It was ketchup and mustard. And he wrote paint. So so at that point, it's like she's not obviously sending a thought.
Right. He seems to be tapping in the second the images in her own mind.
So for us, it was a big question of is this just your telepathy?
Because a few parents have told me, no, this is bigger than that.
It seems like a merging of consciousness of some sort. Yeah.
In a bizarre way, if the mother doesn't know what it is and the child does, that's strange.
Yeah, it's really fascinating. And you know, but I also one of the stories that I loved goes back.
So Dr. Rupert Sheldrake, the Cambridge biologist who's in this project, he didn't believe in telepathy either.
I mean, I think a lot of scientists don't believe this stuff right away either.
And he had a, you know, a senior professor that he really looked up to, Sir Rudolf Peters.
And he was knighted by Queen Elizabeth for being such a brilliant scientific mind.
Right. And the Sir Rudolf Peters was in like the tea room at Cambridge one time and telling young Dr. Sheldrake, young Rupert here,
that he just heard of a blind boy that he tested who obviously is blind and can't read an eye chart.
But if his mother is looking at it, he could read it.
And that's how Rupert Sheldrake fell into this world.
And that boy was diagnosed with, you know, being blind, but also at the time what they called, you know, severe mental retardation,
which now we don't call it that, you know.
But that's who knows what this young individual have if he had apraxia or what was going on if he had autism.
Well, because autism and blindness, like it's a huge impediment, especially nonverbal autism and being blind.
Like, how do you learn anything?
So you would assume that there's something wrong with the child when there's just a lack of the ability to communicate.
Yeah. I mean, with non-speaking individuals with apraxia, they are in there.
They're so smart. It's just that mind-body disconnect and not being able to, you know.
What do they think causes that? Do they have an understanding of what it is?
You know, I don't know.
There's so many wonderful experts out there looking into this, and I don't know what causes apraxia.
But I do know that there's a lot of supports to help individuals who have apraxia to communicate.
And the world is just making it really difficult for these individuals.
Have you ever seen this young blind boy that uses echolocation and he can ride a skateboard and move around?
How bizarre is that?
It's cool.
I mean, you know, in some ways you think of echolocation or being able to see through infrared is like a sixth sense,
like a sense that we don't have, right?
But it's like a sense some other creatures get around with.
So it's like what we're talking about here is almost like a seventh sense, right?
It's something beyond that.
But I just I think there's something so beautiful about that, right?
That if you if humans are so creative that we will find our way to get around the world and find our ways to communicate.
Also, when you're missing a sense, your other senses are stronger.
This has always been a suspicion.
I think that's been proven. Is that correct?
Yeah.
That people are better at hearing things if they're blind or seeing things if they're deaf.
Yeah. Yeah, I think that is absolutely true.
And I think, though, as far as, you know, individuals with apraxia go again, like it's mind, body disconnect.
There's so many of the spellers I've met who don't know they had a body at first.
They can't feel their body.
You know, they want heavy boots to know where their feet are or heavy necklace to know where their chest is.
And and I think not being in your body, not knowing you have your body leaves you to live in this consciousness space more.
Right. This world of thought where where we can't imagine that we're so bound to our body.
We have these dissociative dissociative boundaries where it's like you're Joe when I'm high.
And yeah.
So I think that's that's what heightens a lot of this for them is just not, you know, feeling is grounded into their bodies.
In the wackiest of conspiracy theories, when people talk about the government's connection to alien intelligence,
that they recruit these nonverbal autistic kids because they're the ones who can communicate with aliens.
I don't believe that.
No, I don't believe that you know, wackiest of conspiracy theories.
But the idea being that if you were the government, you would look for someone who is extraordinary in in that they they're more open to this ability to interact.
Yeah.
And we would be they do not have the burden of feeling foolish.
They don't have the burden of societal constraints that we've kind of culturally put on the idea of alien life being able to communicate with them.
Yeah.
I mean, this is I have received a question around, you know, could the government utilize these individuals?
You're not discussing the first thing you think about people think extraordinary.
Yeah.
Like the X-Men.
Right.
Like how will the government utilize this and manipulate it for their own gain?
That's what everybody worries.
Yeah.
And it's a fair worry.
I mean, it is a fair worry.
And, you know, like we try to be very protective of of the families and make sure that they're safe and that they're only out there if they want to be out there.
And, you know, that type of thing.
But even they know what that means.
Yeah.
That's the problem.
You say you want to be out there.
Do you know what that means?
Right.
Exactly.
Every non-speaking individual with these gifts that I've ever met won't use it for bad or nefarious means that they're they're interested in love.
They're interested in connection.
Right.
Yeah.
Of course.
Well, the problem is if they were used and didn't know what they were doing, you know, they would know.
They'll know.
They can read your thoughts and they know it's up.
They know it's up better than anyone, I think.
Interesting.
When you first started, was there stages of acceptance for you with these ideas?
Yeah.
What was the first stage?
I mean, the first stage was I think I never I never had the barrier of whether or not they're in there.
You know, I worked I helped start the inclusion program in my high school and worked and cared for people, you know, with varying abilities my whole life.
So that I knew they were in there.
But I think the next thing for me was the telepathy.
And and and when you see it and when you talk to enough parents who are saying all you need to do is go see it.
It's not like it's not like does it show up or like will it appear?
It's like for the parents and teachers to report this is happening.
If you go work with a speller, you just see it.
So that was pretty phenomenal.
And then the first person we saw being able to do it was this girl Mia.
And she was still in the early stages of learning to spell to communicate.
So she was being touched.
It often helps first with the wrist and then here and then here and then on the head.
And then often then there's no touch at all.
It's like learning that body and learning those supports to control your motor.
So so Dr. Powell was like, no, scientists will take this because she was being touched.
And I think a lot of us in the room are like, wait, people think she's her mom sending Morse code like they're the plan.
I mean, of course, that's ridiculous. It really is.
But then the next individual could do it across the room and wasn't being touched.
And, you know, anyone that we saw thereafter wasn't being touched.
So that was pretty remarkable.
And I don't think touch actually, I think telepathy is really cool if you're being touched.
You know, but so telepathy was the first one.
And then I think the second one was the language stuff.
A lot of parents saying, you know, we have no idea how, but she's speaking Portuguese and no one in the house speaks Portuguese or people talking about.
And this has been documented?
Yeah. Yeah. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yeah. It's quite common, actually.
And these are nonverbal kids, non-speakers, non-speakers.
So what is the difference between nonverbal and non-speakers?
Well, I think nonverbal is this idea, right?
Like that you're not able to make like language, you know, in a way where like speaking is just like they can be verbal.
They can communicate. They just can't speak it.
OK. Just can't speak it.
OK. Without the support of a communication partner like, you know, that is the goal is to type independently.
Do they make noises?
Yeah. I mean, I think especially with apraxia, there's often a lack of body control, voice control.
So there is like a beautiful soundtrack that I've come to love of non-speakers that will often be like some grunting or just lack of body control.
And actually, I think if someone sees a non-speaker out in public, one of the most loving things you can say is like, I know you can't control your body.
I know that's not you. You know what I mean?
Because the person in there might want to be doing X, Y, Z, but just cannot control their body.
And imagine how frustrating that would be.
Yeah. So these people, they're nonverbal.
And when you say that they can speak Portuguese, they understand Portuguese.
Do they write it? Like, how does this manifest itself?
Yeah. So, I mean, there's one young girl I'm thinking of in particular, but there's this again.
This has come up now with, I don't know, 15 non-speakers that I've met.
But the girl I'm thinking of, her, you know, she will work during the day with a paraprofessional and a spelling coach.
You know, there's a, you know, the education system, there might be two or three people in a room and three people who are in the room this day.
And she started spelling in a language and they didn't know what it is.
So they looked it up and it was Portuguese.
And then she started spelling in Spanish and they were like, this is wild.
And she also said she knew hieroglyphics.
And what? Yeah.
And then they were like, how do we test this?
Because if we know the answer, she'll read our mind and know.
So they had to just, which is wild already.
Yeah. Like you have to worry about this kid reading your mind.
It might be bullshit.
So they had to like look up pictures of hieroglyphics and not know what the pictures were representing to be like, OK,
OK, here's the feather.
I mean, I don't know what whatever feather on top of a stone or whatever the picture was of.
And here's this picture and this picture.
And then she identified them.
And then they looked them up and they were right.
Wow. All of them.
One hundred percent accurate.
Yeah. Wow. Yeah.
So and I'm not saying, of course, not how is going on there?
Not every. What is that?
Well, I mean, that is that's beyond bizarre.
Did you give her cuneiform?
I mean, I wasn't there for this.
I, you know, her mom reported it to me and it has the email that she received from the staff.
And so, you know, the staff is just like, this is what happened today.
And, you know, because these individuals are spelling to communicate, it can take a lot of time.
It can take a whole work and effort to get those that information out.
So anything that comes out usually, I mean, a good spelling coach will ask this child first, right?
Is it OK if I share this with your parents or is this private between us or whatever?
But if they say it's OK to share, they will write a letter home.
And this is what happened. And and that was in a letter home.
This is what happened today.
This episode is brought to you by Intuit TurboTax.
One thing I've learned from doing this podcast is the value of having real experts around,
whether it's someone breaking down complex science, health or even philosophy,
having the right people makes all the difference.
That's exactly what TurboTax does for your taxes,
because now taxes is matching with a TurboTax live expert for your unique tax situation.
Your expert is backed by cutting edge technology that cross checks millions of data points for absolute accuracy.
And while they work on your taxes, you can get real time updates on their progress
and get the most money back all while you go about your day,
which means less stress for you and the best possible outcome for your return.
It's twenty twenty five. It's time to file like it.
Now, this is taxes Intuit TurboTax.
Get an expert now at TurboTax dot com in our session.
Your child reads hieroglyphics.
What the hell?
It's like, what does that mean? Is that the Akashic record?
Like, is this child like pulling from all the information that's in the ether?
Like, how would you be able to read a dead language that mean?
What percentage of the human population can read that without AI, without assistance?
It's got to be tiny. It's remarkable.
Tiny, tiny percentage.
I mean, from a scientific perspective, and this is one of the things that there was a professor, Bernie Ridland,
who first, I think, came up with this idea.
And then I know Dr. Powell kind of expanded on it, which Bernie Rimland first saw this kind of gift in non-speakers,
I think in the 70s, a while back, and was like, ESP should be considered a savant skill.
And Dr. Powell has talked about this as well.
So savant skills, right, are studied or accepted by science.
This idea that, like, how do you know the language or math or this or that when you haven't been exposed to it
or haven't been, you know, educated with even maybe the most simplest music skills.
But now you're playing a symphony, right?
So savant skills are being able to really excel at something that you haven't been taught.
And savant, there's people who are born with the savant skills.
And also, sometimes you can be an accidental savant.
So you get hit on the head.
Yeah, I read about a guy who got assaulted and all of a sudden you do complex geometry.
Yeah, complex geometry and stuff like that.
So what's wild is that the materialist scientific point of view accepts savant skills.
We don't know where they come from. We don't know why.
We don't know how people can know this stuff.
They've been taught, but we accept them as these real big question marks as it's real.
So what Bernie Ribblin said and later Dr. Powell was like, ESP should be considered savant skill.
These people know something and we don't know how they know it, but they do.
They haven't been taught it. They haven't been exposed to it.
And that could be thoughts. It could be knowledge about the future.
It could be knowledge about language.
And this is what the whole hope is about the telepathy tapes, right, is that people will start to put money behind this research
because for so long research around this type of stuff wouldn't be funded because it would be just dismissed.
It's impossible. It's impossible. It's impossible.
And one of the moms in the telepathy tapes who I love so much, her name is Manisha, she talks about her son.
She goes, Akhil is the data. You want to look at the data. You want the data.
Look at my son. He's the data.
And some of these parents are wanting, desperate for answers.
They're not in the question of if it's happening. They're wondering how it's happening.
And I think I'm in that part, too, like when the people that are just, is it possible? Is it possible?
I think for most of us in this world, it's like, yeah, you're like 10 steps behind, man.
Like, it's possible. It's not a matter if. It's why.
And that's my hope is that the chains will be like, you know, let off the scientists.
These children that can read things, are they typing it out like on an iPad? Are they writing it physically?
How do they do it?
Usually, so there's different forms of spelling to communicate.
Often there's like a letter board, right?
Sometimes it's a stencil letter board that you poke a pencil through.
So you really know when you get that letter and it's really satisfying to get the pull poke through.
Sometimes there's like just a laminate board where you kind of point to a letter.
Some individuals are typing into a spelling kind of app on an iPad or there's different spelling.
Can they type?
AAC devices. Yeah.
And then and then there's some individuals who end up going to the QWERTY, you know,
the typical keyboard that we all type with on a keyboard.
So there's varying levels of ability in terms of using your body.
Yeah, using your body.
And the thing I think why spelling has been so, you know, there's such a stigma on spelling.
And I feel so bad for individuals using spelling because they're in there and they are communicating.
But people have said, oh, but you need the support.
So these can't be your words.
Right. Like like for a spelling partner, let's say you have to kind of learn to be a communication partner.
You have to learn to to really understand like the mind, body disconnect and what's going on with the non speaker in front of you.
And sometimes their hand gets lost in space.
So it's good to pull the board away and put it back in again.
Or sometimes you have to cue them like go for it.
OK, get that letter because that will help with their motor planning.
Right.
So those supports are critical.
But people look at those supports and say, oh, well, that means they're not typing independently.
But to me, that's as wild as saying, oh, you need reading glasses.
You can't read. No, that's a support to help you read.
You can still read if you're reading classes.
And that's how I think of the communication.
There's still no influence on the words or letters being chosen.
No, no, no.
And I think one of the things.
So the stigma, I think, that really started for spelling was facilitated communication.
Actually, this is like the first thing you asked.
We're going full circle.
So for a long time, there was just no hope of getting people who weren't verbal non speakers out.
There just wasn't. And then all of a sudden, facilitated communication came along.
And it was developed, I think, in Australia, I think.
But this was ideas of put some pressure on someone's wrist so they can really feel where they're at in space.
They'll be able to spell.
And it was a miracle. It was all over the news.
This was great.
And some of the first parents that were using facilitated communication started reporting.
There's telepathy involved.
And this was at Syracuse University in the 90s.
Syracuse knew about this and started kind of burying that information.
And there was a lot of like kind of you'll be let go if you're teaching this and you're talking about this.
So there was kind of big cover up.
So this was new. This is not new that this was going on.
But then there were some claims of sexual assault.
There's awful things that happen where what was being claimed didn't happen.
And so people started blaming facilitated communication.
Oh, well, maybe they're pushing their hand or doing this or doing that.
And I think for a lot of people who train in facilitated communication, you're using your hand to put pressure so the individual knows where the body is in space.
But you're not pushing their hand.
But there probably are some cases where that had happened.
Well, anyway, so then it got kind of just stigmatized, right?
It's pseudoscience.
And then so spelling evolved into these forms where it was like no touch, do not touch.
And so many of those spelling groups now are helping individuals.
And the big tenet of this is you cannot touch them.
And and that's that's where spelling's at now is that you learn to communicate and there's no touch involved.
But but I'm I'm one of these people that thinks like whatever the individual needs to help them communicate.
It's OK. If you need a little touch, you know, your arm is right.
Or sometimes it helps you go faster if there's a little push like I think.
Go for it. You know, help these individuals get out there.
Right. This touch is not guiding them toward specific letters.
This touch is just an affirmation just to help to help them relax, to help them connect.
Yeah. And it was really, you know, on set sometimes because every once in a while some parents like hold the board and hold it there for their child.
And we would use these like dry erase, you know, markers on the screen to be like, is the board moving?
And it wasn't, you know, be really interesting to get them in front of some scripts that are very difficult to read.
That's why I brought up cuneiform and Sumerian and maybe even that crazy Voynich manuscript.
You know what that is? No. The Voynich manuscript is a book that is of an unknown language.
OK. And it's highly detailed and they don't know what it is.
They don't know the language. They don't know if it's a fraud. Oh, look at this.
This is the Voynich manuscript. They don't know when it emerged.
There's a lot of suspicion that someone created it and tried to pass it off and sell it as an ancient language in a book.
But then some people disagree with that because they think that the way the words are constructed seems to be in some sort of a uniform way.
It's not gibberish. It's not nonsense. But they do not know what it says.
Obviously, I don't know jack shit about ancient languages.
So I'm not the right person to be determining who's correct and who's who wants it to be correct.
So they're saying that. Wow. I have not never heard of that.
What is the current state of go? Yeah. Let's see what it says.
Whether they think it's real. Is there like a synopsis on what people think is there's facsimiles.
Interesting. OK. University of Bristol subsequently removed a reference to Cheshire's claims from this website was a website.
Cheshire published its translation in the foldout illustration in twenty twenty three.
He claims it depicts a volcano theories that it places a manuscripts creator near the island of volcano, which was an active volcano during the 15th century.
However, experts in medieval documents disputed the interpretation vigorously approached for comment.
Lisa Fagan Davis gave this explanation. As with most would be Voynich interpreters, the logic of this proposal is circular and aspirational.
He starts with a theory about what a particular series of glyphs might mean, usually because the words proximity to an image that he believes can interpret.
OK, so they don't buy that this interpretation of it is real.
But they're pretty sure it's a language, which is just fucking insane.
Scroll up a little higher. Is there any debunkings of it?
These are different people that have made interpretations and they seem to know.
No one figures it out. Various discussions.
Yeah. Wow. Imagine if you can get that in front of a nonverbal kid and he's like, oh, I know what that is.
I mean, that'd be pretty wild. Pretty wild.
Yeah. Jesus wrote this like, oh, he says he's coming back in August, like whatever it is.
I mean, this is the fact that the child can read hieroglyphics is insane.
I would love to see like cuneiform or Sumerian in particular.
We had a an ancient language scholar named Wes Huff on and he was explaining how a lot of these interpretations were of like the Sumerian text,
which is the oldest version of, you know, a lot of these like biblical stories.
He was like, I can't read it.
He goes, I can read all these different languages, but this one is so different than all the others and it doesn't have anything that's like it.
Like a lot of these other languages, you can find similarities in the way they're structured, the way the sentences are structured.
There's none of that with Sumerian. It's like, this is a wacky language.
He's like, I can't read it. And he was brilliant.
So when you talk to a guy like that, who's humble about it, but also like very well read.
And he's like, I don't know what's going on.
What does it give that to the kid?
So interesting. Yeah.
I mean, it seems like there's a lot of opportunity to really get into that with these nonverbal kids.
If you find one that is there more than one that has this ability to do this?
I mean, I can only comment on the people I've met.
But I think of all the people that we're talking to a lot, you know, for the project and now the film.
Yeah, I mean, it's definitely more than one.
I mean, at least I know 15 or 20 who seem to know various languages they haven't been taught.
15 or 20?
Yeah. Yeah.
And one of the earlier children that Dr. Powell was studying, this boy knew really kind of odd languages like Russian and Japanese.
And I think he was five or six and could just speak in different languages and knew different languages.
It's absolutely remarkable.
Wow. Yeah.
And is there like even the most out there theory about what's going on?
I mean, this is the thing, right?
There hasn't been a lot of research around this phenomena.
And I think I can only go again off of what spellers have said.
I mean, one thing is that they say that there's a neurology behind language, right?
The current, the most baseline language is not with words.
Words are these 3D objects that we attach to these thoughts and feelings.
And that is the thing that they can understand, which makes sense.
That would be what telepathy is, right?
If you're not using words.
Well, that is our version of telepathy.
We make noise with our mouth and then you can read my mind.
Right. Yeah, kind of.
In a clumsy way.
Yeah. But if you think of prayer, right, that's telepathy.
People who come back from a near-death experience and they say they have these communications with someone,
you don't have a body, that's telepathy, right?
Like if a medium is talking to someone or getting messages from someone who's past, like that's telepathy.
So it seems like the baseline, to me, like all of this has proven for me that we have a soul.
Or there's at least, if that word is triggered into someone, that at least there's a conscious body.
There's a consciousness in each of us that doesn't need a body.
And so I think the language thing is like we've put words over this thing.
But the telepathy, the baseline is there no matter what.
And if you can understand the baseline of what's being communicated, the words don't matter.
Does that make sense?
It does. Yeah, it does.
It's hard to grasp, but it makes sense.
Are you aware of the history of research in Ayahuasca?
I mean, I know what it is.
One of the more interesting aspects of it is when scientists first discovered it and discovered its properties and they did experiments on it,
they wanted to call one of the ingredients telepathy.
But due to the rules of scientific nomenclature, they realized that it had already been named harmin.
So this harmin is one of the ingredients.
It's in one of the plants that's used to make this brew.
But when the scientists explored this and started experimenting with it, it was somewhere in the early 20th century,
they realized that they could read each other's minds and that they were communicating
and that they were having a shared experience that seemed to be completely mental.
But independently, they all verified the exact same thing.
And so that's why they wanted to name it telepathy, which is a way more fun word than harmin.
Way more fun.
Yeah. But this idea that we need something to access this dormant part of what is human consciousness.
Yeah. And I think that type of stuff can really help.
I think what's cool is that a lot of the research on psychedelics is kind of converging with this stuff right now around telepathy and the non-speakers.
I think a lot of people have had these experiences on psilocybin or on an ayahuasca trip or whatever,
where there's this realization that we're way more mental.
There is a non-physical world that is out there.
Yeah. There's something. And this work and Thomas Campbell's work,
there's a bunch of people who are considering this now, which I always wonder.
If you get an enormous number of people that have a shift in the way they view reality itself,
what impact does that have on reality?
Yeah. I mean, I think that's a big thing, right?
Yeah.
And I keep thinking you asked about the pushback around this.
And what's interesting is it's not just from skeptics who don't want to believe in telepathy and that the non-visible world is real,
but also from people in the spelling community who don't want people to mention telepathy
out of fear that it's going to foil their efforts to make this standard practice in schools.
In fact, some of the teachers and others who've been involved in our project have been getting letters from the IASC,
like a spelling group saying, don't talk about telepathy or you're going to have your accreditation taken away.
I don't understand. Why would that mess with spelling?
I think the fear is that if you ... I actually don't know.
I mean, because most of the people I'm working with, almost all of them,
every single one of the people I'm working with sees this as happening in their homes and their classrooms.
And it's not just teachers and parents and ministers and rabbis and parapsychologists and speech pathologists and occupational therapists.
These are all the people reporting it, right?
And for them, I think the thing is truth is never harmful.
It might be difficult, but it's not harmful.
And what this truth means is that we have to change our systems, right, of education.
We have to change how we think about things.
And I think there is a deep fear of people having their darkest, deepest thoughts exposed.
That's probably not comfortable for the government, for people in control, for people who are controlling games of money.
Oh, I think that's coming, whether we like it or not.
But why ... I think this truth might be really uncomfortable for some, but it's so important to get out there.
You can't accept and love someone as a whole being unless you can see and know all of them, right?
And the only people I feel really in service to are the non-speakers who haven't had a voice,
and all the people loving and supporting them or who are saying, this is real, we want this out there.
And so the gatekeeping around this has been massive.
I mean, yes, from the science world, but also from the spelling world.
But why from the spelling world? That's what I don't understand.
I think there's so many challenges of people saying, oh, because they're using these supports, these words aren't their own.
And then I think there's this conflated idea like, oh, if they know they're people with telepathy, they'll think their thoughts aren't their own either.
And it's a weird idea because just because you're talking to me doesn't mean that I don't have my own thoughts or words, right?
Like, I can read a book which thoughts are coming at me. It doesn't mean I don't have my own thoughts.
So you can hear thoughts and that doesn't mean you don't have your own.
I mean, so it's like putting too much together that I think is talking about telepathy is not going to foil spelling.
But some people believe that to be true.
And it just doesn't make any sense to me. Yeah.
Like, why would any I don't understand why spelling would even get involved in this?
I don't know. Like spelling is universally accepted as being important.
Well, it's no. But this is the problem. Spelling is not there are so I just talked to a parent the other day who said I've been trying to get a communication partner with my daughter in school so she can contribute.
And the school system will not pay for that. They're like, nope, you cannot have a spelling communication partner because it is just a funding issue.
Well, no, there's a group called ASHA, the American Speech Language Association, who accredits speech language pathologists.
And they say that spelling is pseudoscience. And I don't know how communication could be called pseudoscience.
And so if you're a speech language pathologist and you want to teach spelling in schools, that's considered like.
Wait a minute. Why would they say I don't understand. What is the argument that spelling is pseudoscience?
This is such a controversy that it's just maddening.
I think, again, it's because of those supports, like because because you might need a part because you need a partner to spell.
It's considered, oh, well, you're not spelling independently.
So spelling is pseudoscience for nonverbal people or non-speakers, I should say.
Well, it's not. But but ASHA is saying that, which is making it.
And they're only saying this because of the touch, the ability to touch people while they're doing it.
Well, most of these individuals aren't being touched.
I think that the problem is, I mean, the problem is that no one's presuming competence.
So this is why it was confusing. You're saying spelling in regards to nonverbal.
I'm sorry. Yeah. OK. Spelling. OK. Yes. Yeah.
So when. So spelling is kind of the catchall phrase for pointing to letters to communicate,
be it on a letter board or iPad or even a keyboard, like what we're used to with a computer.
So they're going by this old concept that it's impossible to have any sort of psychic ability.
So if you're proving psychic ability through spelling, this is obviously bullshit without any examination of it.
Yeah, I think that's a that's a good summary.
Back to what we were talking about before, that they don't want to be foolish.
Right. So this is a compounded issue.
But one thing that's kind of I thought this was fascinating is that any type of like alternative form of communication
has gone through immense battles to be validated.
Like, oh, my gosh, sign language.
And I think in the 1800s, there was a conference in Milan where everyone's like, we cannot teach sign language.
Like this is people need to try to speak.
You know, sign language went through battles for, I mean, over 100 years to try to even get accepted as a real language.
And it wasn't until the 70s or 80s when that happened.
And then Braille, Louis Braille, who invented Braille, the people at the school where he invented it was like, you guys can't use this.
We don't accept this and we don't believe you can read by touching dots and we don't believe you can type by poking holes.
That's impossible. That seems nuts.
So when they did, they would do these tests with Louis and other students to be like, OK, you write one word and you spell, you know, and you read it with your dots.
And they did. And then they'd say it's fake. They planned it.
They pre-planned the words and it wasn't to multiple, you know, variations that finally Braille was accepted.
And now we're seeing the same thing with spelling to communicate.
They need a communication partner just like to read, you need glasses.
It doesn't mean they're not communicating on their own.
They just need someone to help support their motor control.
Got it. So you're just using the term spelling in a different way.
Yes.
Most people are accustomed. That's why I want to clarify.
Yes, yes, yes.
Super confused.
Yes.
So that seems like that's on them.
I mean, if there's evidence that it works, like they should be brought up and people should say, like, what you're doing is a disservice, like a huge disservice for for whatever reason, for your own ego, for your own.
Well, yeah, I mean, you think about it right for now, you know, decades.
If you have apraxia and you're a non speaker and you're considered you're not in there, people will will treat them, put them in school systems where they're trying to teach them to like behaviors that are impossible if you can't control your body.
And then often teach them over and over colors and shapes and teach them like they're they're not getting it that they're not smart.
So they've been robbed of their education.
They've been robbed of an entire livelihood.
So to admit that we've been wrong about this entire population and educating them wrong.
I mean, that's a lot of reckoning.
That's a lot of wrong.
And ABA therapy, which is now what kids go into is a multibillion dollar industry.
And I think that they profit very much so from having kids go into this type of therapy.
And I think ABA therapy can be helpful for some people.
It can be, you know, but for a lot of non speakers with apraxia, it's it's like traumatic because you're taught.
ABA therapy.
It's behavior therapy.
And that's like what insurance will cover.
I do think it is.
I think there's a huge financial gain.
ABA therapy.
And I think it's all in bed together.
And money fucks up.
It does.
But it's like anyone listening to this.
The number one thing is that like if you think of a human rights violation, right, you that non speakers aren't allowed to go spell in schools to communicate, to participate socially.
Right.
You know, because these are individuals with ideas and thoughts and career holes.
And want to date and want to have friends and want to be involved.
And and yes, they can't control their bodies, but they can do it.
They can communicate and and to be leaving them out because, oh, we can't afford it.
We don't believe that you should have a communication partner in school.
It's so it's just mean it's a human rights violation.
I think it's bizarre.
Yeah.
I mean, that's yes.
It's also very bizarre.
And it's.
It's bizarre.
Yeah, I mean, that's, yes, it's also very bizarre.
And it's just, it makes sense when you connect it to insurance and money in an industry.
That's where it gets gross.
They're against the competitors, which is probably truth.
Yeah, because if spelling, if you could be, if they'd say, hey, we will approve for spelling
to be covered by insurance, every family could go do this.
Right now you've just spent thousands of dollars, often go to a conference, do an online thing.
It's not cheap.
It's not affordable.
It's not easily accessible.
I mean, it can be depending on where you live, right?
But like, but it's, it's not easy.
That would be a lot more money to going away from AVA therapy.
Right.
Of course.
God, it's always the root of it all.
You get to it, there's someone who's profiting and doesn't want to stop profiting.
Yeah.
And the whole industry of a bunch of people working and yuck.
So you first recognize that there is some sort of an ability.
When do you start expanding your idea of what children can and can't do?
What, what, what they can and can't see?
Like when, when does it get to where you're at now?
So like spiritual gifts, when you start accepting those kinds of things.
Yeah.
I think the corroboration of person after person after person was really helpful.
You know?
Do you remember like the first one that made you reconsider or consider?
Well, okay.
So the telepathy was definitely that, okay, that became pretty quickly.
And it was really funny too, as how like the people working on this, like on my crew and
my camera guy and stuff, my GP Michael, like would quickly, we were all kind of like, okay,
this is happening.
Like you'd get almost bored seeing it, like because it became so common and so easy that
like the telepathy quickly became unimpressive, which is so wild to say out loud.
But then it would be like, I remember Houston, who's a beloved individual, both in my life
and also in the project and his mom as well.
He had this relationship with stones where he could feel like the energy of crystals.
And Katie, his mom is, you know, an evangelical and didn't put much stock into any new age
thing.
And they gave her like a bag of crystals and stuff.
And she was like, come on, and kind of put those in her, you know, bathroom upstairs
behind one door and, you know, and Houston came home from school, like ran into the primary
bedroom and then went to the bathroom and found the rocks and like was so excited and
put them in lines next to his bed and wanted to put his head next to them.
And he could feel the energy coming from these stones.
And I always thought, okay, people believe in stones and maybe they matter because people
believe in them. But like, I didn't actually think they had energy of like healing gifts.
And here's Houston going, feeling the stones.
So that made me think, what?
Okay, maybe there's something here.
Enough individuals saying they could see auras around plants and animals and people.
So that was something I started being like, okay, this is happening enough and enough
that I believe that. And then the language was the next thing.
And that was pretty remarkable.
And I'm not saying every non-speaker has these gifts.
I'm just saying the people that I've met that have been a part of this project and there's
an awful lot ado.
And I think by the gifts change per person, too.
How often do you see the language thing?
You know, I should send out another like questionnaire, but probably every five individuals.
Wow.
You know, but like that's a rough number, but it would be interesting to like survey.
Are there any other data points that would indicate that someone would be more likely
to have these language skills?
Is there any factors about these individuals, like the differences in their conditions or
the environment?
Well, this is one thing that has been really remarkable.
I think especially since the Solopathy Apes came out is how much belief and just like
acceptance of these type of things matters for them to show themselves.
Right. So so I was talking to a parent the other day who's not in the telepathy tapes
of someone I've met through this.
And she said, look, my son, after the telepathy tapes came out, you know, he's about 19 said,
I need to come out to you. I can also read your mind, but just never felt comfortable
saying it because didn't think his parents would respond well.
Right. And and another teacher was telling me, look, now that this has come out and like
I've realized this to be a truth in her clinic or classroom, she will do 10 minutes for thought
sharing in the beginning of the day where they can all talk telepathy and hang out.
And she as she said, it's like the one of the only times when they're all quiet and
they're just thought sharing.
And she said that, you know, now that the telepathy is out, more and more parents are
like being told this and, you know, accepting it.
Because when I fell into this world before the telepathy tapes was out in the world,
almost every single parent or teacher I met was like thinking this was an individual miracle
happening alone in their house.
They couldn't tell anyone. Even sometimes the spouses were fighting.
I met one parent once not in the telepathy tapes, but I met her in the journey.
And she said, my husband wants to take my child away because he thinks I've lost my
mind by saying that this is happening.
Oh, geez. So, you know, so now that it's out there, I think it's a it's just think about
it. If you have kids, right, like if you believe in your kids, I believe you, I believe in
you. It makes a difference.
The placebo effect. Sure.
We know the placebo effect works.
If you believe in something, it makes a difference.
So when you say to a non-speaking individual, like I want to know all of you, I'm
excited to know all of you, even if that means that nothing you can tell me is going to
scare me or make you love you less.
So, you know, I think that's a cool way to approach anyone, really.
Yeah, certainly. And I think skepticism and cynicism is probably also contagious.
You probably feel that that negative doubting energy, which is very suppressing, you
know, just like and if you're already nonverbal and you're already like dealing with a
lot of other stuff like that negativity on top of it, you'd probably not want to even
try. Right. Yeah.
Yeah. There's a shame that I think just negative feelings.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Do you think this is something that you have?
I think we all have it.
I mean, have you have you tried to encourage it in yourself or have you tried to explore
it? Well, because I would imagine if I was doing this work, I'd be like, let me see if
I can do this. Yeah, yeah.
And for sure.
And I will, you know, I often pray at night and sometimes I'll also just beam out
thoughts to some of the non-speakers in my life and hope they catch them, you know.
And, you know, they're loving thoughts, usually, of course.
And then there's been a few times where I'll see a non-speaker that maybe, you know,
I've come to know and love in a dream and they're either communicating something to me
or, you know, write the parent in the morning and say, can you ask so and so if they were
trying to communicate X, Y, Z at all or, you know, were they trying to communicate with
me last night, is usually what I'll say.
And they'll say, oh, yeah, they wanted you to know blank, blank, blank, blank, blank.
And it'll be what happens.
So but that's only happened in dreams, not in real life.
I mean, dreams are real life.
But yeah, so I think I think this I think the more people are open to this and practicing
it, it's it's there.
You'll get there. And a lot of teachers are able to get it back to a telepathy where they
can start hearing their students back.
And they said, you know, there's a teacher and I love the story because she I heard her
on a podcast, actually, and it was sent to me.
I was like two years into my journey and this teacher thought no one else in the world was
going through this. And she said there's a student and he's telepathic and he can read
my thoughts. And then all of a sudden I started being able to hear him back and I'd be
cooking dinner and I'd hear him or and he would tell me things.
He'd just pop into my mind and he was younger.
So she had to set parameters that you can't come into my mind all the time.
But she said that in the classroom, then they started being able to teach just to do the
whole thing, the whole lesson without talking.
She'd ask him something in his head. He'd start typing it.
She'd ask something else in his head.
He'd start typing it. And that was something that like a lot of teachers have expressed
that or speech pathologists.
And and I've often wondered, why is it easier for the educator, you know, instead of the
parent? And I think it's because parents put so much stuff on our kids, right?
Like if I'm watching my son play basketball and he's not boxing out and he's not doing
this, I'm like, oh, good, oh, good, I can't even watch, you know.
But if it's someone else's kids, I'm like, oh, they're fine.
They're just learning. You know, I have no care if anyone else's kid is doing this.
But so I think with our kids, we put all this baggage on them even if we're not intending
it. Like the energy is so great, where if it's just free and you're just wide open and
you're just ready, I think some cool bond can often happen between me and between anyone.
But certainly, at least my experience has been more educators than parents that goes
into this two way thing.
This teacher, did they explain what the sensation was like, like hearing the words in
their head? Like, how did they how did they receive these things?
So at this point, there's a lot of teachers.
So I have like a little bit more data points on this.
And for her, she was hearing like a voice in her head, very clear, you know, very clear.
Was she hearing that she interpreted as the child's voice?
Was it a child's sound?
Yeah. Yeah. And that's what's so cool is for some of the individuals who've kind of gone
through this will say, you just know it's their voice, even though they don't have a voice
in the real world. Like, you just know it's their energy imprint, right?
Like, this is their voice.
And but then I've met some teachers who are like, no, it comes in as like a visual a
visual package, if you will.
Right. Like, or one of the most beautiful things I heard from a mom in England.
And I think her story is great because she knew this was going for years, was scared to
put it out there. She finally did.
I'm not getting any younger. I'm putting it out.
And then, of course, there's a lot of parents who are in England that were like, me, me,
too, me, too, me, too. This is happening to me.
And she once explained it to me in the most beautiful way.
She said, like, if you say the word with a word, Thanksgiving, you've just said the word
Thanksgiving. If you send it telepathically, you receive the smells, you receive the
sleeping in your childhood bed again, like your crotchety uncle who's mad about that,
like the game of, you know, the sound of the football game, maybe snow, you're this person
walking with the pie, like the prayer you say, whatever it is, all the things that make
your experience that comes to you.
And there's no there's no misunderstanding what this means and feels and is.
And it's this whole expansive idea.
So I think she she receives things that way.
Wow. Yeah, it's really cool.
It's so cool, but it's also because of the cultural restrictions that we have.
Put on the idea of telepathic communication, even while you're saying this, I'm so
fascinated and I believe it for sure.
Part of me is like, shut up, you know what I mean?
It's like that part of you is strong.
Yeah. That and I wonder if that part of us, unfortunately, because of all the
charlatans and because of the cultural restrictions on just the concept of
telepathy, I wonder how much of that holds us back because there's some things that
you do know and you don't know why you know them.
You know, and if you're a person who goes on instincts, you'll follow those instincts
and you go, I have no idea how I knew that was the right thing to do.
But it was. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I mean, look, I think one thing is experiencing something.
You just believe it, like I said.
And I think anyone who has engaged with walks into a room with a non-speaker going to
do this, which from my experience has been quite a few, it's not hard to see.
And it's pretty easy to to witness it.
And so when you experience something over and over and over again, right, it's like.
Are all these parents and teachers all around the world and speech pathologists and
principals and ministers and rabbis and everyone who's witnessed this lying, did they
all come in this great conspiracy to decide that we're going to trick the world or
they're experiencing something and telling the truth?
And the first one is out there.
That's like the most impossible thing to imagine.
The other thing I want to say, too, is like there's a motivation for someone who's a
charlatan, right? You want to make money off of someone or something when especially
when they're the most vulnerable, you're going to exploit this and et cetera, et
cetera. Or it's for your own ego, your gain or career or whatever.
You know, to date, because non-speakers have not been able to have the resources that
they need to spell and engage in society, they've not been able to have a career yet.
I mean, some have, but very few or make money on their own or, you know, be in the
popular crowd or have some cool whatever.
And and so what's to gain?
What is to gain?
And it's also to take so much energy off and to spell out something, I can't imagine
that you'd spell out a lie.
I mean, there's nothing to gain in this entire population talking about this in silos
all over the world.
Right. And also very few people engage with nonverbal people.
So for this to be this very bizarre sort of strange phenomenon that's happening
with these people, you would have to be in that experience with those people to even
be able to appreciate what's going on.
Yeah, I think most people, you know, we're so accustomed to talking, we're so
accustomed to typing things out and communicating the way we do normally that we
don't we don't even think about what the experience is like for both the parents and
the child. And that this is a completely different way of living.
So whatever these innate abilities that we may have, of course, they would be the ones who
would have them. It kind of makes sense that they would be the ones that would be so
tuned into us, whereas us, we're sort of probably drowning those thoughts, even if they
do exist. We're drowning them off with language, with cultural expectations, with social
media, with news and yeah, with thought.
Yeah, with everything, with all this.
We're bombarded. We're never even alone with our thoughts anymore.
We're just bombarded constantly 24 7.
And I mean, this is the number one criticism about social media is shaping your mind in a
way that you're not even asking.
You don't really don't have agency over it.
You're just constantly being bombarded with data and that data, whether you like it or
not, even if you're objective, it's it's changing the way you interface with the world.
These people aren't experiencing any of that.
I mean, I think they're probably experience like I think they have so much input coming
in, you know, that it can be overwhelming.
But right. It's not informing their.
Yeah, I mean, not engaging.
Yeah, they're not engaging. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, it's really it's really remarkable, you know.
Well, beyond right now, because it changes the way we think about human beings.
It changes what our potential is.
I've always thought that it was an emerging aspect of human consciousness.
But then as time has gone on, I think I start to think probably more than that.
It's probably has always been there.
Yeah. We, you know, I mean, animals have weird abilities that we don't understand,
like the ability that birds have to to navigate.
We don't understand what that is.
We don't understand how they're doing that.
But we know they do it, you know, and they they have also there's some ability that
animals have to read electrical signals, to read magnetic signals.
What is what's going on there? Yeah.
What what are they doing?
You know, Rupert Sheldrake, again, who's in the project, he he's the biologist from
Cambridge. He talks about something called the mental field.
And that was like a good handle for me to start to understand how this could be possible.
And so by that, we know that fields can exist beyond something.
And we take it as part of science.
Like we know the earth has a gravitational field.
You can't see it. You know, it's there.
But but you know, it's it's real.
And we know that magnets have a magnetic field that we can you know, you can't see it.
But you know, it's there. And so his theory is that our mind has a mental field that
extends outside of the brain and this mental field can like overlap with someone.
And that a great example of the mental field, if you will, would be when you see like a
murmur of birds or a school of fish and they're all turning exact same time.
They don't bump into each other.
They're not like having concussions left and right.
The bird ones, the wild. It's wild.
It's like they do it. It's almost like they have a school of fish is essentially
the same thing, but in the water, in the water.
And and it's like they have one mind.
Right. It does feel like one mind.
And so this this beautiful idea, it's not it's not it's just out there.
And one of the things I came across that I absolutely adored as well was that Mark Twain,
he had he coined this term mental telegraphy.
And what he was responding to was kind of what we think of as phone telepathy, but
that someone would write a letter.
Let's say he wrote a letter to make something up, a great aunt Margaret.
Right. And he and he hadn't written to her in seven years and he postmarked it on
March 2nd. Well, you know, maybe two weeks later, he got a letter from Aunt Margaret
post March, March 2nd.
And that would happen a lot in the time of letter swapping that at the same time,
both people thought of each other. They hadn't written to each other a long time.
The letters were postmarked on the same day.
You know what happened the same day.
And there was such a concrete evidence there of wow.
And so he wrote a lot about that.
He thought that was fascinating, you know, and like,
Upton Sinclair, who wrote The Jungle, you know, wonderful author.
He wrote a book called Mental Radio where he was trying to do telepathy experiments
with his wife and she would think of something or vice versa.
And they draw it out.
And he had done this so many times that he talks about this is real.
I know this to be true because I've experimented it and heard I can thought share.
And so, you know, it's like we have examples of this throughout recent history.
But I definitely think if you go back to many native cultures,
I mean, even the Vikings, the Druids, whoever, like none of this would be shocking.
Right. It's they're not going to go try to prove this.
This is part and parcel of being human.
And I think it still is.
But to your point, it's just been buried by the noise that we've filled up our lives with.
Yeah. Like our feet aren't the same shape anymore because we don't walk barefoot.
You know, our feet are atrophied and gotten withered and twisted and weak.
And that's one of the reasons why people wear barefoot shoes, right?
Yeah, because they want to engage their toes.
And if you don't, your foot atrophies and becomes weird.
It just makes sense that your mind or these
abilities of consciousness would also atrophy because they're never used,
because it's so easy to communicate with words.
And so and it's the and also you're dealing with other people
manipulating those words and trying to decipher whether or not this is true or not.
And yeah, yeah.
And I mean, you know, energy, right?
You did martial arts and stuff.
So you understand, like if someone's energy, how it can impact you.
And I think that like most of us have some sense of like you walk into a room
and someone just like, oh, they're killing you or like if you're really,
you know, I think energy is a real thing.
Sure. But I think as far as like these gifts go or whatever, like telepathy,
you know, we've all had that experience where someone's like,
oh, I just knew the second they died, like I felt it.
Like I felt the ground in my apartment and I have no idea.
And then I got the phone call or or my aunt came to me in a dream last night
and said, I love you and I'm always here and whatever.
And then like the next day they get the phone call, their aunt died.
And there's so many stories like that we hear just an everyday life. Right.
Sure. So, again, like it's just if we sat back and really thought about this,
this isn't wild. This is part of the human experience. Right.
And the non-speakers are just the great skies. Yeah.
Yeah. It's really weird to look at it in reverse, though, for me,
because like I said, I did think it was an emerging aspect,
but now I think it's probably not.
It's probably something that's been buried by our technology
or our progress. Yeah. We think it's progress.
It's easier to communicate with people with noises and saying that,
but we're probably missing this thing that used to be a part of us.
And it comes in these little blips. Yeah. Little weird, you know, waves,
especially heightened anxiety or heightened, you know,
anytime you're stimulated in some sort of a way, which makes sense.
Why? With psychedelic drugs, which dissolves the ego,
you have more of those. Right. Right. This is right.
So if you try to expand your ability
in any way, have you have you tried to meditate
and try to find where that is inside your consciousness?
In the beginning, I think when I was starting to go into this,
I was meditating a lot and doing a lot of stuff.
But but right now, I'm so focused on just getting the story out
that it's like all my time is put on that.
And I've kind of put my own like stuff aside for a little bit here.
But I mean, meditation, I think that's the number one way
to to help open up anything mental. Right.
I mean, that's and meditation, like 20, 30, 30 years ago
was considered kind of fringe and out there and the idea that it could benefit you.
Scientists looking into that were kind of like, oh, this guy's kind of, you know.
And and now it's that those people were right.
Yeah. The response has been insane.
Like the the telepathy tapes shot to the top of the charts,
like everybody was talking to me about it and sending it to me
before I ever wound up listening is that it's got to be gratifying
in some sort of way that like at least people are responding to this
and they're very excited about it.
Yeah, I think so.
And I think, I mean, definitely it's gratifying.
But, you know, the story behind that is pretty remarkable.
And that's, I think, one of the things that was most gratifying
because I never intended to make a podcast.
You know, I was trying to make a documentary of this.
And then the documentary became so big that I was like, oh, maybe I have to make it as docu
series, like pitched it to a bunch of, you know,
streamers and stuff.
And I think people loved it.
And they were like, oh, this is such a good pitch.
And oh, my gosh. But like, it doesn't fit our mandate.
Like, what is it? It's not true crime.
It's not this. It's not that.
And so everywhere we pitched said, no, everywhere we pitched.
And I remember going home and feeling devastated
because I thought this was the most important news in the world.
How could anyone like this is this needs to get out there and thinking
it's the end of the road. I can't afford to go do a documentary of my own.
I can't do this and can't do that.
And I was just like, you know, and and I thought this could be a good podcast,
but I never made one.
So then it was sort of like this will be my final pitch.
Like, hopefully someone will notice and then we can get the film funded.
And so I made the podcast as just like a desperate like Hail Mary.
Like someone listen to this, please, and fun documentary.
And then it like went crazy.
And it was what was so funny, too,
is when I first started telling a lot of families and stuff about the podcast,
they were like, I don't know if that's a great idea because just feeling
is so you have to see it to believe it, to know that they're really not touched
and that they're really communicating and telepathy.
You have to see to believe like none of this will work as a podcast.
And it was just that lightning bolt again, you know, like, no, no, no.
This is it. This is it. You guys like this is it.
Like, I just know it's going to be great.
And they were like, you know, and so the fact that it did what it did
is just humbling and I think so well deserved for the non-speakers.
And those parents and teachers who are brave enough, right,
to tell their stories finally.
Yeah, I'm glad you decided to follow that instinct
because the podcast is the perfect way to do it because podcasts
are easily shareable. Yeah.
So that's how things really get out there.
Someone tells you about it. You tell other people about it.
You go on a podcast, tell people about your podcast.
And that's that's what starts it. Yeah.
I mean, so and I think the medium, too, is so I never realized
what a special medium it is because you're talking directly into someone's ears.
And you're just in their mind like and just can talk to them for a few hours.
And this was a story that we needed some real long.
Yes. You know, exploration.
Also, it's fascinating.
And that's what you really want out of a podcast other than humor.
You want it to be fascinating.
Yeah. You know, you you want it to lock in and excite you.
Yeah. And that certainly does that.
And I think most people want to believe, you know. Yeah.
Yeah. And I would not have put my time and effort and money into this if it wasn't real.
I mean, it is it is real.
And people don't have to take my word for it.
Like they could just go start working with a speller.
And again, not all spellers, I think, maybe.
I don't know. Who knows?
But I think these are gifts are pretty easy to see if you start engaging with.
Yeah. Well, it certainly seems like it.
So what so has the film started?
Have you where you are right now?
So we our first day of filming was yesterday, which is really exciting.
Yeah. Yeah. And so we yeah, we're off to the races.
We have five non-speaking members of our production team, which is awesome.
Oh, wow. So cool.
Like two are specializing in like working on graphics and depicting what
things that they talk about look like, like the chat on the hill.
I don't know if you've heard of this telepathic chat room where non-speakers hang out.
We can come back to that.
And like the realms where maybe they get information.
So or just even what it means to see auras or to see stuff like that.
So we have two graphics kind of advisors
that will be working with the graphics house on that stuff.
We have a scientific advisor who's going to help us figure out
how to best do the telepathy tapes with the scientists that we'll be working with.
And then two story kind of consultants.
So it's really cool to all five of these individuals.
I believe it's the first paying job they've ever had.
So that's it's just cool having them on our team.
So what is this chat on the hill?
OK, so that was one of the harder things to wrap my head around.
When I first met Katie in Houston,
Katie said, you know, Houston talks about this telepathic chat room
where he can go hang out with his friends.
You can kind of tune into the telepathic chat room.
And and that and he teaches there, too.
And it's a place where they can commune and talk and encourage you.
He teaches in the telepathic chat room.
Yeah. Houston's like really special.
He really is. And he's and and I think there are different roles
that this person might talk about plant energy and this person might talk about this.
And I've heard this down from. Well, let's just back up.
So how many people are in this telepathic chat room?
Well, I don't know. But but well, I'll get to that answer.
Let me just so because I think that's an interesting thing.
So Houston started talking about this,
what he calls the talk on the hill, which is this telepathic chat room.
And then I met his good friend, John Paul, who's also kind of based in Atlanta.
And John Paul would go up to his room and put four pillows on his head.
And his mom was like, he's on the hill.
And this is what he does to kind of get everything out, all the sounds of the house
so we can really concentrate and get there.
And, you know, she said he really has like
developed a beautiful relationship with his girlfriend on the hill.
And that and I'm like, what?
So I didn't know what to make of it, only I knew that it felt very real to these parents.
And and and these individuals and people were talking about it in Atlanta.
So I thought, OK, this might be an Atlanta thing that these individuals are doing this.
They don't have to be in the same room, the same zip code that they can connect.
And on the day I met John Paul, he was on the hill at one point.
And I asked that question, I said, how many people are on the hill right now?
And I think he wrote like 4000 something.
And I was like, holy cow, it seems like a lot.
He's like, well, people are really excited about the documentary right now.
So everyone's tuning in to find out what's happening with this.
So I was like, whoa.
And then and then I just like buried that in my heart.
This is something that is real in Atlanta.
And then I was talking to like the next big woe.
Again, telepathy tapes was not out yet.
I met a minister in Arizona who had like the largest youth
like special needs youth ministry or something.
And I was on Zoom with him because he was like found out about the telepathy
and found out about these gifts.
And there was a person in his congregation
who could predict the future and see things happening in other spaces in the world.
And he was just, you know, I think we were connecting to be like,
OK, yeah, you've seen this.
OK, let's talk about this.
And he was kind of going through his list of what he's witnessed
with the individuals in his ministry.
And one of the things he said to me was I was on Zoom the other day
with another young individual or another individual from Minnesota
getting these to connect to connect.
And they start talking about something called the Hill.
They go to this place called the Hill.
Have you ever heard about this?
And I almost fell out of my chair.
And then maybe like a few months after that,
I was talking to a teacher and she goes, you know, some of my students,
have you ever heard about this?
They talk about going to some place called the Hill.
And one of them talks as he goes there to learn about time travel.
And the other one likes to talk about someone from from Norway
who talks about the bees and beekeeping and beach stuff.
And at that point, I mean, my head is exploding just like,
wait, it's like real, like, jeez, you know.
And then there's a father in Israel
who I have talked to a lot about this over the years.
And he's kept a really good track, too, of like how telepathy
has been buried in the spelling community and in the education community
and what's been going on and how teachers are being fired.
So he's fascinating.
But one of the things he told me, he's like, oh, yeah, we have a separate hill
in Israel where a lot of the orthodox, like Jewish folks go
and they have their own hill.
And then I and then I would get some emails and be like, you know,
there's also a hill in Arizona and Florida, like there's different hills.
So it's it's a mystery.
It's a magical mystery.
But they all call it the same thing.
Yeah. And I don't.
And then I've also met like after the telepathy tapes came out,
one family wrote me and said, hey, my son has said he has telepathy.
No doubt there.
But he can only do it with people in the room.
But he's never been to the hill. How does he get to the hill?
And I thought, I don't know.
I guess ask another non-speaker who maybe can teach you
how to like dial into the right frequency.
You know, I'm not exactly sure how that works.
But it's really it's it's awesome.
You know, now is there one hill or is there many hills?
I think there's a few hills.
And have they verified that people who are communicating
in this hill are actually communicating with these individuals?
Yeah. And in fact, that's one of the storylines in the film
that I'm really excited about.
Like one of the subjects is a young girl who's always felt pretty isolated.
You know, it's hard sometimes to make friends
if you're not able to communicate school or whatever.
So but she was bringing up names and has brought up names
that her mom was like, you know, they're not in her school.
They're not in our periphery.
They're not in any of our social stuff.
And then once the telepathy tapes came out, these Facebook groups
sprang up of families that were kind of going through the stuff.
And in that process, she found, I think, like four of these individuals
that her daughter was saying she was really good friends with on the hill.
And they also say they go to the hill.
Yeah. Yeah.
And so we've like corroborated all these points in this girl's life.
Have you tried to corroborate actual distribution of information,
actual communication?
Mm hmm. Yeah. You've done that?
Mm hmm. Yeah. It's yeah.
I mean, that's of course, like you have to imagine for everyone
in this world, all the families that I'm close to and teachers
and therapists and stuff, it's still remarkable.
So anytime someone says something, we will try to validate it.
Like this person just said they saw this person on the hill.
Can you validate, validate, validate they were there?
And then, oh, my gosh, yes.
What did they talk about? This was said and this was said, hey,
this person says that person is on the hill and talking about blank.
Oh, yeah, I can verify that that person teaches about that on the hill.
So like it's not like anyone is taking any of this just in stride.
Like, you know, I think there's still that human nature
like you're talking about that, like even the parents and teachers
and me and the people on the front lines of this are still always trying
to validate it. Like this happened.
Was that true? Did you get that same thing?
And then there's that moment of like, oh, my God.
Like that's happening with all of us all the time, too.
That mind blowing. Wow.
That just, you know, bore out.
It's remarkable when it happens that the hill thing is next level.
It's next level. And why is it the hill?
Why do they call it the hill universally?
Well, Houston named it the chat on the hill. He named it.
Mm hmm. Now the other kids name it.
I think they're all saying it as well, though, right?
They're all saying the same term. Yeah.
But I mean, just like I, you know, someone named this cup
and we're all calling a cup, right?
I think like it just spreads.
So you think that child Houston, he named it.
And then everybody else accepted that name.
Yeah. He didn't hear it from someone else.
I mean, he might have.
That's the question. Like, what is the name?
Like, why on the hill?
Well, I've asked people that.
And one one individual is like, it just feels more like a hill of thoughts,
like just this like mound of just like thoughts and energy and being.
And so I wonder what they're seeing.
Well, we're working on that for the film.
That's like why we have these two graphics,
non-speaker advisors, so they can work to make us understand
what it looks like to them.
Oh, mm hmm.
And then once actually once the telepathy tapes was done,
I started releasing something called the talk tracks, where we like
keep going with answering some of the questions.
And one of them was this
a young man who reached out after episode two.
And he's like, I want to help or volunteer for you.
And I was like, go work with some non-speakers.
That's going to be the best thing in the world.
And he witnessed the telepathy right away.
He witnessed a few other things.
And he ends up in the first talk tracks episode getting to the hill.
And his story is really beautiful as to how as a neurotypical man,
he was able to do that.
But people need to listen to it because it's really cool.
So he figured out how to get to the hill.
Mm hmm. Yeah, yeah.
And what does he describe it as?
Well, he said it's divinely protected, that there seems to be divinely.
Mm hmm.
There seems to be like some sort of guide there that like you can't just go in
like Halliburton, can't go rip it off.
You know, like there's like like it seems to be guarded
and that only people with good intentions can go.
And I think I mean, I hope people don't try to start going there.
I really, really don't.
Oh, they're going to non-spinoff.
I know it's like one of the pains actually for me is that like,
in putting this out there, like.
But I do think the non-speakers are in charge there.
It's their space is a beautiful space.
And and and I don't think anyone can just get let in.
You have to really be open, open, but not just open, have a good, good intention.
Right. Completely pure.
Pureness and love are a big part of this.
And this person who's typical, regular person got in there.
Had they had any experience in the past with any form of telepathy before this?
Well, the reason his story is so beautiful.
So again, he's an episode one of the talk tracks.
And what happened is he had he was diagnosed with
a really rare like autoimmune disease and then like stage four cancer.
And he kind of realized, like, if I need to I need to save my life,
I'm going to die if I don't learn to, like, think, control my thoughts.
And and he was able to cure himself.
And he sent me scans and the cancer was almost all gone.
But I think that that attention to thought and how thought
can change your world and dictate what happens in your world
really did something in his brain that allowed him to live in that mental space.
And I think that helped him.
I think that really helped him get to the hill.
I mean, he he talks about more of how he got there.
And it took a few times.
And for him, it was all audible.
It felt like static and certain voices.
But then he said he did a few tests like there was a
one of the students he works with.
He's like, I knew exactly who it was and I could hear their voice.
I just knew it was her voice, even though I've never heard their voice.
But I just knew it was their energy.
I just knew it was them.
And he's like, so I gave a test and I said, I'm going to tell you
this person's name and this person's name and this person's name.
And, you know, gave them kind of a bunch of information.
And so when I see you next, you need to tell me this stuff.
And then when he saw that person next, they they wrote it.
They spelled it out for him.
Whoa. Yeah, yeah.
So I do think the people experimenting experimenting with this
have their own deep desire to get it right and try to validate stuff.
You know, it's hard just to take on face value.
How do you know if it's real or if it's in your own mind? Right.
But the weird thing is like, if this does, I mean,
I'm sure you've opened up a lot of people's minds to this.
And again, if this expands and then we all agree
that this is a thing and this is a possible thing
and then people start trying to figure out what it is and develop methods
to try to tap into that.
This could be a profound change in just society as a whole.
Yeah. Yeah.
And I think the thing I hear the most, right,
is people are afraid of their thoughts being out there.
But what's kind of cool on your head that you're so worried about.
Exactly. Well, that's how about clean your brain out.
Exactly. Clean your brain out.
You're not going to be afraid of that. Right.
Yeah. What's going on in your head that you don't want anybody to know?
Totally. What are your terrible thoughts?
It's interesting because when people say that, I do because
I mean, we all have certain stuff that like who cares
if someone knows that way all happens to us, right?
Like you're worried about having something in your teeth or something
or like, you know, accidentally pass gas and whatever.
I mean, that type of stuff, I think, who cares?
So that like that's just being human. Right.
But when people are like that terrified, it's like,
what the hell is going on with you?
Yeah, I think it's the concept of it too.
And also the concept.
I think there's the thought that if someone can read your mind,
that you're more vulnerable, that you can't protect yourself.
Like, you know, like if you like, oh, this person's creepy.
Let me get away from them. Oh, you think I'm creepy?
You know, like that kind of thing.
Like that you won't you won't be able to just like avoid people.
I do think you have some control over it, though.
And again, I can only go off of what I've heard from others. But like
one of the teachers who's been just she's been such an advocate
and fighter in this world for years trying to point to this.
And she said the first experience she ever had
around maybe not the first, but one of the most cementing experiences
was she was going to go visit a former student class.
And the night before, this is wild.
The night before, she went out and picked like Swedish fish and,
you know, some donuts and, you know, I forgot what else.
Pretzels or something.
And so she comes in to give him his favorite snacks
and forgot them in the car.
But she went and she sat with him and talked with him.
And right before she was leaving the classroom, he took out a pen
and drew like a donut, a fish, you know, and kind of drew the things that she
and it like rattles her to her core.
Like she he knew what she was thinking that night before.
And and now that he's, you know, graduated,
she still works with him just as an volunteer basis
for the sheer joy of just being with him.
And she asked him years later, how did you do that?
And and and he like, were you remote viewing through me?
And how did you know at that moment?
He's like, well, once you were thinking of me, that was like my invitation
to come in, like I won't just crash into someone's thoughts.
It's like I have to be kind of invited in by like, you know, like the thought.
So so I do think that there's a way to kind of control it.
And I know that the teacher that was having the student
jump into her brain a lot, the younger man, she said, like,
you need to stop that, like if I will invite you in when I want you.
But you can't just come into my mind whenever that's not appropriate.
You know, right.
And and so I think every individual is an individual. Right.
I mean, how this stuff works and is probably different for each person.
But I don't necessarily think, you know, what many spellers have told me
is like, good, good energy allows them to swap thoughts.
Like, good juju allows them to do that.
Being invited in, being open to it.
It doesn't feel like they can just go into like, you know,
the person running for sentence thoughts and be like,
haha, actually, you didn't fund them, you know. Right.
The problem is, like, what if people get really good at that?
Like, what if it expands and then people are just entering
into your thoughts all the time?
I think technologically, that's going to happen anyway.
Yeah. You know, it's one of the things that Elon has said about this
Neuralink device that they're enabling.
You're going to be able to talk without words. Yeah.
Yeah. But here's the thing, too, right.
It's like, again, I think most almost every non-speaker I've met,
their concern is love, unity. Right.
And so if your thoughts are other people and your thoughts are loving
and about unity, it's not scary then for other people
to be reading your thoughts.
You're going to be caring about other people, hopefully.
And the real thought, the real scary thing is that there are a lot of people
out there in this world that do not have thoughts of love and unity. Right.
They're damaged, hurtful, evil people.
And they want to destroy everything around them.
Yeah. And that those people could acquire this ability.
But would they be able to?
I don't. This is the thing.
It's like, has there been any evidence that evil people have been able
to acquire this ability?
I I would say what I have found, and even talking to scientists about this,
that the baseline for this is love.
There's a wonderful neuroscientist named Julia Mossbridge,
and she has studied precognition.
And one of the things she does in these precognition tests is be like,
how much unconditional love do you feel for yourself, for other people,
for the device you're taking this test on? Yeah.
And the more people feel love, the better they do.
And one of the things that I've heard from so many non-speakers
with disabilities that the baseline is love, that love, love, love
is like the thing that unlocks this stuff.
What do they describe love as? Anything that unifies.
Yeah, I've heard that over and over again.
What's love? It's anything that unifies.
Ah, wow. Huh.
Isn't that the best description of love ever? It is.
It's a really good description.
So and and that was, yeah, very specific. Anything that unifies.
So it's almost like they're tapping into some laws of the universe
or laws of reality.
That we kind of know by trial and error.
Yeah. But we don't we don't.
I mean, all you need is love.
You know, this is always the love is a ubiquitous concept.
It's like something that everybody always agrees is very important
to life and happiness. Yeah.
But we don't necessarily practice that culturally.
Yeah. Or as a society. Yeah.
I mean, but you go back to like the all the ancient religious teachers
and thoughts, right?
And so much of it's about love and unity, and we're all one.
And you might not realize this, but we're all one.
And, you know, it's been interesting.
Like, there's a big question mark right now on how how to do these tests
and how to prove it.
And and when I brought that up to a few non-speakers,
one of the questions is, like, why do you need to prove this with instruments?
Like the biggest spiritual gift, the most fascinating one is love
that will cause someone to jump into choppy waters and save someone
and risk their own life.
It's had mothers like have so much adrenaline.
They could lift up a car and save their baby.
Like love is the superpower. Right.
And it's like that's it's just it's true.
And they're like, why aren't you trying to measure love?
And it's like, OK, good point.
But still, people want to measure telepathy.
And then that brings up the question is like of
OK, well, is it best to do it
like in a lab situation that can be really stressful,
that can be filled with a lot of skeptical people and throwing that energy at you?
Or is it better just to go into your environment, take off the lab coat,
learn to spell, go check this out.
And you think of like really good scientists like Jane Goodall, who
who when she wanted to understand like a culture of, you know,
how the chimps were working, she didn't bring them into her lab.
She went and like lived in the jungle for months, you know,
or you want to go look at the lightning bugs that light up in unison in Vietnam.
I don't know if that's going to work out for you.
If you bring them back to Berkeley and put them in a building,
you probably have to go to the jungle and wait for them to light up in unison.
So it's like, is it smart to be trying to test the stuff in our way, in our labs?
Or is it better to be like, I'm going to go chill out with you in your living room
and see how this works?
Well, the reason why to test it with instruments is for skeptics.
Right. So once we've all agreed that this is an actual phenomenon,
this is a real thing, whatever this is, this is real.
The best way to test it is really with consciousness. Yeah.
Yeah. And, you know, I think about this a lot, like the skeptics, because again,
like I've said, the families and teachers, the people who they people are like,
let's just move the signs forward. We know what's happening.
We know now we need to know how, not why. Right.
And I've thought about like how skeptics can hold back that research in science
and like how much time do you give to them versus like just move on without them.
And I was thinking about in the term of like in the olden days, right,
like if a voyager was going out to discover new worlds and people,
you can't go find something that worth this flat and you're going to fall off of it
or out there is a blah, blah, blah, blah.
And someone comes back and it's like discovered Iceland, let's say.
And it's like, oh, my gosh, you would not believe it.
Like geysers are coming out of the earth and there's black stone beaches
and black sand beaches and northern light, you know, whatever they're explaining.
And they come back and some people will be like, wow, let's go explore it
and find out more and, you know, draw things of it.
And some people might be like, don't go with them. Don't go.
Don't even try it. They're making it up. It's not real. That couldn't exist.
You're going to die if you go.
And I feel like the scientists there are the skeptics now are those people
on the shore being like, there is no Iceland.
Don't go look and you're going to blah, blah, blah.
And it's like that's such a it's such a weight to forwarding thought.
And research and this is such a cool, exciting new frontier.
Yes. And well, the thing is, is like there's levels of skeptics.
There's people that are just objective and they're like, I need data.
I need to see something.
And then there's people that it doesn't matter what they see.
They're never going to believe.
And those are the weird ones, because there's a lot of people out there
that are self professed skeptics.
Yeah, those are the ones that are the problem.
Yeah, like they call themselves skeptics. Right. OK. Right.
Well, how about just be objective? Right.
Well, don't just be skeptical. Right.
Because if you're completely skeptical and you're always looking for a negative,
you're you're, you know, you're going to be biased by your own preconceived notions.
Right. I mean, if you're if you're only skeptical, you're a closed minded believer.
So you are you're not open minded.
You're as dogmatic as like, right, as the next person
who just believes their beliefs and won't look any further.
This is it. Like, right. That's not skeptical.
Well, that's atheists. Right. And a lot of for a lot of.
Yeah. Well, I mean, there's different kinds of atheists, too.
There's some that I would just I'd say they they're self professed atheists,
but they're really more agnostic than anything. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. But I would say I mean, I would say I'm skeptical.
Every time I hear something new, I'm like, can it be that's right?
Like, we got to go test this. I don't know.
We got to find out. OK, we got to test it four or five more times.
But like, be an open minded skeptic.
Like, I don't even think that's skeptical. That's just objective. Right.
Because you hear about something completely novel and you're like, OK,
what is it? What is that?
Is this bullshit? Because you know bullshit.
The bullshit's real. It's a real thing.
Like, that's why skeptics are important.
Or at least being skeptical is important because there are people that tell you,
if you join my cult, you will you will experience bliss and happiness.
Totally true.
We all give up our money to the guru and he has sex with all of us.
But it's great. Like, what? Right. Totally.
So skepticism is important.
It is important. It keeps you from getting hoodwinked.
It does. I mean, yes. Open minded skeptical. Right.
But this is the problem with not having the ability to read minds. Right.
Is that people can deceive you and you can't really tell.
And some people are terrible at it for some reason.
Like, some people just fall in line with the wrong crowd over and over
and over again, and they never get it right. Yeah.
Yeah, that's so true. You have to be skeptical.
Yeah. Or you have to be able to read people. Yeah.
And what is reading people though? Right.
There's people that I've met that like right away.
I'm like, this person's broken. I got to get the fuck away from them.
There's a famous story that with my friend Brian,
Brian Callan, who's a hilarious comedian who always has the worst friends.
Always. And one time he showed up at this show that we were doing together
with this gal that he was dating.
And I met her for five seconds and I and he'd always had the worst girlfriends.
They're always just disasters.
I get I go get rid of this one, please.
I go, trust me, you got to move.
He's like, what are you talking about?
I go, dude, she's crazy. This one's broken.
And he's like, no, no, no. I go, dude, I am telling you right now.
Turn out she's a meth head.
He didn't know she wind up being a prostitute.
Like it was off the charts, but she was pretty.
And he just thought she was friendly to him.
And so she was fine. And I read her right away.
I'm like, oh, everything's wrong here. Yeah.
And he's like, how did you do that?
I'm like, I don't know. I just knew right away.
You got to get away from her. Yeah.
And he eventually one day
ran into her after they had broken up.
She was street walking. What?
Yeah. Like that crazy. Yeah.
Poor thing. Poor thing.
Yeah. But it was like I was like, that one's going to drag you down.
Like, get out of there. Yeah.
But I knew I don't know how I knew. Yeah.
I mean, it was a simple exchange.
Like, hi, nice to meet you. Nice to meet you, too.
Like, what the fuck's going on here?
It's like all my spidey senses. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And it's not normal. That's not normal.
That's not every day. It's not like everybody I meet,
like some people I meet, I'm like, something's off. Right.
Something. Yeah.
Just you have to be able to go on some kind of instinct.
We all know.
And a lot of it is sort of pattern recognition.
A lot of it is prior experiences with similar
the way similar people engage with you. Right.
And you're like, oh, I've seen this before. Yes.
Like, this is a con man. Oh, I've seen this before.
This is a this and this is that. Yes.
But sometimes, sometimes it's just like, this is a bad person.
Yes. This one's broken. Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
So, yes, I think having some degree of skepticism can be good.
Yeah. But emotional intelligence can be good.
I think it's objectivity. Yeah. Objectivity to recognize
that people that are deceptive are real, you know,
and there's people that have ulterior motives
and these ulterior ulterior motives you might not understand.
And you've got to be able to
you got to be able to throw everything through a filter.
And unfortunately, until we can read minds,
you're kind of going on these like, did you hear that?
I think I heard something.
You know, that's really what it's like when you meet a person.
It's like there's something.
I don't know. You're being paranoid.
I don't know. You know. Right.
And then you can convince yourself that you are being paranoid
when you actually you're not. You're actually accurate.
Yeah. And you're like, oh, you're being silly. Yeah.
You're not being silly. Right.
Followed your initial instincts. Right. Exactly.
And I think that's what has happened with like materialism
being such a for years is that anyone who believed in anything
like would be made to feel silly. Right.
Oh, you're so gullible or you're not smart.
Like intellectual people certainly don't believe in ghosts or God or whatever.
And, you know, put anything in there that you can't measure.
Right. Yeah, exactly. The secret.
And so that's been effective.
No one wants to be ridiculed and dismissed and made to feel silly.
I mean, even editing the podcast, like I was so certain.
I'm like, OK, well, episodes one through four, there's a lot of science.
This is great.
The one that took me weeks, like I was in turmoil over,
was having to like put out into the world that like the teachers were hearing
telepathy back because I'm like, no one's going to believe this.
It's just so hard. But it's like you can't censor it.
This is what people's experience is.
And the whole point was to like put out the voices of people
who have been completely dismissing and ignored.
Also, if love is unifying, the love of a teacher and a student is absolutely real.
Yeah. Again, it's a special bond, especially really good teachers.
Oh, my gosh. Really good educators have like this because they really
genuinely just want to help. Yeah.
And when someone did genuine and you're a child that's vulnerable
and confused by the world around you and you're nonverbal
and there's someone with genuine love for you.
Yeah. Like it kind of makes sense that those would be the people that bridge the gap.
It was interesting because I saw my best friend for college this morning
and her husband was there and he was like, why is it so many women
in the podcast that have telepathy? Like, can dads do it and whatever?
And I was like, in fact, the first person Dr.
Powell tested the telepathy test with, this girl was adopted
and she had the best telepathic bond with her father, you know,
and I know a young man in Israel whose best telepathic bond is with his father.
And another, you know, so, yes, it does happen with dads,
but I think there's more women who go into teaching and more women that do caregiving.
And so that's probably why it looks like more women,
but I don't think it's like a gender gendered thing that mostly women have this.
You know, I think it's whoever is in that like loving open.
Yeah, I think men are generally more inclined towards brutish thinking,
you know, and an ego and like silly ways of viewing the world.
And then also preoccupied by their status in life
and what that means to, you know, them and their worth as an individual.
And all that stuff is a massive impediment to any sort of like real love.
Yeah, you're just so self-focused.
Yeah, that's very. Yeah.
And that's definitely a male trait, especially in this capitalism society
where you're constantly trying to achieve a higher level of status. Yeah.
And no one's satisfied, including billionaires. Yeah, right.
Yeah, which is just the nuttiest thing of all time. I know.
It's like, what is the point? You won the game. I know.
You spread it out over.
You should like you have this crazy opportunity with all this money
to help so many people and lift up like all of America.
Also, why are you still just chasing numbers? Right.
In a ledger, because that's what you're doing. Yeah.
You've got lost in this weird game.
I actually cannot comprehend that. I cannot comprehend.
I wonder if you could, if you were super wealthy. Maybe.
Yeah. And if you went down that path, the thing is that the one thing would be
if you were super wealthy by some divine intervention
or someone just gives you money. Right.
You know, like some crazy billionaire who's like a telepathy tapes fan.
They're dying. And on their will, they say, listen,
guy, you seem cool. I'm going to give you two billion dollars.
Like, what are you going to do with it?
Yeah, it's different.
But if you went and tried to earn it and so your whole life,
you were focused on these achievements.
I want to have this and that.
And I want to have I want to be I want to be important.
I want to be able to influence political parties.
And I want to be able to fly in my private jet.
And I want to I want an island. You know, you get crazy. Yeah.
And then you're never you never have enough because you want more and more.
Yeah. And then you're around people like we were talking the other day.
Also, my friend Brian has a friend who's worth like three billion dollars
and he feels poor because he hangs out with these guys that are worth
fifty billion dollars.
I'm like, that's so crazy.
But that's the world that you live in when you're
only thinking about numbers on a ledger.
You've you've gotten caught playing a game. Right.
You're playing poker. You have chips.
You know, you're you're all just quantifiable numbers.
Well, none of it matters to who cares.
So here's the real number.
You got a hundred years. Right. You're lucky. Right.
That's the real number. Yeah.
And if you're 60 and you're right, yeah, you're almost at the end, buddy.
Right. Like, what are you doing?
Well, I just I always think about like the impact you're going to leave behind.
Like, what's your legacy?
Like you had a big boat.
I mean, who cares about that? Right.
What does that mean?
You know, are you going to be the person when he died?
He had so many things.
I aspire to be like, will you? Right.
Yeah. I mean, there's a lot of people that are like that.
And they think about old dead rich people being boy.
He really nailed it. He killed the game.
You know, and that's, you know,
that's the thing that they have focused on, unfortunately.
This is the problem with financial institutions, because they're like,
if all you're doing is trying to acquire more money, well, that's your game.
And your game is just do that.
And then as you get bigger, you eventually reach a point like, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
You kind of control everything.
Like, you control natural resources.
You control land.
You control building, housing, transportation.
You have everything.
This is not good for everybody else.
It's not good for everybody else for one entity to have so much power
and only be concentrating on numbers. Right.
Yeah. Yeah.
I don't know where that comes from.
I mean, I guess if you grow up really rich, maybe that's it.
Or maybe if you grew up without anything, it's a competition.
It's a subversion of what it's initially supposed to be.
It's like when you put mandates on officers
achieving a certain amount of arrests in a month.
Or even arrests in general. Right.
Or prosecutors. Right.
What's what is a prosecutor's goal to win? Right.
They have there's the competition.
The competition is I provide evidence that this person is guilty.
The defense provides evidence that he is, in fact, innocent.
And we sort it out.
And if you're just trying to win the game, well, then you're a corrupt prosecutor
because then you withhold evidence that might exonerate that person.
Or you don't allow DNA or you don't.
There's. Yeah. And there's a lot of that.
I mean, I work with a guy named Josh Dubin, who's a friend of mine,
who's his whole thing is freeing people that are unjustly accused.
And he's just because this podcast, a bunch of people are free right now.
And the shocking stories that you hear about corrupt prosecutors
where these guys get caught.
And it turns out there's hundreds of people rotting away in a cage
that are innocent because of this one corrupt person.
And because they played this game of just trying to win.
Yeah. You know, and this is the same game.
It's the same game of acquiring numbers, whatever you're trying to do.
If that is what your game is, your game is just numbers.
I mean, it just makes me wonder if like people believe there was more.
Right. Like if it wasn't just like, you've got this one shot
and you're just going to hear and like tackle the numbers and be super rich
and whatever, like would making a difference and make it
because it does feel like, yeah, oh, Pollyanna, like we're going to just,
you know, yeah, love each other.
But like, but if you really believe that there was something more, right?
That like you had a higher purpose here, that you were more than just your body.
I think I mean, I think if you believe that to some degree,
you're going to act differently.
Yeah. You're more focused on difference than acquiring numbers of money.
Yeah. It's just hard to get through people that are completely lost and obsessed.
Yeah. You know, when someone is completely like, say, a gambling addict, for instance,
they're very hard to get to.
Because they're completely lost and obsessed with this thing
that they become addicted to, which is all numbers.
Gambling is just all thrills and wins and losses and numbers.
It's all just I bet 100,000 on the game.
And I'm like, I think I got five points on the spread.
Yeah. They cover the spread.
Then I went and like that amount of the hole.
And then it's this roller coaster ride.
And so it's very difficult to get to those people that are lost
in whatever the game they're playing is, whether the game is gambling addiction
or financial addiction, whatever it is.
If you're lost in a game, it's very hard to get to those people,
especially if they don't have love in their life.
And so if all their status is acquired by numbers, by achieving this
and pulling up in the brand new Mercedes and wearing the fine suit
and having the expensive watch or whatever it is that your thing is
that you want to show up with.
And there's in this world, this this, especially today,
there's all the lures and trappings to pull you into that.
And you can never get enough.
You know, you can get hand purchase.
I mean, hand created this and, you know, rare that and a limited edition that.
Oh, did you get the new one? Oh, and then, you know, you're lost.
It's just yeah, it just doesn't fill you up.
I think it empties you out more, really, in the end.
So right. But what it does do, oddly,
is it promotes technological innovation.
So keeping up with the Joneses and materialism,
one purpose that it does serve, oddly, is this constant push
towards newer and better things, which I think is also part of the purpose
of human life in some sort of a strange way, is that we are
we are pursuing technological innovation above and beyond everything.
If you could see us objectively, if like you could see us outside of culture,
outside of language, if you were an alien race
and you're observing this weird species, like what does it do?
Well, it keeps making better stuff.
Yeah, that's what it does.
It keeps making better stuff.
It puts all of its resources into making better stuff.
And it's obsessed with acquiring better stuff,
even though it has a finite lifespan.
It never recognizes or rarely.
It's an odd and beautiful thing when someone recognizes they have a finite life.
Yeah, yeah. I was just thinking about that, what you're saying.
And I was thinking, God, then every four years,
the aliens would be like, oh, but then they pass a torture on the world
and they go and they compete in games and the whole.
And for like one small two week period, they're all playing
these games against each other.
And then they like put the torch out and go home and right.
And that's subverted by numbers, because the people that are playing the game
who everybody wants to see them, they don't get any of the money.
The money is all by the commercials and advertising and networks,
networks in the organization where they profit in a tune of billions of dollars
and literally pay zero to the athletes,
which is so gross, another disgusting subversion of this whole thing.
So the purity is in the athletes,
or especially if you're competing in a game that has no financial future.
Now, if you're the world curling champion or whatever, whatever it is,
you know, whatever some goofy ass fucking Olympics. Right.
There's no there's no you're just trying to be the best at this thing.
And I think like if you can
achieve something that makes you feel really good about yourself, right?
I think there is a worth in that.
This is beautiful. Oh, yeah.
But and that's like where sports can come in, right?
That like the underdog can win and you can work together and blah, blah, blah.
Like that's where stuff is.
I think that's like really beautiful.
You create something that's beautiful.
But yeah, just buying something is not cool.
I mean, that's right.
I mean, just what does it do?
That's not cool.
Like creating something is cool. Achieving something is cool.
It's also one of the weirdest attractions.
Yeah. Attractance about social media is what the stuff that people are showing
you they have, you know, which is like you can get a lot of followers
by having great stuff and like, look at my stuff, look at my house,
look at my car, look at my jet.
And it's like people go, wow.
And you see like millions and millions of likes.
Yeah, it's really because kids like they love the YouTube videos.
Now, like my son will watch like Hot Wheels, like people being like,
this new Hot Wheels, it goes, and he want to make these Hot Wheels things.
And I'm like, what is happening right now that you're like basically
doing an ad for Hot Wheels?
You know, it's just like I would have never wanted to watch kids
unbox Hot Wheels, I mean, or Barbies or whatever.
Like none of it, you know, unboxing things are strange.
Yeah, it's like techno porn.
Yeah, you know, you're you're watching someone do something
you wish you were doing. Oh, I wish I had that on.
Yeah, that's it's so weird.
Yeah, but it's, you know, it's also very strange when you think about
how many people are tuned into that,
where you never would have expected that in the past.
Like there would never be a television show on NBC where someone unboxes stuff.
You'd be like, no one's going to watch that.
But meanwhile, put it on YouTube and millions of people will watch that stuff.
So there's there's a part of it that we didn't anticipate.
Yeah, I don't know.
I hope it'll be a pendulum because when you brought up television,
I thought, well, that replaced the dance hall.
Right. People used to go dance and hang out before those television.
Like you'd be out doing something. And right. How cool. Right.
You know, or they also thought the world was flat. Right.
It's like this benefits to all this ability to communicate as well.
The problem is when it's centralized. Right.
The real problem with television is that television has advertising,
advertising limits, which you can say.
And because of that, you know, we censored language. Right. Right.
Advertisers didn't want you swearing on television.
So the way people talked in real life, they never talked on television. Right.
Yeah. And you know, and so that got subverted.
True free expression got subverted by advertisement.
Well, and that is what is cool about that world we're living in right now. Right.
Because like YouTube and Twitter, X or, you know, whatever, Blue Sky,
all the things, podcasts.
I mean, people are free to kind of speak and talk and share.
I bet I can get bad pretty quick, which is some simple scientific facts.
But, you know, I mean, there is a democracy to information now where,
I think like stuff that could never have gotten out there 20,
30 years ago when the gatekeeping of like you were saying,
advertising and all that was so extreme.
It's just changed. And that's awesome. Profoundly. Yeah.
And in a way that I don't think we even appreciate because we're a part of it.
Right. I think it's one of those things we've become accustomed to checking
the news on your phone when you wake up in the morning and having and friends
sending you things. Oh, my God, you see this. Right. And cool things, too.
Great music. And so many things get they get shared.
Like your show got shared to me.
I don't remember who shared it to me because so many people did.
Because I don't remember who the first person was.
Well, and I think that's the thing that is cool.
Right. We actually have like evidence of what this democratization
of information looks like.
Like the U.I.P. phenomenon has become so much more mainstream.
People are talking about it, like things that could not have been shared
or spoken are now out there.
Same with psychedelics and psilocybin.
And, you know, going on ketamine trips or whatever, like all that now
is just common knowledge that this can be great for healing PTSD
or, you know, depression or whatever.
The stuff with telepathy, you know, I mean, channeling, whatever it is,
like all these things, especially tick tock.
You're like, holy cow.
So I'm glad you brought the U.I.P. thing up.
I hate to interrupt you, but because I think a lot of the
what we're hearing is nonsense. Yeah.
I mean, I think a lot of what is being shared, especially publicly, like
there's too too many voices that I think are either intelligence assets
or are disinformation experts that are doing it on purpose.
And there's too much of, you know, the same feeling that I get,
you know, like when I said to I met my friend's ex-girlfriend,
I was like, oh, get out now. Yeah.
There's a I have that feeling about the U.I.P. thing when I hear people talk.
Nothing seems real to me. Yeah.
When I talk to people about it, there's not one.
I mean, even when people tell me their own personal experiences, I believe them.
It does not register as real. That's so interesting.
Something registers as being nonsense.
There's something maybe not nonsense, but maybe way weirder
than what they're explaining it like, like nonphysical interaction
that they are reinterpreting as like physical interaction.
Yeah. That there's some there's some disconnect between their work.
Like if someone tells me an experience that they had, like here's a good example.
My friend Steve told me a harrowing experience
of them being attacked by a brown bear in Alaska.
And when he tells you this story, first of all, I know it's real
because I know multiple people who are there.
They were all there. It was no one got hurt.
It was very fortunate.
But they got charged by a grizzly who ran through their tent.
One of my friends was on its back. Oh, my God.
For like 10 yards. Oh, like it literally plowed through the people.
And he wound up like riding its back for like 10 yards before he fell off. Wow.
Yeah. It was just like, I mean, it can cover 10 yards in a second. Yeah.
And the whole thing was just insane chaos.
And the way he describes how your reptilian brain
completely takes the fear is so overwhelming
and different than anything you've ever experienced before.
I know it happened. Yeah. He's telling me this. I know it happened. Yeah.
When these people are telling me about talking to aliens and all that,
I'm not getting nothing out of them. I'm not getting nothing.
I'm getting a flat piece of paper. Yeah, there's no fear.
There's no there's no charge. What it is. I don't know what it is.
I just don't get anything from their story. I hear it. It's interesting.
But I don't get anything that lights any bells.
There's no bulbs go off with me.
I just sit there and go, wow. OK, so what were you thinking?
You know, and I'm asking them questions, but I'm not getting nothing. Yeah.
So that leaves me because I know that.
For sure, the government has technology
that they do not want the general public to be aware of
for reasons of national security or whatever it is.
Or, you know, money has been pushed through to finance things
and they lie to Congress and they have to keep lying, whatever the reason is.
That's real. There's most certainly black ops programs
that the general public is not aware of.
That's always going to be the case.
If you have those, what better way to hide them than in plain sight
and with a bunch of people that are air quote whistleblowers
that go out and tell everybody about all these experiences.
They're not of this earth.
And that's what I would do.
If I was the government and I wanted to be super sneaky,
I would have a bunch of my like really clever agents
go and whistle blow, tell some stories, talk, talk about people
that have been abducted, talk about all these different things. Yeah.
And then on top of that, there's real experiences.
So I think I think there is something because it exists throughout history,
just like telepathy exists throughout history and ghosts exist throughout history
and and religion exists.
There's something there. Yeah.
There's some thing there that's distorted by our very slippery grasp on truth.
Yes. Yeah. I think that's a very true assessment.
Yeah. Yeah.
There's also just too many stories from hundreds of years ago
that are incredibly similar to the things that people are talking about today.
Yeah. That's the stuff that's interesting.
Like Jacques Fillet. Exactly.
I just finished his third book. Yeah.
I mean, that's the mind.
Yeah. But he's great because he's not a believer.
He's very skeptical about a lot and highlights a lot of the bullshit
to the point where like, OK, what's true? Yeah.
I mean, those are the people you have to trust, though.
The only ones. Yeah.
The only ones you can trust. Yeah.
Because there's too many people that are out there telling you,
I know what's happening.
We are about to experience a contact.
Yeah. The all the people, the joint chiefs of staff have been notified.
And like those people I don't want to talk to.
Well, you shut the fuck up.
You don't know anything. There's no way you know.
You're you're just taking advantage of this very weird moment
in time where people aren't sure.
But there's all this discussion, this phenomenon, and you've grifted yourself.
Right. Exactly. There's a lot of those people.
There are. Yeah. And it's click bait.
And it's their profit. Yeah.
Because they're they're gross.
No. But the true intellectual people is looking at the consciousness side of this.
I think that's fascinating.
That's what's like what's going on.
I think that's where it is. Yeah.
It's a conscious. I mean, that's why.
You know, I wasn't into the UAP stuff until people started saying to me,
like, you should at least start looking at some of these great thinkers,
because a lot of this has to do with consciousness.
And what what are we and why are we here?
And like, what's a hyper object, right?
Like like a lot of stuff that I'm like, what is going on?
So you start reading about it and understanding, OK, like
where things might converge is an exploration of consciousness. Yeah.
And our consciousness is confined by identity.
It's confined by so many different things.
So many so many walls that we put up and we go and blinders and self-delusion.
There's always just weird things that we have in our mind
because we don't necessarily have a very good.
Direction book of how to be a human, right?
You know, or what we're just limited to by our vision, right?
Like if you were to talk to a dog and be like, hey, there's
does this dog know about calculus?
And does it know about like the, you know, whatever electoral college?
Of course not. Like, there's no way there's no universe
in which a dog would know about that stuff.
But it could smell a cat four blocks away.
You ever see a cat dog just like, you know, in the air, you know,
they have insane noses.
They can smell individual ingredients in a hamburger.
That's so fascinating.
And a bear is like 10 times stronger than that, which is bananas.
They can smell human beings hundreds of yards away.
Just a whiff of the wind.
And then all people get the fuck out of here.
Well, and that's like we don't have that.
But like a dog doesn't have X, Y, Z.
What are we living in?
We might not be able to see half of what's there or sure conceive of it.
So wave your hand above an earthworm.
There's no idea. There's no idea.
Yeah. Like it doesn't need to.
Lives its life underground.
Those senses are not necessary. Right.
So that's the mystery.
Yeah. And our senses most likely have atrophied.
You know, that's the real thing is that, you know,
there's a lot of talk from, you know, ancient,
whether it's ancient religious texts or of contact,
of something communicating with you that's not physically there.
And you got to wonder, like, was this really common for people like there's
there's so many descriptions of being contacted by something that's not there.
Like, what was that before language normal?
Yeah. And and was it physically someone contacted you or was it in a mental space?
Right. Like, were you in this thought world?
Like almost you were astral traveling or whatever.
Right. Like, I mean, that's the question, too, is can you be experiencing
something in your mind that's not happening physically? Right.
And I think that question is pervasive in the U.A.P.
world as well as in this telepathy world. Right.
It's the birds flying around in unison somehow or another.
They're tuned in to some some pattern that they never collide.
How do they not collide?
I mean, that's like so spectacular that you're literally
hundreds of feet above the earth.
If you collide, you get knocked unconscious.
You're both dead. And no one collides ever.
And they're going fast. I mean, imagine, like, why would you do that?
Like, what what benefit evolutionary benefit?
What natural survival benefit would there be in a bunch of you
flying around in weird patterns in the sky?
Like, look at that. Here we go.
That is so beautiful.
I've heard is they just look like a bigger thing.
So that's going to be it. Right. You look like a big monster.
That doesn't scare off fish.
They go right to the big thing. Well, that's the problem.
You know, when tuned to see that big thing, they're like, fuck. Yeah.
Look how crazy that is.
I mean, it's.
But why would that be a benefit to like being a bigger thing?
That would make you a bigger target.
I don't. I mean, it's just so weird.
It's so weird. Like, no one's fallen.
No, no one's colliding.
How come they're not falling and doesn't look like art?
I mean, it really is like an elaborate dance.
Have you ever seen wolves hunt?
No, they communicate.
And we don't we don't know what they're doing.
We don't we don't know how they do it, but they decide.
Yeah. Yeah, there's something because they flank animals.
They know how to do it.
Like they know to chase animals into canyons.
And then they get on the other side of it
and they capture them when they're trying to escape.
It's still up.
I mean, one of the teachers that I've come to love so much
and she was also in England, she said that the first time
she realized something like this was going on.
She's working at a school where the individuals weren't speaking.
And she saw people of like a bunch of her class playing at recess.
And she's like, it was a fully orchestrated game.
Like this one need to go here and this one need to go here.
And they were doing this.
And she's like, but they weren't speaking.
And I was watching this through the classroom window.
And I thought they are communicating through telepathy
because how else do this is a huge organized game.
And she watched over and over again.
And then she thought in her head, like, I want to be in on this.
I want you all to teach me.
I want to get in on this.
And then one of the boys started, she'd start hearing him in her head,
like if he had fallen down outside or couldn't find his lunch money or,
you know, something happened, skinned his knee.
And she would hear him and like would know where to go find him.
And she was like, oh, my gosh, like he's this is starting to work.
And then, yeah.
And then like one of the students' mothers died.
And she became and the mother said to this teacher,
I want you to really take care of my son as he ages.
He loves you like he really respects you.
And she's done that his whole life.
And now, you know, he's a grown adult and they still communicate.
But she's like, now he communicates with me telepathically.
I'll get these huge visual packages.
And she's like, and sometimes I think first, did this come from me
and my making this up?
But it will be like an update on someone from, you know,
that they knew both 20 years ago.
And she'll be like, that can't be that this guy is suddenly a priest.
He was so unreligious or whatever it was.
There'll be something that makes no sense.
And she'll go look it up on Facebook and it proves to be true.
So, you know, she'll constantly have to double check things.
And she yeah, I mean, so it's it's remarkable.
But I do not doubt that the wolves are probably using telepathy.
Yeah, I think chimpanzees do it, too.
I think they all have roles and they know what role to play.
And they just sort of like lock in on this task together
and somehow or another communicate like they lay in wait.
They know when to wait. So weird. It's so cool.
Yeah, it's so cool. I mean.
Imagine if one day we can figure out through technology
to access minds of animals and see how an owl thinks,
like, see, like, what is what is the what's the process in their mind
when they lock on to what is a predator thing?
What is it? What is it?
Does a prey animal know when it's being watched?
Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, there's been that trust me.
I'm a hunter.
They don't always know.
They don't know at all.
No, sometimes they don't know at all.
That's so how far away are you when you're sometimes like 50, 60 yards
and they have no idea you're there. Wow.
And they're, you know, but a lot of times they're distracted
because they're in the rut.
So they're mating and they're distracted, which is a rude way to hunt them.
Yeah, that's that's how that's how people hunt.
Yeah, the worst way to hunt someone.
I mean, not always a lot of animals.
You got the music that are not in the rut.
But, you know, like white teal deer elk, primarily,
you hunt them when they're in the rut. Yeah.
There's some animals, though, that are very, very difficult to hunt.
And one of the reasons why is you don't hunt them when they're in the rut.
Like mule deer, mule deer are the most clever
and the most aware of all deer species
because they're constantly being pursued by mountain lions.
So they're always like, what the fuck is that?
They're like always on on edge and they have an uncanny ability
to get out of the way.
They just they they know something's there and they're like, fuck this.
And they just bounce out. Yeah.
Yeah, you got to sneak up on them when the wind's blowing.
You got to like like people take their shoes off to creep up on them.
So tactical. Yeah.
Well, you have to be. Yeah.
Because you have to especially bow hunting.
Yeah. So you have to get ideally you want to get within inside of 60 yards.
Yeah. That's really what you want.
Especially a mule deer is not that big.
An elk is a much larger target.
But a mule deer is, you know, a big one's like 300 pounds.
You've got to get pretty close.
And they fucking know something's up.
Yeah. You know, something's up. Yeah.
You know, sometimes you're staring at them and they're just like,
you know, they're just tuned in.
Yeah. There's also I don't know if this is real or not,
but there's a company called Hex and they make these
they make clothes that block out your electrical signal.
And one of the things like it's very hard to discern
whether or not it works with right with mammals.
But it seems to work really well with fish.
So there's a lot of video evidence of these people putting these
Hex suits on underneath their their wet gear or their scuba gear
and then going in the water and being able to get like right up close to fish.
They don't even know what the fuck is going on.
And they couldn't if they didn't have the suit on.
This is their assertion. OK.
Now, obviously, they're selling a product.
Yeah. Very controversial in the the hunting world,
whether or not these things are real.
Some people 100 percent believe in them.
And there's a bunch of evidence that people wear them.
And then they sit in a field and turkeys like get right next to them.
And turkeys have incredible vision.
Turkeys have better vision than humans.
Yeah. Huh. I'd like to know more about that.
Yeah. But the the really compelling stuff to me is the water stuff
because they do it in the water.
And the idea is that prey animals have this electrical
some sort of signal that they're giving off.
Yeah. These animals can pick up.
That's really interesting. I'd like to learn more about that.
That's fast. Well, fish have a thing called the lateral line.
You ever seen that line on the fish?
So that lateral line is interpreting movement in the water.
It's interpreting. So, yeah, a filmographer.
He says it lets them get closer to anything. Really? Yeah.
Well, it's just showing different.
So this is the problem is obviously this is a commercial. Right. Right.
And the problem is, you know, these people believe it.
And I don't know if they've done like,
how would you do a double blind study with this?
You know, would you you're you're dealing with?
Yeah. Completely different fish.
Completely different time. Yeah.
You know, there's a what did that fish experience?
Did that fish just experience a shark 30 minutes ago? Right.
What do you know what's going on?
Are they on edge? You have to do a bunch of them, I think.
You have to do it a lot. Yeah.
And I don't know if they've done that, because I think they're just trying
to sell this thing that may or may not work.
And it's because it blocks out your magnetic field.
Is that what they're saying? Supposedly.
What is what is their explanation for what it does?
Has something to do with measuring that?
Well, the human body is essentially an electrical system, right?
So it kind of makes sense that we would give off some sort of a
a visual representation or some senses that we don't understand.
This is electromagnetic patterns or OK.
So about that. Huh?
All right. What is it?
Google HEC suit debunked.
Oh, Google that HEC suit, HEC suit debunked.
I wonder if anybody's ever tried to debunk it and say that's nonsense.
Because I know a lot of people that don't think it's that works.
Yeah. They don't wear them.
But I know my friend John Dudley, who's one of the best hunters in the world.
He wears it every time he goes hunting. Really? Yeah. Fascinating.
He thinks animals can't see him as well when he wears it.
So interesting. I mean, if he believes it works and that's like, you know,
sometimes the the act of faith is more important than the fact of it.
All right. Sometimes. Maybe.
I don't know. No, I think the fact is more important,
because if you're doing both things, if you're doing
if you're you're doing everything correctly,
but one thing does give you like camouflage works.
We know it works because there's something about the way animals see.
They they essentially see movement and line detection.
So to see the frame of a human being clearly, if you're wearing black
and you're standing there and you're a bipedal thing, they're like, oh, fuck that.
That's person. Yeah. Let's get out of here.
But if your lines are completely broken up by camouflage
and you stand still, they don't see you.
They see nonsense.
They see the woods. Yeah. See, you know, you blend in. Yeah. Yeah.
And that's why camouflage doesn't have to look like leaves and sticks.
It can just look like patches of black and stripes and tiger stripes.
Right. It makes sense. Yeah. Yeah, it does. It does make sense.
I mean, that's why animals in nature have that. Yeah.
You know, I was watching this thing where they were explaining
what animals see versus what we see, why tigers would be so beautifully colored
because the animals don't see that color for whatever reason,
but they do see the lines and the lines completely blur in with the grass
because animals see in black and white. Right.
Or in a weird shade. Interesting.
Have you found anything about Hexsuit debunked?
Tons of anecdotal evidence.
Few videos, people, though.
A good point is like, how did Fred Bear do it?
How did he get so close to stuff?
That's just their example.
The old, you know, the original hunter. Right.
Those guys all wore like final shirts.
And they weren't doing odor blocking.
Yeah, that odor blocking shit doesn't work.
Yeah. And I have no real no one did like a study.
And by the way, if you have odor blocking, the animals smell the odor blocking.
And they're like, what the right?
Yes. Yeah, that was that was that stinky fucking weird smell.
There's no way we smell so bad.
Animals, there's no way they smell us like we smell skunk.
Yeah, that's so interesting.
Yeah. You know, you could smell skunk that gets killed like five blocks away.
That's how they smell us.
They know we're in the neighborhood. Yeah.
Yeah. So I don't think that scent stuff does anything.
I mean, maybe it blocks a little bit.
So maybe it helps a little bit.
Maybe. I mean, you're looking for every little edge
because you're essentially competing with the survival instincts
of something that has existed in that form for a thousand years or,
excuse me, a million years or more. Right.
You're walking into an environment you're supposed to lose.
And you're hunting an animal.
Yeah. The only reason why you win is because you have a bow and arrow. Right.
Or you have a rifle and you know which way the wind's blowing.
Yes. The big thing.
Yeah. It's like if you get winded, if they smell you, it's over.
Like the whole thing is the wind has to be in your face.
So if you're looking at the animal, the wind has to be coming in your direction.
If the wind hits the back of your neck, it's over.
You feel it. You're like, oh, shit.
Because they'll smell you instantly.
Oh, 100. They're like, what the fuck this?
And they're gone. Really? Instantaneously. Wow.
Yeah. That's 100 yards away.
They just start running. Really? Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
What if the wind was going like perpendicular?
No, it has to go to them. OK. Right.
That's why they always find themselves.
They always bed down in a position where the wind is coming straight to them
towards any threats. Yeah.
And then the the females will line up and look in the other way.
So they'll look towards the way where the wind is going. Yeah.
And then everyone will line out.
So the wind comes to them and then some will look in the opposite direction.
Wow. Yeah. And try to keep their eyes open.
But again, it's because they're dealing with cats.
It's a fascinating sport, though.
Yeah. It's just because it's so it's so I mean, it is so tactical,
not just like the physicality of it and the wind and the environment,
but just like the mental, you know, it's also bizarrely psychedelic
in this weird way.
When when you're there, the world doesn't exist.
And when you see these animals, you connect with them in some sort of a strange way.
And you're you're trying to, like, almost not exist.
You're trying to, like, give off nothing, which is what cats do
when you see them creeping up on things.
They're not like, oh, yeah, right.
Not rolling. Yeah. Like locked in.
Yeah. It's locked in almost like non-existent until they go.
And then the whole thing is like, I got to be able to move quicker
than you can run away. Right. Yeah.
That's such a weird sport. Yeah. It's a weird.
But it's whatever these animals are experiencing with each other
is probably some form of telepathy as well.
You know, how do they know, like how do wolves know to work together?
Is it just trial and error? Like, hmm.
It seems like they have roles that they like predetermined roles.
Like one of them will chase them down.
The other one will be laying in wait.
They do stuff together. They coordinate.
Yeah. Some strange way.
You had that wolf woman on your show, right?
And boy. Yeah. Fascinating.
Yeah. Yeah. So interesting. Yeah.
But she was most afraid of people.
Yeah. Yeah. Rightly so. Yeah.
How many people get killed by wolves every year versus people? Yeah.
Yeah. People are way creepier. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Wolves are just real.
I mean, clear, not simple, complex, obviously,
but clear in what they're trying to do.
They're trying to eat and survive.
And that's that's their job. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, this was a tangent, wasn't it? Yeah.
Yeah, we got a lot of tangents,
but that's the beauty of the human mind.
It is. I love that. It does go on tangents. Yes.
I think that we're we're all sort of trying to understand
why we view the world the way we do
and how much of that has been projected upon us by culture and society.
And how much of it is things we understand innately?
How much how many things we can't prove,
but that are a part of this world that we live in.
Right. And I think what your show has done with the telepathy tapes
and I'm sure what the documentary has done is I think more important
than anything, open up this possibility to be explored,
you know, and recognizing that it's real and that these preconceived notions
that we've held on to for so long are probably erroneous.
We probably have screwed ourselves by latching on to the idea that this is it.
Yeah. This is all that we have.
And this is the way to live life.
And, you know, put your suit on and go to work. Right.
Yeah. But a boring way to live life. Yeah. Gosh.
I can't imagine working in an office.
Yeah. I mean, I think it's a pendulum's shift.
I mean, the whole world is opening up right now. Right.
I mean, there's just like so much is happening, I think,
that people are challenging these preconceived old fat.
Oh, I might have some coffee now. Please do. Sorry.
No, I said no earlier. Now I'm now I'm into it. Cheers.
Cheers. Thanks for being here. Yeah.
I like your mug with a third eye. You can have it.
Really? OK, I'll bring it home. That's cool.
So I can't wait to taste your coffee. See how strong it is.
It's pretty good.
That's great. Shout out to Black. It's perfect.
Yeah, it's good. It's great.
So what is your hope for this stuff?
Like in your most ideal scenario?
How you're you're obviously your show has been received
in a tremendously positive way and people are super intrigued
and really popular. So that's great.
So so more more discussion.
But what would like in an ideal scenario, what would you like to happen?
OK, I think there's three things, right?
I think for one, like baseline for people to presume competence
and non-speaking individuals or someone who can't control their body
don't think just because they can't speak doesn't mean they can't think.
You know, yeah, they're in there. Right.
And then I think the second one is certainly to try to get spelling
validated and in schools, right?
Like it's almost like telepathy in a way operated as a Trojan horse
to get people to acknowledge and notice these incredible individuals
and just take note and help them.
So I think getting spelling validated and affirmed
and make it accessible in schools, that would be the next thing.
And then I think the third thing is, I mean, truly a paradigm shift.
I mean, I want people to know,
because I've come to what I feel like is believe this, right?
That there is a non-physical world that's real.
Our idea that consciousness is at the tippy top.
That's the result of this physical world, I think, is incorrect.
I think consciousness is at the bottom of it and started everything.
And with that in mind, consciousness, then we're so much more possible.
It can survive our body.
We can communicate without our bodies.
We can see into the future, maybe into the past.
I mean, whatever it is, anything mental we're capable of.
And that helps us explain a lot more.
So the paradigm shift, I think, is really cool
if it can happen.
And a lot of people have been working toward that, you know?
I mean, so I'm just like a tiny bit in a large puzzle of huge giants
have come before me. But I think that
that if this is going to help more people like just be aware of the system
of what is called, again, like this materialism,
which is the idea that it's only what's real can be observed and measured.
If we can get people to realize they're living in that system,
that system was constructed and it's not necessarily the truth.
So don't be embarrassed to talk about stuff, to research stuff, to ask a question.
You shouldn't be ridiculed and dismissed just because the system
tells you you should be.
That concept is just so hard to grasp.
If you've not if you haven't read any of Tom Campbell's stuff
or haven't considered this or listen to Rupert Sheldrake talk or your show,
it's like it's so hard for people to grasp that.
Yeah. Tom Campbell blew my mind.
I mean, he is like, yeah, I got a lot of text messages from buddies after that.
What the fuck, dude? Yeah, I'm so confused. Yeah.
But this is what I will say, because I actually had a friend
that when I was sort of like going through my own thing,
she was just like, just if you just start reading about some of the stuff,
just reading it, you'll find what you're looking for.
Like there's so much there, whether if you start reading about near
death experiences or Ian Stevenson or Tom Campbell and any of this stuff,
it's just like and the people are researching this. Right.
Yeah. It's not like this just happened.
This has been going on for a long time. These questions.
So once the documentary is out, what do you hope to do next?
Do you have a game plan?
So we just started working on the doc.
I'm hoping that will be done and wrapped up early next year.
Maybe we'll premiere at South by we'll be back, hopefully.
I mean, who knows?
And so so after that, then we're going to do an impact campaign
where you take a documentary around and you screen it with a panel.
So that'd be cool. It'd be non-speakers.
And, you know, we can get people from the Department of Education there
or whatever in different cities.
And then hopefully that will make an impact at people into the rooms
talking to whatever.
And then after that, we have a really long term goal
where we want to try to work with like a few foundations
or maybe start a foundation to open centers that can.
If you can imagine something
maybe like kind of like the size of an REI in every city
where non-speakers can go and get like physical and mental
and spiritual supports and spelling help and education or whatever.
You know, there's physical therapy that can help.
And for respite care for these parents who are working 24 seven
to take care of these individuals.
And it could just be a beautiful thing.
But then there's so many academics to what you kind of noted earlier,
like that might want to work with non-speakers who might want to.
Can can you help me decode whale language
or figure out how to stop blanching the coral reefs or whatever?
So if there's, you know, I know non-speakers
who want to work in plant medicine, who want to work in this,
who want to work in X, Y, Z.
But I think the most important thing is these centers
maybe could vet those individuals, make sure these academics
learn to become a spelling, to communicate partner and and be
background check to make sure they don't have some nefarious goal.
And then this could maybe create opportunities for spellers to make money,
to have a career, to really contribute in these meaningful ways.
So that's our goal is to create these like centers that can both nourish
and support non-speakers and their families, but also allow non-speakers
to engage and use their intellect and abilities to have like meaningful careers.
That and more.
Right. More, more people coming out, more people understanding it,
more people grasping it, more people accepting.
And then this sort of changes.
The level of cynicism, so it changes the level of negativity
and it opens up the acceptance of this stuff.
And then maybe we learn more.
Yeah. Yeah.
And it's just in history, too, people would look at deaf people
or blind people before and think they're not in there, especially deaf people.
It was just like, oh, they must not be in there.
No one thinks that anymore. It's ridiculous to think that. Right. Right.
You know, but we're doing the same thing to this population.
So, yeah, I mean,
there are some of the most brilliant individuals that I've ever met.
And actually, I talked to a teacher right before I left here today.
And I said she was talking about her student.
She just had a conversation with who she said in middle school or whatever,
high school, what did you learn that whole time?
What did you learn in school?
Well, he was being taught like he was little.
And what he answered was patience.
I mean, just so beautiful, so wise. Right.
He wasn't crapping on it like I learned nothing.
They kept telling me animal colors and this and whatever.
Like it wasn't anger. It was I learned patience.
Because us, you know, our stupid system that has made these individuals out
to be like they're not smart. Right.
Has taught them, has failed them when it comes to education.
So I just thought that was a beautiful answer.
And so so in line with how wise and kind and thoughtful so many non-speakers
I've met are. Yeah, it's a beautiful answer.
That's a good way to wrap this up.
Thank you very much for being here.
And thank you very much for your series.
It's really incredible.
And I can't wait to watch the documentary.
And I'd love to have you back on when whenever it releases.
Yeah, wonderful. I'll bring some parents with me.
I'll bring a non-speaker with so you can see it.
OK, I'm going to bring Katie in Houston and your mind.
OK, OK, let's do it. Let's do it.
All right. Telepathy tapes.
It's available basically everywhere.
Spotify, Apple, whatever. Right.
Wherever you get your podcast, you get your podcast.
It's really incredible. I loved it.
All right. That's it. Thank you. Thank you, Joe.
Thank you. Bye, everybody.