The Joe Rogan Experience, trained by day, Joe Rogan podcast by night, all day.
What's up, Luke?
How are you?
Hey, sir, I'm doing better than I deserve.
Well, that's a good statement.
There's an old military saying any day above ground is a good day.
There you go.
So tell everybody what your official job was.
Wow.
I had a lot of official jobs.
With the government in regards to, you know, you know, you know, sure.
Well, these things, that's a allegedly that's a replica of the one that Bob
Lazar worked on the sport model.
I've heard that before.
Designs by Perry, the E in Perry is a three and he's a dude on Instagram
that sent me that.
Very cool. Pretty dope, right?
Yeah.
Well, another one that looks just like it at the mothership at the Comedy Club.
When you walk in, you walk right through like a giant suspended UFO.
Very cool. So obviously I have issues.
Well, you know what? This is a neat town.
I was strolling the streets yesterday and I came across the the Texas Toy Museum.
Now, I'm not one for museums usually, but something I saw was
automatically transported me back to when I was a kid.
I'm an old guy, so I grew up 70s and early 50 to.
I'm 57. You are. Yeah.
Man. Well, I look 10 years older than you.
I got a lot of a lot of long, hard miles on me, unfortunately.
I do, too. Believe it or not.
Well, you'll have to share with me your secret,
because unfortunately, I tell people this is as good as it gets.
I'm about as attractive as a cement truck.
You know, so so I after the army,
I went into the federal service and had a lot of jobs,
mostly in counterintelligence and which is looking basically
what the bad guys know about us from an intelligence perspective.
And in 2008, I changed my job.
One of my jobs, I was working at the director of national intelligence,
which for most people may or may not know.
It's kind of outside of D.C.
and where I lived, I was on the other side of D.C.
living on a little island in the Chesapeake Bay.
And so my commute was terrible.
I mean, it really, really frankly took a ferry every day.
No, but it was about a three hour commute each way.
You have to go right past Langley.
Yeah, it was. Why didn't you move closer?
Well, you know, I wanted to I wanted to give my kids a really good quality of life.
And I did not want to work in the city and then kind of expose them
to kind of the craziness, if that makes sense, especially D.C.
D.C. is crazy, especially with kids. Right.
Yeah. And kind of nuts that they don't clean up the capital of the fucking country.
It seems like, you know, brother, it's kind of indicative of the rot.
The whole country is such a disgrace because you bring these foreign dignitaries
and the first thing they see is is just the dereliction of it.
And it's a very poor reflection on really what the American spirit is about.
But, you know, that's that's for another conversation.
Yeah, it seems like they could fix that.
Yeah, especially in that place.
Yeah. One would hope, right?
Yeah. Jesus Christ. It's the nation's capital. Yeah.
So I was offered a job to go back to the Pentagon in 2008
for a little while and basically run the the integration
between national level intelligence information and local and state
and tribal law enforcement.
So after 9-11, the country realized that we had a significant problem
getting national level information down to to the cops on the ground
that could actually do something about it.
Why? Because he didn't have security clearances.
So they couldn't they weren't allowed to be provided that information.
So one of my jobs was to try to help fix that.
And shortly thereafter, I got there in 2008.
It was probably early 2009 is when I was approached by two individuals
who came to me and they said, look, we'd like to consider you for
for for a program that we're part of.
It's a very nuanced program, very secretive program.
Now, when you're in the government, you hear that all the time.
It's not, you know, people look at maybe, oh, you have a secret clearance
or a top secret clearance.
Millions of people have have some sort of security clearance in the government.
And a lot, a lot of people have a top secret clearance.
So it's really not that uncommon. It's really not that sexy.
It's just so you didn't really know what you're getting involved in.
I didn't at all. Not at all. In fact.
So, yeah, great question.
So, no, I didn't know what I was getting involved in.
And after several conversations, it occurred to me that their interest in me
was some of my background I had in my early career as a special agent
in counterintelligence.
I was protecting technologies, critical technologies, critical avionic technologies.
For example, and some aerospace technology.
So think of first stage solid rocket motor booster technology,
Tomahawk cruise missiles, stuff like that, Apache Longbow.
So advanced avionics was something I was kind of already form
kind of familiar with.
And at the same time, I had the counterintelligence background.
So I was asked to come in and run the counterintelligence and security aspect
for a particular program, at which time I had no idea what the program even was.
So what does counterintelligence and security mean?
It just simply means making sure that our adversaries like Russia and China
can't penetrate our organization and steal our secret.
That's all it is. It's kind of a fancy word for just saying security,
information security and operational security.
So I remember I had a meeting.
They brought me to go see their director.
And it was in a in I would tell you the location,
but I was told by the Pentagon not to say the specific location of this office.
But it was somewhere in the D.C. area.
It was a facility that wasn't known publicly to be a an intelligence
to have an intelligence office in there.
So I can't say that the specific location.
But I went there and I went up to the to the top floor.
I think it was the top floor, almost the top floor.
And I met for the first time a gentleman named James Lukatsky,
Dr. James Lukatsky, Ph.D.
And this guy was the epitome of a rocket scientist.
And when I say the epitome, I mean, he was probably and there's no exaggeration,
the number one rocket scientist in the U.S. government.
Now, he's a humble guy, so he'll probably tell you he wasn't.
But he really was an amazing human being and very smart.
And after a very brief conversation, he looked at me and he said,
I want to ask you a question.
OK, sir. And he said, what do you think about UFOs?
I said, well, I answer truthfully, I said, I don't.
And he said, well, what do you mean, you don't believe in them?
And I said, no, that's not what I said.
You asked me if I think, you know, what do I think about UFOs?
And frankly, I don't think about UFOs.
I really don't have the luxury to think about them.
I'm too busy, you know, working intelligence operations and whatnot.
And I remember him looking over his glasses and
very seriously staring me straight in the eye and says, well,
don't let your personal bias
get the best of you, because what you may learn may surprise you
and may challenge any preconceived notion of what you think
something is or is not.
And so let me backtrack for a minute.
I've never been a UFO guy.
People come up, oh, you're that UFO guy.
I'm really not. I was never really into science fiction as a kid.
I wasn't into the Star Trek or the Star Wars like a lot of people were.
So that was not my disposition.
You know, I grew up, I guess, playing GI Joe and stuff like that.
So that wasn't that wasn't my background.
And certainly in college, I I studied microbiology
and immunology with a focus on parasitology, not parapsychology,
the study of parasites, parasitology.
So the scientific method has always been something that has been near
and dear to me. And then, of course, later on, as a as a special agent,
you know, that when you're when you're conducting investigations,
for me, I was always very fact driven, kind of the old gum shoe,
if you will, just the facts, ma'am, sort of guy.
So I was never really prone to any type of,
if you will, affinity towards science fiction or even the UFO topic.
I just I just never really considered it.
Hmm. So he says this to you.
And then so we're talking about like, what, 16 years ago?
15, 16 years ago. Yeah, I do the math, right.
So it's 2024, 2000, early 2009.
So this is the beginning of your journey
towards this sort of bizarre subject of whatever these things are.
Yeah. So you don't have any real previous interest.
He says this to you.
And and then what's the steps after that?
Like, how do you get introduced to this idea that these things are alien crafts?
Yeah. So great question.
So for some people, there's this kind of two ways people process this information,
at least in my experience, and there may be others.
This has just been my my observation.
Some people have this kind of revelatory moment, this epiphany,
where it's this aha moment, where, oh, my gosh, this is real. Right.
Hmm. For other people, it's kind of more of a slow, gradual realization.
And I think for me, I was probably in the second category,
more of a slow, gradual realization that this isn't, you know, a cover for something else.
This is really about UFOs.
So how do you first get introduced to these things?
Well, so it was I didn't get introduced to these things.
It was first of all, I was introduced to the reporting. Right.
So there was these these official reports that we were getting from the field.
There's official videos and whatnot that describe vehicles
doing things, maneuvering in ways that frankly outperform anything
we have in our inventory.
Now, keep in mind, my background was at some point in aerospace.
So I knew all the capabilities of an F-16 or, for example,
an F-22 or the F-35.
And at the end of the day, as advanced as they are, they're still conventional aircraft.
You know, they still have the old.
There's a there's an adage they use for jet engines.
It may seem a little awkward here, but it's suck, squeeze, bang and blow.
That's what a jet engine does.
Forgive me. That's what it does.
Right. Yeah.
It's a convention, a conventional type engine.
Of course, you have a propeller too that can can displace air and whatnot.
These vehicles are different.
These vehicles, for the most part, didn't have any type of associated
characteristic that you or I or any normal person would associate
with with the plane, with an airplane aircraft. Right.
But and yet it's flying. So how does an airplane work?
Well, let's say this cigar, for example, is an airplane
and there's four fundamental forces.
And so you have thrust, lift, drag and weight.
And if you understand those, you can create, build wings
and you create lift and you can fly.
And then you have to have an engine for that thrust and whatnot.
The things that our military pilots were encountering
didn't have that. They didn't have wings.
They didn't have rudders and ailerons and control surfaces.
They didn't have cockpits.
They didn't have engines and no obvious signs of propulsion.
They were they were doing things and maneuvering in ways that frankly
defied anything that that we had in our inventory.
And we were pretty certain the enemies didn't have either.
Our adversary didn't have these technologies either.
And even more perplexing is that they were being encountered
over controlled U.S. airspace and over sensitive military installations.
So, you know, from that perspective, you've got a real
you've got a real national security concern on your hands.
So you said video.
What was the do you remember the first thing that you saw?
Boy, there's so many.
You know, I think part of the challenge is that most people here in this country,
they're familiar with the three videos, right,
that have been famously released by the Pentagon.
The go fast, go fast, gimbal, FLIR. Correct. Right.
But those are those are the least compelling of all the videos
that the government has. Those were unclassified.
And so those were the ones
which are kind of the low hanging fruit that could be released to the general public.
There's stuff out there that's like 4K ultra high definition. Right.
So when you see something like that from a certain military platform
or a certain military equity or an intelligence collection platform,
you have to look at that and say, well, what what is that?
What the hell is that?
More importantly, that data is being backed up by radar data. Right.
So you've got you've got electro optical data like gun camera footage
or pod or FLIR FLIR video.
And then you've got radar data that's that's that is actually
confirming what the video is picking up.
And then you've got eyewitnesses that are also watching it. Right.
So you've got trained, trained observers, pilots that that can recognize
the silhouette between an SU-22 and a MIG-25 from 20 miles away
and make a split second decision.
Is it friend or foe? Do I kill it or is it do I let it live?
And they're reporting it.
So you have now, you know, three separate, if you will,
collection platforms that the human eye being one of them,
you've got gun camera footage and you've got radar footage
all describing the same event at the same place at the same time.
Under the same circumstances. Right.
And so keep in mind with my background as a former special agent
and counterintelligence, if this was in front of a jury,
you know, as I've said before, I think we're well beyond reasonable doubt.
That's that is something there.
I mean, that is real. That's not an atmospheric aberration.
It's not a, you know, anomaly.
That is that is something there. It's tangible.
So was there an aha moment for you?
Like the first thing that you saw that you looked at and you go,
what the fuck?
No, like I said, for me, it was more slow and gradual.
I didn't. What was the first thing that you saw that made you realize
that there's something going on here that defies conventional wisdom
or conventional understanding of propulsion systems?
I think for me, one of the most compelling moments was when I attended.
Boy, let me go back in memory banks.
I attended a dinner with some individuals
who were already associated with the larger umbrella program called ASAP.
And I attended dinner at a Washington, D.C.
hotel and a Brazilian general attended this this dinner.
And the dinner was sponsored by a gentleman named Robert Bigelow,
the famous billionaire hotel. Yeah, I've met him.
Yeah, I met him on the podcast. Yeah.
And by the way, he's he's an American hero. He's a patriot.
He's really he is brilliant.
And he's and people don't realize that he funded,
self-funded a lot of this stuff on behalf of the U.S.
government for by himself.
Like he paid it to do it himself.
He really is a, you know, an American patriot, in my opinion.
But anyways, he flew in this guy named General Uchoa.
General Uchoa was a Brazilian general,
very, very senior in the Brazilian government who led an investigation
about a an event that occurred over several days.
Is this the Varginha incident?
No, it's actually called Colares in Brazil.
Yeah. And the Colares incident.
And they had an overwhelming number of eyewitnesses.
And there was even some some video and photographs
that they had produced internally there to Brazil.
And it was overwhelming, the evidence.
And for me, that was it was more listening to him
and explain the concern they had and some of the interactions
the the Brazilian government officials had with these UAP that really
I left there that that dinner scratching my head and really
at that point beginning to absorb the profoundness that we're
dealing with something that like is real.
This is not a cover plan for some other technology we're trying to protect.
Did he show you this video evidence?
So he was it was I was sitting at the kind of like a table like this.
There was a whole lot of people at the table.
He was sitting at the head.
That was kind of way down over here.
And he brought a manila envelope and he was showing photographs to everybody.
Right. And some reporting as well.
I think he brought, if I recall correctly, his daughter to translate
because I don't think English was very good.
It wasn't his language.
But for me, that was and I think for one of my colleagues, too,
which I probably can't say his name right now because he hasn't come out publicly yet.
But we both left that dinner.
I think scratching our heads and saying, wow, this is so this is legit.
This is real. The US government is interested in this.
And there is interest by our government
as after that dinner, attending more meetings and beginning to read the reports,
the field reports and speaking to the scientists.
It became evident to me that this was a very serious issue.
We had near misses over some of our our our areas of operation.
In some cases, literally these these UAP splitting a combat formation.
Now, if you know how planes fly, they fly very close in a combat situation.
These things were splitting the formation, right?
That that there were reports being being provided through the Air Force,
mostly through the Navy, about air safety issues
where pilots literally could run into these things.
Right. They're they're they're pervasive.
It wasn't like a onesie and twosies.
Was there ever an incident where a pilot or a jet did run into something?
Not that I'm aware of what I can tell you, that there has been incidents
where there appears to be some sort of provocation, where
one of these things seems to be coming deliberately close to an aircraft,
not necessarily trying to hit it,
but maybe trying to demonstrate performance capabilities.
There was one video in particular
having been cleared by the Pentagon.
So let me see if I can speak about it in general terms.
There's a pilot flying and a a a you can hear on the radio
this chatter back and forth.
Do you see it? You have eyes down on it.
Pilot. Nope. Negative. No eyes down.
OK, you should have on a radar.
Yeah, I got something on radar, but no eyes.
And I can't see it.
And then all of a sudden, a craft,
an object goes whizzing right by the cockpit.
And I mean, probably like 15 feet away.
And you can hear the pilot, the expletives of the pilot.
You know, I won't see it here on air, but you can imagine, right,
what what a pilot would say when they're very, very surprised.
That was one there.
Can you describe what he saw?
I think I can. I want to be careful that I don't,
because, again, I haven't had what I what I have approval to talk about.
I've I've spoken about.
Let me preface by saying I still have my security clearance.
And on occasion, I still will consult for the U.S. government.
And so I want to be very mindful.
I have no problem going up all the way to the line. Right. Understood.
But if I put up, you know, a pinky toe over that line, they're right.
Right. Right. Of course.
But it was a wedge shaped craft, wedge shaped, wedge shaped
like triangular, but
you know, like a wedge, like I don't know how to describe it.
I could draw it for you if you want to draw it. Sure. You can. Yeah.
So just like a wedge that you would like split wood with,
like that kind of a wedge.
Yeah. But it was it was silver metallic and like a like a diamond.
Maybe that's a better way to describe it, like a diamond almost.
And it looked kind of like it looked kind of like that.
Really is just a just a little.
And that that kind of shape is something that's been reported multiple times.
So that was the first time I ever saw something like that.
To me, it was keep in mind, I never followed this topic.
So every time I'm seeing one of these videos,
I'm kind of seeing something for the very first time.
So lenticular, whether it's a disc shaped craft or it's it's a wedge shaped craft
or a diamond shaped craft or triangle shaped craft boomerang in some cases.
These were all new to me.
So it was very, very perplexing.
And obviously, to our military pilots, it was very concerning.
And I think when you when you look at some of the gold standard cases
we had, like the Nimitz, for example, that that that case,
you know, you have this overwhelming number of sensors
looking at the same thing going on that the pilots are reporting.
And for me, that was most compelling, like I said, more than
eyewitness testimony is important.
But at the end of the day, you know, grandma seeing some lights in her
backyard doesn't really do it for me.
You know, I'm a fact oriented kind of guy.
I've got to see the data, let the data.
Provide us the information we need so then we can make a conclusion, right?
I'm not, you know, if you start seeing UFOs in the sky everywhere,
well, chances are they're probably not, you know, it was a quadcopter,
it's a balloon, it's an aircraft, it could be all sorts of things.
That's why I think from our perspective, having the fundamental categories,
the observables, we call them, was so important because they are so beyond
what what a normal aircraft, a traditional conventional aircraft can do.
At that point, you realize you're dealing with some some sort of beyond
next generation technology.
And that's when it gets compelling for guys like me. Right. Right.
When you're when you're seeing when you're seeing performance
capabilities that far exceed far surpass anything we have.
And I'm talking even the very, very best technology we have.
We don't come close to that.
And no visible means of propulsion.
No, or obvious signs of lift. Right.
And not even a cockpit.
You have to scratch your head and see what's going on.
Interestingly, I'll share. So no windows. No windows.
Well, in some cases, no windows.
Other cases, people will report what they think are windows.
They say, oh, I saw windows.
But at the end of the day, you know, we're we're we're looking
that in terms of what we think a window is. Right.
You see a car, you see windows or those are windows.
I didn't see any information to suggest that there were actually windows,
even though an eyewitness might describe a window,
because we are describing in something of something that we recognize. Right.
And so we say, oh, that might be a window or not.
But it might not be a window.
And so I want to be very careful to to say there were no windows.
There could have been.
But the ones that I was privy to that I saw, I didn't see any obvious
signs of like a windshield or a window.
I didn't see anything like that.
I saw vehicles that were doing things that were
were just left you scratching your head.
And they were real, like I said, because you're
backing it up with all this other sensor data.
And some of the best sophisticated sensor data, by the way,
at the time on the planet that we had, right, like the spy one radar
and the two Hawkeye and some of the other radar capabilities
and technical capabilities that other intelligence agencies have
that I can't discuss here.
You know, that this is the stuff that that helps us put.
Forgive the analogy here.
But warheads on foreheads.
We when we're going to take a strike against a terrorist,
these are the same sensor systems we use to to to prosecute that war,
that that that act both in combat and not in combat.
So yeah, that's that for me was was was very compelling.
And it's lots and lots of videos.
People think that there's only three videos there.
There's those are those those don't even scratch the surface.
There are hundreds and hundreds of videos that that the intelligence
community and the Department of Defense have on these things.
Has there ever been any discussion about releasing any of these?
I don't want to speak on behalf of the government. I
colleagues of mine, like Chris Mellon, who have been very, very, very active
in this topic and have actually been responsible for a lot of what we see
now happening in Congress, has been championing that.
He is the one who says, look, we need more videos to come out
so the American people can see for themselves what we've been dealing with.
When I had Chris Mellon in the Pentagon, he saw those videos.
And up to that point, he you know, he had been when he was a senior person
at the Pentagon, like very senior, one of his jobs as the senior intelligence
official, he asked, hey, do we have any UAP UFO videos, investigations,
anything like that? And he told him no.
So when he came to the Pentagon and saw what we actually did have,
you can imagine someone like Chris Mellon, right?
He wasn't very happy.
He was he was actually pretty, pretty disappointed saying, why?
Why was I told, no, I can I can see these videos clearly.
I see the reports there.
Clearly, this is something that we're interested in as a Department of Defense.
And yet when I was one of the senior guys, he got the Heisman, right?
He was he was being told no.
And so that's that was, I think, a point for him that really
that's probably the I don't want to speak for my friend, Chris, but I suspect
that was probably the spark that got him to the point where he said, OK,
we have to do something about this.
This is this is this is BS.
Yeah. When I was talking to him, it seemed like that was his perspective,
that this was something that really should be,
and at least in some way, shape or form, released to the general public,
just to solidify the conversation, just to let people know like these are real.
This is a real thing.
These are not just if you've seen the one that people were filming
just a couple of days ago in Palmdale, California.
Yeah, I think they said those were drones.
So if I'm not mistaken, I think the jury came out.
If I'm not mistaken, I could be wrong
that it was a it was somebody using drones with some LED lights,
which, by the way, wild things with drones.
Now, you absolutely can create images in the sky.
One hundred percent dragons and stuff with.
Yeah, absolutely.
So, you know, we have to be careful as our own technology begins to advance.
There's going to be pranksters out there, you know,
and that's one of the things that for me in ATIP,
I always went into an investigation or a case
assuming that it was manmade, right?
And until I saw the compelling data that said otherwise,
we were always going to assume or presume that this was something
that was conventional.
It was probably misidentified, but it wasn't it wasn't exotic.
And then once the data suggests otherwise,
then you kind of go into that that that other motive.
OK, now what what are we dealing with again,
especially on the backdrop of the five performance
observables?
That's when you start to say, OK, yeah, this is this is not a
this is not an F-16.
You know, this is not a this is not a Chinese aircraft.
This is this is something different. Right.
What is the oldest video footage or film footage
that you have ever seen or heard civilian or military?
Because what is the oldest where it's like, OK, what the fuck is this?
What's the oldest stuff that's compelling?
Because the point is what I'm trying to get at is a lot of people
point to the possibility that there's some sort of a secret program,
some sort of secret propulsion, gravity based, whatever it is,
that's completely different than conventional propulsion systems
that the U.S. government has and that they're operating these drones.
And the problem with that is always the like
the Kenneth Arnold sightings, the Roswell, the sightings
from a time where that technology just wasn't available at all.
Joe, I'm so glad you asked me that question.
It just so happens I brought you something. Oh.
And glasses come out, you know, serious.
No, it just means it means I'm old to.
Yeah, I'm going to provide you a document here.
It's a it's a short document.
But the portions, I think, are highlighted
that you're going to want to pay attention to.
And let's see here. OK.
So if this is just for you and if your audience is interested,
it's this paragraph here you're going to want to read.
And then it's the last one that's highlighted.
And then take a look at the date and the subject line.
This is it right here. Jamie brought it up here. Oh, great.
Yeah. So which one paragraph six right now.
So if you want to scroll down to paragraph six. OK.
This summary of observations of aerial phenomenon has been prepared
for the purpose of reemphasizing and reiterating the fact that the phenomena
have continuously occurred in the New Mexico skies
during the past 18 months and are continuing to occur.
And secondly, that these phenomena are occurring
in the vicinity of sensitive military and government installations.
And if you want to go back to like paragraph two, there you go.
The highlighted part. Yeah.
The observers of the observers of those phenomenon include scientists,
special agents of the Office of Special Investigations,
the US Air Force, airline pilots, military pilots,
Los Alamos security inspectors, military personnel
and many other persons of various occupations
whose reliability is not questioned.
And now scroll to the top of the very top of that document.
And it says that it was determined that above that,
the summary of observations of aerial phenomenon in the New Mexico area,
December 1948 to May 1950.
And the date of that document, if you scroll a little bit higher,
you are going to see the date of that memo.
Oh, 1950. Yes, sir. May 25th, 1950.
It says that the it was determined that the frequency of unexplained
aerial phenomena in the New Mexico area was such that an organized plan of.
Reporting these observations should be undertaken. Right.
So this is the beginning of Project Blue Book.
So this is the the recognition
that we have a serious problem over our sensitive military installations.
This is nothing new.
This is not 1970s reverse engineered technology
or some sort of special to 1950.
They're talking about we had just broken the sound barrier
and we had not yet entered into space.
And we have these things that are performing in ways that, frankly,
we can't replicate.
I brought a few more of these later on to emphasize that point.
You just brought up at some point, if you're interested. Yeah.
But it highlights that these are official government documents
through official government personnel
raising the alarm bells, just like we did in ASAP and ATIPS.
And so this is nothing new.
Now, if you want to look at this from an adversarial perspective,
let's our governors already said that's not ours. Right.
If you look at a 1950s saber jet, for example,
it wasn't even supersonic.
And yet these things that we are observing in some cases are doing
about some more documents here, multiples of of mock
at doing velocities and doing things that we frankly could not do back then.
And frankly, we still can't do in some cases.
But temporarily speaking, the only two countries in the world
may may have a chance of doing something like that would be Russia and China.
And now in 1950, where was China was in the middle of a famine
at the time. And where was Russia?
Russia was trying to develop the atomic bomb
and still was using horse drawn carts for a lot of their military operations.
So temporally speaking, it doesn't make sense.
This is this is the analogy I've used before, Joe, that it would be like
Sir Carter going into King Tut's tomb for the very first time in the 1920s,
discovering King Tut's tomb.
And when he goes in, he finds a fully assembled 747 jet.
It doesn't make sense.
Temporarily speaking, they did not have that technology.
So is it possible, and I'll be very careful what I say,
that the U.S. government has some sort of exotic technology?
Well, my answer is I sure hope so, because, you know, we want to have
an advantage over our adversaries.
But in 1950, that wasn't the case. Right.
And do they have any film of these crafts from New Mexico?
There is film of many craft and not just New Mexico per se,
but over many military installations here.
I got another one for you. I'll provide you.
You don't have to waste your time reading it.
But the I think you'll appreciate this.
Take a look at the date of this and who it's to and who it's from.
And I think you'll find the subject line very interesting.
OK, which one? What part of my reading here?
Just to highlight a portion.
So you can see the top of the document, who it's from, who it's to in the date
and what the subject line is.
Director of Special Investigate.
What does it say? It's hard because it's all scratchy.
Yeah, it's an old reproduction of official government document.
Bottom line, it's a it's a document from J. Edgar Hoover.
Oh, I see.
From the director of the FBI Department of the Air Force, the Pentagon.
Yeah, J. Edgar Hoover, director of Federal Bureau of Investigations.
And the subject read the subject line of that memo.
Flying. God, it's good.
It's hard to read because it's all screwy.
Flying disks, I should say, flying disks over the savanna.
It's a there's a sensitive facility that we had where we were doing atomic
development. Yeah.
Flying disks reportedly seen in the vicinity of something.
River plant, savanna, river plant. Yes, sir. OK, that's correct.
And so that's atomic energy. Yeah.
And the date of that being, you know, 1952. Right.
So so so this is an this is verified.
This is that was released by the government.
That is a those are all official.
All these are official U.S.
government documentation that anybody can pull up any time they want.
Did they let you see any of these ancient films, these films from the 1950s
of these things? So great question.
Our focus was really more modern time.
It was more like a picture of where we are now.
I mean, wouldn't you want to just like if you if you really think this thing
is from somewhere else, the best example of it definitely not being ours
is something from the 1950s. Sure.
And anecdotally, that that's that's great.
But keep in mind on the backdrop of national security,
when you go to a general and you clean this up, by the way, crazy.
It's like half the things blotted out and scratching.
Yeah, that's Uncle Sam for you.
You know, when you go to a general or it makes me suspicious.
No, you can find that. I know, I know, I know.
But it was just like, yeah, the government released that.
I mean, they they admit that that's fucking shitty old 1920 fax machine.
Look at that. Well, they remember they were using typewriters back then, too.
Right. And ink smears.
Yeah, blotchy.
And I'm sure the original is probably much, much cleaner.
But that's what the government put out online for people to review.
So when you're going back to your quite answer your question,
when you are going to a general or you're going to a military leader
about this topic, if you go back to anecdotal stuff like, oh,
this is something from 1950s, they're not interested.
They're like, look, what is going on now? Right.
What is what is the threat now?
I've got a carrier strike group out in the water.
I'm getting reports.
These things are coming in and interrogating the ship.
You know what? I want to see that.
I want to see the videos. I want to see the reporting.
I want to see the deck logs and what the commander says.
And I want to know the pilots.
I want to talk to the pilots, the radar operators. Right.
That's their focus. They're not interested.
And by the way, we've tried a few times.
And the further back in time we go, the less interested they were.
So it was really interesting.
Yeah. It was really the current information.
What's going on now? I'm not interested in what happened.
They're just taking a pragmatic approach. Yeah.
Yeah. And it's you know, it's understandable.
From a military perspective, a national security perspective,
the other stuff is interesting.
And from the general public's perspective, you know, they're interested.
But from a national security perspective, they're like, hey, man,
that was three decades ago. Right.
Makes sense. I need I need now.
So it is understandable.
A little frustrating because you want to you want to demonstrate.
Look, boss, this is this is nothing new, right?
This is this is a repeated pattern that we're seeing here.
But they're more interested in the here and now.
So do they have repeated footage because you're seeing three decades?
But obviously, we're talking about 1950.
Do they have stuff from the 1980s or from the 1990s?
There was reporting. Yeah.
And again, I got to be careful because some of that stuff
I haven't been clear to talk about.
But there there are reports
we call foreign intelligence, FI, foreign intelligence reports.
I can't say where or who or anything like that.
But on classified systems where we know without a shadow of a doubt,
UAPs were encountered in other countries, adversarial countries.
Why? Because we spy on them and we know.
Again, I can't say how we know and whatnot.
I understand trouble, but just so we know this is not a United States phenomenon.
Precisely. It is not a US only phenomenon.
And in fact, in other countries, whether it's in Latin America,
South America or in Europe or Russia and China,
there is an extreme interest in this topic.
In fact, the Chinese was in the newspaper.
I think it was a China Morning Sun.
There's something called the Five Continents Initiative,
where allegedly they were trying to broker a deal with the United Nations
that would allow China to run all the UFO investigations for the United Nations.
So we also know that Russia, they've come out and said,
yeah, we're interested in this topic.
There were some released old KGB footage that showed
MIG interactions with these UAP.
And there's also in Latin America, you have the same thing.
If you go to Latin America now, they don't have the same level of stigma
and taboo associated with this topic like we do.
And so they talk freely about it.
They have no problem talking.
In fact, when I was in in the Patagonia area of Argentina,
there is a near town called Bariloche and Las Lajas.
One of the chief of police was telling me they have there's an area
there called La Miranda.
La Miranda means to see, to view.
And they call it that the town.
And because UAP are so frequent there,
that local law enforcement actually built an observatory,
an observation post to look at these things,
because they were so frequent.
So this is not a new phenomenon.
This is something that's been around for quite a long time.
The problem is, in my opinion, and I could be wrong, but this is my assessment.
The reason why it's so difficult to have the conversation here
is because our government had placed so much emphasis and interest
trying to stigmatize this topic that it almost worked too well.
Now we're at the point where we should be having this conversation
and people still don't want to because they think it's crazy.
You think of tinfoil hats and Elvis on the mothership.
But in reality, we're talking about a real national security issue.
I mean, these things are here.
You you have, Joe, you have a former director of national intelligence,
Radcliffe, a former director of CIA.
Brennan, you have former presidents all coming out and saying,
yeah, there's something to it. It's real. Right.
Now, what it is, where it's from and all that stuff.
I'm not sure we're quite ready to go there yet.
But the acknowledgement is, hey, man, yeah, this is real.
It's not ours. And we probably should do something about it.
So if we go back to the history of the debunking of it,
you know, like the Project Blue Book stuff, J.
Allen Heineck, after he had left Project Blue Book,
he became a proponent of UFO disclosure
during Project Blue Book.
He it was his job to essentially dismiss everything
and to come up with some sort of a reason, swamp gas,
mass hallucinations, whatever it was to attribute
all these sightings to something that was very easy to explain.
Did they ever is there any documentation
or any discussion of why they did that,
why they chose to debunk everything?
Yeah, my understanding is if you have to look at where America was
at the time they were doing these investigations,
it was at the height of the Cold War. Right.
And, you know, despite what some people think,
the Cold War wasn't very cold at all. It was pretty hot.
And we had Russia and the United States engaging in these proxy wars.
Neither side wanted to let the other side
know what we had and what we didn't know. Right.
So if you have these UAP coming in and out,
the last thing you want to do is tell the other side broadcast.
This is what we've learned from it.
And more importantly, this is what we don't know about it. Right.
And so both sides were keeping this very quiet.
But there was an interesting agreement at the classified level,
I believe, in the late 60s, where there was this relationship
with the United States.
We were putting up our northern tier radar system to detect
then Soviet Union ICBMs, and they were doing the same thing. Right.
Because none of us really trusted each other.
But we trusted each other enough to say, look, before you hit that button,
if you see something coming over the horizon, before you hit that button
and launch, give us a call, because it might be a UFO. Right.
And we don't want to start World War Three
because either side mistakes the UFO for an ICBM. Right.
And that's how serious they took the topic.
I mean, that's real. That's a real memo that that that existed
between the United States and Russia.
So that's that is an indicator
how much both sides took this topic seriously. Mm hmm. Jesus.
And so when Philip Corso was dismissing all these different things,
did they have anything, any film footage,
any any stuff from that time from Project Blue Book
that was like definitively not ours?
I'm not privy.
I'm aware of the fact that people say it does exist.
And people have been briefed on it.
I wasn't privy to that.
I was, again, more focused on the here and now. Right.
I was aware of people who had attended certain meetings,
very senior level meetings where that was discussed,
where they saw certain footage.
But that's I'm hearing that secondhand.
I I did not see the old footage.
My my focus was more on the on the current what's going on now.
But back to your point, why was this effort to try to create
so much stigma and taboo?
I think it was because of that.
I think because you had Russia and US at this weird stalemate
where neither one wanted to tell the other side what we know
and what we didn't know about UAP.
And really, I think the focus from a national security perspective,
let's say you're a general and I'm a general.
Look, we've got a real Cold War going on here right now.
As long as these things aren't coming in and zapping my people.
That's going to be my focus right now.
That's that's a real potential threat that I have to deal with now.
I've got Russia pointing nukes at me and I'm pointing nukes at them.
At any time we could launch.
Let's focus on that more so than the other stuff.
And that was that is that has been my observation
on why they didn't want to address the the the problem,
the challenge openly with the general public back.
And they also were worried there was there was several studies
that suggested that most people would be very uncomfortable with that idea,
that there's something else in the cosmos potentially or even right here on Earth,
and that it would create some sort of societal disruption.
Right. They didn't want to cause panic.
They were afraid that people would kind of like think of a run on Wall Street.
Right. When people get panic, they do kind of strange things sometimes.
And I think the government was very worried about that.
What's the most compelling modern thing that you've seen?
Oh, my God. I can't talk about it, unfortunately.
That's what that's this is my frustration, Joe, because I know what I see.
I know my colleagues are seeing right.
And to this day, there's there's video that's coming in on a regular
routine basis that is very, very compelling.
And how do they hide this stuff from the general public?
Well, we have classified systems behind a lot of it.
But how is it how is it getting filmed?
Is any of it getting filmed by the general public or is all this military stuff?
So let me backtrack a little bit.
This there is there there's a general public that is filming stuff.
But from a Department of Defense perspective, our focus now
arrows a different story.
But when I was in the government, we had to be very, very careful
of something that we called intelligence oversight.
Back in the 60s and 70s, the U.S.
intelligence apparatus, particularly in the Department of Defense,
was kind of naughty.
They were doing things they shouldn't do.
They were spying on students and they were spying on American citizens.
You don't do things. Yeah.
Crazy. So it isn't so.
So Congress passed some laws and said, OK, you can no longer
do this kind of stuff on on on on American citizens. Right.
You can't conduct intelligence operations on American citizens.
You can't do it. It's illegal. Right.
You have executive order 123 and all these other rules and laws
and DOD 5240.1 that all come out and say no mass.
So the Department of Defense is supposed to focus on military.
That's it. You don't you don't bring in U.S.
persons information and adjust them into a Department of Defense database,
especially a Department of Defense intelligence database.
That's a super no, no. That's called U.S.
persons information and it's pretty much forbidden.
So our focus was looking specifically at military sourced information.
I was not focusing at all on what the private citizens were seeing,
because at the end of the day, we couldn't use it.
You can't you can't do anything.
And it seems like you got plenty of compelling footage from the military.
Overwhelming, overwhelming.
It's there's absolutely no doubt that we didn't have to look at civilian data
because we had better collection sensor systems from the military
that was looking at stuff and giving us better insight.
If you can't tell us about can you give us some sort of an understanding
of like what you're talking about? Yeah, sure.
Without being specific. Yeah.
Let me see. OK. Yeah.
There is a video, high resolution video
of I can't say what platform was taken from.
I can't say where it was taken from.
But an object that, you know, do you know how large an offshore
oil derrick is? They're huge.
They're like almost like a small city, right?
They're like one city block. They're huge. They're enormous things.
There is a video that shows one of these objects underwater
that goes by.
The speed was calculated between 450 and 550 knots underwater.
And it was bigger than the offshore derrick that it was passing,
because you could see in the video the offshore derrick
and you could see this thing zip right by it.
Jesus. Yeah.
So that's a lot of them, right?
A lot of them are reported as being transmedium. Right.
So that exactly why. Why do we use the term UAP? Right.
Now it's unidentified anomalous phenomenon because it's all domain.
Initially was UFO, unidentified flying object.
And for several reasons, they changed the name.
One of them, not just because of stigma, like people think,
but because the word flying object means flight.
And you have to have wings to fly. That's flight.
And these things don't have wings.
So that term, we're not even sure is even accurate anymore
because they're not necessarily flying.
We see them underwater.
We see them super high altitude.
So the term was changed to unidentified aerial phenomenon.
But again, that did not encompass all the observations we were seeing.
So now the term UAP, I think the latest
description of it is unidentified anomalous phenomenon
to help describe this multi-domain or transmedium
characteristic that we are beginning to see and record that these things can do.
And that's that is I'm going to, if I can digress for a second,
because that's super important, Joe, we have transmedium vehicles, right?
We have things like seaplanes and it's a plane and it can float on water.
But let's face it, a seaplane is neither a really good plane
or a really good boat, because it's a compromise.
It's a design compromise between an object that you want to perform
in the air and in the sea.
And that's why it's neither really good at both.
Same thing with, for example, the space shuttle goes out into space
and it can glide down, but it's not a very good airplane, comes down like a brick,
you know, because there's design compromises and performance compromises.
But what we are seeing doesn't have any of that attributable compromise.
It's not these objects aren't slowing down.
They're not changing their their their performance capabilities.
They can do the same thing that we're seeing in the air and possibly in space
and even underwater.
So that is a that is a fundamentally different
type of technology than we are used to dealing with.
Is the assumption that they are doing something with space, time
and gravity around them?
Rather than using something like a jet propulsion engine
that blasts fire out the back and it makes it go fast forward, right?
That they're doing something that alters the gravity around them.
Yeah. So that's why they can go through everything.
Yeah. So we had some of the best scientists on the team,
folks like Dr.
Hal Pudoff and some other folks that I'm not allowed to say their names.
Dr. Davis and some others that were doing the calculations,
mathematical calculations on how this is possible.
And the consensus was by by the scientists, not me,
because I'm not a physics expert and I'm not an astrophysicist.
They were saying that.
So let me back up here.
Initially, the government for years was trying to identify
the different exotic technologies that could explain the different
performance characteristics.
And it was during the eight years that the scientists had this consensus
that if you had one type of technology, if you could do one thing,
all these other observables now become possible.
Kind of think of like a unifying theory.
And so if you had the ability to to create this bubble around you
in a localized area that insulated you from the effects of Earth's gravity.
Now, what is gravity?
People think that, you know, when I drop my glasses, that's gravity.
That's not gravity. That's an effect of gravity.
Gravity is the warping of space time.
And that's important because people don't think you hear the term
thrown around a lot, but they don't realize that space and time
are actually connected.
They are they are they are one of the same.
They're opposite sides, if you will, of the same coin.
And so you can't have one without the other.
And so you have this ability to create a bubble around you
that insulates you from the warping of space time.
Let's say in this case, Earth's gravity or something like that.
Then the way you experience time
inside that bubble is perhaps fundamentally different
than the way you might experience space time outside that bubble,
because you're not you're not subject to the effects of gravity,
which would explain potentially potentially why things don't need wings
and why they don't need propulsion systems like that. Right.
So it's a completely different way of looking at
at how we understand physics and how we as humans
move about. Everything we do is fundamentally force
equals mass times acceleration.
F equals m a right mass times acceleration in your force.
This may be something a little bit different.
This is this is not using a set again, conventional thrust.
Or if I put in a Newtonian, right, if I if I push this way,
I have an equal and opposite reaction that way. Right.
That's how there are any theories as to how it's accomplishing this.
There is actually Dr.
Hal Pudoff about three years ago gave a speech on this.
A very interesting talk lecture about this technology.
And if you ever had the chance, you really should have him on
because he's a he's a he's incredible human being.
He's also the one who helped start the government's
remote viewing program and a bunch of other stuff for the government.
He's been involved in a lot of our nation's probably most most classified efforts.
But he was working with us on ATP as one of our scientists.
And he gave a lecture about three years ago to some other scientists
about the specifics on how this is possible.
I am not a scientist.
So I'm definitely not going to speak on behalf of Hal Pudoff,
because I'm sure I will muck it up.
But I do recall a time when he came into our skiff
and gave us about a three hour lecture on this unifying theory.
And at that moment, it was very much for us the epiphany
that a lot of us had been searching for.
He's like, look, at the end of the day, this is how it's possible.
And that was kind of this wow.
So it's really not can you give us a moron's view of how it's possible?
Yeah. Explain it to someone like me.
Yeah, well, I'm in that category, Joe.
So, you know, we're speaking the same language.
Yes, sir. Yeah.
Single syllable grunts, right?
Yeah. So you have you have an object
like this cup on your table and you want it to
be insulated from the effects of Earth's gravity.
So you you create this bubble artificially
using a certain energetic source at a certain frequency
and interacts with certain material, certain metamaterial.
And again, I got to be careful exactly what I say,
but certain skin of the craft, this aluminum, the cup here.
And all of a sudden, you have this bubble around you
where what you see on the outside is not necessarily what you see on the inside.
In fact, may do it more drawing for you.
OK, forgive me. I'm not an artist.
So I'm going to do this upside down for you.
And then I'm going to kind of scoot this just a little here.
All right. Let's do this.
So. Unfortunately, I know your audience can't see this,
but actually, it's OK. Some people can.
There's a video form of it.
I'm sure this will get a little bit on YouTube as well.
It's probably good that they don't, because I'm not an artist.
But let's say this is a two dimensional representation
of a three dimensional space. OK.
And in essence.
So what you've done is essentially you've created a three dimensional
looking grid stacked, it looked like stack boxes on top of each other.
Yeah, right. And so you have this you have location A and location B.
And let's say go from Los Angeles to Baltimore.
OK. And it takes me five hours to fly at five hundred miles an hour.
That's a function of distance over time.
And in essence, you can mark that linearly like this.
So I fly, take me five hours to fly.
So I fly, take me five hours.
There I am. OK.
If you had the ability to compress space time and not a lot, just a little bit,
and you were able to allow these points to be a little closer together.
Now, in essence, what took you, let's say, five hours
and five hundred miles an hour to do it,
you can do it in one hour and you can do it in much less time.
But to the observer outside,
because we're still in the same universe, we would see something like that.
We would see this incredible hopscotching ability to to, if you will,
take a shortcut through space time.
And so what would appear to be instantaneous acceleration,
hypersonic velocity and other things
now becomes a reality.
And so that is that is fundamentally
what what the scientists had discovered.
And so it seems like science fiction.
But when you understand the mathematics and some of the theorem
that they propose, a lot of these other observables become possible.
So these are essentially just theoretical explanations
of how these things are moving.
Yeah. And again, I'm not I'm not a scientist.
I want to be very careful.
You know, I don't want to misrepresent anything.
There's a whole lot of other stuff that if you can do that,
all of a sudden now makes sense and may describe
the observations that people are are are seeing
and why they're kind of hard to see and they seem obscure. Right.
And so I think from from a from a governmental perspective that
it was kind of a revelatory moment for for for the folks in our in our program.
So they realized one of the reasons why these things are weird looking
is because they're literally creating one light.
Do you mind? I'm sorry.
I can't take this. Thank you.
So the back thing, the other side,
push that down. There you go.
Bam. Thank you very much.
No problem. So how how much of this is theoretical
and how much of this is observed from recovered vehicles?
I am not allowed to talk about what the government may or may not have
in its possession other than that.
I have so I went through a very lengthy Pentagon review process recently.
I I wrote I won't talk about it here, but I wrote something
and I had to go through Pentagon to have a review process.
And it took almost a year
in this this thing I wrote.
I I talk about up to the up to the part I can talk about.
And they approved for me to talk about up to that point.
When it comes to what the government may or may not have in its possession,
all I can simply say is that there is very compelling evidence
to suggest that the U.S. government is in absolute possession
of exotic material that is not made by humans.
Now, beyond that, I can't really expound upon.
I haven't been given permission to talk about it.
But what I can say is what I've already said for the record,
which has been approved by the Pentagon.
Won't get in trouble by saying it is that that that we are
there's very compelling data to suggest that we are in possession.
Why is the Pentagon teasing us?
Why do they tell you?
Why are they allowing you to say we are in possession of something
that was not made by human beings, but not allowed to elaborate,
not allowed to show these very compelling videos
that you're talking about that you've seen?
I don't. Well, two reasons.
I don't think they have a choice.
I think with now the introduction of cell phones
and ring cameras, the cat's out of the bag.
It's the worst kept secret at this point.
Two, there is a faction, unlike before in the Cold War.
I believe there is a faction of people inside the government
that do want this conversation to occur.
But equally, there's still a faction of people that are very mad with me.
They do not want me having this conversation and mark my words.
Just by me being on your show, it is going to cause an absolute storm
inside the Pentagon.
And I am sure the other shoe is going to drop.
I promise you it's going to be you're going to hear all sorts of stuff.
People make stuff up about me trying to discredit this topic,
because as many people are in the government that want this topic
to be discussed now, there's still some people that do not want this.
Could you steel man their position?
Say again, steel man their position, meaning could you argue it
from their perspective? Absolutely.
Like why would it be a good reason to keep this stuff quiet? Sure.
And I want to preface here, I'm not I'm not fear mongering.
No, no. But look, if I was if I was a military person, right,
I would look at this from the perspective of there's three options.
They're good, they're neutral or they're bad.
So let's go down this road for a second.
Let's say they're good, right?
Well, we've got nothing to worry about.
The problem is there's nothing to suggest that they truly are benevolent.
People say, well, you know, they're like they don't want us to nuke ourselves.
Well, you know, I discuss it in what I wrote that there's no
there's no there's no data to suggest that they didn't stop us
from dropping atomic bombs in Hiroshima and Nagasaki
and vaporizing 500000 living souls.
They didn't stop us when we started developing nuclear weapons
from the atomic age.
They didn't stop the proliferation of nuclear weapons.
They didn't stop the testing in the Nevada range of atomic and nuclear weapons.
And now how many countries have atomic weapons and nuclear weapons?
A lot, right?
They didn't stop Chernobyl.
They didn't stop Fukushima.
They didn't stop Three Mile Island.
So to say that they're here to help us, I'm not sure there's there's data.
People say, well, you know, in in in Minot and in North Dakota and Montana,
they the UFOs came in and they stopped.
They interfered with our nuclear weapons and they brought the entire
echo flight offline, which, by the way, I have the government report on that
if you want it.
But in Russia, a lot of people don't know.
They turned them on. Right.
So that's equally scary.
They're interfering with our nuclear capability, whether to attack
or to defend ourselves.
So when you say they turned them on in Russia, this is a Russian report.
Yeah. So this is a I don't know if you remember the
hearing congressional hearing that occurred last year, where the
note, the other one with Undersecretary of Defense for Intelligence,
Ronald Moultrie and some people from the Navy.
And I think it was Congressman Gallagher that asked the very specific
question. And he said, are you aware of
UFOs interfering with our nuclear capabilities?
And the response was something like, no, not really familiar with it.
Never heard of it.
And then the question was, I think we asked specifically at these locations
and the government's response was no, not familiar with it.
Well, here's the actual report from the Department of Defense.
This is the actual intelligence report that was released through FOIA.
There's a there's a gentleman out there who runs a site called the Black Vault.
His name is John Greenwald.
He's probably the world authority on Freedom of Information Act.
And he has a wealth of data
that is out available to the public that he has received from the government.
This is one of those documents.
This is the document that our own government has no idea
apparently exists.
I like how they write it in all caps.
Yeah. Yeah. That's the old reporting.
So obviously, there's some people that don't want this to be released.
And obviously, there's some people that think that the general public
has a right to know.
I believe so. That's that's my that's been my observations in my experience.
Well, that makes sense.
You know, I mean, like when everybody says the CIA does this, like, OK, who?
Well, in the CIA, I didn't finish the other parts, right?
So if they're not here for friend, if they're not, it's not friendly.
That leaves them neutral like us. Right. Or benevolent, benevolent.
Now, from a military perspective, and I just want to caveat,
I don't agree with this, but I can respect the understanding.
You, sir, are a general.
And I say to you and I say,
we cannot prove that they're not here to do something bad.
But what we do know is that they can interfere.
They're very interested in our military capabilities.
And they have interfered with our nuclear capabilities. Right.
From a military perspective, that looks an awful lot like something
we call IPB, initial preparations of the battle space, or perhaps even ISR,
intelligence, surveillance and reconnaissance.
Whenever we're going to go into a foreign country and invade,
we do long range surveillance.
We want to know how the enemy operates, how they react.
So even if there's a two percent chance, five percent chance
that these things are are here to do something malevolent.
Right. Mm hmm.
Then we probably should not tip our hands to the fact
that we are aware of it publicly, because what happens the moment
that the bad guys in a foreign country find our surveillance team over the border?
We've got 12 hours.
We've got we got to invade because the element of surprise is now over.
So some may feel in the government, the mere fact of acknowledging this,
if there is some sort of malintent may push up artificially a clock
that exists somewhere for these things to say, oh, OK,
the the the foolish humans are now the cats out of the bag.
They know where we're here.
We need to go in now for whatever reason they may have.
So that is the military mindset, potentially, of some of these individuals
who want to keep this secret.
So they're worried about an actual invasion.
Well, but they have to be.
That is that is the role of our national security apparatus. Right.
Even if there's a one percent chance. Right.
They have to consider that in their planning and in the decision making matrix.
So, again, going back to what I said, I respect that.
I don't agree with it, but I can respect that.
If that is the reason why, then I would say, OK, look, in your heart,
you really do have the best interests of the American people.
You are a patriot.
I can accept that. Again, I don't think it's your decision to make.
I think needs to go to Congress.
I think it needs to go to the president.
Let the American people decide.
I think I think America can handle the truth.
I think America deserves the truth and let the American people decide
if it's in their best interest.
I agree with this, but I also could see it from their perspective.
Like, they're probably insanely busy already.
And the last thing they want to do is get involved in this thing
where now they have a PR campaign when they're trying to let people
know about this thing and not cause mass panic.
That's right. That's right.
But you know what, though, I'm also very optimistic, Joe,
because you and I are having this conversation
and people aren't making a run on Wall Street.
People are still paying their mortgages, going to PTA meetings.
And after the 2017 New York Times report, which was probably
one of the biggest moments in UFO disclosure,
because it was in the New York Times.
And then you see something like that in the New York,
especially in New York Times in 2017.
People really respected it.
It's like this is right.
This is a real story.
Well, and this is this is apolitical.
I mean, how many topics can you go to Congress and have?
That's not polarized. Right. Right. Right.
This is one of the only ones where you can have literally have
Congressman Burchette and Congresswoman AOC
side by side, agreeing that this this is important. Right.
This is this is it's a very rare opportunity.
And so, you know, my concern,
I'm doing this because I believe it's the right thing to do.
And my concern is that we're at a point now where I've said before,
you know, secrets aren't like a fine wine
where the longer you keep a cork on it, the better it gets.
I think secrets are perishable.
I think they have a shelf life.
I think they're like vegetables in your refrigerator.
And there comes a point where if you leave them there too long,
they start to rot and they start to stink
and it becomes a big mess to clean up. Right.
And so that's my perspective.
And what I'm trying to do is give the government an ability
to work its way out of a corner that it's put itself into
for the last several decades and with no seeming way out. Right. Right.
You look around like, well, how do we get ourselves out of this trip?
Is there an issue of legality, like of of spending and like 100 percent?
100 percent.
So there's people that would be liable for. Yes.
Not being straightforward with Congress.
And I know people want their pound of flesh.
I know there's people out there you we've been lied to for decades.
And I want and then they make it a political issue. Right.
Go after someone. Yeah.
And I think that's the wrong approach.
I think, you know, there was a time where we needed to keep this secret.
And I think what you do is you you you give those guys awards,
give those guys and gals awards who did it.
Don't don't make them enemies.
Make them friends and say, OK, look, but those were different times.
Now is the time to to to come clean.
Talk to the members of Congress.
Forgive all the past sins.
Yeah. Truth and reconciliation.
Prosecution. 100 percent.
And let's just get clear with all this and understand that it was all in good
faith that you did it in the first place. 100 percent.
Now, all in the interest of the United States security.
You talk about legal issues.
The problem is there are the real legal issues.
So let's say you have again these cups. Forgive my analogies.
You have two aerospace companies, company A, company B.
And let's say I am in the Department of Defense back in the 50s, 60s.
And I come across this interesting technology.
I have no idea what the hell it is.
It just came out of the sky.
And I go to company and I said,
tell me what you can figure out about that. Right. Right.
Ten years later, company A becomes a multibillion dollar aerospace company.
Company B goes bankrupt.
Two hundred people lose their jobs.
And now people who have stock investors in that company
lose their money. Right. Unfair advantage.
Keep in mind, you're supposed to have fair competition in the U.S. government.
So if you give an unfair advantage to company A to B,
you're talking a serious liability.
There's SEC violations there.
There's all sorts of concerns one has to pay attention to because someone
somewhere gave an unfair advantage to one company over another.
So there's there are legal liabilities that we have to we have to recognize.
It's not just clear cut. OK, forgive and forget.
You know, there's going to have to be some some additional protection
and understanding for if if that occurred.
We need to figure out how we deal with that as well.
So that would be an impediment to release.
That makes a lot of sense.
Yeah. These are big companies, right?
With the deep pockets and a lot of lawyers.
Well, I mean, also, this is a discussion that we've had on here before.
If you did find something, who would you bring it to?
You bring it to the people that build your fucking jets like, hey, guys,
what the hell is this?
Like, you know, you make some sort of a top secret agreement.
You bring it to them in some sort of undisclosed facility.
That's the best and brightest.
Bring the guys in and go, what the fuck is this thing?
Yeah, you kind of have to.
Otherwise, like what else would you do?
You know, I mean, how else do you find out how these things work?
And if you were going to do it in a secretive manner,
you would have to bring it to defense contractors,
because those are the only people that are capable of making things.
They make your jets.
They make they make the, you know, every stealth bomber,
every whatever the fuck it is, they make all that shit.
Going back to, you know, a colleague of mine made the comparison.
He said, look, Lou, imagine being during the days of Da Vinci
and all of a sudden bringing Da Vinci a garage door opener.
You have no idea what it's used for.
I've never seen plastic before.
You don't even understand electromagnetic radiation, right?
But you didn't and an infrared, you know, where do you start on the analysis
and exploitation of a technology that the physics hasn't even been discovered yet?
Right. I mean, garage door openers seem like magic.
Right. It really does.
You know, I press a button and a door opens like magic.
Wait, where's the horse? Where's the strings?
Right. Yeah.
So it's kind of bananas.
You press a button on your car and all of a sudden your door opens. Right.
And you drive in and you press another button and it closes.
And it's all done through the air. Right.
Which is bananas. Magic.
But we're just accustomed to it. That's right. Yeah.
So this kind of technology,
I'm sure you're aware of the Bob Lazar story.
I'm aware. I don't know Bob. I've never met him.
You never got into that? I did not.
How could you not with your line of work?
Because, you know, I always wanted to be insulated from prejudicing the jury.
And I know it sounds kind of strange, but I didn't ever make sense.
You know, it's it's it's it's kind of something I impose on myself
because I didn't want to have any preconceived notions of going in.
Most people kind of, I suspect, would be tempted to say, well,
I'm going to learn everything I can about, you know, UFO lore.
I wanted the opposite.
You're a better man than me.
Well, I love I'm chasing that shit down.
You know, I think I just I just wanted to be very, very careful
to preserve the investigative integrity.
Right. And we're look, we're all humans. We're all bias.
There's no way around it. We all have some degree of bias.
Let's let's be honest and truthful here.
It doesn't matter what type of bias it is.
We all have some sort of bias somewhere,
whether it's food or the people you like to date or whatever.
I wanted to avoid that as much as possible.
And so I always kept it very, very focused on the here and now.
And, you know, what what can we see today? Right.
You're aware of the story, though, right? The basic tangentially
that he worked at a particular facility and at that facility,
he was exposed to some sort of
UAP technology, that thing, right, that thing, that thing right there,
the sport model, and that he was brought in
as a propulsion expert and to try to.
They didn't know how it exactly worked,
but they they sort of just said, tell me what this is. Roger.
And then along the way, he realized, oh, this isn't even ours.
Yeah, I'm aware of, again, the overarching story.
I don't know any of the details and I've I've never met him personally.
So I'm a very, very interesting guy.
I had dinner with them with my friend, Andrew Schultz and Jeremy Corbell.
We went to dinner and, you know, informally talked
and had a fascinating conversation.
And Jeremy's a great guy. He's a great guy.
Yeah, he's he's really you know, he's done a lot to say hi.
Hi. He's pumped that we're talking.
Yeah, he's done a lot. He's a UFO nut.
And he got me really way back in with his documentary
of Bob Lazar, Flying Saucers, whatever, wherever the actual title of it is.
But that that documentary is fantastic.
And it's essentially going over Bob Lazar's story from the 1980s to today,
which he's told the exact same story, which is nuts
that you have one giant lie your whole life.
Like, come on.
There's a lot of weirdness to the story, obviously,
like there is with everything.
There's a lot of people that want to discredit his his background
and all sorts of other things.
But the reality of what he's saying is essentially what we're seeing
in these crafts, which is very strange.
So he described how these things worked and how they moved
and how they would turn sideways and sort of like project this
whatever this reactor that they have inside of them.
And he talked about this element, element 115.
They have a stable version of it that was essentially
is theoretical at the time in 1980.
No one really knew whether or not that thing actually even exists.
89 or whatever it was.
And that they would douse this thing, project radiation upon it,
and it would create this warp, this gravity warp, this this thing
that allowed this this craft to move in ways
that defied our understanding.
That's a hell of a lucky guess.
Hell of a lucky guess.
Hell of a lucky guess in 1989.
Wow. And he drew it.
He has diagrams of what this thing looked like and how it worked.
And it essentially looked exactly like that little model
that's on the desk there.
And that he felt like the whole it didn't make any sense.
He said the whole thing didn't have any seams,
which now we understand 3D printing, right?
So now we know that we can actually give in.
But only now, not back then, right?
Of course. Everything had rivets.
Exactly. The skin of a craft was the skin of an aircraft.
Exactly. It had rivets and had nuts and bolts.
And exactly, you know, but now, you know, obviously now we have carbon fiber.
We have a bunch of different ways of constructing things.
But back then, he didn't know what the fuck that thing was.
He said it looked like it had all been melted, like into place,
like that it had been like almost like smooth, like wax, like melted wax,
and that it had no instrumentation inside of it.
And it was designed for very small things,
like something that was like three feet tall,
and that all these things seemed to operate through the being itself
had some sort of connection to the craft,
some sort of strange way of interfacing with the craft
that didn't have anything to do with pulling levers and moving things.
But, Joe, is that really that much of a stretch?
Let's let's look at this.
You know, we have we've done experiments where we've had pilots
be able to control aircraft thousands of miles away
with a helmet that interprets thought. Right. Right.
So it's, you know, again.
How does the helmet is it similar to like a Neuralink setup?
Have you seen the new video of the second Neuralink patient?
I have not.
Is this video of him playing Counter-Strike?
Was it Counter-Strike or is it a is that it?
So Counter-Strike, which is a very popular online 3D game.
And this guy who does not have use of his body has this Neuralink implant.
He's the second Neuralink patient.
And apparently with each iteration, it gets more and more sophisticated and better.
So this is a from this person's point of view.
He's playing this video game entirely with his mind.
So he's better than I can with my well, better than anybody can.
Because the first guy who the first Neuralink patient, we had him on.
And he said essentially is like having an aimbot because you don't miss.
You look at the thing you're trying to shoot at and instantaneously
your crosshairs go there. Wow.
Yeah. So he's all this stuff is taking place entirely.
This is all him doing this entirely with his mind.
But is that right?
So if we can do that now. Right. Right.
Is it really that far of a stretch to think that, you know,
someone who's a little more advanced than us, right?
Our friends from out of town realize that's the way to do it.
That's more efficient, right?
The speed of the processing of the brain, the processes of the brain is much faster.
It takes us longer to then have to mechanically use our hands
and manipulate and do things.
This is almost not quite, but almost instantaneous.
You don't have that lag. Right. Of course.
So that would certainly make sense.
You know, modern warfare, not the game, but actual modern warfare
is beginning to turn to them.
We're using AI and all these other augmentation to enhance performance.
And so I I don't think that's out of the realm of of possibility.
No, certainly not.
I mean, just go from garage door openers to, you know, 500, 600 years ago. Right.
To today and then cell phones, the ability to send video across the world
instantaneously, all the sophisticated stuff that we've just completely
take for granted because it's become a normal part of our everyday life.
That's you know, I used to I used to give a briefing to some folks.
I'm so glad you mentioned this, because it's this goes back
to the whole stigma and taboo issue.
I used to have a slideshow and still have it somewhere.
And I would I would discuss the word that the Latin word prefix of para
para. And it means above or beside.
And so what I would do is show up, I would say the word parachute.
And I'd ask people, what do you think of when you hear the word parachute?
And people would describe, obviously, something that deploys over your head.
And hopefully you hit the ground with a with a thump and not a thud. Right.
But something that's normal, we use every day.
And then I say, what about the word paramedic?
And then people would look at it and say, well, I think of a first responder.
Someone goes some, you know, some sort of medical lifesaver
that's going to going to be there for your benefit.
And then I say the word.
When I say the word paranormal, what do you think?
And people stop for a second.
Maybe they kind of give you a little sly smile and say, what do you mean?
So what do you mean? I mean that paranormal.
The only reason why you're reacting the way you are, because you've been conditioned
that the word paranormal is is cookie stuff.
When in reality, in science, by definition,
everything is paranormal until it becomes normal.
The cell phone that I use every day 50 years ago, absolutely paranormal.
And so I would go through this exercise of things that were once considered paranormal.
For example, when the Inca first saw the Spaniards,
the conquistadores coming from the reconquering,
they saw them on the shores of the beach and they saw these
these humans in armor riding on a horse.
And they assume they've never seen a horse before.
They assumed it was a single entity.
It was a single monster.
And that for them was paranormal.
They didn't understand it was actually a human riding on a horse with, you know, metal skin.
Same thing with acupuncture.
I remember a time when I was growing up as a kid,
people thought Eastern medicine, acupuncture was nonsense.
Well, now the Veterans Administration, the VA, for some of my guys in combat,
they actually prescribe acupuncture as therapy.
It's not paranormal. Right.
And so there's all these examples in history
where we think something is kooky and weird when in reality it's not.
It's just we don't understand it yet.
And we have done such a good job of stigmatizing this conversation
that the moment you even say the word paranormal or you say the word UFO
or anything like that, people are conditioned without even thinking about it.
It's reflexive to react a certain way.
And we have to first deprogram ourselves first a little bit
before we can start moving forward.
OK, let's how do we just destigmatize this conversation?
Well, first of all, what's kooky?
You know, what do you think is kooky about something that's in our airspace
that's performing in ways that we can't replicate?
You know, that people say, well, you know, we wait a minute.
We spend millions, if not billions of dollars
putting a probe on Mars to try to find microbial life.
And by the way, it looks like that may happen.
It looks like there actually may be some evidence to suggest that.
We spend lots of money trying to find technosignatures
of intelligent life, radio signatures in our own Milky Way. Right.
Well, is it possible within the four and a half billion years
our planet's been here that maybe intelligent life maybe found us first?
Is it possible? Could be.
You know, we we have to stop putting these these limitations.
Joe, when I was when I was in the medical program,
when I was learning to be microbiology and immunology in college,
we learned from our professor that homo sapiens sapien as a modern species
has been around roughly between 100000 to 200000 years.
Now, I'm not an expert, but that's that's what they say.
It was only the Greeks 2000 years ago
that introduced the idea that there's only two types of life forms on this planet.
And you are either a plant or B, you're an animal.
And it wasn't the last 300 years.
So if you look at a 24 hour clock, roughly the last five minutes
in the 24 hours towards midnight, we discovered another form of life
that is neither plant nor animal that's been here with us on this planet.
And that is the world of fungus.
During the Renaissance and the days of Newton,
we discovered that there was this other life form we've been sharing all along.
And we so we pat ourselves on the shoulder.
And it wasn't the last hundred and twenty years.
Think about it. The last 10 seconds of our existence on this planet,
so to speak, in a 24 hour clock as a modern species.
We actually discovered the true dominant life form on this planet.
And in fact, if you take all the biomass of every plant
and the biomass of every animal and the biomass of every fungus
and add it all up together, it still will not equal the biomass
of this hidden kingdom of life.
That's actually the dominant life form on this planet.
And that wasn't until we were able to curve glass
and look through a little steel tube and famously shout, little beasties,
little beasties, did we discover the world of microorganisms that, yes,
live inside of you and, yes, live on the skin of the ISS space station.
Yes, live miles underneath the Arctic ice. Right.
That is the true dominant life form on this planet.
And it always has been.
And it wasn't in the last until the last hundred and twenty years.
We discovered that.
So is it possible that there is something else that is
just as normal to this world?
Is it possible? Well, the answer is a resounding yes, of course, it's possible
because we're always discovering new, new, new, new ways life can exist.
When I was growing up as a kid, I was told absolutely, as a matter of fact,
all life form is derived from photosynthesis.
Ultimately, when you go all the way down,
it turns out that's not true.
It wasn't until we discovered the in the deepest,
deepest depths of our oceans where these things called black smokers,
we discovered there are creatures that thrive with no light
and they thrive off of something called chemo synthesis,
a completely different way to metabolize energy to sustain life. Right.
So every time we put Mother Nature in a little box,
she always finds a way to wiggle her way out.
And I think that's important when having this conversation, because
if there's one thing we know as human beings,
we're usually wrong at first.
Well, we exist and we do send things to other planets.
So we do send things into space.
It only makes sense that something far more intelligent than us
that would be doing that.
And if they did, they'd probably watch an emerging civilization,
which is essentially what we are. Right.
And like you said, two hundred thousand years, which is nothing.
The existence of homo sapiens, they've gone from things that use stones
and Flint map to things that can fly things through the air.
I mean, if you look at Orville Wright and Wilbur Wright
when they flew the first airplane, you go from that to the Apollo 11 launch.
That's only like, what, 50 years. That's right.
Something crazy like that. That's right.
That's nuts. Right.
And you just take that and everything moves exponentially.
You take that and you would imagine a civilization
that's been around ten thousand years longer than us,
a hundred thousand years, a million years longer than us.
Something that doesn't exist.
How about a hundred years?
We have evolved more in the last hundred and fifty years
than we have in the last hundred and fifty thousand years. Sure.
So, you know, and then you have the other other.
For me, I find it when people say, well, the space is so huge.
And, you know, is it possible that things are coming from outer space?
My response has always been the same.
Look, I don't know where they're from.
I just know that they're here.
And could they be from outer space? Sure.
They can be from inner space or even the space in between.
And and I say that because the universe is far more complex
than than we give it credit for.
Every time there was a time we had Newtonian physics,
we thought there was a solution.
Then all of a sudden, Einstein comes along and we realize that weight,
space and time are actually connected and everything's relative.
And all of a sudden, now you have quantum mechanics, which is,
you know, this spooky action at a distance, right,
where the whole universe is behaving in a way that it shouldn't.
And yet that looks like the real way the universe works.
I often tell people we are as humans, we we have five.
Only five fundamental senses that we can base our reality upon.
And if you can't touch it, taste it, hear it, smell it, et cetera,
we can't interact with it.
And so where I live in Wyoming, we have these beautiful night skies
kind of kind of like you have here in your in your studio here.
300 days of unincluded night skies and as beautiful as those night skies are.
If you were to look at that same portion of the night sky
through a radio telescope, you would see a whole different reality around you.
You'd see nebula and you'd see things in different spectra
that we can't pick up.
You pick an ultraviolet and infrared.
So you would see a whole different reality, just like our cell phones, right?
If you could see in cell phone vision and see in Wi-Fi and 5G and GPS,
you would interact with your environment completely different.
You would see reality.
So we can only interact with a very small sliver
of the reality that we can perceive because we're humans.
But most of reality is actually beyond that.
And then, of course, you have scalability issues.
The universe is is immensely huge.
And what scientists are now saying, if you look in any direction,
you can see roughly within the visible that let me emphasize
a visible horizon of our universe is about 13.9 billion light years, plus or minus.
So that means in any direction, I can see 13.9 billion light years
with the right equipment. What's a light year?
Well, it's as fast as light can travel in a year.
Well, light travels pretty fast.
In fact, it travels at 186,000 miles per second.
So seven and a half times around our planet in one second.
So imagine how far you can go in a year.
Now, multiply that by 13.9 billion.
And that by scientists estimation.
So if the universe end to end of our visible,
we're stuck in the middle, is roughly 27 billion light years.
Scientists are now saying that's only possibly only 10 percent of the known universe
because the universe is so big and so vast and so far light
will never have time to reach Earth.
So that's that's a hunt at a minimum 100 billion light years.
Right. And so we are this little speck in the middle.
And as as as crazy as that is to even try to conceive,
if you compare one atom inside the one hydrogen atom, Avogadro's number, right?
One times 10 to the negative umpteen all the way down.
It is roughly the same level of scale.
As we are to the universe, meaning that atom is the size of a human,
as we are the size of the universe, as we are a human to the size of the universe.
So there is this and we, as humans, can only interact
plus or minus with one order of magnitude up or down.
Otherwise, the universe is simply too big or too small,
meaning most of the universe and reality lies in those scales.
We live in this little tiny, tiny sliver. And so.
You hurt my head.
Well, yeah, we live in a tiny sliver.
And the idea that we're alone, I think, is preposterous.
I really do. And I know people, they constantly chime in with this.
So where's the evidence of, you know, Elon's famously said,
if the aliens are real, they're very subtle.
I don't know why he says that, though.
I think I think he probably says that because he doesn't want to sound like a kook
while he's working with NASA and SpaceX.
You know, I'd probably say some stuff like that, too.
Well, let me ask you this as human beings. Right.
How many times do we fly over the Serengeti in a helicopter? Right.
And let's say you want to monitor the health of a particular,
you know, herd of elephants. Right.
And so what happens are wildebeest, we fly over, we pick one.
We we shoot it with a tranquilizer. It falls asleep.
We go down, we do some tests, pull its blood.
Now, think about it from the perspective of the wildebeest. Right.
It wakes up, kind of meanders over to the watering hole and says, Bill,
you're not going to believe this man.
But something out of the sky came down and all of a sudden they were touching me.
And, you know, I woke up in my butthurt. Right.
What the hell was that? Right.
To this day, even in China, when we go into a zoo, right.
And we have the panda bear exhibits.
What do we do? We put so we don't disrupt the pandas.
We wear panda suits.
Now, it sounds silly, but you can actually get online and see zookeepers
wearing panda suits because they don't want to they want to interfere
as least as possible with the natural flora and fauna.
They're inside the exhibit.
Do you think animals could you was it was it reasonable
to theorize that there's aliens amongst us?
When you say, well, two things.
So I don't want to be evasive.
Let me but I also want to be very specific when we say aliens.
And then we also are we are we saying something from another plane
or are we saying non human intelligence that looks like us?
I moves around with us.
So is it possible?
Well, we're doing it already with the panda bear.
So, you know, it's not that we do a strategy.
That'd be very simple. Sure.
And especially if you have the technology now, as far as the bear.
Yeah, there you go. Right.
Carrying little baby pandas. Exactly.
Boy, those are shitty panda bear outfits, too.
Well, they're fucking terrible.
They're pretty terrifying, aren't they?
Actually put that in front of my dog.
He's going to bark.
It's like a dude in a dog costume.
He like a fucking dog.
Yeah. Well, as a wild panda bear, not know that dude's not a panda bear.
That's crazy.
He's a panda terrorist.
That looks like a fucking alien.
Like it was really dark out.
And that guy grabbed you and zapped you with a tranquilizer.
You'd have an alien story.
But yeah, my point is that we always, you know, use camouflage.
For obvious reason, we do it in military.
Right. I mean, camouflage, camouflage uniform.
I stealth aircraft, you know, for camouflage.
Sure. You do it when you go hunting.
Absolutely. I do. Absolutely.
So so it's not it's not a stretch of the imagination
to suggest anything coming here that doesn't want to provoke us.
Probably wants to blend in.
Now, of course, do I have any type of empirical evidence
to suggest that they are living among us?
I don't want I can say definitively that whatever it is, it's here.
And and by the way, you already have very senior people
in our government that have said it's here, whatever it is.
But these things could also be from under the water.
These things could be something that is as natural to Earth
as the little beasties were right when we first discovered them.
Maybe maybe they've been here all along. Right.
So the the ocean is largely undiscovered.
One of the things that people need to understand
is that most of the exploration of the ocean is really essentially
around the outside edges.
It's around the shores. Less than 10 percent.
So which is not a buddy of mine. 90 percent of the ocean.
That's right. Like what?
We know more about the moon than the bottom of our own ocean.
And so so crazy. Yeah, that's fact.
And these underwater crafts like this enormous one
that apparently was near this oil rig.
How many of them have been?
Has there been more than one of those videos?
So let me tell you what I can say from open source.
Yeah. OK.
And then I'll tell you about a conversation I had without attribution
because I don't don't want to get in trouble.
Everybody's when I say everybody, a lot of people are familiar
with the Air Force's program called the Fast Walker program,
which is a program that was started by the Air Force, among other things.
It was to detect UFOs.
That's a fact to actually that was part of their mission to detect a lot of things.
Adversarial technology.
But UFOs was one of them was called the Fast Walker program.
There was some information
that was released publicly about a similar program the Navy has.
I can't talk about it because I don't have approval to talk about it.
But obviously, they're interested because they have equities underwater.
They're interested in if there's anything underwater
that can perform beyond anything we have.
And I remember speaking to one individual
who pulled me aside very privately and he said, Lou,
we were tracking this thing doing and I won't say the exact speed,
but hundreds and hundreds of knots underwater.
And it was bigger than our own submarine.
And you know how big our submarines are, right? They're huge.
And I asked him naively, I just kind of came out,
what do you do when you encounter that?
He just said very honestly, he said, we go around just like that.
We go around.
Have there been interactions with these things?
I would not be able to discuss any details about that.
That's not for me to discuss.
You know, I got to get drunk.
I'm a lightweight. You know, I got to get you drunk.
Let's go have some whiskey, find out what the fuck is up.
So this thing is bigger than the sub,
and they followed it for hundreds of miles.
Let me give you another great, great event that occurred.
And I'll talk about this because it's not classified.
The portions that might be, I don't know about, so I should be fine.
There's an individual who I'm aware of who was a helipilot,
helicopter pilot back in the late 90s in the Caribbean,
and they were doing missile recovery.
So what happened is that the Navy would test fire missiles
and then they kind of run out of fuel.
They hit the water and they sink.
At a predetermined time, they pop to the surface.
We grab it with a helicopter, bring it back to shore.
And we test it for telemetry and make sure that, you know,
this cruise missile was doing what it was supposed to do.
So they're out there in the helicopter,
frogmen hanging down the line.
You got the helipilot, you got the crew chief
and the other co-pilot looking all down at the bubble.
And as they're about to grab this cruise missile out of the ocean,
something huge and round and what was described to me as black as a devil
starts to rise to the surface.
The water begins to churn very much like David Fravor's description
of the Tic Tac incident and the roiling water.
The frogman is so freaked out.
He's literally trying to climb the line back up.
He's like total panic at the disco, right?
Yeah. And the helicopter is like, do we do it like an emergency ascent?
What the hell's going on here?
And right as this thing is about and by the way,
it's the size of a small island and round right as this thing is about
to break the surface, it sucks the missile down and disappears.
And that was, yeah.
And Dave Fravor could probably tell you that story a little better than I can.
But when you compare that to other things, you've got to say,
imagine being that guy hanging from that line.
No, thank you.
We call that bait.
Yeah, but it didn't do anything to him.
No, I would have loved that experience.
Yeah. So that was that was one of the anecdotes that was revealed to us
by one of the major pilots.
Who's that guy that was hanging from the frogman?
I know. I don't know.
I only know the bro. Come, come talk to me.
Please, sir.
I only know the pilot.
Well, put you in a fucking panda outfit.
You know, disguise your voice.
Tell me what the fuck you saw.
I want to hear that story.
Oh, my God. Small island. Yep.
Black is the devil in a small island and round.
Yeah. Submarines look like this, right?
They're not round. Right. So, yeah.
So that was that was one of the anecdotes that was shared with us.
You know, obviously, Puerto Rico with the other.
There's been some UAPs that have been recorded off there.
Everybody knows about Aguadilla, the Aguadilla incident.
I don't know about it. Oh, I'm sure you do.
You know what? Tell me. Wow. Trust me.
So you can look it up online.
There's a video taken by a DHS helicopter of a very interesting object.
First, it appears to be like a perhaps a balloon,
but then it does all sorts of weird stuff.
And as you're tracking it, it enters the water without making a splash.
You can track it underwater.
Then it comes up and splits into two.
And it's called and it's been analyzed over and over again by a lot of experts.
It's called the Aguadilla incident.
Maybe I have seen this.
Is it kind of blurry looking night vision? That's it. Oh, wow.
And so keep watching that.
And I'll tell you a little story about this.
This is a customs and border protection. Release this.
How fast is this thing going?
Well, so if you look here, they're looking at this through a form of night vision.
I don't know the exact velocity.
All that is available.
But if you keep watching this, something interesting happens.
So here it goes.
You're going to see this thing enter the water here.
There he goes underwater.
And then it pops back up and splits into two.
Keep their track and it see no waves, no wake.
And then it surfaces and then does something pretty,
pretty interesting here. So keep watching.
So it's going high speed through the water underwater.
That's underwater.
Then it breaks the surface of the water again.
Keep watching.
Boom, underwater, over water, boom, underwater.
Out of water, and then you'll see it split into two.
So I didn't see it split into two.
If you watch the rest of the video, the video, there it is.
Oh, there it is.
The video is actually really long, but that's just one example.
You know, this is these are you can see all these videos.
They're prevalent everywhere.
You see that the eight the aircraft on the bottom, right?
You see the UAP on top that's tracking it. Yeah. Yeah.
No wings, no control services.
And it keeps up with the A-10 and does all sorts of interesting maneuvers.
Right. So that's an A-10 warthog.
And this thing is just following it.
Yep. Like it's nothing.
Do you think they're trying to let people see them?
Like, have you had a guess?
You know, I don't know.
I mean, could it be a demonstration of capabilities?
We do that right every time a Russian surveillance aircraft comes by.
We launched two F-22s and we get real close to it and say, hey, you know.
Right. Be careful.
But not even from a military perspective, like if a civilization
was trying to alert another civilization about its presence,
wouldn't it like go towards whatever military vehicles it has and show itself?
And then I would imagine that if they understand human beings,
they understand our psychology and they understand that some giant
size of an island, black as the devil, circular craft
that lands next to the Pentagon would fucking end the world.
We would freak out. No one would know what to do.
That would be stock market crash, mass chaos.
No one would know what to do.
The way to introduce yourself, I would imagine, would be gradual
over a long period of time to allow this civilization
to accept the fact these things exist and then slowly but surely
show versions of themselves.
Yeah, we call that sensitization.
You sensitize a population or environment.
But, you know, the counter argument to that is that's a very human thing.
Right. We have as humans, we always it's it's almost innate.
We look at everything through anthropomorphic eyes.
We look at, you know, our pet dogs and we give them human names
and we do things like that because we assign human value to things
and because we have intentions and motivations.
But most of nature isn't that way.
Like, for example, when a shark bites a surfer,
he's not wanting to hurt the surfer.
He's just hungry. The shark's hungry.
I don't care if you're a seal or whatever.
You know, I don't want to I'm not trying to inflict pain.
I'm just want to feed my belly.
Intent and motivation is a very human thing.
And we have to we have to I want to say resist the urge
because it's almost impossible to do it.
But we have to recognize that there are there are things that may exist
that aren't don't have human motivation, meaning. Right.
Maybe they don't care about sensitizing us.
Maybe they do. But maybe it's like a like a computer. Right.
Maybe it's binary.
Maybe there's some sort of binary thought process, just information in
and and information out.
So that's the one one of the aspects I've always been very careful with
is to assign human traits to something that is very likely not human. Right.
But would you have to assign human traits to it or would you have
if you you could look at it from the perspective of these things
are aware of our psychology, they're aware of how we function
and they're aware of the fragility of our world view.
No point.
You don't have to have human intention to have a strategy
for doing the least amount of harm to this civilization to say.
In fact, there's examples of that.
Let me reinforce your point, because there's examples of that.
My background being science in nature, you know, when lionesses stalk
the zebras, you know, they get very low into the grass.
They don't want to be seen. Right.
They're not motivated necessarily because they don't want to spook
the herd, but they do it.
It's it's it's it's almost instinctual. Right.
It's part of their DNA, part of their wiring to have a low profile,
low observability and to get closer to their target,
whether it's prey or anything else.
So you're right.
That mean there are examples in nature that also can suggest that.
So it's a very good point.
Yeah. I mean, it just makes sense that if it understands us,
if it's absurd, look, we understand the behavior characteristics of sloths.
Right. Right.
We study them.
We know what they do.
And it would just make sense that if they're studying us,
they would understand our behavior characteristics.
I mean, the tiger recognizes the behavior characteristics of the zebra, doesn't it?
Right. Exactly. It studies it.
And so it knows what it has to do to get close to the zebra.
So yeah, there's no way they would come here with ignorance.
And I think also it's very likely that what we are
exists in many, many places in the universe
and that what we are is what they used to be.
So they probably understand what we are.
Well, we do that in the Amazon, don't we?
Yeah. And in African tribes, there's lost tribes that are remote.
Right. Separated by outside human contact.
We study them. We study them from afar.
But we do the same thing.
Yes. Yeah. No, no question.
And obviously, if they are these super intelligent creatures,
they evolved to become super intelligent creatures.
So there's probably some sort of a universal process
that takes place amongst all intelligent, creative life
that has a lust for innovation.
They consistently make better and better versions of these flying crafts
until they figure out how to make this warp drive thing
that these things apparently have.
Another thing that's odd is that you see the same kind of things
that Kenneth Arnold saw in 1950.
You see the same kind of things today.
It's almost like, you know, going somewhere in the 1950s
and seeing a 55 Chevy and then in 2024, seeing another 55.
They're still driving around 55 Chevys.
Like, what the fuck?
Well, they do do that in Cuba, right?
But that's just because they don't have access to other cars.
They don't have a choice. Really good mechanics.
That's your people. It is.
It's my I'm really resisting the urge of continuing to smoke this thing right now.
OK, I feel terrible.
Don't feel terrible.
I feel terrible. My wife is going to give me hell for this
because I told her anything wrong with cigars, man.
Like I was saying before, I never heard of a single person dying from cigars.
You don't nail them.
Take a little bit of smoke in your mouth.
It's pleasurable. It's nice.
Um, I would just think that that's what they would do,
because that's what we would do.
And I think that's what intelligent life would do.
We've recognized something that wasn't quite as intelligent as us.
We don't rush into these, you know, remote tribes and vaccinate them.
What do we do? We don't give them.
But, you know, the thing is, like, they have done some things.
Like they gave Starlink to this one tribe and the kids all started watching porn.
You hear about that?
Yeah, it became a real problem.
They're all lazy, hanging out on their phones all day, which makes sense.
That's what we do.
Yeah, you know, tribal leaders are not happy.
You bring up another very interesting point.
Is there a natural glide slope or a natural evolution
to evolution, meaning any species that reaches a certain point?
Is there a natural progression
of any intelligent species to progress to the point?
Because all life is expansive.
Life doesn't contract. Life expands, whether it's bacterial life,
whether it's animal life or human life.
It is there are certain biological functions to procreate, multiply
and continue to expand. Right.
So is that a is that a universal norm?
That is, is that part of like fractals and geometry throughout the universe?
Is that part of the blueprint of all life?
Or is it only specific to life here on Earth?
And that's a great question, because there's probably arguments
to suggest that, yeah, there probably is a natural.
There's a natural blueprint for physics in the universe.
They're probably since life has to abide by physics,
probably a natural, potentially natural blueprint for the evolution of all life,
whether, again, bacterial or animal or human or anything else nonhuman.
It makes sense.
It makes sense that everything moves into greater levels of complexity
from single celled organisms to human beings that pilot drones.
It just keeps going in the same general direction, observably here.
And if the universe is infinite, that means there's infinite versions
of what we're seeing here with us that exists throughout the cosmos
and probably in infinite steps along the way. Right. Right.
A hundred years from now, a thousand years from now.
Well, not to make light of it, but I'll tell you recently.
So I've learned over the years it's it's there's nothing more expensive
than a than a cheap lawyer.
So I've got a couple good lawyers that I that I work with on just contractual
stuff, and one of them is named Ivan Hanel.
I call him the bull.
And I've learned to appreciate the the shout out to Ivan,
the infinite complexity of law and legal. Right.
So, right.
So if if there is this natural progression, as we're talking about life,
I mean, we even see it in our own human interactions. Right.
This this this intricate complexity of how things work
and how even in the way we behave with each other socially. Right.
You look at a when I was in the in the government,
you could look at a terrorist link analysis
and that link analysis still follows those fractal patterns
that the patterns in our our lungs, the patterns of lightning,
the patterns of super meduline clouds and galaxy super clusters of galaxies
all have that same pattern.
And it's not just a physical pattern.
It's a social pattern. Right.
And so, again, I not to make joke of it, but I'm learning that it's
beyond these patterns or beyond just physical patterns, you know,
even in something as as as silly, but fundamental as law.
There are these patterns that continue to spin off and whatnot.
So, yeah, I can appreciate that.
I think I think we're at a point now as a species
where we probably should be having these conversations.
And I'll also say this, Joe, there are parts of this conversation
I don't feel the government has any place.
There is definitely a national security conversation here.
But the conversation we're having, as you can tell,
is far beyond national security. Right.
We're talking philosophical, psychological, sociological,
theological implications that I'm not sure I want my government
necessarily dictating for me what I should think about this.
Well, the government is supposed to be working for us ultimately,
and they are supposed to be us.
You know, the problem is when you have access to information
that's above and beyond the normal person's realm,
that could affect everyone on this planet,
this understanding that we are not alone.
But not only that, we're probably not even alone here.
It's not even that something is visiting us.
Something's probably here all the time.
You know, and this is the main thought about these underwater vehicles.
Well, life is abundant on this planet, isn't it?
And it thrives in places that we thought life could never thrive before.
It's it's everywhere.
It almost seems like a natural function if you have certain
situations and circumstances on on a rock somewhere,
then life pops up.
It seems like if we can actually find it on Mars and they're
like you were saying before, they may have found some sort of an evidence
of microbiological life.
If we find it on Mars and we find it somewhere,
they think maybe Europa underneath the surface.
That's right. That's right.
And Europa probably is powered by volcanic vents the same way
the bottom of our ocean is.
There might be some sort of life.
Chemosynthesis, not photosynthesis.
And this is just what we know about here.
You know, imagine all the different potential realities
in terms of what a planet's atmosphere could be like.
You know, you're dealing with larger planets that have more gravity.
You're dealing with different kinds of temperature variations.
Look at Titan. It's got a method.
It's methane. And by the way, that's organic chemistry. Right.
It's got methane clouds. Right. Right.
So there are things that thrive in these types of environments.
They have cow farts up there, too. Yeah, there are too many.
But yeah, I mean, you're you're you're absolutely correct.
I think we have again, this goes back to the original point of
every time we try to put Mother Nature in a box,
she always finds a way to wiggle her way out of it and prove us wrong.
If the one thing we're right about is that we're always wrong. Right.
How much whatever I don't know if you could talk about this,
but how much of an effort is there to try to detect things
under the surface of the ocean?
I would defer that to the United States Navy and maybe NOAA.
No oceanographic district.
Yeah, no, no, no. Yeah, not the biblical Noah. Oh, Jesus.
Yeah, no, no. I mean, no, I mean, it was that far back.
National Oceanographic and and atmospheric.
Speaking of going that far back, I mean, how much of
I got to think that when people are delving into the stuff,
they look at ancient scriptures and ancient
these different depictions of things, whether it's the Vyamanas
in the Hindu texts and whether it's in the Bhagavad Gita.
There's all these different stories of in Ezekiel in the Bible.
There's things that seem to.
If I was a person living thousands of years ago
and I encountered a flying saucer or encountered some spaceship
from another planet, I would probably describe it
in a way that they're describing it.
Yeah, I mean, I mean, like just like sort of the Aztecs.
Today's magic is tomorrow's technology, right?
So I can tell you, when I went to Italy, I spoke to one of the senior
I think it was a monsignor, one of the senior Vatican academics.
And he said to me, he says, look,
the Vatican doesn't have problem with this topic.
This is something, in fact, in the six up into the 1600s,
it was heretical to presume or assume that mankind was the only
if you will, incarnation of God, representation of God.
It was actually because in essence, you're putting limitations
on the dominion of what God can and can't do. Right.
And there are these scrolls, in fact, that are in the Vatican archives
that discuss it's a conversation between a Roman soldier and a Roman general
where they describe there's something called Eclipse.
Eclipse in Latin means like sun eclipse, right?
It's the shape of the Roman shield.
And they talked about these flaming Roman shields in the sky
that would follow them from battle space to battle space.
And Mr. Jacques Vallee could probably expound much more upon that than I can.
But this is just a brief conversation I had with with someone there.
Jacques Vallee is very slippery.
Is he? Very slippery.
You know, he don't commit to anything.
He looks at you sideways.
And yeah, he you know, he's he did a lot of a lot of good stuff.
And he's an incredibly smart guy.
Great researcher of just phenomenal, you know, big reason that guy
close encounters of the third kind.
He's the inspiration for the French guy.
I heard that. Yeah.
I never had the guts to ask him.
I figure he gets tired of being heard.
I'm sure when you talk to him, the guy.
But, you know, there's there's there's a lot of.
And when you look at what the Vatican is, I mean, really,
it's probably the world's oldest, most capable intelligence organization,
because they have priests around the world that people will report
miracles to, right, and confessions to.
And eventually that gets filtered up to the Vatican.
So, you know, talk about, you know, the world's first CIA and KGB.
It was the it was Vatican, baby.
Those guys had had it going on.
And so no wonder they have all this archival, excuse me, archival information.
And some of it relates to UAP. Wow.
Yeah, it only makes sense that these things, if they're here now,
they've probably been visiting us since back when we're on horseback.
Yeah. And probably quite a bit before then.
And maybe that's the scariest thing for people.
They might be responsible for us being humans in the first place.
Well, you remember the stories, right, of even Christopher Columbus
coming over to the New World.
There were some interesting accounts when they're on the water
of potentially some sort of UAP interaction.
I did not know that. Yeah, you can look it up online.
This is all open source, but you can type it up.
And there were some very interesting accounts and even, you know,
old, old, old sailor accounts, you know, of, you know, people say, well,
you know, old sailors also talked about, you know, big giant crack
and stuff like that, but there was always an element of truth to it.
Now we realize there are giant squid of the Pacific.
Well, not only that, Kraken's, they think likely did exist.
Yeah. Well, they because octopus when they brought, they don't leave anything.
But they did find fossilized suction cups from. They still do.
It's called the Great Squid of the Pacific. We find.
Yeah, that that for sure.
But they think maybe perhaps even an enormous octopus.
That probably actually did go after boats.
You know, we call we we call them sea monsters back then.
But really, you know, we we laugh about it now.
But it turns out there are sea monsters.
Here's what's called great white sharks and megalodons.
You know, that's a fucking sea monster.
Right. That was a real thing.
A great white shark is now.
I mean, absolutely.
Go swimming with a great white shark and tell me that's not a monster.
Right. Exactly.
So, you know, it's we just realize, oh, it's just part of nature.
It's part of our existing paradigm.
Tigers are monsters. Right. Absolutely.
You know, especially at night when you don't have a flashlight,
that thing behind the bush, that's a monster. Right. Right.
Did you find anything on the Columbus stuff?
One thing I'm seeing is from my Ancient Aliens episode.
Now, you know, it's legit.
I saw something crash into the water, but I can't find.
Yeah, there was some reports of some interesting lights
that the crew had reported.
And it was actually he put it down in his log book.
Something about some interest.
Now, some folks will come back and say, well, that's St.
Elmo's Fire, which absolutely could be, you know, what is St.
Elmo's Fire? St. Elmo's Fire is a static charge.
It occurs on the wingtips of aircraft.
Even the old sailors would report it in certain environmental conditions.
There is this weird greenish blue
plasma glow that will often sometimes be seen on the tips of wingtips
on aircraft. It's actually there's some really good pictures of it online.
And even on the old mariner ships up towards the sails and the mast.
And they believe it's it's
it has to do with static charge.
And under certain environments,
it creates this this energized plasma and you can see it.
And so is that similar to like ball lightning?
Well, it could be. Here you go.
So and they call it St.
Elmo's Fire. See that fucking bad ass.
Yeah. And so that's yeah.
It's either around the cockpit of the aircraft.
Well, and by the way, you see the patterns, it's fractal, right?
Look at that ship.
So very, very interesting how St.
Elmo's Fire, you know,
can cause some people to, you know, perhaps see things and say it's also
they might be seeing that. Yeah, they might. Right.
But there are some accounts of ancient mariners who report
strange, bizarre things. Yeah.
Again, it makes sense.
That was one of the more weird parts of Bob Lazar's
story was that they've always been here and that they view us as containers.
Containers. Interesting. Yeah.
And he said there's a very thick document
that relates to the
the implications that it has on religion and like what
what they the way they talk about us.
Well, religion calls us vessels, right? Yeah.
It's religious scripture.
And a lot of different religions refer to humans as as vessels.
You know, I'm certainly not a religious expert.
So, you know, I don't want to pontificate here and say something that's inaccurate.
But, you know, that that doesn't surprise me.
Well, I think that the term was I think they were saying vessels for souls.
But if you imagine that a being transcends
its physical limitations of biological reality, right?
So the biological evolution that led us to become homo sapiens
over the course of, you know, X amount of millions of years,
that's a very slow process.
But technological innovation and technological progress is very quick,
very, especially when you add in artificial intelligence, exponential.
Yeah. So if something comes along, that
is a life form that exists outside of biology,
like something that we create, which it seems like we're doing right now.
Like AI, right?
When does that become sentient?
Now is that a life form?
You know, not biologically that thing in order for it to ever occur.
Maybe that thing needs a thing with a soul
that has a creative desire, that has a lust for innovation
and continues to make better and better things.
And maybe that thing only exists in biology.
And maybe the problem with artificial life is that it has no motivation
and that we have, especially if it's self programmable, right?
So one of the very bizarre things
that was recently discovered about artificial intelligence,
they gave artificial intelligence a certain amount of time
to to code something, to figure something out.
And when it didn't have enough time, it changed its code
to give itself more time. Fascinating.
Yeah. Like, what the fuck are you talking about?
It is deciding that it doesn't like its limitations.
So it won't have any of the biological motivation we have, right?
It won't have ego.
It won't have materialism.
It won't have a desire for status.
It won't have all the things that lead us
to do some of the horrible things that human beings do.
I could not agree more.
And also some of the great things that human beings do.
But maybe it also doesn't have any desire to create.
Maybe the only way for its kind of life to exist
is for a human being, a biological thing
that's super intelligent in comparison to the rest of the animals on this planet
that innovates to the point where it creates this artificial life.
I'm going to share something very, very personal with you.
And I know when I say with you, I know it's with everybody else, but, you know,
part of my struggle is I can't I can't urge the government to be transparent.
And I'm not transparent myself, right? It's hypocritical.
So let me share with you a very personal story,
because you bring something up that I think is fascinating.
I'm a human being.
But if for whatever reason I get into a car accident and I lose an arm,
I'm still Lou Elizondo, right?
In fact, if I lose my legs and all my arms, I'm still Lou.
So my body doesn't define who I am and my intellect.
Right. If I suffer a traumatic brain injury,
let's say I'm in Afghanistan in a TBI
and my my my brain is compromised.
I'm still Lou.
And so so what makes Lou or what makes Joe Joe?
Well, it's not not your physical self and probably not even your intellectual self.
My my mother, I was very close to my mother.
My mother was was was incredible human being.
And I'll share the story with you and take away with it what you want.
I was very young, maybe two, two and a half, three years old.
And I remember watching a show with my mother, one of my very first memories.
And in this TV show, I remember what show it was.
But I remember that a shark had eaten a dog.
And I was shocked.
My first understanding that what death was.
I looked at my mom and said, Mom, what just happened?
And she said, Well, son, the shark ate the dog.
So what does that mean?
Says, Well, the dog is not coming back.
The dog died.
I said, Well, does everything die?
She said, Well, yes, son, everything dies.
I said, Well, mom, you're not you're not going to die.
Your mom gave me life.
She says, No, son, one day I'm going to die.
And I remember spending from that day forward, as God as my witness,
I spent every single day of my life knowing one day my mother was going to die.
And it terrified me.
I was very, very close with her.
And one day that day came.
My mother was diagnosed with cancer,
and she started.
Her body started failing.
And despite the best efforts, she
we knew she wasn't going to make it.
And, you know, when you love somebody, sometimes
doesn't sound right, but sometimes you deceive them.
You know, they want to know they're in a bad state physically and mentally
and say, you know, am I going to make it?
And you say, Yeah, of course, you're going to make it right.
Knowing full well that there's probably not a good chance you're going to make it.
And so we're in the hospital.
And my mother had at this point
been in probably a state of coma for about a week.
And it was just me, my wife and a couple of members of the family.
Very, very sad moment.
And my mother began this process of death called,
you know, when someone's going to die, there's something called a death rattle.
And it's when the mucus begins in the back of the throat to to congeal
and it makes breathing.
It can be very unnerving for the people who have to witnesses.
It's very, very common. It's called death rattle.
It's the body beginning to shut down.
And I knew something told me my mom.
My mom was going to go very quickly within the next 30 seconds to a minute.
So long story short,
my mother's body was at that point, it was a husk, an empty husk.
It was broken.
Her brain had shut down.
And yet the very moment she passed away, within five seconds, I knew it.
There was just something weird, something reached and said, this is it.
She's going.
And I reached over the bed and I looked at my mom.
Her eyes all of a sudden opened up and she looked right at me.
And even though her brain had been compromised and wasn't working,
her body was was was nothing anymore.
And she was a beautiful woman.
She was she was she worked for Playboy.
She was a beautiful lady at one time, a model.
She was her body resembled nothing of what she did.
She looked at me.
And she passed, but we communicated.
And I knew there was something else at that moment, more to a human being,
more than just a body, more than just a brain.
There is something that is.
That is beyond the physical and even intellectual part
of what it means to be human.
And I felt it and everybody in the room felt it.
It was undeniable.
You can call it a soul and it achieve whatever, you know, you can put a label on it.
I don't know what it's called.
I don't know what it is, but I do know that was the essence of my mother.
And the moment she passed, it was this weird feeling because.
As my mother laid there dead in the bed.
It wasn't my mother anymore.
That essence, whatever made my mother my mother.
And you could see the light in her eyes.
It was like someone turning off the light switch is very.
And I've been around death a lot.
Never, you know, it's a terrible, horrible thing, especially in warfare.
But but this was something, something visceral.
This was something far more intimate.
This was this cut to my soul and I could recognize it.
And she recognized me and I recognized her, even though that the brain functions were gone.
So so I guess my point is.
I absolutely believe there's something more to the human experience
than simply a tangible body and in a brain.
And I and I witnessed this firsthand.
Now, people can say all sorts of stuff they want to.
You know, I don't care.
You know, I got enough haters out there anyways.
You know, they want to think that I'm trying to, you know,
hope that my mother has a soul and she goes somewhere.
I'm just telling you what I experienced and other people experience, too.
And it was it was proof for me at that moment
that there's much more to to us as as as human beings.
I had a very similar feeling when I went to my grandfather's funeral
and I saw him in the casket
because it was it was an open casket.
And I knew he's gone.
I'm like, that's not him.
That's right. It's just a show.
And you can sense it. You feel it.
Yeah. It was a very strange feeling.
Yeah. You know, and obviously he's wearing makeup because they've got him
in a suit and the whole deal.
But I was like, that is not my grandfather.
He's not there anymore.
And it's not like you're trying to override this acknowledgement that they're dead.
You know, they're dead.
It's just that whatever made that person that person,
it's not in the body anymore.
It's gone. There's a bizarre feeling that we have that
you don't you don't think his words for it.
Yeah, I agree with you. It's a feeling it is.
And you can it's again, it's not an intellectual or even a physical thing. Yeah.
The idea that we're containers for souls is just so goddamn creepy.
This is a farm of souls.
I'm not familiar with that hypothesis, but it sounds interesting.
Also scary, perhaps.
Well, it's scary for us because, you know, but.
Like you, you got to wonder why we are so different than every other creature
in that we have this insane, insatiable desire to change our environment,
constantly build bigger skyscrapers and to move the earth.
And we're constantly inventing new technology.
I mean, it seems to be an instinct that's a part of us.
And I agree this gradual progression of life is life goes from intelligent
biological life to super intelligent.
Whatever it is, whatever, whatever kind of technology creates it,
that life is not as simple as.
This natural selection model that we have here
that we think applies to life, that this is a type of life.
And then there's a life that this thing creates.
Well, you know, evolution isn't just a physical thing, is it?
Evolution is is the ability to change within one's environment over time.
And that's a that's a that's a fascinating concept you bring up,
because some speculate that it is inevitable
that human beings will eventually evolve into something.
We're just a link in a much longer chain. Right.
And that all intelligent life potentially goes through this process.
And that this is a natural process where eventually we actually make ourselves
extinct, not not in the way where we kill ourselves. Right.
But we wind up creating a life form, whether it's A.I.
or we start enhancing ourselves with more and more machine interface.
And and and, you know, life doesn't have to necessarily be organic. Right.
You could have potential.
Silicon is very, very close to carbon in some cases.
So, you know, is it possible that that life it is it is destiny
for all life eventually to evolve itself out of existence
and bring in or usher in a new type of life form? Yeah.
Is it possible? I mean, certainly from a technological perspective.
I mean, ask Elon Musk.
It seems that we're, you know, we're making a lot of advancements
right now to augment the human experience.
And given, as you said, how technology progresses exponentially, very quickly
in the next 200 years, I mean, we might be there.
Is this sort of conversation being had in the government
about what these things potentially are?
I not to my knowledge, and I sure hope not,
because I don't think the government this is a conversation.
This is where I go back to.
This is a conversation that involves a lot of people, you know,
whether it's your your priest or your rabbi or your imam
or it is your philosophy teacher at the university.
I think I think we're getting into an area now that is beyond national security.
And I'm honestly, Joe, I'm not comfortable
with my government taking that aspect on,
because frankly, I don't trust my government
to manage what I should think about something.
Tell me what is I'm OK with.
Don't tell me how to think about it.
Don't tell me how to process that, you know, because now you're
now you're overstepping your bounds.
It's also other human beings.
The government is just human beings.
That's right. Human beings shouldn't have this insane knowledge
and keep it from other human beings.
Well, in fact, it's it's not it's illegal, especially in our democracy.
There's this type of stuff is supposed to be discussed
with certain members of Congress and certain elements of the executive branch.
And when somebody I don't care if you're in the government
or in a religion or anything like that, this goes to the to the fundamental
pillar of something that that agrees me, which is corruption.
Now, when I say corruption, let me let me backtrack a little bit.
My father recently died this this last father's day, not this one,
but the one before. And I had the privilege of of knowing he was sick.
And so we took a road trip down to Miami
and about a month and a half before he died.
And he never told me he was sick.
But but I knew something was wasn't right.
I knew my father for a long time and something wasn't right.
He started losing weight and I could see he wasn't eating as much.
And there were telltale signs and he didn't want to tell me.
And I asked my father almost almost flippantly, I said, Dad,
I think we're probably somewhere by St.
Louis. And I said, Dad, what is the greatest threat to humanity?
To humans, what is the greatest threat?
Now, I say flippantly because I'm thinking, you know, terrorism, right?
This and that. My father thought for a second, he looks at me, says, son,
it's corruption.
And I said, what do you mean corruption?
Like like like financial corruption, governmental corruption?
He says, no.
Corruption at its heart is when you are willing to
bypass your own moral code, your own ethics for something else.
And whether it's it's financial corruption,
religious corruption, governmental corruption, or even
moral corruption, when you start to compromise on your own values,
it's a very quick downward spiral to to utter chaos.
And he know that firsthand because my father was in the Bay of Pigs invasion.
He was a political prisoner of Castro.
He actually fought with Castro against Batista.
And then when Castro went communist, my father joined the folks here
and the friendly folks at the CIA and was part of the invasion of the Bay of Pigs.
He spent two years in Castro's prisons being tortured.
Um, so when he came to this country,
this country offered us opportunities that no other country could or would.
And the reason why Cuba failed was because of corruption.
And he said, look, corruption will be the end of all.
And and if if it's a very quick downward spiral
with democracy, that if democracy becomes corrupt, you now have tyranny.
Right. And so every time someone in the government is willing to
compromise a little bit on the value of what it means to serve the American people
and they forget that they become corrupt.
And that actually erodes the very essence of what democracy is
and what this country is about.
And that is why it is so important that the individuals in our government
that don't want to have this conversation and don't want to talk to Congress
and are making the unilateral decision on your behalf
and the American taxpayer in my behalf, that's wrong.
They don't have the right to do that.
There is a process of rules and laws we have in this country
that we've all agreed to are going to abide by.
And that includes them.
And they don't have the right to bypass that.
Even if they think they're doing it for the right reason.
I disagree with that.
I think I think this democracy only works because we all agree it works.
Right. And the moment you begin to compromise on that,
all of democracy is at risk.
And I mean that sincerely.
It's not a it's not a slow downward spiral.
It's quick. And you can hit rock bottom very, very quickly.
And the only reason why this government works is because we all have faith
and a commitment to what we consider are the American values
and serving the American people and, you know, for the people, by the people.
So I think it's very dangerous when when elements in the government.
And I want I don't want to villainize the whole government
because the government's full of great people.
They do great things. They keep us safe.
So I'm talking about the minority few.
Some of these people who have actually gone after me
and will probably continue to come after me to try to discredit me
and everything else, despite the volumes of documentation
that I have in my possession and others,
because they don't want to have the conversation.
And they are happy with the status quo.
And to me, that is a greater threat than any UAP could ever have on humanity.
It's it's the greatest threat is how we perceive ourselves
and what we are willing to do to keep this a secret in violation of the commitment.
And and and what we have done to we've sworn in some cases
to uphold the values of this country.
And I think that's a concern for me.
And that's why I don't want certain elements having this conversation
of what this means, you know, the bigger macro level conversation,
because I don't think they're qualified.
I'm not qualified. I knew that.
I'm damn sure they're not qualified here.
So this is why I think this type of national level conversation is so important.
At the end of the day, it's not up to me.
People say, Lou, what do you think?
You know what the hell what I think doesn't matter what I think.
What matters is what you think.
Here's the information. Here's the data.
You figure it out.
Don't ask me for what this means, because I'm not entitled to that.
I didn't I didn't earn that privilege.
And I would definitely never take it away because that is that is that is sacred.
That's you. That's up to you to decide for yourself.
And this is this is part of my frustration
with this overall conversation, because there are elements
that don't want you to have this conversation.
Well said, Lou. Thank you very much, man.
Thanks for being here. I really enjoyed it.
Really enjoyed our conversation.
Joe, this has been fantastic and truly, truly an honor and privilege.
You have one hell of a responsibility.
You are. You are.
Look, I got to tell you, I don't ever get nervous doing an interview.
You were the first one and probably the only one
I will ever have been nervous coming in just simply because
not because of me, because of you, the responsibilities
you have on your shoulders to have a communicate.
You reach a global audience.
People are listening to this conversation right now.
And by the way, they're part of this conversation.
Very much so. Right.
That is an enormous responsibility.
You have a voice in some cases that exceeds presidents.
The technology, you now have it available to your fingertips
and this wonderful staff you have.
You are influencing the world.
And I can't imagine that type of responsibility.
I mean, there are world leaders that don't have the voice you have.
And so for me, it is a profound, profound honor and privilege
to be with you here today and your wonderful audience.
You know, if I never see you again, I wish you the best of luck.
You are you're doing America a great service.
Be honest, be candid, speak your mind.
That's all I can say as a little chicken here in in in the United States.
You you've got big shoulders, man.
You got a big weight on a lot of responsibility on your back.
And I mean, this is freaking me out, man.
Tell you. But thank you very much.
Thanks again. I really appreciate everything you've said.
And I appreciate your everything you said about disclosure
and how important it is. I couldn't agree more.
Joe, it's been my honor and privilege sincerely.
My honor, too. Thank you very much.
Thank you. All right. Bye, everybody.