It's like we have different species of humans on this planet, I'm quite certain there's
different species of alien life forms.
So we could run into mental evidence, in fact President Reagan on several occasions alerted
concern about the potential hostilities from outer space.
We know for a fact that the U.S. government has solid information about negative health
effects from being in the proximity of UAP UFOs.
And people, Congress individuals will be speaking with the Department of Defense Inspector General.
Now when they have this, it only took a couple of years to get this meeting to go to place,
but the idea is that the DODIG, they're going to work with Congress and kind of let them
know about some of the stuff going on.
Secrets, cover-ups, and strange phenomena.
UFOs and ideas that challenge reality itself.
All these mysteries, all this time, are we ever going to get to the bottom of these?
My name is George Knapp, I dig into news stories that others can't or won't.
I'm Jeremy Corbell, and for some reason people tell me things they probably shouldn't.
And this is Weaponize.
Hey Jeremy, how you doing?
Good man, how you doing?
Busy.
Busy week in UFO world.
Arrow came out with its long anticipated second report.
Did you read it?
Oh yeah, I read it, man.
You know, it's the same thing.
Oh, my little puppy's, my little boy's crying about the Arrow report.
Everybody's crying about it.
Oh, okay.
So yeah, man, it was kind of towing the line.
They use all these things, like during our investigation timeframe, we didn't find any
negative biological effects on people.
It's like, it's really frustrating to people like you and me and people that know a broader
scope of the UFO history.
You've got Sean Kirkpatrick, Dr. Sean Kirkpatrick, kind of like tallying up the recent, you know,
things that they've seen that the military has been able to film or document.
But isn't the whole point of Arrow that there are these illegal programs that we have been
reverse engineering, that we have these things within private defense contractors, and they're
just playing around with things they see in the sky?
I mean, if we have these things on the ground and they've been notified of that, which we
know they have, what game are they playing?
I don't get it.
Well, it's a game that we've seen many times before.
I mean, we've seen this movie.
We saw it with Project Sign, which, you know, was the first really big Air Force study of
UFOs.
The staff members came up with what they thought was a compelling case that these were possibly
extraterrestrial, but they knew that they weren't ours.
And the guy who was the head of the Air Force at the time put the kibosh on it.
He wouldn't allow that report to be made public.
So then you have Projects Grudge and a blue book that came out that basically did their
to explain away UFO cases, even when the explanations were more outrageous than the possibility
that these are from somewhere else, some non-human intelligence.
You know, Project Blue Book was a public relations exercise.
It's starting to feel like Arrow is the same thing.
You know, they're ostensibly supposed to investigate these sightings, and it sounds like they are.
I mean, in terms of the good news of what we heard this week, it's that Sean Kirkpatrick
saying that they've received dozens of reports per month.
So at least there is a flow of reports.
Some of the stigma has decreased to the point where military pilots and military witnesses
and some commercial pilots will go ahead and file reports.
That's a good thing.
It's good that they've got a total of 800 or so, which is up from 650 the last time.
You know, but you start to feel the creep of what we've seen before.
Half of these are easily explained.
They're balloons and drones.
Only two to 4% are truly anomalous, I think Kirkpatrick said, and require further investigation.
Only a very small percentage display, quote, unusual characteristics.
But it was interesting to me that Kirkpatrick gets out in front of this report.
He goes on CNN to spin it before the report is actually released.
Were you, did that catch your attention?
It sure did.
I'm sorry.
I just have to say.
He's a little boy.
He's really crying about the error report.
Right.
So there's nothing I can do.
He's going to do a little crime.
So yeah, that was something that really struck me was that we see immediately before this
report comes out, Dr. Kirkpatrick, you know, he straight up gives an interview to CNN to
absolutely try to spin it, try to put it in his favor.
And they were compliant.
They were like, oh, cool, great.
So it was really bizarre.
I just, you know, here's the deal.
You have always said that with Arrow, they have to earn our trust.
They haven't done that.
There have been lies for decades.
And I was like fighting for them.
I'm like, come on, man, this is really cool.
It's going to be okay.
But I do see what you're saying now, which is that the way everything is worded, it is
absolutely a whitewash.
And that's not even what we know.
They've been told and have not investigated or have covered up.
So when it comes to just reports coming in from the military, they go above and beyond
to try to dismiss and try to show us cases that are already resolved as if we need a
lesson on what that looks like when things are resolved.
Right.
So, yeah, man, it's really, it's really annoying.
At the same time, I think the real frustration I have is that we know for sure David Grush
says we have the locations, I know the program names, I've got hostile and non-hostile witnesses,
but we know that Arrow is not pursuing that in a public way.
And they're even throwing it back in the face of the people that we know, some of whom we've
sent to testify to Arrow.
I'm never doing that again, by the way.
So yeah, man, it's really frustrating if people go read the Arrow report.
It's like this little bait and switch thing.
It makes you think that they're doing something legitimate, but then they're edging towards,
oh, we can verify everything.
This might be adversarial tech.
Did we have this adversarial tech before our military even existed?
I mean, come on.
Yeah.
I thought Kirkpatrick's comments to CNN about Grush and other whistleblowers were pretty
telling in that he said something like he dismissed the sensational claims saying, quote,
He has no evidence that suggests anything is extraterrestrial in nature.
And I'm not sure that Dave Grush ever used the word extraterrestrial.
It was non-human intelligence.
And then he said, if anybody thinks they know what these things are, they should be coming
to talk to us.
That's why we've set up this entire architecture for people to securely come in and talk with
us.
Well, you and I know people who have come in to talk to him, and they don't seem to
be taking their testimony very seriously.
We know people who have provided information to other alarms of the US government.
Arrow either hasn't paid attention to it or hasn't gone after it or hasn't read it.
And then, lastly, I guess, we know people who have been invited to speak with Arrow,
but are not going to get within 10 feet of that office.
They don't trust them.
They don't believe that they're doing an honest investigation.
And there's no way that they're going to come up and cough up what they know to Sean
Kirkpatrick or his staff.
I mean, I would actually argue that they've taken very seriously the testimony, but they've
completely locked that in to not allow that to be part of public disclosure.
When people go and talk with Arrow, there's this new thing.
When they submit, it becomes part of an investigation.
They can no longer talk about it.
So they become silenced just because they went to Arrow.
That's what I'm hearing from people that did actually go and testify.
So it's kind of this catch-22 where I think they are taking things very seriously when
people say, I was in this program.
This was the name.
This is what we did.
It was exploitation of non-terrestrial, NHI, non-human intelligent craft.
And then they just lock it up.
So I think it's more diabolical than they're just not taking it seriously.
I think this is a positioned organization like Blue Book, like Project Sign, Project
Grudge, where they're trying to get as much information, oh, come tell us the information
and then lock that shit down.
That's the fear and the understanding of a lot of people that have come forward to them.
I am hopeful though, because we do know that on the 26th of next week, we do know that
Representative Burchett and people, Congress individuals will be speaking with the Department
of Defense Inspector General.
Now when they have this, it only took a couple of years to get this meeting to go to place.
The idea is that the DODIG, they're going to work with Congress and kind of let them
know about some of the stuff going on.
Now, I don't know how that meeting is going to go, but I'm hopeful that that meeting
is happening actually this week when people are listening to it.
It would be this week.
A couple of other things that Kirkpatrick has said or the report said that jumped out
at me, and this was the one that both of you and I reacted to off camera, offline, is that
they have found no evidence of adverse health effects documented to date, which is maybe
they haven't.
Maybe the cases they're getting mostly come from pilots and they're not getting close
up to these UFOs, whatever these objects are.
But we know for a fact that the US government has solid information about negative health
effects from being in the proximity of UAP UFOs.
There's a, Shanker Patrick could walk across the street to DIA and get the DIRD that was
part of the OSAP program.
Sorry for all the acronyms, but there was a report compiled that the guy who was in
charge of it is Kit Green, who worked for CIA for a number of years.
He's a neuroscientist, a medical doctor, and he cataloged all these hundreds, hundreds
of cases where there have been deleterious health effects caused by being in the proximity
to UFOs.
Burns and body marks and serious really weird diseases that pop up when people get too
close to these things.
It's hundreds of cases.
It's a DIRD that is now public information.
We posted on a mystery wire a couple of years ago.
You and I have talked about it before.
So the fact that Shanker Patrick seems blissfully unaware that this report exists is telling,
I think.
Right.
So I think they hide behind language because when you read it, it's like within the
reporting period.
How do you even have time to really look at the brain scans of individuals who had an
experience within that reporting time?
So they kind of hide behind language.
He is very well aware that there are negative impacts to human biology, including the brain,
when it comes to close proximity to UAP.
I don't know if he's read the great work of OSAP and these reports, the ones that you
released to the public showing that human beings have these really devastating biological
effects.
But remember when you asked Dr.
Colin Kelleher to come on Weaponize a number of episodes ago, he really brought this up.
He talked about this.
Now, remember, this is a, for our audience, this is the government's acknowledged biggest
ever acknowledged UFO program run through the DIA, but it was the one that was funded
for 22 million called OSAP, Advanced Aerospace Weapon System Applications Program.
And one of the DIRDs, the Defense Intelligence Reference documents that you released to the
public shows a really intense knowledge, a very studied knowledge of what UAP or UFOs
can do to the human body when people come into close proximity.
Not that they're actively targeting human beings in general, but just that close proximity
to that power source.
Although there are other cases like in Cholaris, which in this new episode we talked about.
So yeah, man, it's super frustrating.
An aspect of the UFO phenomenon is human health effects.
And Dr.
Kirkpatrick damn well knows that.
I think, yeah, we had some great comments from Colin Kelleher, a biochemist who was
directly involved with OSAP.
He was one of the program managers.
He oversaw a lot of the research into the health effects.
He was directly involved with it.
He told us about that months ago.
Somehow that information has never got to the Aero folks.
I'm not sure.
I know that Kirkpatrick said they have almost 40 people on staff for Aero now,
which is a great thing.
They need to ramp it up and maybe they'll be adding more.
I wonder how many of them are medical doctors or have some kind of medical experience where
they could actually have the expertise to investigate the possible health effects.
As we have said on this program before, they've been well documented for a long time.
One of them, I mean, there's John Burroughs, that guy who got too close to the Bentwaters UFO.
His injuries were severe enough that Senator John McCain authorized,
got him authorized to have federal health benefits because his injuries were directly
related to his service during the military.
That's right.
So I remember that because when I was with Ruben Langdon and he was putting on the citizen
hearing on disclosure, which everybody should watch, it's 40 witnesses and a week of testimony
in front of five Congress people and one Senator, John Burroughs was part of the Rendlesham Forest
UFO encounters and he had a heart problem.
They wouldn't admit that he was even there because it was a UFO incident.
It was all classified.
So when he testified at that panel that we all set up there, they couldn't believe it.
They wouldn't give him health benefits because of an injury he received because
of close proximity to UFOs.
So you're right.
John McCain jumped in.
That was a letter that everybody signed that was there.
We documented that signing and it worked.
They gave him full medical benefits.
He had a life-saving surgery on his heart.
Very weird thing happened, though, when he was in surgery.
The doctor got a call from a military individual telling them exactly what to do to repair this
issue that was caused by UAP and that showed knowledge of our military and exactly what UAP
does to the heart in that situation.
He then came forward and I have this also documented where he's thanking everybody for
putting this pressure on during the citizen hearing because it did save his life.
It gave him full benefits.
It's a really neat piece of footage, but it's part of history.
It's true.
So look, yeah, the investigations into leaks is an essential part of the way intelligence
agencies work.
I get that.
I take no offense on that.
You and I as journalists, no one's coming at us.
We're obtaining information.
We're releasing it for public good as long as we vetted it and we do our best.
So I do understand why these investigations are going.
Maybe you have a different opinion, but I understand it.
No, yeah, no, I agree.
Yeah, totally agree.
Sure.
Because I mean, there might be foreign agents involved in this stuff.
They're very interested in our UFO programs and what we know about this issue for sure.
Yeah, and you and I have been notified by numerous agencies at different times when
there's a new hack to signal or that kind of thing so we can shore up our security.
Because agencies know that we have people leaking to us all the time information
and they're more concerned that a foreign nation will get it than impeding upon the
work of journalists.
So I kind of admire that if it actually stays that way, but that's what you and I have
experienced.
So I don't know.
Hopefully we find you and I find the time during this season, which I know we will have
weaponized to put out information that we vetted and we think is worthy of public discourse.
Is that what you call a tease, Jeremy?
I'm just saying, man.
I'm just saying it's hard.
We got to make sure it's worthy.
What do they say?
The juice is worth the squeeze.
That's what you and I have been kind of wrestling with for some of it.
So Sean Kirkpatrick has now said they have around 40 people working for Arrow.
That's great.
We haven't known how many people they had working.
They wouldn't even tell Congress what kind of budget they had or anything or how many
staff members they had.
40 people working for Arrow.
That's great.
We'd like to hear from some of them, maybe.
I mean, I wonder how those folks go to work every day trying to figure out these UFO
cases, UAP incidents, and then they have Kirkpatrick saying, you know, we've explained
pretty much all of them.
I wonder if those folks go along with that, if they're frustrated.
But whatever, we're not bashing their work.
We're just asking questions about their boss and what he is sharing with the public.
Right.
And I think you and I are asking that because we have a little bit of insight into the
inner mechanics of how stuff is being portrayed publicly compared to, you know, whatever
information they may be getting.
So look, bottom line, let's bottom line it because we're about to talk about what
happened last week, which is really interesting with Dr.
Lukatsky and Dr.
Colin Kelleher.
I think people need to hear how we took that interview that we did last week.
But, you know, before that, I think just looking at the idea that, okay, great, you're
looking at military cases trying to discern what shape is this?
Is this a UFO?
What's going on here?
Hold on.
If we have craft and we are exploiting those craft and they are UFOs, this is a charade,
an absolute total charade.
Arrow is a charade.
And if that's the case, it's really frustrating.
And unfortunately, I believe that to be the case.
And there's a reason why.
So last week, you asked your pal, Dr.
James Lukatsky, who is a career DIA intelligence individual who ran the UFO program for the
United States government with Dr.
Colin Kelleher, who is the project manager when they got the contract for this DIA program.
And we had him on.
Only you could get guys like this on.
Dr. Lukatsky doesn't do a bunch of interviews.
He's a buy the book kind of guy.
So there he is.
And we're reading through his book.
And you show me a certain paragraph.
And in there, he straight admits it.
He admits that our government has a UFO in their possession.
He admits that they're trying to open it up, that they have an exploitation program
with the idea of reverse engineering.
And then he admits they were able to breach the hole.
And you just fly by it in the book.
But it's so frustrating.
I wanted to really look, they're friends of ours in a way.
We're not against them.
We understand they have to hold secrecy.
That's why they have these positions of power within the DIA because they're trustworthy.
But they done did set it.
They wrote it in the book.
So you and I pushed.
We pushed really damn hard and it was frustrating for us.
And sure enough, we get them to say, yes, those events happened.
What I said is true.
And that's as far as I can go.
I understand why many of our listeners expressed frustration with the interview
because there's only so far that Dr.
Lukatsky and Colin Kelleher were willing to go.
And beyond that, they're just not going to talk about it.
That approach has served Dr.
Lukatsky well.
I mean, he was a career intelligence analyst.
He worked for DIA for a couple of decades in the defense warning office.
He's walked the walk and talked the talk.
And he does not really support full disclosure of everything right away.
He's done it a bit at a time what he can get away with.
So, you know, we had skinwalkers at the Pentagon where we revealed a lot about OSAP.
If not for Dr. Lukatsky coming forward to me and Harry Reid in 2018,
we wouldn't know anything about it.
We would have still had the New York Times story about ATIP as being the only record
about that period of history, of UFO history.
But we met with him in Washington on St. Patrick's Day in 2018, and he laid it out
about the OSAP program that had received $22 million, what they did with the money,
showed me a variety of documentation that backed up what he had to say.
And if he had not come forward at that point and in subsequent releases and interviews,
we wouldn't know anything about this stuff.
So I understand people's frustration, but we've already learned a heck of a lot
from Dr. Lukatsky about what the government knew.
And he has done it incrementally as he could get away with it with permission from
the Dobser process for the books, the two books.
The Dobser approved this new book back in April.
And it approved basically the manuscript back in April.
We've tinkered with it, and I'm a co-author.
We tinkered with some of the content since then.
But Lukatsky wanted to include the fact that, yeah, it's true.
We do have a craft.
This is, I think, before Grush's big revelations before Congress.
And he was acknowledging that we've got one, that we gained access to the middle.
He could not say where it is.
He could not say who has it.
He couldn't say who exactly got into the craft itself.
But he shared with us what he could.
That's what he could do without going to prison.
Right.
So look, it's like stepping back a second.
Dr. Lukatsky admittedly, so the negative that I've heard about him is that he's glib
and he likes holding these secrets.
I don't see it that way at all.
He's a patriot.
He's worked in the DIA.
He ran this UFO program.
That's heroic of him to get that through the Dobser process where they look at what can
you say publicly and print it in a book.
He's just a buy the book kind of guy, which you've said is the kind of guy you want in
our intelligence agencies.
But it sounds like you've had a lot of interaction.
I know you've been a fly on a wall in a lot of places.
You have a little extra information that I think is public so you can kind of push a
little bit and I can push a little bit to try to get more out.
But I think don't let that be lost on you.
So if you watch that whole last episode of Weaponized again, it's not that you see
somebody trying to hide anything.
The guy is on our podcast for God's sake.
I mean, he's coming out trying to tell you something.
But he just has confines of which he can do that.
One news station did pick it up.
News Nation is really like on this UFO thing now and they really picked it up.
When they saw that episode, they're like, wait a second.
Wait a second.
You're saying the head of the DIA UFO program straight up admitted that we have a UFO.
The government does.
We've been exploiting it.
We got inside the hall.
I'm like, yep.
They're like, come on the news.
So I did that yesterday.
It was also to promote, by the way.
I just want to say there's a two-part special on George Knapp.
They released part one last week.
And by the time you hear this, part two will have been released and look it up.
It's so cool, George.
I just got to take a second.
It shows your reporting from the mob to politics to UFOs.
It shows how you got on this weird and wild path into UFO investigating with
the Bob Lazar interview as kind of like the thing that happened right after you interviewed
John Lear.
And he laid out this hypothesis of what's going on with the government covering up UFOs.
It was just such a cool thing.
I know you hate that kind of stuff.
But as a fan of this topic, it's cool to see how we got to where we are.
You were saying things 37 years ago that now we know are true.
And I know you didn't believe it back then.
You were investigating it.
But man, that's got to be kind of weird, George, to see your whole life out on display
when it comes to your investigations on another news network.
Yeah, it's weird.
It's odd.
And I have not seen that part one yet.
I just saw the first 10 minutes of it because Sunday night I have a radio show.
So I'm prepping for that.
I've got it recorded and I'll probably watch it later today or something.
But I have not seen part two.
But yeah, it is weird to see all that unfold.
And thank God they haven't got my whole life to show on television because there's
chunks of it that would not be pretty.
But yeah, it's interesting that the ideas and concepts that we pursued 36 or 37 years ago
and that people had a hard time swallowing back then are now almost mainstream.
I mean, we've come a long way.
But it's the same stuff that Lazar and others said back then is coming to fruition now.
And hopefully it keeps marching forward.
Yeah, that news, the guy, Brian, who did the news report that I was on yesterday,
he was like, look, for most people, this is kind of new information.
I was like frustrated.
I was like, this is like the movie.
Don't look up.
It's been so obvious.
This has been said, you know, for so long.
And he's like, but for most people who were not as educated on this.
And I was kind of set back.
I'm like, okay, no, I get it.
You're right.
Let's start, you know, at level one here.
Yeah, I think it's a lot to process, though, Jeremy.
I mean, you interview people every day.
This is sort of your specialty.
For guys like me, mostly on the outside, you know, it's a lot to take in.
But what's interesting, since I've been interviewing and studying George Knapp,
your sort of partner in crime who's been doing this for almost 40 years,
you know, a lot of the stuff that you're breaking now
and the things that people are saying now,
he was reporting, you know, decades ago, like with Bob Lazar,
another person who worked out at Area 51, saw things and then first spoke with
George decades ago.
I want to play you a clip from the special on Sunday with Bob Lazar.
What's going on up there could be the most important event in history.
You're talking about contact, physical contact and proof from another system,
another planet, another intelligence.
That's got to be the biggest event in history.
Period.
And it's real.
And it's real and it's there.
But I want to bring us into so this idea that Dr. Lukatsky came on our show
and he verbally and on camera made this admission.
It was a huge deal.
Is you're officially allowed to tell us
that the United States government has in its possession a craft of unknown origin
and you were able to access the inside.
Is that correct?
The wording that you read is correct.
Ah, you're going beyond the wording.
No, I'm not.
I'm not.
I'm asking you, did that happen?
And is it true?
And it's true.
Okay, you're telling us you told us because you were allowed to tell us
that our government has a UFO in its possession
and has been able to access the inside of it, right?
Yes.
It made me kind of go back and look at the archives.
And one of the things that I found was this guy,
this researcher, this UFO researcher named Bob Exler.
And he had this, I kind of famously in my mind,
he had this interview with Admiral Bobby Ray Inman.
And Admiral Inman was, I mean, this guy was, his career was incredible.
So let me break this down real quick.
I want to play some clips and get your thoughts, George.
So Bob Exler was a national mission specialist.
A serious guy from what I understand from looking through his history,
he interviewed Admiral Inman.
And that was once Inman was out of the military.
But Admiral Inman, just check this out.
This guy in military and intelligence, he was the director of the DNI,
the Naval Intelligence until 1976, which is the role,
the same role that Scott Bray now holds from what I understand.
So Scott Bray was one of the guys that was kind of like nothing to see here,
move along in that first UFO hearing.
So that's Inman held that role back in 1976.
Then he was the vice director of the DIA until 1977.
Then he was the director of the NSA until 1981.
Then the deputy director of the CIA until 1982.
So 1981 and 82, he was both the director of the NSA and the CIA simultaneously,
which is crazy because he'd write one thing that he wanted authorized
and he'd approve it himself from what I hear.
So it was a lot of power this guy had.
So this is a guy in position to know.
With that said, oh, by the way, and then private industry.
So after his military career, he went on the board of SAIC,
Science, Applications, International Corporation.
What is SAIC, George?
Well, that's one of those big Pentagon contractors.
Those two of us who believe there is UFO information
and craft and materials stashed suspect that SAIC would be one of the likely candidates
to get that stuff.
It's right in the heart of the larger conspiracy lore.
You can't prove it for sure, but there are a lot of arrows
pointing toward SAIC as being directly involved with this.
So when he leaves all those multi-letter agencies and then goes to SAIC, another acronym,
a lot of eyebrows were raised and suspicions.
Bob Exler, as you mentioned, he was a UFO guy.
He got into the UFO field in the late 80s,
right around the time that I joined the cause, the investigation,
and stayed into it in the mid-90s.
He played a role in the Bob Lazar investigation that we can talk about later,
but he knew enough of the lingo to talk his way into a phone call with Bobby Ray Inman.
Wow, the stuff that came out and what Inman thought was an off-the-record conversation
is pretty amazing.
Yeah, so we're talking about an admission from a DIA official when it comes to Dr.
Lukaski, but he was authorized to admit the three things he did.
Our government has at least one UFO that we've been exploiting it,
trying to get inside of it, and then we did that we got inside the hall.
So that's one thing that we learned.
But going back to this Exler interview that I found, I want to see what you think about it.
So the first clip is just him kind of giving us a basic understanding of where he's coming from.
Talks about the paper trail, and I think that is how you got involved with this too,
is that our government is hiding something from us, and that pissed you off.
So let me play this first clip with Bob Exler.
What is it?
24 seconds.
I just want you to hear what he said.
And this is probably 1997, just for context.
Let's hear what he has to say.
I started out extremely skeptical about this whole thing.
I thought this was just rubbish from the tabloids,
but I was surprised to find thousands of U.S. government documents from intelligence agencies
that tended to indicate that there was a little bit more to this than met the eye.
So I went to seek guidance from the various highest levels of the United States intelligence
community, and I was quite alarmed at what I was able to learn.
Does that sound familiar to you?
I think we met Exler in 1989 at the MUFON conference and then stayed in touch with him
over the next couple of years, until up to that point.
And yeah, his voice rings a bell with me, sure.
Yeah, but I mean, also just like getting hooked on it because you realize there's all these
documents that are leading towards we're studying UFOs.
We take it very seriously.
He got hooked and he had access.
That's kind of what happened to you.
Yeah, exactly.
That's exactly the path I followed.
All right, so let's now listen.
There's just a 58 second thing, a new thing from that same interview.
I want to lead us into this interview that he had with Admiral Inman,
who made an absolute astonishing admission.
So let's hear him set it up again.
This is Bob Exler, who was investigating this, a NASA specialist who really got
bit by the UFO bug and was like, I want to find out what's going on.
Here's his next little clip.
I had contacted Admiral Bobby Ray Inman, who was the head of the National Security Agency
in the United States, Deputy Director at CIA, Director of Naval Intelligence and a variety
of intelligence posts, a technologist and clearly someone that if this was really
accurate, that there really were UFOs and non-human intelligence around,
this is a man who had to know.
So I was able to contact him thanks to a contact through Admiral Lord Hill Norton
here in the UK, and this conversation, he alarmingly not only indicated that
these issues were covered under national secrecy laws, but that the United States
government did in fact have possession of the hardware associated with this.
In other words, this was an actual physical phenomenon as a craft, a spaceship, several
of them, and they were in operational condition, which I assume suggested that they had been
in contact, that they had been given these craft for some reason or another, because
they certainly weren't crashed vehicles.
Wow. So here's a guy, he's a UFO investigator, he's got high credibility, he's got some
insight in the intelligence community because of his role at NASA, and he's like, I'm going
to call this guy, Admiral Inman, and I'm going to get through to him.
Now, I don't think he legally recorded this recording you're about to hear,
but it was an admission. He said, we have craft. They're not just crashed, almost as
like they're given to us, which would mean we have some sort of communication.
Where have we heard this before?
Bob Lazar, maybe. Yeah, yeah, and a lot. And now, now where we are now with that, there's
multiple craft, not just one, like Lukatsky, Dr. Lukatsky was able to admit, but like multiple
craft. So let's play this audio and again, understand the gravity, who he's talking with,
this former head of the CIA, DNI, I mean, NSA, this guy was involved in every intelligence
agency. He was a really respected and really trusted guy. I don't think he knew he was
being recorded. He was talking with a colleague is what he thought. But wow, let me play this
for you 25 seconds. Just hear what he said. Do you anticipate that any of the recovered
vehicles would ever be become available for technological research outside of the military
circles? So 10 years ago, he says the answer would have been no, none of this is coming
out. It's not going to get out to this broader scientific community. So that would have made
it about 1987. No way. But he's saying maybe now, maybe now this stuff is going to be able to leak
out. Again, this is in 97. Here we are in 2024. We're just starting to see maybe some of this
kind of coming out. Maybe, maybe this big mystery is going to crack open a little bit.
Yeah, 26 years later, we're finally seeing little glimpses of it. I don't think that the leaks,
what we're getting right now is part of some master plan, though. I think that the hand of those
folks keeping the secrets has been forced on this. And we know right now that the pushback is
underway in Washington at the Pentagon and other places. They're trying to plug the leaks right now.
Right. And so another thing that happened this week that's really interesting, or last week,
is that they got a skiff for David Grush to be able to go into or the documents that he has,
the reports that he has go into and inform people like Representative Burchett and others who have
the authority. So finally they got that skiff. Do you remember that? It was so weird. You and I have
been in skiffs. That's no problem for us. Why wouldn't they let a decorated intelligence officer
tell Congress for oversight what they need to know? Well, luckily we're there and we saw a post by
Representative Luna that they got the skiff. And I confirmed that with
Representative Burchett. So they're going to be able to hear what David Grush couldn't say
in the congressional hearing. Are you optimistic about that?
I'll believe it when I see it. I mean, they've already run into substantial opposition from
within their own party in the House. And, you know, I suspect that there's the hand of some
Pentagon folks and defense contractors who's been pressuring senior members of the House,
the Republican leadership to stop this, which is why there's been a problem in getting a skiff
approved, which is ridiculous. They should have had that as soon as they wanted it, asked for it.
I'm hopeful that they get to hear it. I'm hopeful the public gets to learn some of what they
are shared with, but it might be a test case, you know, where they're going to give them little
breadcrumbs and see who leaks what to see how much further information they'll get down the line.
And for our audience that's listening or watching, if you don't know what a skiff is,
it's just a secure facility where you can transmit classified information if everybody in that skiff,
you know, has the proper clearance. So it's one thing to get a skiff, but it's another thing to
make sure that everybody has proper clearance. But from what I understand, David Grush is going
to be able to tell them not only the program names for these exploitation or reverse engineering
programs for UFOs, but he's also going to be able to tell them a list of hostile and non-hostile
witnesses, people that want to talk and tell you that they've been working on these craft, first
direct firsthand individuals working on non-human intelligence craft, but also from program names
to, you know, this direct testimony of people working on the crafts, that kind of thing.
But also the locations, the locations, the holding locations of these non-human intelligence craft.
Look, man, that will be huge. If you got somebody like Representative Burchett in there,
and he hears this information, like he'll keep it confident, but he will push even harder to
get that information out. And with that meeting coming up with the DOD Inspector General, man,
it feels to me like it's colliding, like everything's colliding. Like I am optimistic
because we have rogue individuals trying to do it right, like David Grush. I feel like we're
going to make progress. I really hope so. I'm optimistic. Well, I am too. I mean, you know,
we've talked about it before on this program and elsewhere that national security implications are
inherent in this topic. You can't get around it because the technology, if you could figure out
how to reverse engineer it, how it works, it'd be an incredible boon to our defense establishment,
to the Pentagon, DOD, intelligence agencies, everybody. I mean, the weapons potential alone
would be tremendous. We're worried that our adversaries are doing the same thing, that Russia
and China and maybe some other countries are investigating this and trying to get a leap
forward in technology as an advantage over us. So national security is baked into this,
which is one reason that James Lukatsky has been reluctant to spill all the beans that he might
know. He worries that appearing before Congress, even behind closed doors, would lead to leaks.
And it would be the equivalent of telling Congress would almost be like telling Red
China in some words that I have heard. So, you know, I know people are mad at him because he
didn't tell everything he knew at once. But of course, you know, in UFO world, people are
always mad about something. But he told us what he could, what he was authorized to say,
and didn't want to go beyond it. But he's hoping to push the topic forward in coming months and
years. So I know people are mad at James Lukatsky right now, but I think he went as far as he can.
And as he has told us, there are national security implications baked into this topic,
and that will apply to Tim Burchett and Luna and other members of Congress who want to push the
ball forward. Yeah, I'm really glad you brought that up. And people are kind of like pissed. They
watched last weaponized. They think he's being evasive and Dr. Callum Keller her too. But I'm
going to remind everybody. So Dr. Lukatsky made it clear. He says national security is the number
one most important thing. This is the kind of guy we trust in the DIA. You know, he's doing his best.
He says, I'm not for disclosure when it hurts national security. But you know, obviously he
is to some degree because he's trying. He's making an effort to get this information out.
I will remind people that when we interviewed Dr. Keller her on our show, that was the first
time we had somebody running the as the program manager for the acknowledged UFO program called
awesome. He admitted that we had UFOs in government possession. He just came right up to that line.
And when I asked him, he said, yes. And that was a that was a bombshell back then. There were no
details before this this new book. There were no details. He just says, yes, we have them. And I'm
like, oh, cool. So that was something that we were able to break back then. But now there's more meat
on the bone with Dr. Lukatsky giving a little bit more information that we were exploiting it,
trying to get inside the hole. And we did. So look, there's another thing I want to play for you.
There's this little clip. There's this guy named Tom King who was in Admiral Inman's office.
So after Exler made this announcement on television or maybe just before that,
he's like, can I go public with this? And they were like, nope, it would be a big problem.
And it was just a cool little audio. They left it on his voicemail. And I thought we should play
it because this is the kind of call you and I have got. This is the kind of call we're like,
no, don't do that. So I just want to play this real quick. It's 17 seconds. But listen to this
guy, Tom King from Admiral Inman's office, kind of tell Exler, don't go public with this. Check this
out. Mr. Exler, this is Tom King in Admiral Inman's office. Yes, you would be breaching
confidence and or a violation. Discussing his involvement in any matter.
Right. So you would be breaching not only confidence, but it would be a violation of laws
in discussing, you know, Admiral Inman's involvement in any manner. I mean, man,
that kind of call is really, it sucks to get. Yeah, I love that mood music that was playing
in the background there. I don't know whether he said a hookah lounge or what was that?
That was just, I grabbed something online where I got the audio and it had like dramatic music
from a TV show. Well, I would just say that there are, you know, the pushback is real.
There are people that do not want this to come forward. That was 1997 when those exchanges
happened. We're still waiting for that crowd to come forward with what they know. I would
remind people that Lukatsky and Kelleher and Bigelow, when they were involved with OSAP,
they were trying to track this stuff down. In Skinwalkers at the Pentagon, we had a section
where we described one reason for the demise of OSAP is they went knocking on the doors
of people who were the keepers of the secrets, trying to access what they thought was a reverse
engineering program and the doors were slammed in their face and then the knives were out for OSAP
and that was the beginning of the end for the program. I noticed, so there's two more clips
I want to play where Bob Exler kind of goes big picture, like why the secrecy? Because everybody
wants to know this. Why the secrecy? Why no great photographs? Like why the secrecy? But before I
do that, I remember in our last episode of Weaponize, I mean, you were getting pretty annoyed
too. You're getting pretty heated and you asked them because you felt like, gosh, let's just say
it. But one of the things you really focused in on is, look, you guys went, so Dr. Colin Kelleher and
Dr. Lukatsky were trying to figure out where the good, as you say, the goodies are held, where the
UFOs, where the saucers are held and you were really pushing them on that. Can you explain that
a little bit? Well, you could sense that I've had these conversations before with those guys in
private and it has gone a little bit further, well, much further than what we're allowed to say in
public. So I was trying to encourage Dr. Lukatsky to use the platform available to go ahead and say
more about it and I wasn't getting anywhere with either one of them. They're my friends, they're my
co-authors. I know them really well and you do too. So we wanted to get what we could while the
moment was available to us. So we tried and we're still in good terms with those guys, but
that's our job, is to try to push a little bit further. Yeah, and they respect it and I'm sure
in some way they want to be pushed further. And I think we definitely got Lukatsky just that one
millimeter further when he says, yes, it's true. Yes, it happened or whatever. I was like, whoa.
So, but yeah, it's got to be frustrating to you all these years. Again, looking back, if you watch
the new special, you see that you've been on this case from the beginning. I mean, everything John
Lear was saying to you sounded so crazy back in the day in 1987 or wherever you first interviewed
him. But along the way, we've learned so much of this is real. So I want to think big picture now.
I want to think about the same interview with Exler. He kind of said some really profound
things. Let me play you a clip. It's about it's a minute and a half and it's just kind of how he
threw down. And I believe it's 1997 when this was done, this interview, but just hear what he had
to say a minute and a half. And I want to get your response. Check this out. His governments,
the Canadian government, the American government, if they are in possession of spacecraft, if they
have made contact with aliens, why don't they tell us? What I was able to learn is that the
issue of secrecy dates back into the early 1950s. And in 1959, actually, NASA had a study
conducted by the Brookings Institution in Washington, D.C., addressing the issue of whether
this alarming issue of a confrontation with an extraterrestrial culture should be released to
the public, this information. It was determined that there would be grave consequences for just
an overt public pronouncement by government officials. What does that mean? We would all
panic. Well, not necessarily just panic, but the issues that it presented, not only theology,
but issues involving economics, standards of monetary concerns. If you acknowledge a type
of technology that renders fossil fuel-related industries obsolete, for example, you have
grave consequences economically all the way around the world. All our values are rendered.
So the determination was made that the only way to avoid this chaos would be through a slow
indoctrination process over a matter of decades. The decisions to maintain secrecy regarding this
center more around not upsetting the economic apple cart, religion, theology issues that come
into play, and quite a number of issues that essentially center around science and technology.
How does that hold up now, all these years later, what he was saying?
Well, I think some of those concerns are still a reason to keep this stuff secret.
There would be disruption of the world's economy, the fossil fuel industry. At a time when our
planet is baking and climate change is real and we're seeing the consequences all over,
maybe it is time to reevaluate our reliance on fossil fuels. Do we just keep going with that
and cook the planet even though it's as dire consequences for the future of humanity?
There would be repercussions if we released this stuff. But as Exler says, and as many people have
said, and as the Brookings report said, you'd have to do this over time. Well, it's been a long time.
That Brookings report came out in 1960. We're a long way down the road. We're 63 years
since then. I think the public is ready for it. I think we have been conditioned to accept it,
and I don't think there would be tremendous turmoil in religious circles or social institutions would
necessarily collapse, depending on what the ultimate truth really is. We don't know what it is yet.
Yeah, and just to kind of affirm and confirm to people, like, look, you and I were interested
in this. You've been doing this for so long. We're not part of some government conspiracy. I mean,
look, that would be super fun if we were leaked stuff so we could put it out, just, you know,
Machiavellian messing with the consciousness of humanity across the globe about UFOs. I wish my
life was that exciting. We're hungry for the information, too. This is not an organized
attempt. In fact, we've had to fight for every millimeter when it comes to confirmation of this
information. But just hearing Exler talk about that, look, this has been something that we have
been kind of fighting for for a long time. It's been so obvious, again, like that movie, Don't
Look Up. It's so obvious if you really get in there and start looking. And now that we know a
lot of the people involved, they're not coming forward willingly. We're having to pull teeth.
Now, the next thing is the legislation. This has not been finally decided yet,
but we are in a good place. If this legislation goes through as powerfully, the UFO legislation
right now and the National Defense Authorization Act and the Intelligence Authorization Act,
man, it's going to put pressure on private industry where this technology that you and I know has been
sequestered to, to say, what do you got? You can keep it. You know, us as the government can't
directly work on it. We want you to keep it, but you got to admit it. We have to have oversight.
So I'm hopeful, fingers crossed, it will be a huge day if that legislation, Schumer's legislation,
if that gets passed and President Biden signs it, it's going to have major impact.
Closest thing we'll ever get to confirmation is right now. Yeah, I mean, I'm almost hopeful,
which is incredible because I'm usually pessimistic. I'm also hopeful, almost hopeful
that that legislation will pass. But as we have discussed here many times, you know, it's always
unpredictable. UFOs have been on the front burner in the past. There's peaks and valleys of public
interest and congressional interest. And something always comes along that trumps UFOs. Right now,
Congress is a mess. You know, the House of Representatives can't pick its next leader.
They're shut down, in essence. There's no going forward on budgets. There's still the looming
possibility that there will shut down the U.S. government. There's impeachment proceedings
against President Biden. There's war in the Ukraine. There's terror in the Middle East.
There's always something more important and more pressing than UFOs. So I'd like to say that I am
hopeful. I am a little bit, but I'll believe it when I see it. So let me play this last part.
It's a minute and 11 seconds. And this is again, Bob Exler. And he's kind of summarizing kind of
what's going on, this idea that we might not be the top of the food chain. I just want to give it
as food for thought as we end this episode of Weaponize. So check this out. We do have to come
to grips with the reality that perhaps human beings aren't the only intelligence in the
universe and that they have in fact been here to visit in spite of projects like the NASA SETI
project, the search for extraterrestrial intelligence in deep space. There are serious
issues associated with this. And we have a mentality where we like to kind of poke fun at
the issue through tabloids and so forth. You know, if there's one that comes, there's obviously going
to be more. And just like we have different species of humans on this planet, I'm quite certain
there's different species of alien life forms. So we could run into mental evidence. In fact,
President Reagan on several occasions alerted concern about the potential hostilities from
outer space and why it would be important for us to work together on this planet with superpowers
and so on uniting. Clearly the problem that we're confronted with here is that although
technologically these beings may be more intelligent than us, we appear to be more
advanced in areas of civility. We have emotions and things like that. We have concern for our
fellow man, whereas that doesn't seem to be the case necessarily in some of these other cultures.
What do you think of that? Well, it raises the kind of big questions that we tackle all the time.
I mean, the fact is we don't know the ultimate truth. I don't know, we don't know anybody who
knows all of it. David Grush, Jim Lakatsky, Callum Kelleher, Robert Bigelow, Bob Lazar,
all those guys know more than we do maybe, but we're not quite sure what the ultimate truth is.
So it's hard to predict what the effect on society will be, what the effect on the planet will be,
and we don't know what it is that's going to be disclosed. We have a long way to go on this,
and there are legitimate concerns both for national security and how the public handles
whatever the disclosure might be. The best we can do is keep plugging away at it.
Yeah, it reminds me, I saw this thing recently where President Gorbachev, where he came out
way later, and there was this meeting that he had with Reagan where they were walking alone,
and they dismissed all of their individuals surrounding them. And I think Reagan was in
Russia at the time, and they were taking a walk. And Gorbachev admitted that what Reagan said to
him, and this is like, he admitted it, like this video of this, he says, you know, look,
if we were, if the United States was attacked by an extraterrestrial species, would you guys defend
us? Would you guys have our back? And Gorbachev said, absolutely. And so did Reagan. So at that
time, when you see him at the UN making those big statements about if we were attacked by somebody
else, you know, that came from something, that came from the idea that we don't know what this is.
And I do believe now it appears that we have technology of unknown origin from what appears
to be non-human intelligence. Was that given to us? Or is that something that we got from a crash
retrieval? These are big questions. We just don't know. But David Grush says that he has the holding
locations. I know he actually does. So the holding locations of these crap, full on UFOs. We are this
close if we keep pushing within the next year or so to get more information on this. So I will
kind of remain optimistic until proven otherwise. It's an exciting time to study the UFO topic.
It's got to be exciting for you to see all this coming out.
Oh, very much so. Yeah. After all these years. You know, there was the late Stan Friedman used to say
one reason for the cover-up could be that when the people of Earth start thinking of themselves as
Earthlings rather than as Americans or Russians. Well, no government in the world wants that.
They don't want us to think on a global scale. They like the idea of us being nationalistic and
provincial. So that might be a reason why it's been so hard to get some of them to cough up what they
know. We'll see. We'll see where it goes. All right, man. Well, thanks so much. And I know
that with the remaining episodes of Weaponized for this season, I hope that we can put some
really great stuff into those episodes. Everybody stay tuned and thanks so much,
George. Talk to you later.
Entertainment and Cadence 13 Studios available now for free on the Odyssey app or wherever you get your shows.