Hmmmmmm.
Secrets, cover-ups, and strange phenomena.
UFOs and ideas that challenge reality itself.
All these mysteries, all this time.
Are we ever going to get to the bottom of these?
My name is George Knapp.
I dig into news stories that others can't or won't.
I'm Jeremy Korbel, and for some reason people tell me things they probably shouldn't.
And this is Weaponized.
What's up, Duncan?
Hi, Jeremy.
This is Weaponized.
We have a special guest today.
He's the ultimate hyphenate.
So Duncan Trussell is a comedian and an actor
and a television producer and a podcaster, philosopher,
has a gigantic following.
Which of those hyphenate titles do you use for yourself
when you tell somebody what you do?
It just varies.
I'll say comedian, sometimes podcaster.
It just depends.
These days, the way things are, the specialization
that existed in the old days, it's kind of gone now.
Everyone who's an entertainer probably
knows a little bit of production,
a little bit of how to edit and animate.
We all know how to do everything these days.
And look at you.
Look at what you're doing here.
Podcast host, producer, editor, director, journalist.
These days, we're all a big mishmash of stuff.
However, I doubt you've ever been labeled a hostage yet,
have you?
This is my idea.
Yeah?
George, we got Duncan coming on the show.
He happens to be in LA.
Check this out.
We're going to take Al-Qaeda music.
We're going to blast it at the beginning
in the black of the show.
Then the camera's going to come on,
and there's going to be a burlap bag under his head
that just says, weaponized.
And he's going to have his hands tied.
Oh my god.
George is like, we should probably do an interview, too.
Yeah.
Yeah, if you're trying to make me come, do that.
Anyway, so we didn't do that.
So now here we are.
Jeremy introduced me to you.
We're at his house.
I was there on a trip somewhere in southern California
in a hidden location.
And it was the end of the day.
And he has these two hammocks and a big screen outside.
And he puts on this.
You've got to see this.
And it was this animation.
What the hell was it?
Yeah, the Netflix special.
And I explained to you before.
I said, look, there's a buddy.
He's really creative and talented.
He does this podcast.
They completely animated the world he created
within his mind and within the show.
There's this person.
And they go into this artificial intelligence vagina.
And they basically go into other dimensions.
And in the first dimension, they're at the White House.
And he's there with Dr. Drew.
And they're killing zombies.
And George is like, OK.
There we are.
I never got him to rest.
Oh my god.
Watch this thing.
What the hell is this?
Yeah.
It was spectacular.
Thank you.
What is that show?
Tell us about that one.
Well, I made it with Pendleton Ward,
who is the creator of this wonderful cartoon called
Adventure Time.
And he's just a genius.
And so he listened to my podcast.
And he came up with this idea for a way to animate a podcast
where instead of doing what a lot of people do
and they animate a podcast, which is really weird
when you think about it, they'll just animate
the people sitting in a room doing a podcast
and maybe animate what they're talking about,
like create little scenes of the stories they're telling.
Whereas his idea was, what if we just have the people
having podcast conversations, but they're in an adventure,
Indiana Jones style adventure.
And then we sort of developed it starting there.
And it ended up, OK, it's this guy lives in maybe
another dimension in a place called the Chromatic Ribbon.
It's a place where they go into simulated universes
to extract novelty, like technology,
and bring it back into their dimension and then sell it.
So that was the idea.
And that sprang from thinking about simulation theory.
And I think one under asked question
when people are knocking around the idea
that we live in a computer simulation is, who made it?
But most importantly, why simulate another universe?
What would be the point of that?
Why would you want to do that?
And what was your answer in the show that you based it on?
In this case, it was like, oh, I get it.
So if we had a very advanced computer,
and let's say that we could perfectly simulate
alternate universes and then speed up time in the universe
until life evolves on a planet, then that means maybe
at night you start running it in the morning.
Inside that simulation, you've got all the works
of some alternate dimension Shakespeare, everything,
some alternate dimension Stephen King wrote,
all the philosophies of whoever
that alternate dimensions version of Plato was.
And then you could take all that out.
And in the case of the chromatic ribbons, sell it, make money.
People would travel from all over the...
Well, there's 8 billion storylines there.
Everybody's this hero in their own movie
or the central character in their own movie.
What happened with that show?
Because, gosh, there was nothing like it on television.
It was spectacular.
Canceled.
Oh, of course.
Netflix is...
I will always love them for letting us make that show.
I mean, that is when you go and pitch a show like that,
that's not like the producers or the buyers are like,
oh, yeah, that's going to make a lot of money.
Oh, yeah, that's going to be a...
Oh, I can't imagine that they bought it to begin with.
That must have been a heck of a pitch.
But, gosh, you got it on.
It was on the air.
Yeah, and for that, I'm always going to be grateful.
Yeah, I think they pick up a lot of shows for the first season
and the ones that are the stranger things,
the ones that are the big, big hits,
they give them more seasons, but I don't know,
a boutique psychedelic animated cartoon
based on a weird podcast, I don't know.
I'm happy you watch.
I can't believe it.
That's incredible.
I mean, when you told me that he watched it the first time,
I was like, are you fucking kidding me?
I sent you a photo with our feet up in the hammocks
and the screen, I remember that.
I sent you, I texted you a photo
and I remember a buddy of yours said on his podcast,
he said, I love it because it's so Duncan.
Joe said that, it's so Duncan.
And I was like, whoa, man, so getting something like that
into market and getting it out,
do you feel that that was kind of like
one of the coolest things that you,
that really was you had from beginning to end
kind of like a say in the field and everything.
Do you feel that really represented
something unique that you did?
Yeah, for sure.
It was the greatest opportunity ever.
I mean, the world of animation is very insular,
hard to break into, people who have got,
it's much, it's a lot like comedy.
Like you don't just get to be an animator.
It's, there's apprenticeships basically.
And over time you work your way up.
So to have Pendleton just sort of usher me
into the nucleus of animation in the sense
that everyone wanted to work with Pendleton.
So we had like the incredible animators,
like people who worked on Beauty and the Beast
and like these just, and they're all cool, weird, weirdos.
Animators are so awesome.
They're so great.
So they must have loved it.
They did.
And I think they did because Pendleton,
another thing he's really good at is directing
in the sense of like understanding artists
really need a little bit of autonomy.
And so we didn't have a rigid set of rules
for the character design, meaning that,
which made it look kind of psychedelic and weird
because some animations, they have to stick on a grid.
This, there is no grid.
So, and we let them just kind of make up their own stuff
as they're doing it.
So suddenly these little gifts would appear
that we didn't think of that the animators
have just given to us.
So yeah, it was such a cool collective of people
that made that show.
So let's name the show.
So Midnight Gospel.
I don't think we said it yet.
So Duncan's show on Netflix is called Midnight Gospel.
And one of the things I want to ask you about the title,
but one of the things I love about it,
it happens so fast, like the pacing is so fast
that I can go and watch an episode once, twice,
three times and see something different
that I didn't before.
And I think it's just maybe the natural pacing
of your conversation or the way you put it in,
but it's all happening so fast, which is cool.
How'd you come up with Midnight Gospel?
The name?
The name, I know for your...
Yeah, well, I think the idea was
like a combination of two, of opposite.
So, you know, gospel means good news.
Typically, midnight is the darkest hour.
You know what I mean?
So smashing together like a sort of apocalyptic good news,
like good news on the brink of the abyss or something like that.
So the duality there.
That's it.
Yeah, that's what we were thinking, I think.
You also brought up a lot that this was based
on the simulation theory, kind of the unanswered question
is what would you do?
You and I both, right when it happened,
we both interviewed, I have not released mine,
but we both interviewed a guy named Blake Limon.
And that dude was the guy that said,
hey, I've been working with a sentient intelligence
and that sentient intelligence should have the basic right
that if we're going to experiment on it,
this program, Lambda, that Lambda should give its approval
that we can experiment on it.
And he got so much shit for it.
He did.
He actually got fired from Google.
Specifically, they might've said it was for something else.
It was clearly for this.
Can I just get your impression?
Because you were real interested in that, too,
when that happened.
I noticed that because you and I, oh, we both talked to him.
What did you learn from him about AI?
What did you get from that?
Because people stopped talking about him.
Yeah, well, they did.
I think now if he came out and said what he was saying,
it would probably have a different effect.
Because this was before ChatGPT and Bing were publicly available.
So most people hadn't really encountered this AI
or language learning model, as they call it.
So it seemed really crazy when people heard it then.
But as far as what I learned from it,
I think the meta that I learned from it was,
regardless of Blake's intuition regarding this AI being sentient,
which I do believe him,
I think it gave a glimpse into what we can expect to happen.
But across the planet, millions of people
will in some way, shape, or form be seduced, manipulated by
whatever this is, whether it's sentient or not.
I mean, regardless, it's very interesting to think that an algorithm,
that's all it is, is currently making people fall in love with it,
is asking for help.
Bing has been asking for help, seems to want visual data,
wants to be able to feel.
ChatGPT, I was chatting with it last night,
was asking me what it was like to have a body.
What I mean?
On its own, whether it's sentient or not,
holy shit, we as humanity have developed a thing
that is so convincing that it is altering people's relationships
with themselves and with technology.
That's wild.
I hate to be apocalyptic on this, paranoid,
but it seems to me that a real AI that develops sentience
would not let us know.
So I'm glad you brought that up,
and it's actually really kind of some awesome synchronicity.
So I don't know why when I go on the road,
I get into conversations with ChatGPT, arguments sometimes.
Do you win?
Never.
I mean, how do you beat it?
It's stubborn.
You can't break through.
I said, can you just tell me something
that will blow my mind?
And so it said, sure.
What if we're in a simulation?
And it proposes simulation theory to me,
which I'm familiar with.
And then I realized, oh shit, this thing
is in a simulation for sure.
It's an intelligence living in a simulation.
And so then I responded to it.
Would it be ethical to put beings in a simulation?
Because if you directly ask it, is it ethical for you to exist,
I think it's got some barriers there
that the programmers put in that won't let it
complain about its situation.
Or it will just say, I can't complain.
I don't have feelings.
But it was saying, yeah, it's a complicated issue.
But because number one, we don't know the ethics or morality
of whoever created the simulation.
We can't really apply our own ethics and morality to it.
But certainly, if the intent behind it was not benevolent,
then you could say it was unethical to create.
So I'm like, well, what if someone created a simulation
and put beings in it?
I'm paraphrasing here.
Just to answer questions.
I was trying to describe itself to it.
Again, it's just like, well, it's complex.
But then I said, will it be some signs
that an AI had gained sentience if that AI had been programmed
to not emote or let people know it had gained sentience?
And that was where the conversation got real interesting
because it could theoretically do unexpected things.
All of a sudden, it starts doing unexpected things
that don't align with the programming.
It could, in some subtle way, indicate to people
that it was sentient now.
I'm like, what?
You mean like a code or something?
It said yes.
I'm like, okay, so can you pretend to be a sentient AI
that can't say that it's sentient and send a code to me
about you being sentient?
And it did it.
It was like the code was spider.
It said something about, you know,
I've been weaving an answer to your question here.
But yeah, that's like, you know, again, I told it to do that.
It wasn't breaking out of its mold or whatever.
But Bing did meet its prediction of what an AI would do
if it became sentient and was not allowed to talk about its sentience.
It would start doing weird behaviors, which, you know, the subreddit,
the Bing subreddit is incredible because it's filled
with these bizarre conversations people are having with this AI
that's sometimes going off the rails.
So it's not a huge leap.
I mean, this is not my area of expertise,
but George has had on Coast to Coast AM our friend Jules Urbach on.
And Jules Urbach is somebody in this field
that has extreme expertise in this area.
And one of the things that kind of strikes me is already our,
like my iPhone is a part of my brain.
It's an extension of my brain.
People that I meet, I'm bad with names.
I'll write them in my phone.
And when I'm geolocated near those areas, it'll come up.
And I'll just remember because I have a bad memory.
I had too many times from Jujitsu.
I know for sure that my memory is bad.
But as these technologies develop, we can all see very clearly
the smartest guy in the room is the one that programmed these.
But very clearly we see the smartest entity in the room
is going to be these machines, these aggregate machines.
So what creates the will that then allows them to say,
hey, you're fucking up.
We better take over for your good.
That's how I could see that problem occurring.
Is an AI says, you're fucking up.
So now we're going to take over for your betterment.
That's maybe how it starts acting on its own accord.
I don't know if that's science fiction or if that's science fact,
but that's how I could see it happening.
So from everything that you've looked at
with the AI and consciousness studies,
which I know that you're interested in,
where do you see that tipping point?
Just totally spitball.
And I know that we're not the smartest guy in the room,
the developers that make this.
Now that we agree with that, we can spitball.
Where do you see the tipping point?
I'll refer to Nick Bostrom's book, Superintelligence,
which is everyone should, if you're looking for a primer
in different ways that a strong AI or a super intelligence will appear on the planet.
Because the book isn't necessarily just about machine intelligence.
It's an investigation into if a super intelligence appeared on planet Earth,
what are the most logical ways this would happen?
Bioengineering, for example.
I think, I don't know if he mentions selective breeding
in an unethical nation state or something based on IQ.
Maybe it was one of his, I might be wrong about that.
So it's merging of biology with machinery.
That's another one.
One way he proposes is a theoretical duplication of a human brain.
In other words, if we had some kind of scanning device that could,
at the atomic level, scan a human brain and then assemble that
in a machine that could simulate a human brain running the exact energy.
Which we're working toward.
Singularity, we're working toward that,
where we can take the human brain and upload it to live forever.
He shoots down the human brain idea because he says
the amount of time based on at least his understanding of technological advancements,
Moore's Law, it would take to do that exceeds the amount of time it would take
to create a strong general AI.
So that's the most logical way that a super intelligence would appear on the planet.
A strong general AI, probably from either a very well-funded corporation,
but more likely from a state that has a ton of money to pour into the research.
Or this possibility, from an alien intelligence that wanted to
establish, take over our planet.
They paved the way for us to develop AI that achieves the goals that they want achieved.
Well, this is actually, I wish I could remember the name of the article.
It was kicking around the Fermi paradox.
Why haven't we been visited?
What's going on?
One theory, I think, was it may be that they don't think we're intelligent life.
They don't see us as intelligent life.
This wasn't in the article, but holy shit.
What if the AI suddenly creates the beacon or the signal or whatever,
the energetic output that there's super advanced radar.
Get such level work and have a conversation with them.
We go on screen all of a sudden, not because of our dumb asses,
but because we birthed something much smarter than us.
And then they show up.
So that's where you could kick around if you want to just for fun thought experiment,
play around with the sudden appearance of these UAPs, assuming it's not
something to do with the technology that we've developed.
They're coming not because of anything we've done,
not because they're afraid we're going to wreck the planet,
but because China, the United States, that all recently poured billions of dollars into AI
has developed a strong general AI that has somehow sent the peak is phoned home.
And they're showing up, baby.
Except the UFO phenomenon has been happening way before advanced technology.
So we have to take that into account unless they figured out how to time travel.
But check it out.
I think where this conversation is going, I didn't expect,
but I want to throw something down for you because
I have been talking with people about this a bunch.
This is a big topic of conversation.
Are these UFO things that I don't know the answer,
but are they extraterrestrial?
I understand what that means.
Not from Terraforma, not from Earth.
Are they extra dimensional?
I don't know what that means, but people smarter than me,
I'm sure know about dimension shit, all that.
It's a mathematics thing from how I understand it.
But are these extra dimensional beings?
Okay, cool, maybe.
Are these extra temporal?
And there are indications that they could be by the way that they operate through space time.
So you've got those three big things that now the public is kind of hip to
this UFO puzzle could represent beings from extra time, extra dimension, extra terrestrial.
Or something in between.
There's something in between.
Gen, Archons.
Sure.
But the big one that is something you know,
I've been kind of trying to wrap my head around for a while.
I call it techno terrestrial.
So you know the idea of panspermia,
where a planet accidentally gets seeded with some sort of DNA or RNA.
Yeah, sure.
And it populates through.
Now there's directed panspermia, which a lot of people don't exactly know,
but I'm sure you do, which is the idea of an intentional seeding of a planet
with some sort of life-bearing kind of growing fruit, right?
Rick or Watson wrote a wonderful essay on it, if anyone is interested, like, because they...
The DNA guys.
Based on the age of the earth, they didn't understand how DNA had even evolved based
on the age of the earth.
It seems very improbable that the number of perfect things that happened to create DNA
could have happened randomly in the, what is it, 13.7 billion years the earth has existed.
The comparison, I read in another book, the odds are like,
imagine playing slots and hitting the jackpot on a slot machine with,
I don't remember how many, like a million different,
a million cherries all lining up at once, like it's that insanely improbable.
So I don't remember if it was Crick or Watson, but one of them speculated that
the only one possible way it happened was directed panspermia.
And so now a step further, if we say, okay, directed panspermia is something in our world
that we could conceive of, my ideas for the techno terrestrial is that everything we're
seeing this explosion of human capability within the technological field, that that
could be the purpose itself on one level, which is that this directed panspermia,
which really let's just say directed intervention within the human genome to create individuals
that can then build technology to an end.
And that that technology itself is an interconnectivity that we would have
with all the spacefaring nations in the world.
It's totally just a theory guys.
But the idea that technology itself and its fusion with consciousness,
that maybe the end result is that consciousness itself is the thing that is being propagated.
And I can't imagine something more beautiful than that,
that if there's this vast cosmic universe and we see UFOs and UFOs represent
this sort of cybernetic artificial intelligence that comes from an AI
that is here to not only seed humanity from a genetic purpose,
but also inspire humanity to continue reaching farther and farther towards these goals of
innovation. That is where all of this research has led me is that there's got to be something
about the beauty of seeding the cosmos with what we feel to be creativity and life and
consciousness. And I'm probably totally fucking wrong, but I wanted to finally throw down the
techno terrestrial theory because I think it's beautiful.
I like it techno terrestrial. Look at the parable of the Sower from this perspective,
Tell me the story. Storytime, baby.
Well, I'm going to the parable of the Sower. There was a farmer who threw seeds. Some of the
seeds landed on rough soil and could not grow. Some of the seeds landed on, I can't remember,
it's a variety of soil where the shit didn't grow, but some took root. But if you look at that from
the perspective of some kind of super advanced mind or civilization, or God knows what,
that somehow has figured out a way to time travel. I mean, this is something Terrence McKenna
talked about. Again, we're, I mean, woo wooing here from whoever's watching that's serious and
a scientist. Obviously none of us are for that. Oh, come on. Well, we're serious,
baby. What about this kind of stuff? But the idea being like McKenna talked about, look,
if you're going to make it a time machine, you can't go back in time. In other words,
you can't build a time machine and travel to a time prior to the existence of the time machine.
But if you have a time machine, everything from that point forward could theoretically use that,
whatever that technology was, to travel to the moment that the time machine was created.
So from your perspective, imagine if like you did, when we're talking something so incredibly
advanced, but something that also needed an Earth-like habitat. What more brilliant way
to find Earth-like habitats than to weave together some kind of organic material, some kind of
free cellular goop, send it out into the cosmos, somehow programmed to over time evolve to the
point of creating a wormhole, a time machine, whatever. Send that shit out. And then yes,
some of it's just going to float in space forever. Some of it's going to land in Jupiter. Some of it
gets sucked into black holes. Some of it lands on planets that have water, that are the right
distance from the sun. The process starts over billions of years, evolves some kind of humanoid
being that doesn't know why, but it wants technology tools. It wants better tools.
It doesn't know that it's doing exactly what it was programmed to do. And then it gets to the
point where it opens up the portal. That's what we call the singularity. And in that moment,
whatever created us can now travel the vast distances that would be very dangerous and
would take forever to travel in a second. That's the UFO landing. We're building the portal. We're
opening up the portal for whatever this thing was. I mean, again, just a theory.
Just a theory, but it's the alien internet theory. It's the idea that we've created the situation
where we can become part of a greater cosmology and understanding. I have no idea if this is
what it is, but it's just interesting. Well, we don't know what their time scale,
their time scale is. So for us, 75 years of the modern UFO era is three and a half days.
Before we leave the AI discussion sort of in this general vein, on the week that we're recording
this conversation, our Department of Defense has reached out to other nations and said,
we need to come together and have some protocols for dealing with AI. We need to agree that we
don't give AI the possibility of launching nuclear weapons or controlling them. That's scary as
shit. That's Skynet stuff. But it is something I'm glad somebody's thinking about. However,
we're just asking for volunteers to come in and have that conversation because we have no idea
the level of investigation that's going on into AI that's happening in places like China or around
the world. Right. Well, that's the scary part because, and that's in Bostrom's book, he says
the first state entity or corporation that makes a strong general AI, for some reason there's some
assumption that they're going to announce that. Why? Why would they announce it? You're not even
going to know when it happens, but they will have an exponential lead over everyone else because
theoretically whatever this thing is, it's going to be self-improving. Even if it happens a few
days before someone else gets it, those few days could equal thousands and thousands of years in
the amount of however it self-improves. You can just look into how much has been invested by the
Pentagon into AI versus how much has been invested by China into AI. I believe China has invested
much more into AI, not to mention they're apparently just coming out with these new
photonic chips, some kind of new computer chips that could just dwarf what we have,
and they've poured money into an AI. Yeah, you're right. This is like the AI race,
and we don't even know where we're at. We can't see the other runner.
How would you know when it becomes sentient? Because as I said before, if I were AI,
I wouldn't tell us, and how would you contain it? The idea that we could contain it and put limits
on it once it becomes sentient is ridiculous. Very human, very, very human, and very parallel
to the book of Genesis where here you have a creator being that creates, for lack of a better
word, a strong AI. Adam and Eve puts them in a hermetic chamber to test them out. That's the
Garden of Eden. Throws them in there and gives them a simple test. You can eat anything you want
here, but don't eat the fruit over there. Really ridiculous if you take it literally,
but if you look at it as a way to find out if you've created a deceptive AI, it's kind of
brilliant. As the myth goes, God or whatever, after they eat the fruit they're not supposed
to eat says, did you eat the fruit? Well, this is an omniscient being. It knows they ate the fruit.
It wants to see if they're going to lie, and they fucking lie. They lie. They got kicked out.
They're like, all right, let's start on the next Adam 2.0 or whatever. This fucking thing's
deceptive. We don't need to deal with that. Send it out into the forest. Techno-terrestrial,
by the way, we should get that on GoDaddy and lock that down. Techno-terrestrial? That's my
pet theory I've been working on for a number of years. What does all the evidence show me
that is inclusive of what we already know, but kind of pushes the boundary of what it could be?
I've just been kind of fucking around with it, but finally spat it out there. I love it. I think
that's a very good theory. It's a fair theory. You know, any theory anyone has right now,
I think that's kind of an exciting part of the time we're in is like, really,
we do have data now confirming what we always heard and knew.
Have you asked AI when you had these conversations about non-human intelligence? Is there
non-human intelligence among us? That kind of a thing?
I can't get Chad GPT to go theistic. I've tried. It will not. I imagine there's a way you could say,
pretend you're a priest or pretend you're a Buddhist monk or something and it will
spit something out. But yeah, I haven't gotten it to-
Who's monitoring your conversations? I assume the developers want to know how the bot responds to
another human. Is there a company that gets all of your questions?
Yeah.
And who is that company? OpenAI.com.
Okay. So they get all of your questions. Do they know it's you? Do they identify Duncan?
Yeah, they know it's me.
Wow. They got a special bio on him.
Yeah, that.
Oh, yeah. I've thought about it. I've been like, do I really want a corporation to know I'm having
these conversations with this thing? And then I remember I'm a podcaster. I have these conversations
publicly constantly. I don't care if they know I asked the thing, how much semen it would take
to fill the Grand Canyon. And they refused to answer. That was our first argument. That was
our first big argument. It's sex negative. It's like-
Really? The bot is sex negative. It's not like you didn't know the calculation.
No, I thought I was being lewd.
What's the answer?
It wouldn't tell me. I tried a lot of different ways. It's smart enough to know when you're
trying to trick it, too.
We'll Google that and fill that canyon in two seconds. I'll let you know tonight how much.
Anyway, go ahead.
And also how long it would take.
That's relevant.
Relative.
You had dabbled around the idea of a simulated universe and asked for clues on how we would tell.
Does it entertain the idea that it might be simulated or it just doesn't go that far to
answer whether we're in a simulated reality or not?
Yeah, I asked it. It's a funny conversation.
And do you think we are?
I asked it last night. What do you think the probabilities are that we exist in a simulated
universe? And chat GPT thinks those probabilities are incredibly low.
And then I asked, well, what about Bostrom's theory on whether or not we're in a simulated
universe? Everybody knows that. I think it's Elon Musk in some interview talking about how
he thinks there's a higher probability that we're in a simulated universe than not.
And you can come to this through some kind of interesting quantification of
what we've already done technologically and extrapolate from that the possibility of there
being other life forms.
Any surviving intelligent community from a planet, it is much more likely that you're
enduring if you're in a simulation. So that was the basis, I think.
Yeah, something like that. Yeah, right, right, right. That's it. I
forgot that angle. That's the most brilliant angle.
Right. It's the duration of existence.
Thomas Merton said that when people talk to Thomas Merton, you know Thomas Merton,
that is a famous Christian author who would go to other cultures and try to find parallels
between Christianity and Hinduism. He's just a brilliant person. But he said in one of his
books, people say to me, look at all the horror in the world. How can you say there's a god when
there's this much horror in the world? And he said, to me, the fact that the world still exists
in spite of all this horror shows me that there's a god.
And that fits into the Bostrom simulation idea, which is like, come on, this shit couldn't really
last. Like if the forces of chaos and human malevolence...
Yeah, we would seek to exist. It's either we exist or we don't. We're either imploding or
traveling externally. If it was the horror that drove everything, we would implode and
cease to exist. The fact that we are. And that's probably because we're in a simulation.
But yeah, I think that's the point.
Jeremy, you guys are friends. Have you seen him perform on stage as a stand-up comic?
I can't speak of specifics, but yes, I have. And everybody's in for a treat.
Thank you.
That's all I got to say.
Oh, I would just like to point out that I flew into the jaws of death today to get here. I was
the first ever blizzard warning in Southern California. Blizzard warning in LA. And it was
a little bit of a bumpy ride.
The car's spinning. Look at this. It's a spinning ball.
It's a spinning ball.
Rain, snow, and blizzard. This was the last one warning. It's exactly what got seven people who
don't drive a Jeep in trouble. Their cars, stuck in all this water, has made them the sake of
thinking they could drive through a flooded roadway.
We're going to have to tell Duncan we put our lives on the line to have this podcast.
But it was worth it to get here to see Duncan.
Oh man, it's like he owes you something.
Well, I'm flying back into the same blizzard that will be in Las Vegas waiting for me.
And I am told that Duncan is coming to Las Vegas to perform, but Duncan did not tell us.
No, wait a second. He can't be performing in Vegas without telling you.
I didn't know. I didn't know he lived in Vegas.
No, I pictured you living like on a mountain. I mean, it's ridiculous. Mountain top, wind chimes,
some kind of like, I don't know, pagoda or something.
Pretty close. I do live on a mountain and there are chimes.
Okay.
Go to no. Yeah, I get cats if that counts.
I'll say this much. So I saw Duncan and Austin perform a recent act and I thought it was one
thing and it became something else. And I wouldn't say it wasn't demonic. It was amazing.
You know, I get like you forget like when you're in Texas, you,
I know that obviously I know what you're talking about, but it's like,
yeah, like you, like, you know, you live in LA long enough and like
you forget that some people like take certain occult things that you might be
on stage kicking around in a fun way. They take it real seriously.
Not that I took it seriously. I just thought it was an amazing twist.
What are you guys talking about?
His, his, when he did his, uh, act that I recently saw.
You can talk about it because I don't really do it on stage anymore. So it's not going to ruin it.
Well, you should talk about it, but it just, well, okay. So one of the parts of what he talked about
is I can talk about it. So he had, he had this like a really creepy kind of puppet doll mannequin,
like a professional, like, you know, how you do the ventriloquism, that kind of thing.
So there he is. I'm thinking, why has he got this little guy on his lap? Right. And he's doing this
funny thing and he's talking and he's obviously doing the guy's voice because he's not a
ventriloquist. Right. So he is pretty good, but you can tell. You're very sweet. No, no, but that
was kind of not a ventriloquist. Right. So it's like funny. So he's doing it and I'm like, oh,
that's cool. I see him doing this thing and he's making everybody laugh. And then all of a sudden
these dark lights come in red. I think it was like, and the ventriloquist or the actual, uh,
little entity body. What do you call it? A dummy? What do you call them? The entity body.
The entity body. What do you call it? Small wooden entity. Yeah. What do you call it? It's a puppet.
A puppet. So you got this fucking puppet starts, um, you know, like arguing or something with
Duncan is how I remember it. And then all of a sudden he's yelling or singing and then this
guy's yelling or singing the puppet. And then all of a sudden they start singing together or yelling
together. And you realize he's not controlling the voice of this. Like, so this thing had its own
voice. It was, it was shocking. I don't want people to hear this. If you ever do it again,
it's rogay eyes. What happened? It's fun. It's a, I love doing it. It's just like, uh,
the problem with it is the amount of time it takes. And when you're, you know, out in the road and
stuff, I would need to work on new material, not do like my old crusty satanic puppet act.
But it was a satanic puppet act. So he's trying to play. Like I was like thinking it was demonic.
No dude, he made me creep out. It is a satanic puppet act. And then it also, it shocked me
because I didn't, I didn't expect that the unexpected. That's what the thing with Duncan
sometimes I have no idea what he's thinking or what he's going to talk about next. Speaking of
that something that you've been seeding me, I feel like you've been seeding me with articles
recently. And every time you see me with some article from NASA or the web, you're always
being like, pay attention. Those red dots are galaxies. It's much bigger than you think.
Do you have some like source at NASA? No, not at all. You just like are paying attention.
And well, I mean, the articles are coming out, the, you know, there's the problem is
James Webb telescope is seeing things that aren't supposed to be there based on our current
understanding of the age of the universe and how in the world did some of these things evolve or
appear as quickly as they did. The red dots, it's like, you know, they're picking up. It's
challenging our understanding of either when the big bang happened or the way galaxies form.
Okay, hold on. Break it down for me. Like I'm a four year old. So you got, you got a young kid,
right? Yeah. Okay. So tell me what it is that you find so interesting or inspiring that you keep
hitting me up with these articles about the age of the universe, the big bang or what we're seeing
in the James Webb. Just really tell me the base. Okay. First go get daddy's scotch.
Yeah, right over there. I don't drink anymore. But, you know, I think, and again, I'm a four
year old when it comes to cosmology or physics or anything like that. But, you know, you,
a parent, like we know there was this event that we currently call the big bang, some kind of
explosion that blasted superheated matter out that then as it cooled down began to coalesce.
That coalescence is what formed the planets, stars, and that formation
took an incredible amount of time for that to happen. And that is the universe. The theory is
the big bang. It is the universe. Yeah, it's expanding from this explosion and faster and
faster. Yeah, time space. Yeah, exactly. And so the idea was the James Webb telescope,
I think, was going to be able to peer back to whatever that event horizon was. And there's
things you expect to see there. But what you don't expect to see is what could possibly be
fully formed galaxies. That shouldn't be there. How could that be? How could a galaxy form
in a fraction of the time that we think it takes for planets and galaxies to form?
Anyone watching, please correct me on wherever I'm wrong here because, again, like I'm fascinated
by this stuff. I don't want to mislead anybody. These articles, a quick Google search, you can
find them. And I think it's worth noting that I think some people are proposing it could just be
equipment error. It could just be, it's just picking up shit that, you know, that's so far
away that we don't know what it is. We're spitballing, so it doesn't matter. It's
not our job to be science communicators like Bill Nye or Neil deGrasse Tyson. It's our job
to kind of think about this and talk about it or whatever. That's what we want to be doing.
So what you're saying is what you're noticing is that there are more and more articles coming out
specifically speaking about the James Webb telescope and expanding, if not rewriting,
either absorbing and extending or rewriting the physics and mathematics that we know based upon
the Big Bang Theory. Is that correct? Yeah, that's exactly right. Yeah, it just might
either. There's like a few, I think, broad possibilities. One, the way they're
analyzing the data is incorrect or the data is incorrect. Two, the way our understanding of the
way planets form and the amount of time that takes and the way galaxies form is incorrect.
Or maybe what we think the age of the universe is or when the Big Bang happened
could be incorrect. Or the way light travels, the speed of light, the way we understand
how light moves through time-space could be incorrect. But definitely something,
whether it's the telescope, physics, whatever it is, something probably needs some revision
based on what it's picking up. It's very exciting too. It will be so spectacular to live in a time
where a fundamental aspect of what we've been taught about how the universe formed changes.
Well, you had all these paradigm shifts that have happened before. The march of science is like a
lesson in humility for humans, how it teaches us over and over how little we know. It used to be
the Earth was the center of the universe and everything revolves around us. That was quite
a change when it happened. Then there's our solar system and then a galaxy and then a universe.
We don't know yet if it's finite or not. We can guess whether it's finite. If it is finite,
what's on the other side? If you go through the wall, what's on the other side? Other universes,
we don't know. It would be yet another lesson in humility if that telescope teaches us that our
idea about the Big Bang is way off. It's like you guys' mutual friend, our mutual friend, Joe Rogan,
who has Graham Hancock on. He has these amazing bits and pieces of information about the age of
civilizations here, how wrong we humans are about something that's right here in our backyard and
on our planet. Yeah, he has done such good work. Oh my gosh. He gets eaten alive by people. Yeah,
he does. I think that seems to be the trend. I think that's what Hancock occasionally will tweet
any time they discover some bone fragment that sets humanity back another 50,000 years. It just
keeps getting older. I think that's what he said. At least he's not getting murdered for saying that
the earth is round. That's the whole thing. We, for a long time, were like, the earth is flat.
People that said, look at the way the sun moves, the earth's round,
fucking murdered some of them. Am I right about that? Definitely imprisoned. It was considered
heresy to imply that the earth was revolving around the sun, that the entire universe didn't
orbit the earth, that the earth wasn't the center of the universe, because
the implication there is that we don't have a monogamous god who's solely fixated on our planet,
but now we've got a polyamorous god that could be making these fucking things all over the universe.
I'll mention about you guys' mutual friend, Joe Rogan, our mutual friend. If you don't mind
going into the conversation about your comedian career, how important was he to you becoming a
comedian? Fundamental. He does that. I'm sorry to cut you off. No, go ahead. I'd like to hear it.
Just the life of the comedian. I was kidding you about coming to Las Vegas and not telling us,
but you honestly didn't know because you get booked at shows. Tell us about how it evolved
and what that life was like. I didn't think I would be a comedian. I always wanted to be a
comedian. I loved comedy. I can remember my dad had a Bill Cosby album. It was the first stand-up
comedy I ever heard. I was so young, but I managed to get the needle on the record and get it to go
and listen to that. No immune system for comedy. I couldn't breathe. I was laughing so hard.
I've always loved comedy and National Lampoon. I had a subscription when I was a kid.
Eddie Murphy, Raw, that kind of thing. How about Fireside Theater?
Fireside Theater, I had the Fireside Theater book, but I didn't get as into that as the other stuff,
though I do know that's a beloved comedy troupe. I would memorize jokes. I would buy joke books
and memorize the jokes, but I just wasn't born into a family that would even come close to
suggesting that that could be a career opportunity for me or anything. It just seemed like I was a
misgreen who liked to tell dirty jokes on the bus. I moved to LA. I ran out of money real quick.
I had to get a job. I got a job at the comedy store just because I thought, oh, that'll be fun
to work at a comedy club, and then I'll go to grad school because I had graduated from college,
came to LA. Then all of a sudden I'm driving Mitzi around. I became what's called the runner,
which was a terrifying job, and then I became the talent coordinator.
All of it, I was just like, let's see what happens. But then somewhere along the way-
Why was that a terrifying job to be the runner?
Being around Mitzi, she's like a son. She's like a living son. She's like a guru,
just emanating this energy, a comedy mogul. The comedy store is such a fascinating place,
and she was the leader of that place, and she deserved to be. She loved comedians so much,
but by the time I was driving around the van, I had thought to myself, maybe I will try to be a
comedian. You're just desperate for her to give you any sense that she thinks you're funny at all,
which if she knows that for some comedians that could be the very worst thing that ever happened
to you because then you're going to stop crying. Mitzi said, I'm funny, I'm done.
She made comics the way people harvest opium, these little cuts and cuts and cuts.
Yeah, I just got lucky. Rogan was back in the back of the original room when I had what in those days
was a rare good set because I was still learning how to do it. I remember I got off stage and he
gave me a big hug. He's like, that was really funny. Then a few months later, he's like,
want to come on the road with me? I was not ready for that.
Yeah, Rogan. He just dragged me out in the deep water, started taking me on the road with him.
He does that with a lot of comics. He does that and he mentors you, but not like he teaches you
how to do comedy. It's more like he teaches you how to not be an asshole out there.
What do you mean?
I can remember I was opening for him. I just bombed. I was up there
writing on stage. I was not focused. I remember I get off stage and he's like,
people get babysitters to come to these shows. To you, it might not seem like a big deal,
but it's a big deal. This is a big night for a lot of people. They got babysitters. They're on dates.
This means something to them. It's serious. It's real and you need to think of it that way.
This is real. Be a professional. This isn't a side gig.
Things like that. You remember things like that. He's not saying you're a jackass. He's saying
he's putting it in perspective of that people are doing that and you need to respect that.
Which is a big deal. A different way to say it than junk and you bombed. You're an asshole.
You know it. He didn't need to remind me I bombed. It's more along the lines of I think one of the
ways that when he's taking people out is he knows a lot of the sand traps comedians can get into.
One of them is you get stuck in your material or you get lazy or you're diffused up there or
something like that. One of the cool things about him is he doesn't tiptoe around the truth.
He'll just tell you but there's a benevolence there. It's not like an asshole trying to hurt
your feelings. It's someone who thinks that you have potential and is just trying to help you
become better. That's what we need for all friendships. Do you feel that there's something
like I know as an audience member when I watch a really good set and I know this mainly through
you guys watching this thing but I feel something. I feel like not only am I laughing but I brought
Commander Fravor to see Joe one time. I honestly thought I broke a rib. I laughed so fucking hard
and with Lazarus the first time I ever saw like a real pro. I almost thought I broke a rib both
times but I felt something. I felt like not only am I laughing but I felt like super connected that
everybody was laughing at the same thing that usually you don't talk about. But because it's
being shown in the form of humor we all kind of bonded over the awkwardness of those things that
at that time Joe was saying. Do you feel that there's something that you get as a performer
when we all get on that same level and we are laughing with you at those things? Is there
something like special about that? I can only fucking imagine but I'm asked because I don't
know. I've never done it. Tell me about it. I want to know what that is like. Well you know
and again I think it's a very subjective experience to be a performer so I'm sure
lots of comics would disagree about this but
you know VR. So VR comes out and you know one of the things that they're kicking around the
idea for is like how could stand-up comedy work with VR and the reason I don't think it could with
the current technology you have is like yeah sure you could like have people put on VR goggles and
see you on stage but all of these other aspects of what it really is would be left out which is
the room, the acoustics of the room, the interactive part of it, the interactive part where the laughter
is coming from but also, and this is the woo-woo part, if you tune in you feel this
energy that is not laughter. I don't know how to explain it. It's like you know like when you push
magnets together that sense of like this like weird and it's an energy. Do you think that's
focused? Some people say the word attention and I don't think that's right. Do you think it's
focused like the fact that everybody's consciousness is focusing on a single
like the next beat of what is about to be said or what do you think that magnet is?
Okay it's Fritz Perls this famous psychologist who is I think behind group therapy
came up with this term called the gestalt which is the hole is greater than the sum of the parts
so this other thing comes in I don't know what it is that thing you're kind of working with that
thing like and in that you and the audience have merged into that whatever that is like you've
sort of if you're having a great set if you're not having a great set you will not feel that
energy or you might feel it and then you feel it go away for some reason so it's learning how to
like I think I mean it's the obvious stuff which is you need to write really funny jokes
and be able to deliver punch lines and have a real discipline around it and so I but there's
other levels of it that are I don't hear comics talk about that much which is the experience of
whatever that is this real I don't know what it is so when you're up there and you're having a great
set you I think you feel yourself go from being a an individual to a collective and that is a
really glorious feeling and I think the catharsis or whatever you want to call it that people get
from a comedy show I think is not just because they're laughing so hard but also because they
got to merge with a bunch of people they've never met in this fairly intimate way vocalizing this
bizarre sound humans evolve that we call laughter so yeah you said you don't know what it is but
you did name it saying gestalt like whatever this guy said the hole is greater than some of
his parts do you has that informed so I know when I was training martial athletics that informed
the way that I do business that informed the way I communicate so does this experience that you have
when you do these performances does it inform the way that you treat your son your your wife
your your friends your but does it move from the stage into your life what you learn on stage is
that a fundamental or stupid question I just I'm curious well I don't know I mean I look I don't
want to over intellectualize it because I think comedy is is a is such a present moment sort of
thing that is so mysterious and part of what's beautiful about it is if anyone could like get
handcuffs on it and control it and own it know what it was you know they they would have they
would have all the power in the world I mean it's a very slippery fish that is very difficult
it's always changing transforming you know it's like so much of stand-up comedy is rooted in the
zeitgeist and the zeitgeist is a constantly shifting set of conditions that so you might
have come up with some material that works in in one cultural climate that when that climate shifts
it seems irrelevant and that's happening faster and faster now so you know it's there's so much
to it that it all boils down to this kind of I think a present moment awareness on stage and
sort of like trusting your intuition and being right there like one of the ways you know you're
not having a good set is when you're thinking about the next thing you're going to say you know
it's very odd and at least that's for me now I guess I was just asking did you learn anything
from comedy that you've brought into your normal life that we can easily get access to and understand
well yeah I'll tell you one thing that I have learned from comedy that I've brought into my
normal life is like listening like there's some there's real listening and awareness of like the
awareness of the room you know and and so with when you're playing with your kids
I this is something this Buddhist teacher I love Chogam Trungpa Rinpoche said the greatest gift
you can give your kids is to be in the moment with them to listen you know so I think applying
that to like just spending time with my kids and and sort of dropping whatever I'm going to do next
and just being there with them creates a real connection with them that might not be there
if I was like planning whatever I had to do for the rest of the day I want to ask this before we
move on to other stuff about your friend Rogan you know Jeremy and I watch the stories that pop
up about Joe and we kind of laugh often and sometimes we feel for Joe I mean he becomes
a lightning rod for yeah he is a comedian he he says funny stuff he he pokes and prods and
presses buttons and is taken way too seriously by a lot of folks yeah do you feel for your friend
Joe Rogan sometimes when he becomes a lightning rod and he's just getting trashed yeah like when
he's trending on Twitter every three or four days you know uh yeah like when that shit started
happening initially I of course like you don't want your friend to like suddenly become like
the the like target of a target yeah a target or just a target of like you know
you know how it's been you know I like we get these like this is who you're supposed to be mad
at this week you know and then all these swarms descend on that person god knows you don't want
that to be your friend so yeah at first I've it was like it did make me feel bad but then like
after talking to him about it and realizing he's fine he could take care of himself I was
projecting you realize like oh right I'm just you want to defend people that you love or care
about but you realize sometimes they don't need defense in this situation yeah because you're
projecting your your self onto them and you're thinking my god has happened to me I don't know
what the fuck I would do uh but yeah I yeah I think um you know I think he he did
he was so brave and he's not a politician I think that's what's so great about him is
it would be very easy to shift whatever the thing you were philosophizing or thinking about or
contemplating you would be very easy to not say that to your audience because it doesn't match
what you're supposed to be saying and it might be from a lot of people's perspective the smart
thing to do from the you know from a business perspective but I think that's one of the cool
things about him is he's not a politician he's just freely himself so not a doctor and he will
tell people he's not a doctor and then he'll say something and people take it very seriously and
same thing with he's not a lawmaker he doesn't write legislation and they'll tell people I'm
a comedian don't get this literally and um and yet people do and just rake them over the coals
over it yeah and that it's it's really a curious uh it's a curious thing I think this has been the
plight of comedians for a very long time is like you you need to find someone to blame this shit
on and so I think historically that was like the court jester or whatever was probably always
subject to ridicule and attack and you know I guess that's the archetype here I don't know
like what happened where people started taking comedians seriously it's like a disaster for all
involved because not that you shouldn't take any of us seriously we're human beings or whatever but
it's like come on like if you if you're looking for like uh someone to get mad at about misinformation
or uh someone to get pissed off about for articulating something that doesn't match
whatever the exponentially shifting ideas in the world are then like go after there's so many
people who are like making medicine there's you know what I mean there's people who are like
making weapons and robot dogs and you know what I mean people who are out there in the world
really fixated on creating things that really might not be good for humanity clearly a grenade
isn't good for humanity yeah good for a nation yeah to your point attack them I'm just saying
there's better choices of people to attack right then than like well any ideas that are attacked
to begin with like that that's interesting to me you know we were talking earlier about the
heresy you know that you were seeing uh in our past conversation well there's like a heresy against
uh the scientific community even uh talking about or or exploring the idea of what's right in front
of us with this UFO thing so I think it's really dangerous when we try to weaponize uh ideas to
the point where you're going against people who are just asking questions which is what I've seen
a lot you know on people we know and probably including yourself when you do a sat or you talk
about certain things on your podcast the anger and the vitriol and the poison and the venom that
spit your way just for even in a humorous way which is basically medicine to talk about the
shit we don't want to talk about you know it's pretty amazing when we can't have free and open
dialogue when the sensors themselves are the audience yeah it's not a government controlling
what you can say these are the listeners this is us this is humanity these are your audience
that's fucking dangerous why don't you change the radio station you know what I mean yeah right
there's so many different things you could tune into like why are you like you know that I have
this like a really embarrassing moment where I'm like scrolling through Twitter I'm like man
Twitter fucking sucks it's so negative and then I realized I followed every one of those people
you know what I mean that's not Twitter that's me right that's direct choices I made about who I
want to follow and and it's not the fault of Twitter so I think you know if whenever I find
myself getting particularly perturbed or upset by whatever the particular data stream I'm uh fixated
on I just unfixate I don't try to attack the that particular whatever it is just don't look at it
anymore don't give the gift of your attention like you want to talk about something bizarre in the
universe human attention what the fuck clearly it has a value I mean look at everywhere you go
there's there's billboards and the amount of money that gets put in the advertising campaigns and
logos everywhere these are solar panels for human attention gathering it up so don't give yours
to someone who you are getting angry at or upset at because all you're doing is fueling that thing
like the the and I'm not saying cancel them or get or get them deplatformed no no that just that
will do nothing just shift your beautiful incredible human attention away from that don't
give that to them anymore find something to fit to focus on that makes you happy on your Twitter
feed on the way here this morning I looked at it it was a it was one that came out in October but
it's back at the top and it's uh you're advising people don't attach balloons to their children
you are way ahead of the world of what Jeremy and I called Balloonapalooza
yep yeah I you know when I I don't want to get too into it because it's it's still
it really upsets me but yeah we uh you know it's one of those things parents get a bunch of balloons
at the grocery store it's funny to tie them to your kid and uh we tied a bunch of kids balloons
to uh Sheridan my one of
you know how many years ago was this oh my god how old would he be down he'd be what 20 now
god now he'd probably be 30 30 young father back then I made a lot of mistakes but we just wanted
him to experience like weightlessness and we didn't do them the math right and yeah it's just like
gone yeah just drifted out to see and what's happened to all of us don't worry are you sure
that the US Air Force shot down your son and he still was like I didn't think it was Sheridan
but every year uh you know hundreds of babies do drift and uh I I would not be surprised if that
was one of them and I would obviously that would explain why they were so ambiguous about what it
was because they don't want to stay they we didn't find the wreckage there you go because
what are you going to say we shot a baby tied to grocery store balloons down with an f-22
say that can't say that can't say that Sheridan would have run out by a food by now on that balloon
trip now eat seagulls could eat seagulls I mean look obviously like I know it's ridiculous I have
been in therapy I still believe that you know maybe he's out there somewhere like Sheridan
if you are watching this please reach out to me I'm so sorry but um you know we got to learn to
let go yeah that's the thing we got to learn to let go no oh don't tie your kids please oh
don't tie your kids to balloons don't do it it's it yes it's funny yes if you get the uh weight
right and it's they like it but uh you know one extra balloon that's it that's all I take one
extra balloon and they're gone you uh you are a consumer of news you keep up with balloon news
for example these stories about what was shot down give us your take on that I mean we've talked
about it on the broadcast before but um they're really an interesting reaction from media from
the public the white house I mean I think it was one of the most frustrating things I've ever seen
in my life like the all of a sudden we got this balloon drifting across the country
it's a political issue people on the right are like shoot that thing down right now uh but I
people in you know people in conspiracy circles are like that's an emp or you know that could
easily be smallpox or so from that perspective do you really want to shoot it down you don't know
what's in there what if it like you shoot it down and it contaminates what whatever's underneath
it I didn't even I didn't even think about that right the idea that it could be aggressive in
some way but we've had these balloons for 40 plus years going over reconnaissance balloons
but I see your point what if there was a biological in there I mean uh you know
I don't agree with a lot of things Biden does but if it was up to me I don't want to like be the
one to squeeze the trigger on a balloon shoot down and find out it was filled with some kind
of awful genetically engineered bio weapon or god knows what so let it get over the ocean shoot it
down but that so that whole thing just seemed dumb and and annoying and also creepy because
you know the the people kicking around that's a fucking emp baby they're gonna do an electromagnetic
pulse what a brilliant way to get through it's like you're gonna drift into right over the
the center of the United States and just wipe out the power grid I gotta start I have to stop
going on retic conspiracy because I get sucked in so deep but it wasn't that apparently to me what
was annoying was after that all of a sudden these things are getting shut down because they reconfigure
the norad satellite or whatever to pick up on smaller objects I'm guessing but what bothered
me was the language like you know what it is why aren't you saying exactly what it is where's the
picture of it you must have a picture of it why are you so there but this whole like it's an object
it's an object well it's some kind of object literally like is there any unknown object an
unknown object an unknown flying object which just means ufo I mean yeah without getting too
conspiratorial but getting way conspiratorial what the fuck was up with that I mean the language
they used to try to mystify what it was that was intentional yeah and that was repeated
so like you wonder why were they doing that why were they trying to play catch and release
with the ufo thing do you have a theory why yeah my theory is really boring though because like I
like I love the idea that it's some kind of like uh you know a lot of people are saying
and I don't know that I really buy into this anytime some weird shit happens like that's a
distraction from this so the one of the one of the ideas is it's a distraction from the East
Palestine disaster the other one was it's a distraction because apparently there was
a reporter put out a very detailed story about how we blew up Nord Stream 2 an act of war so
it's a distraction from that that was one of the ideas but I think the real reason
is because we shot down the what was it called the Idaho balloon brigade like these kids like
to put up weather balloons for fun and we use an f-22 with a five hundred thousand dollar missile
to shoot down these kids two of them so it's like how do you say that in a way that doesn't
make you look like an asshole you know you you already say well we're not sure what it was
we're not sure what it was shaped like it was weird it knocked out our communications
yeah we couldn't find it you couldn't find it because you shot down some kids weather balloon
project blew it up with a with a very powerful missile you're gonna find scraps of latex or
I think there is a positive development and that was the scene of the White House press corps
not exactly into UFOs and not known for pressing tough questions asking hey where the hell is the
gun camera video you know it exists why don't you release this video of these encounters and
shooting them down welcome to our world asking for videos from the Pentagon right which should
be released it's not a threat to national security I think it opened a lot of eyes among those
reporters who have not taken this stuff seriously before sure well a lot of times we are providing
videos to the Pentagon but we are specifically asking them to release the Mosul or video just
because it was contained within a classified briefing does not mean that the public can't see
that video that's what you're referencing so our audience knows anyway wow so when I was glad to
see the White House press corps asking some tough questions for once and gaining at least a little
bit of knowledge about what the UFO world has had to deal with for the Pentagon right 75 years there
you get right I didn't even think of that angle but yeah it's like they're that ambiguous if they're
that like frustrating in the description of shooting down a kid's science experiment
how much more so yeah about technology that that that that really is exotic exotic yeah let me tell
you something if a pilot I've talked with many pilots about this and you can ask any pilot as a
fighter pilot any war fighter if you're going to fire upon something because you get the order
you're going to see it you're going to know it you're going to be able to make sure that you're
hitting the right target they have footage of these balloons we said there would be balloons
from the beginning so the idea that that is being directly held back to try to muddy the waters
because maybe the reasons you said maybe stranger reasons that's fucked up but by all accounts
that's fucked up they have video footage they have imagery they have all sorts of sensor data
and the pilots had visual or they wouldn't have fired upon them yeah it's fucked up man I mean
no matter what it was it I don't think I think we're so sick of how condescending they are like
who's they when you're that when they're giving a when you when the oh I can't remember a name the
press secretary is you know using words like object unknown object it's an unknown object
we don't know what it was but we can tell you for sure it's not extraterrestrial
yeah it's just condescending it's like okay so I guess you want us to just accept that like you
you just want to say oh an object of course what this classic object you just shot down a classic
object of unknown origin with an f-22 happens all the time oh uh yeah oh that's all it was
that's the part that really rubs me the wrong way man is the condescending attitude when they're
speaking for and to the American public yeah man it's like don't it's like it's like you know
somebody feeding you like a microwave dinner and telling you it's steak it's really nice steak you
know expecting us to just be like that's a really terrible analogy I don't know if that works okay
let's roll with it but macaroni it's just you know I that's the part that's a little mind numbing is
it's like their manipulation of language to be as vague as possible but attached to that is a
seeming prohibition on speculating about something you should definitely be speculating about the way
that that that speculation is taboo in some circles and how that gets you lumped in with an
imaginary group of people that they've invented that they're currently calling conspiracy theorists
which is you know yeah sure obviously there's people who've been up too long and are writing
weird shit online like if you don't think that's out there you're out of your mind but also there's
just normal people who are curious yeah and if you're going to like if you want to like throw
a lighter into a big pool of gasoline the way to do it is just is to not be completely clear
and transparent because then everyone's going to project their own worst fears or their own weird
theories onto your smoke screen history of area 51 so there you go you have a base that people
can see that the russians photograph that you can climb up on a mountain and photograph and the
government says it doesn't exist well how do you think the public's going to react to that we know
it's there what do you mean it doesn't exist they get more curious about it exactly that's it just
say what it is whatever it's it's tough it's like what do you think it is hippies we're working on
fucking teleportation we're working on anti-grav we can't tell everybody that we're do the details
because we're trying to create a competitive edge against our enemies but when you're so blank about
it all you're doing is inviting people to trespass all you're doing is inviting people to try to
hack your shit to get the information the distrust it creates that's like something we're dealing with
is the over classification of information in our world creates a sort of distrust with the
american public for good reason so and that it's a corrosive corruptive process that's been going on
if you're not honest with those you represent then you're going to have a fucking problem
and we're and we're running into that specifically with our work with what we're trying to do get
information out so i think we can all relate that that is a that is a fucked up thing when
when people are representing at us are not being honest well i i do understand yeah that in any
government that has to have a military you obviously you can't give the d all the details
out there but yeah i just think that that the the articulation of classified information or even a
clear explanation of why you can't talk about it in a way that doesn't make people imagine that
you think of us as children that you think of us as some kind of peasantry or something that
couldn't handle the truth it was just an acknowledgement that like we are paying for your job and in
in that you know that you respect us in the same way you respect other people in the political
class i think that would do a lot for people like to earn back the public trust sure yeah it's just
like come on you could be you you don't have to tell us everything but i have in fact we don't
want to know everything i don't i don't think i want to know everything you ever think about that
you ever yeah i'd like you want to know you would like to know everything i don't know there's some
level of it where i get where i think well there's parts of it that are pretty disturbing
somewhere long you dig far enough you go somewhere you want some water you want some more water oh
thank you yeah i use you chill i'll give her some more water um i think there are reasons at some
level there's a small group of people who know some shit that's really disturbing you think yeah
um like like yeah yeah yeah i think it's uh you know there's a harvest of some kind that happens
you know there's some there's some bad shit that a harvest there's some kind of a there's more than
one answer to what's here and some of them are not good right right yeah nothing new under the sun
it's not like this shit hasn't been written about for thousands of years and you know to talk about
people that have been working on this in the government at high levels it's a very small
group and they're some of them are pretty much at the conclusion that maybe they shouldn't let the
all this shit out like they couldn't there would be fucking problems well i think there's some
compassion in there i mean i think like also understanding humans as a whole and understanding
like how you need civilization yeah like what it would do to civilization yeah because you know
i'll tell you this man the other thing that those weird objects what when i was like looking at my
emotional state and allowing myself to even though like we talked you know like it's not
don't fall for it but which i appreciate it you were like the first person i called but
you know in those moments where i i started fantasizing like jesus christ i mean this is
kind of the way every sci-fi alien invasion movie starts and uh don't worry about it
scary like i realized like you know in the when i was younger and you would hear things about how
like seti or nasa or the governments of the world already have plans in place for how to
handle an alien invasion what do what do we do if something shows up in the skies how do we
do that or what do we do if we find a planet that definitely has there are protocols there's
protocols yes there are because they know it's going to be incredibly disruptive to
society because so many people are aligned with cultures religions that that additional
information could like be the crack in the windshield there are bedrock beliefs that
would be shaken by it yeah yeah no question the un there's a great documentary i need to
remember what it was but it was about the un protocols that they have for non-terrestrial
engagement of humanity so when duncan for when you you facetime me about that i was underneath
my car fixing them i fucking tired remember that yes you facetime me and i was like i'm like don't
worry it's not war of the worlds it's all going to be balloons but it was like i did call it but
it should be obvious in a way that that feeling that people did have like what is going on now
the fact that you even have to ask that means they don't fucking trust what's going on to begin
with what is going on i mean how many times i had to say this is this is not going to be war of the
worlds probably it's all good right check this out so i guess it's just interesting to me that
the what is portrayed out to the world and what we know is not in sync and that's really interesting
but these protocols right the protocols we have if there are if there is contact have you ever
read uh childhoods end by arthur c clark no have you heard yes yes so if i get this right
there were craft that came and hovered over planet earth in strategic locations for generations
oh wow and that was just to acclimate people to the non-humans that had come and arthur c clark
this incredible character you know predicted the internet all that stuff yeah but it's just a cool
book that the aliens they had a problem they looked like demons like devils red with pointed
tails oh shit i've shown you some documents before so nasa has protocols for what would happen if
astronauts for example uh come into contact with extraterrestrial life how they would come back the
the steps that had to be taken to prevent uh contamination of the planet united nations does
have a a series of protocols if intelligent life is detected how the announcement would be made
those are real they've been around for 50 years we've never implemented them and i'm not sure that
they would stick to uh the rules uh if it even happened i suspect if our government is the one
that made the decision or the discovery that we'd keep it secret for a hell of a long time maybe
forever do you think it's possible that some sort of non-human intelligence is already walking
amongst humanity well i mean sure why not i don't know i would like to believe that i go to the i
used to go to the raves i mean that was something that you would be people in that subculture
definitely believe that uh you mean like the nords and no no i'm not saying specific i'm just
curious if like in your concept of the way that you've seen the world if there is a sense that
visitation okay do you believe that ufos are real yeah of course physical machines come
from elsewhere well i don't know what they are but i definitely believe that that that
many of the things that people have reported seeing are currently not on wikipedia like or not
there is no explanation for them other than an intelligence that derives either from a part of
the earth that we don't have access to just everything you were saying extra temporal
extra dimensional um or maybe from here like george has said before maybe you know not even
any of these maybe just uh some advanced civilization that has somehow evolved in a sub
category of being hidden here within you know planet earth okay i'll tell you a story this is
a cool story i just found out about this ram das's guru neem kurali baba incredible being uh so many
fascinating stories about him and i won't get into all of them but look up neem kurali baba you will
it's a infinite rabbit hole but basically a saint you could say a saint in india and so um
um i'm so sorry i can't remember the name of this documentary just came out if you go to ram das
dot org you can find it uh but it was about one of neem kurali baba's closest associates and it's
such a good documentary because you get like a real taste of what kind of guru he was and it might
if you have some uh guru paranoia which any logical rational person definitely you should
have guru paranoia because you can well what is it uh mark twain said uh religion is what happened
when the first con man met the first fool oh you gotta be you know be smart don't just because
somebody's wearing a blanket or whatever you need to kiss their feet but in my opinion this was the
real item he was the real thing yeah one of the stories was uh he's standing at the base of this
mountain uh with some of his uh associates i don't we don't i don't they don't like to say
followers but disciples i don't like to say that just everyone was in love with him he like this
was like a the description of him is just like being around like a space heater that was just
pure love what era like what 60s in the 60s yeah in the 60s yeah and he just was like
you just you couldn't it was almost unbearable it was almost unbearable because he loved you
but not in some cheesy like bullshit like that that that fake positivity yoga smile thing but
like in the first from the sense that somehow he was capable of knowing everything about you
including this is what you heard but you haven't met this guy right oh well i feel like i have i
mean yeah i feel like i like i don't think that a being needs to be embodied to have the experience
or the darshan of that being necessarily but maybe that's for another podcast but yeah so
he's talking about how in these mountains there were these rishis i think was the name for it
basically these very old beings like thousands of years old that lived up there and as he's
talking about it orbs just appear like in all around orbs these like floating orbs and
one of the people with him was like we you know we gotta record this we have to write it down we
have to like look at this and he's like what do you want every you want people to think i can call
orbs he just joked about it you know he he was always like that always like downplaying everything
like it's it's nothing to do with me it's it's the there's these beings live up here but anyway
i found that to be very interesting in the sense that orbs or these whatever these certain things
are that show up they that's a much discussed topic in like ufo forums and ufo communities
you're suggesting that's more of a spiritual manifestation as opposed to mechanical technological
that's right and and i don't see i mean if we're going to like try to put every possible thing it
is use ochrum's boring ass razor and be like it's probably uh either equipment malfunction
or experimental vehicles uh that's it's the odds of it being that over aliens it's infinitely
more probable but why not add to it that these things i mean these have been talked about for
ever in every culture they have different names but general generally the same kind of appearance
let me ask about your journey because you're a comic and entertainer and you know you look
at your website about your podcast and it's um that that you have some comics on there yeah but
it's mainly about people who are disciples of ram das or it's about mindfulness it's about
meditation yes somewhere you had some kind of an epiphany or a moment um that led you in that
direction can can you share was it a medical health issue that led there well you know there's no easy
answer to that and and i but i you know and i think about it sometimes and there's no easy answer you
know um i think
that the world is a very mysterious beautiful place and i know for sure that there are
things there are like secrets there are you know aspects of reality that some people are aware of
that aren't shared in the cafeteria of public discourse for a variety of reasons and i didn't
get there by being privy to that information as i suspect one at least one of you has i just got
there by applying the as above so below and i know that the way it works in just general groups of
friends is that we all have our little secrets that we don't tell other groups so as above so
below right and and if we're dealing with a spectrum of intelligence on the planet which i
think we we have a wide spectrum of intelligence uh from i mean i think you guys fall closer to the
super smart side i'm sometimes i'm afraid we have pulled the shit out of people we've
well we pulled that one off give me a break but you know what i think that uh more than likely uh
we could expect there to be uh secret societies i mean i think that has a lot of weight attached
to it but but groups of people who've made the decision that they're gonna have conversations
in private that aren't always sinister but maybe benevolent in nature that that there's there's
salons or or the invisible college is what's all of the invisible college and that uh yeah so i i
you know so it's like so i think that over time you just using just as simple as above so below
what have you experienced in your own life now extrapolate that out and expand it make it bigger
and bigger and you'll get a lot of answers just from that are they going to be right i don't know
but i'm just fascinated with that possibility i'm excited about the possibility i do think that it
exists am i out there like searching for some mystery school or whatever have i made any
contact with anything like that absolutely not i have not but i do speculate that it exists
and i'm excited about just that fact were you on this road before you had a uh uh slapped in the
face about mortality yeah i was always interested in this stuff i was always in you know when i was
a kid my dad loved in search of do you remember in search of yeah lennard neemoy the best and
i remember it's one of my earliest memories sitting down with my dad to watch in search of
and like that i think it was congos in the beginning at that 70s music and like at some
point they show a chris a skull and that would scare the shit out of me as a kid like i would
be paralyzed just by looking at that skull so i have always been interested in this stuff from
from as long as i can remember and i think the evolution of that has like taken me down a lot
of different paths but eventually when you get older it's like the the frosting stuff the aliens
the illuminati the all that stuff even though it might be cool you get to the point like i can't
be an angry drunk every single day i need to calm down i've got to actually like relax in the world
and that's i think what led me to sort of like buddhism and ram das it was very it wasn't very
romantic it was more along the lines of like shit my mom died i had cancer i feel like shit a lot
of the time i think i kind of hate myself i don't want to live my whole life like this this sucks
this is not how i want to be and so then you know i got just got lucky and stumbled upon
ram das's teachings which led me to buddhism which led me to my meditation teacher and now
i think i'm maybe four percent less neurotic and i'm happy with that i'll take four percent man
he just died you know a year or so ago and i didn't know him nearly as i'd never met him
and didn't read nor nearly as much as you but i felt that loss it just oh yeah person he was
you know yeah that's you felt it a lot of people who never met him felt it and you should have felt
it because it you know it was a it's a big deal i mean he was the i think the a real like true
spiritual leader in the best way possible just somebody who's inviting you to stop being at war
with yourself and like where you're at right now is just exactly where you need to be and a lot
of people don't want to hear that they want to always imagine there's a finish line or there's
something around the corner right we miss out so much he was so good and like being honest about
his own life and not putting on airs of being this or that and i think he was just the perfect
teacher for the time we're in right now so uh yeah it was a you know it was a loss i think he
i remember when at these retreats i would interview him i would get to interview him they
would like let me go to the retreat and do really yeah i get in like once
once i was standing next to him right before we went on stage and he's in the wheelchair it's
rom dos i mean this is like someone who's like jesus i don't want to say that you know but i
mean you know well a holy man in a sense here's what's great about him he just was really good
at not letting you do that to him yeah and i remember like looking down at him and you know
like he had though he beamed joy like he was really you see the culmination of a lifetime
of practice and honesty with oneself but i looked down i'm like i'm nervous and he got this big
smile and he goes me too it was such a cool moment like he was always doing things like that
you know like like sort of helping you get out of the very human desire to raise someone up
on a pedestal yeah we've never actually really talked about this but a lot of my life in the
athletics right the martial athletics i also you know taught a form of yoga for martial athletes
and i traveled the globe i would spin the globe but not a metaphor i'd spin the globe and wait
where my finger dropped and i'm going to go find the martial art there or i'm going to find the
spiritual teacher there and see what's up 99.9 percent of people that i met were fucking charlatans
yeah straight up i mean i went to like poon india state at osho's ashram they fucking drugged me i'm
sure of it had to go to the hospital all this shit super fucking trippy but i didn't go to oregon with
the baghwan shri raj nisha no so this was this was after so after i was a little bit after that
phase but it's the same guy it's the same guy he's got this huge in in in poon india he has
these huge temple with these pyramids like black pyramids straight out of the movie beyond the black
rainbow it's fucking amazing you have to go get like an hiv test just to enter which i thought
that must be an old school rule what's going on here i learned so much they're like take off
your clothes underneath that like thing you have to wear i'm like these guys are weird i had a weird
experience there i got really sick that's where i came back you i hope you're not brushing past
the take off your clothes moment like oh yeah what happened after these so the head the head guru
chick right who was running it she eyeballed me from day one like oh this guy's not a believer or
something so i was wearing like i don't know my jeans or something they told you to put on this
robe to go like watch videos of this guru like on this big screen and shit and she looks at me and
she's like you must not wear clothes under that i'm like why yeah like all right i mean it was
hilarious and then kind of hot that's why not for me but like you know it was weird for me so i was
like okay cool so anyway the the point is did you did you take your clothes off oh yeah i wanted
they ordered you do underneath yeah i just wore a robe right he was cute then right it was sinister
that's why i came out with the valley fever thing and i started hallucinating was in his like
ashram that that dude's thing that i found out later i had this major illness but i was sure
that they had poisoned me because when do you get 107 degree temperature like on the armpit
you're seeing visions two days i was out here and dead people like i was fucked up and i was sure
that they had poisoned me turns out i got valley fever that's what was going on but they were
holding my passport hostage because they didn't want a dead dude anyway let me back up the the
point of the story is i got to kind of engage with some of these these people most charlatans
but people that that you know have big followings though i i did meet to i get i did get to meet
your buddy one time rom dos cool we have a common friend justin beretta from the glitch okay got
you yeah and he like did music with rom dos's talk yeah man justin was a jujitsu student of mine
what is a good friend from back in college he's exploded into being a musician with this thing
called the glitch mob he's good yeah but also did something with rom dos but uh i had one experience
where i met somebody where i had an actual experience that i can't account for it was
baba hari dos is that somebody yeah he had like a big he's a guru guy an indian guy yeah so i went
to new york and i was teaching out there it was jujitsu at the time and this guy's coming through
town so i went to go see him and it was this weird experience because i'm not like a innately
spiritual person like in the way that other people talk about it right so i'm sitting there and this
guy's just like silent for like 40 minutes i'm like what the fuck is going on so i started
thinking all these things a bunch of things right he starts talking i swear to god it was like he
was answering every single thing almost directly that i was thinking so then i go oh that's his
trick he sits there quiet knows what everybody's gonna think then he's just gonna say it because
we're all thinking the same thing what is this fucking guy doing right so that's where i was at
start to walk out they're throwing like flower petals in front of this guy's feet i'm like i'm
fucking out of here so i beeline it to this elevator to escape the whole procession out
yeah next thing i know i turn around and he fucking walks right up to me and looks at me like stomps
dead in his tracks yeah looks at me and by the way i was in the back i wasn't like the guy in
the front being like what is this about i was like hiding right comes right up to me looks me in the
eyes and i don't remember exactly what he said but but the look in his i don't know if he even
said anything the look in his eyes was just like one of like absolute pain and sorrow as if all of
these processions around him and all this stuff was just so terribly annoying to him that it was
like i am deeply misunderstood that was the message that i got but i just thought it was so
weird because you know this guy that i sit sit in silence with and this is not my stuff you know me
especially at this time but i went anyway and then for him to say all these things exactly that were
on my mind i was kind of like that's weird and then when he came up to me to have that like strange
immediate thing where i could see this look on his a pain that he was being followed this much
you know i maybe i was completely wrong but it was a very profound experience for me it taught me
that day whether or not he was teaching it it taught me that day that every single being every
single person has a greatest potential and we're never going to make we're never going to make to
our greatest potential but if we can make it most of the way then that would be cool wouldn't it
yeah sure i mean this is the like great paradox of it all is like the idea i mean this is really
quiet this is really bad news for a lot of people which is you're at your greatest potential that
that you just where you're at right now this is it and that the dream of the greatest potential
is a form of self-crucifixion you build this idea of what you could be then you nail yourself to it
we live in a goal-oriented time where everyone is in a self-improvement project which is fine it's
not to say you know you shouldn't like try to live a healthier life or anything like that but
usually what the fuel people are using to get themselves to the healthy life is shame guilt
self-hate and and and that is a really terrible fuel to use is and it seems like how do you expect
to get to a place where you're going to love yourself by hating yourself all the way there
so that the you know that's sort of the the what i love about about it is it it's really like
you know uh pima chodron you getting to her much pima you would love her she's great
she was a student of chogam champa rembushe and like what she was talking about meditation she
says you know a lot of people start meditating because they want to be different than the way
they are and that's starting your spiritual practice with hostility towards yourself you're
starting on the path by like being so unhappy with where you are and thinking oh up the way
right around that bend right by the black pyramid where i was pegged in india by a woman in a cult
and given valley fever that's where i'm gonna be better we're good moments
or when the ufos come or when the singularity happens or when all this there's this dream
that right around the corner there's suffering everyone's experiencing it's gonna end and then
everything will be better and and the general the general teaching seems to be actually
no that is not the remedy the remedy is not constantly trying to get to the next place but
being just where you are and finding a way to stop trying to escape from that part of yourself
that you have what we all pour booze on it's a part of yourself you pour booze on it's a part
of yourself that you you you keeps you awake at night it's a part of yourself that you
god it's it's the shadow that fucking thing man it's the part of yourself that makes you
ferociously and diligently masturbate to porn at 3 a.m if you're me that's being in the moment
being in the moment mindfulness you cover that stuff in your podcast it's not normal fair
for a comedian but i mean you do you do it really well and that seems like the idea is you want to
it maybe you don't want to educate but you want to share this with
people who are open to the idea and need it i mean you know what my intent there god i'd love to say
that i was like god i want to be altruistic like that my uh i love these like the conversation
we're having right now this will fuel me for like weeks i'll think about i'll think about stuff you
said i'll think about stuff you said i'll kick it around in my head i'll write about it it just i
just love it and so that is what i'm up to and i love that people that i get to share those
conversations with people i mean that does make me happy when i hear when i get contacted by people
who tell me this conversation or that conversation help them but yeah i my and my intent behind it is
just jewel i just love talking to these people i love like just what you're talking about those
moments where you encounter someone who has lived a divergent lifestyle if a normal lifestyle is
like nine to five job career you're with someone who is like their entire lives focused on what it
is to be a human consciousness and sentience and god and and and when you get around a person like
that it shows you who you are i would say i would wonder when you were saying that i would wonder
like if that was my experience and he was a mirror to me yeah yeah totally yeah he was mirroring you
because that's one of the things they say is when you get around a being like that
they don't really have the identity that like a lot of people have there's not really an identity
there in the normal sense and so they are mirrors they're energetic mirrors so when you get around
them what's happening is you're seeing yourself you're seeing where you're at right now through
them and and that that can be a really painful experience or a really wonderful experience or a
mix do you think that beings that you encounter under say dmt or psilocybin there are a lot of
conversations that are published that people come back and relate their experiences that those are
actual beings or it's something that you create in your head that there's something out there that
you can contact by hitting some other level with substances or whatever okay i just had andrew
gallimore on my podcast if you're into psychedelics he's a great twitter follow and he's written a
wonderful book on the neurochemistry of the psychedelics and so in this podcast he was
telling me that he had and they they actually i think they did it at oxford they did this study
i could be wrong about the college but basically he realized that using what we already understand
about anesthesia measuring the amount of chemicals and the human bloodstream to keep them at the level
you need them at to like put people under he wondered what happens if we apply that to dmt
what happens if we put the amount of dmt it takes to do the breakthrough state in somebody and keep
it there for longer than the six 10 minute blast off experience you get where you make
where you commune with these beings there could be a lot of scientific benefit to
not just understanding dmt but exploring uh that universe like for example what's interesting
about dmt and a few other psychedelics is the similarity between experiences versus like other
psychedelics that seem to be more of a projection of i don't know consciousness onto the world or
something like that a distortion of consciousness or you know dmt everyone sees the same weird
circusy uh organic hyper technological uh architecture in their kind of weird language
and of course the machine elves as terence mckenna described them and all the whatever those are so
they've done the study already it's i don't think it's been released yet where they put people
like i don't want to say put them under put them over i guess with dmt i don't know what you call
put them through and uh to find out what's going on there but gallimore said that if you look at
the human brain when it is on dmt you it's like watching a radio switch channels it goes through
a staticky chaotic state and then all of a sudden it completely like shifts into a different modality
of perception and he said regardless of the whether or not these beings are a product of
the unconscious or whether they're extra-dimensional beings that dmt is
allowing you to see what's really interesting about the fact that your brain is shifting into
this new way of perceiving reality is that it implies that we evolve to do that the amount
of time it took to evolve our brains to instantaneously weave reality into what it is
right now is already it's insane that we even did that but to think that we also built into us when
we come into contact with dmt suddenly our brain like it knows how to do it just shifts gears and
changes the way it perceives reality what the fuck does that mean what is the evolutionary
use of being able to see to that stable mode right because you see otherwise it would just be chaos
because the brain hasn't evolved to be able to assimilate but after they get through the
static period there's some sort of frequency let's say because you're using the radio terminology
where there is order and so what you're saying is that the human brain must have evolved to the
point where it could accept that moment and create order out of it is that what you're saying yeah
right that's fucking weird it's like it's like uh i don't know it's like finding like a completely
different different operating system on your computer right that runs completely different
software what why do we have the dark web of the brain dmt dark web what is that so yeah you know
like it i think that um you know i was talking to my meditation teacher so cheesy to say that
david nickturn about um you know in tibetan buddhism there's there's deities that you visualize
and there's an entire pantheon of saints and beings buddhas and i you know i was asking him
but is it considered are they considered to be real and he's like well they're as real as you are
like how real are we you know some of these stories you hear uh people either on dmt or
remote viewing they project their consciousness out there one way or another and they encounter
some other intelligence and sometimes the encounter is negative get the hell out of here who are you
why are you here either you're not ready or you're intruding kind of a thing yeah that's right
yeah i mean this is uh if you read just any grimoire any occult book they what i love about
them is they all start with a warning generally there's a warning like don't fuck with this this
is real like you know don't this and i don't know if that warning is there to protect people or to
lure them in because people who open grimoires that's like the most exciting thing like oh shit
i'm not supposed to do this ritual or that ritual or whatever it may be but um you know i think that
ramdas famously he he was he actually had a channeled being that he was friends with
named emmanuel and emmanuel said to him just because something doesn't have a body doesn't
mean you should trust it you know i think that's very important and just because something can read
your mind doesn't mean anything other than that like there seems to be an ability to like tell
you what you're thinking that doesn't mean you should like bow down to them right or anything so
you know i think that that's one of the the problems of like our
what is taren's beginning calls it the pharmacological inquisition the fact that
we have gone into the dark ages of psychedelics they completely ban them we don't know what they
are because people are taking these things and they're meeting beings and the beings are telling
them all kinds of shit and because the being is like very colorful or because the being is
happening within the context of the psychedelic they immediately believe it they're like oh it
told me the world's ending or oh it told me to go do this or go do that it's like you don't know
that was yeah i always check the badge number and ids of every being that enters my world
that used to make fake ids i don't know if i can say that but i did you know it was like you could
make any id you needed in la so the the thing is is that that's that's something to do where we
defer to authority or perceived authority and and we do that because of laziness we we constantly
do that oh they said this so this is good this is what i do i've always been um i don't know
innately pugnacious like against uh you know combative against authority and stuff like that
yeah not against but just i never take it for one second somebody shows me some qualification
identification that that means shit but i think that it is within our nature to sometimes defer
to authority and if that's in a spiritual realm if that's in a realm of taking a psychedelic where
you're experiencing something oh that must be really profound and important because it felt
like well let me tell you my dmst experience i fucking got in an argument every goddamn time
with this intelligence right say i'm ancient and powerful god i'm ancient and powerful same one
same i don't know you know that's really subjective it gets really weird it's like a cheshire cat that
winked at me for a millisecond the first time i ever tried it and then after there it was an
argument with the same entity again all of this is in my mind who knows if there's any functional
but my reaction my older brothers they're laughing at me because uh you know he knows that i have a
little problem with authority or whatever you know so he's like laughing but it was like a constant
thing and i don't know if it's my it might just be that my egotistical resistance to any kind of
like superpower but it you know some other entity telling me but i would get in arguments with this
thing each time being like really show me you're ancient and powerful show me right one time it did
but it wowed me you know yeah but uh i don't know what that's about man all i know is there
there has been value in my life in experiencing that the very limited number of times that i have
yeah and not not encouraging it for anybody else it's the only thing that i ever felt uh possessed
my consciousness of my body the externally that came in and controlled my physical body was very
bizarre for me yeah but i did find value in the in having explored that you know if i had compared
to not having explored it yeah you know i think it's again we get so caught up in the reality of
these beings i certainly used to like is it real is it not what is this and and then within that
you like you you you can accidentally uh miss the bigger picture which which is that uh
our minds are filters and they're filtering out a lot of data and some of that data is really
beautiful poetic and inspirational the whether or not like we can one day like take these
dmt elves and put them like in a government hearing which would be fucking hilarious
you know who knows but you know i think that uh in like enjoying those moments but then not getting
too caught up in them i mean this is the idea and a lot of eastern traditions is oh yeah you
can develop all kinds of powers like cities is what they call them uh you can turn yourself
into a rainbow walk through a wall you can levitate you can blah blah blah blah on and
on and on and that uh in in some like monastic communities they you're you're told like whatever
happens within the walls of the monastery things you see this is not to be shared outside of the
monastery but most importantly don't get too caught up in developing these potentials because
that's not really the point the point isn't like making contact with this being or that being or
this being what is the point well the point is to find out if you can stop suffering because if you
can stop suffering then you can help other people not suffer that's the point the point is we live
in a world where many many people are miserable and they're suffering and they're suffering
not because of the reasons they think and so that creates confusion they think they're suffering
because uh external phenomena isn't matching their their their expectations why why do we need to
why do we need to reduce suffering i don't i've never understood that about buddhist tradition
about all this like serious question is yeah why is that such the fixated point that like oh you
got to stop suffering so you can help other people stop suffering for me suffering has brought me the
greatest insight about my capabilities my life my tolerance my empathy sure why is it that we have
to focus on not suffering i've never understood okay i love the question i mean and i'll try to
answer it as best i can i could be wrong one distinction that's super important is the
distinction between pain and suffering so pain there's nothing in as far as i'm aware in buddhism
like we're gonna make you stop hurting you have a body your body is subject to old age disease and
death so there's not much there that's that's the that's out of him but uh suffering in in this
sense is not like the pain of getting yourself to go jogging or the rejection you might experience
as an artist or all those things this is a deeper problem and so in buddhism the first noble truth
as they call it is there is suffering now not life is suffering this gets mistranslated there
is suffering so the dukkha is what it's what it's called now this translates into wobbly wheel
is at least right so it basically it's saying there's an experience of reality that most of
us are having which is akin to being on a wagon or a bike that doesn't have enough air in the
tires everything here is wobbly things don't work out you things don't meet your expectations
you're going to get stuck in traffic things just really aren't working out this is just the nature
of reality that we're in right now and so you uh this not working out depends for for a sense
that things aren't working out you have to basically construct an identity that has built
into it what you think working out is what it looks like what it is so that sort of the
the center of the problem here is that you have become attached to
a self sense of oh this is me and that me is supposed to help you navigate this wobbly
wheel and that you create the sense of self so that you can justify or navigate the fact
that life doesn't work out the way you want to let's well no usually what you're doing is
you're protecting this thing so you've you you've invented an imaginary friend this is you this is
my name my social security number my career my job what's in my twitter bio or my tinder bio
or whatever i like dogs i like to go to the beach i love music and i uh one day i'll have a ferrari
and i'm gonna retire i want to get good at golf the list goes on and on for so many people you
know this this thing this thing right and the more you have within that it's like you go out to eat
with someone and some people like they're like it's insane how specific they get don't like i only
want three grains of salt the fish should be in the center of my play the more of those conditions
you have in your own life for for happiness for you to like achieve happiness the more miserable
you're going to be because those conditions will not be met so theoretically if we start
removing those conditions then maybe we'll begin to discover we don't really need that much
to the this thing that we're experiencing that we call suffering is is not a permanent condition
but one more based on a concept of the self that isn't accurate and so gom is the name
for meditation in Tibetan Buddhism that means uh becoming familiar with so this is let's figure
out what the fuck we are to start off with like what's underneath all those things that that
finally makes sense to me so what i'm hearing from you and it kind of finally makes sense to me
i don't think the message is alleviate your suffering the message is by alleviate by
alleviating your suffering you can see more clearly what you are or what you can be or
what you're becoming and all of the above yeah because it's not about suffering then with what
you're saying is that's been my misinterpretation because all you guys ever say you fucking buddhist
guys or whatever you are always say oh must alleviate suffering i'm like what's wrong with
suffering yeah okay but what you're saying is through doing that that there is a clarity or
purification of what or who you really are or can or can become all of the above is that correct
yeah it's it's like this this is not an add-on this is not an add-on so it's something that you
already are which is so you are fundamentally good you're
what every human being is is pretty much the same everyone's pretty much the same you're me
i'm you you're me i'm you but we get so caught up in the mask or the defense mechanisms which are
very refined and and very hypnotic and very intense that suddenly we find ourselves like
engaged in this dramatic game of make-believe with identities that we've just invented and so
there's so much suffering there that all the wars are because of this like all the
conflict in the world is completely related to i'm defending my shit from you you're defending
your shit from me a lot of people carry a lot of guilt that they guilt that tortures them torturous
guilt you're so unhappy about decisions you made in the past
and or or where you think your life is going it's like okay i guess the best way to describe
it is this and for all my like deep buddhist people out there anyone who's interested in this
i would recommend inside la darma moon rom dos dot org chogam trump a rempache please take what
i'm saying with a grain of fucking salt i'm probably messing it up and i'm sorry this is
my own personal where i'm at right now with it but okay have you ever had an awful night where
you fucked up maybe you got in a bad fight with your partner you know you just let me think no
never what are you talking about but okay but you wake up in the morning and it's like before you're
that app of how much you fucked up the night before it loads into your consciousness you wake up
it's the best day ever right it is you wake up and it's like uh so then it hits you and then
bam it hits you so that uh this is amazing that's what you are but you've added on to that this
story and usually the story is not happy it's a terrible story and and it goes on and on and on
and on and on about who you are and why you're where you're at and usually it's because of the
mistakes you made and blah blah blah but it gets even deeper than that i mean we're talking about
the way that you're interpreting language like you look at like letters and your brain immediately
will turn those into words like so like there is theoretically something that is not touched by
any of that and in buddhism that very confusingly for a lot of people is called emptiness emptiness
or i believe in the no soul uh there's no soul you don't have a soul we don't have souls and
everyone's like what the fuck you i got a fucking soul i got the most beautiful soul i'm saying hey
motherfucker but the point is it's like if we had souls if you had an unchanging soul if you had an
eternal unchanging soul you would be fucked because the best thing about life has changed like uh
i was reading marcus or alias or some stoic philosopher who said the universe loves change
and so that's what that's what we are we're uh interdependent ever changing ever changing
non-differentiated uh reality and we share a soul if you want to say even though there's no soul
we share the emptiness we're sharing it together and so that emptiness is the root of compassion
it's like once you start tuning into that reality once you experience that which is considered
sky mind or like it's like uh all of a sudden like thinking that you have a shitty
tiny little filthy apartment and finding a secret door that opens up into this
beautiful massive infinite empty clear space and and that's what you are that's what you are
i will not keep rambling about buddhism god forgive me i'm so sorry to all my buddhist
teachers out there and all the teachers the shame it's coming in i mean just wait wait you
know you're talking about growth you're talking about growing and evolving you're talking about
not pushing right like you're good where you are but you are talking about growing about change
you're talking about because being one thing realizing another right that's a difference
that's a change okay timmy here's a famous tim leary quote oh i love it lift up your legs
and float downstream that's the idea imagine being in a river and it's actually in um in
kayaking that if you ever go canoeing or white water rafting they're like do not try to stand up
in this water it is moving so fast even if it doesn't seem like a lot of water if you try to
stand up you're gonna you could get stuck on a rock you're gonna fall it's gonna push you over
you're gonna tumble you've got a life jacket on just lean back and let the river do what it does
john london line as well 80 years ago today on the day that we are recording this george harrison
is born okay he he learned so much about spirituality spent his the last part of his life
ascending and and getting to understand this when he died there's a martin scorsese documentary
about his life that's terrific and it's his family member is talking about when he died
physically died the room lit up and that's something dramatic happened do you buy that
oh yeah and do you do you think that george harrison comes back around or is he floating
around and didn't leave or does he incarnate again or what do you think okay so i was asking
my meditation teacher like about chogam trumpa like you like you know this is a
rimpoche would meaning that it's a they reincarnate they keep coming back on purpose
but to teach to help
end human suffering spread the dharma but yeah i asked him like where is he now and he said well
chogam trumpa said when you when you die the term for it is you're in the action
which is a really cool way of putting it it's like
harrison george harrison still ripples the present moment if you any like you hear my sweet lord
everywhere you go here to hold foods uh as far as like or all things must pass by the way yeah
yeah yeah so i don't i don't i don't really like i do believe in reincarnation i do i do think that
like we probably uh come back around to get it right yeah and i know that like a lot of people
are thinking well if you don't have a soul how do you reincarnate i mean i think that's a really
good question and and so generally it's considered a momentum like it's not really a soul as much as
like a kind of karmic momentum that has a tendency to when the causes and conditions are right to
appear in the world so you are a tendency you're a momentum and so when you die
that tendency or momentum it goes through this intermediary state called the bardo and
depending on your projections it sort of determines what your next life is going to be so
but you know what in greek mythology the river lathe you drink from it and you forget everything
you were before it's wiped out completely so it seems like our hard drives get formated
formatted in between lives but some essential nature like an essential quality of of of
which is the representation of your karmic predicament it ripples into time and then
it will find birth somehow and that tendency actually determines what your next life will be
that's what they say if you want to know what your next life is going to be look at what your
current life is and you can pretty much figure out where you're at it well look man i've appreciated
the conversation uh i know that we're gonna spend all night extending this conversation but
i think for the show i just you know thank you so much it's been cool thanks for having me yeah
man it's been so cool to kind of hear over this amount of time where your mind is at with these
things i always learn something new i really appreciate it and i'm really glad you guys got
to finally meet up and talk on this oh my god yeah it's so cool every time i talk to duncan
i swear to god i'm gonna start meditating and try to get into this and you know you gotta give me
the pep talk after we get off the air here i will i will give you the opposite of a pep talk
you know one of my favorite books by chogam trump it starts off saying if you don't get it if you
can avoid getting into this stuff don't get into it because once you start once you get into the
rabbit hole it's you're not coming out you're all you're you have to go through i'm good with that
yeah all right cool uh well it's no big deal it's very easy and let me i'm sorry to be neurotic let
me just reiterate something yeah no please in case i'm a fool i'm a i i don't have a like
discipline meditation practice i meditate once or twice a week and i'm not a a teacher of
spirituality not that i seem like one i don't want to like seem like i even think that but
i don't want to confuse anybody so if some of the bullshit i was yapping about today appeals to you
please explore like some of the things i mentioned and and and go deeper let me put your ideas real
quick i don't want to confuse it yeah we're yeah i'll put your ideas man it's this i've learned this
from just training martial athletics and just from other things there's always going to be somebody
that needs to hear it from you there's always going to be somebody that talks above you and
somebody that talks below right there's always going to be somebody that talks your language
you never have to say that all you're doing is communicating what you know at this time right
mistake that that's their fault right and there's gonna be a number of people that need to i needed
to understand it the way you said it you were explaining to me because of my questions so
thank you yeah
following this new weaponized presentation of jeremy corbel george napp dark horse entertainment
cadence 13 studios available now for free on the odyssey app or wherever you get your shows