Nice. I thought Merengue. Isn't that Dominican?
Yeah, so my family's Cuban. My father was actually in the Bay of Pigs. My father was
a revolutionary. He was captured by Castro's men on the beach during the invasion. He was
on the USS Houston when it got rocketed. Some CIA guys also were there, didn't make it unfortunately.
But he was for two years in Castro's prisons. My father was a wonderful human being, but
he's also a very tormented soul. And now we can recognize, oh, he had PTSD, right? Or
as the old timers used to say, shell shock. So he struggled with anger and volatility
for a very long time during his life. And as a young person, I had a really weird background.
There was always this idea, this understanding that after the Brigade 2506, which was what
my father was part of. In fact, if you type in my name, Luis Elizondo, in Bay of Pigs,
you'll see my father's prisoner number. There was always this understanding that there would
be a reinvasion by the new generation, by us, by the kids, and part of Alpha 66. So
I had a really weird upbringing as a child, always smoked filled rooms and dim lights
and weird conversations. And so at a very early age, I had my taste of paramilitary.
And I didn't even know it. I thought it was part of Boy Scouts. And, you know, you go
back to school one day, what'd you guys do? Well, I got my, you know, how to light a fire
badge. What'd you get? Oh, we disassembled AK-47s. You didn't do that?
We should dig into that. We should dig into that on the show. But
Whatever you want.
Yeah, we will. So Luis Elizondo, welcome to the show.
You can call me Lou if you want. I know I look more like a Bob or a Bill or a Joe. Thank
you very much. Sean, if I can say something just for a moment. This is an incredible honor
and privilege of mine, and not for the reasons that most people might think not because you
have a very successful show and you have a big audience. It's because of who you are
and what you have done in the service of your country. There's a lot of people on the outside
that will see things that people like you or maybe I've done, and they kind of glorify
that. But we also know the other side of that. We know the truth. And we know the pain that
it causes for the loved ones we leave behind. It causes even to us to some degree, right?
To keep a piece of that those experiences with you at all times. And some of us try
our best to try to suppress it. But what you have done for our nation, I'm not sure most
people in your audience can really appreciate. And I only know because I've been there and
experienced those things with you guys. And I just want to say from the bottom of my heart,
and on behalf of a very grateful nation, although maybe they don't realize it, thank you for
what you do. We are only here today having this conversation in a wonderful country that
we are in. We have in this incredible experiment because of the sacrifices you and your colleagues
have made. So before we begin, please accept my humble appreciation, sincere appreciation
for the sacrifices you and your family has had to make for us, for the rest of us chickens.
Thank you, man. Thank you. That means a hell of a lot. Thank you. But, wow, thank you for
saying that. Yeah. And likewise, here, likewise. Let's get into the interview. So everybody
starts with an introduction here. So I think we might wind up doing a little bit of a live
story here. I wasn't planning on doing that, but this sounds super interesting. Lou Elizondo,
Lou Elizondo, you're a former US Army counterintelligence special agent and former employee of the office
of the Undersecretary of Defense for Intelligence. You led a previously covert program within
the Department of Defense investigating unidentified aerial phenomenon, UAP. You came forward to
the public about Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program, ATIP, bringing to
light what the government knew about these mysterious objects in our skies. Since then,
you've worked to educate both the public and policymakers about the potential implications
of UAPs for national security, science, and human understanding. You've been involved
with organizations like To The Stars Academy of Arts and Science aimed at advancing research
into these phenomena. You're a fixture in the UAP transparency movement and have appeared
in numerous interviews, documentaries, and media segments discussing UAPs where you've
shared insight from your experience while critiquing the government's approach to transparency
on this subject. Welcome to the show.
Thank you. One point of correction. The UAP program at the Pentagon was not covert. I
did run covert operations and activities, but that was for another effort while working
for the US government. The ATIP program, Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program, which
I helped lead and working with some of my colleagues, was a very sensitive program,
but it wasn't covert. I know people like to, and forgive me for that saying that, I don't
know why it says that. There's a legal definition of covert activities, and then there is from
the Department of Defense, which is Title 50, and then from a Title 10 or DOD perspective,
you have clandestine type operations and sensitive operations, but ATIP was not covert. It was
sensitive in a lot of classified aspects to it, but it was not a Title 50 program, although
I ran it under, when I was wearing my Title 50 hat, under the covert umbrella, but in
itself, it was not a covert program. It was a highly sensitive program with a lot of classified
aspects that I ran while I was running covert operations.
Did you start ATIP?
I did not. No, no, no. It's fascinating, actually, the way ATIP started. It actually started
off as a program called OSAP, the Advanced Aerospace Weapons Special Application Program,
You know, we love our acronyms, right, Intel Community. It was in 2007, Harry Reid, Senator,
who is, by the way, the Senate Majority Leader at the time, you had Senator Ted Stevens and
Senator Inouye, so Alaska and Hawaii as well, so Nevada, Alaska, Hawaii, and even former
astronaut John Glenn, all got together on the Hill, and somebody like bipartisan, so
Republican and Democrat, got together and put funding together to create a program called,
the contract vehicle was called OSAP. OSAP was a big program in order to look at, from
the Pentagon's perspective, the UAP or UFO in vernacular, the UFO issue. From there,
there was an aspect of, OSAP was kind of thinking of a big umbrella, and then you have a little
umbrella fitting underneath this bigger umbrella, which looked at a lot of stuff to include
elements of what now is known as Skinwalker Ranch and some other things. ATIP was really
focusing on nuts and bolts of the UAP phenomenon, so OSAP did too, but they were much broader,
think of a shotgun approach versus a sniper approach, the shotgun being OSAP, the sniper
being ATIP, and so I was actually part of the ATIP program, although I worked with a
lot of the elements in OSAP, my focus was really nuts and bolts on ATIP.
Interesting.
So it was started by Jim Lakatsky and Jay Stratton on the OSAP side.
You mentioned, so it was three state senators that started in Alaska, Nevada, and Hawaii,
is there, I mean, interesting, a lot of UAP activity in Alaska.
Well, Ted Stevens had his own UAP encounter while he was a pilot, believe it or not.
No shit.
And let's not forget that he was in World War II, Senator Inouye actually gave his arm
for his country, all of our veterans, Stevens was a pilot, and he had his own UAP experience,
and then of course, interestingly enough, you had-
Who was Alaska?
He was Alaska, yeah, Ted Stevens.
What was his experience?
Well, he reported, you know, classic Foo Fighter experience, these objects that would
would pursue him while he was a pilot, and they were performing in ways that he couldn't
explain, they were outperforming anything that he was aware of as a pilot,
but instantaneous acceleration, very, very fast maneuvers, well beyond the structural
limitations of what we had at the time, technologically.
And so, and this is, by the way, this is not isolated, if you get a chance to talk to members
of Congress privately, a lot of them will share with you their own UAP experiences,
they're like, hey, man, I was fishing with my son, and all of a sudden this thing comes
out of the water and saw it right there in front of us.
I think, you know, politically, they're a little shy to have that discussion publicly,
now, maybe it'll come out.
But you'd be surprised how many people, members of Congress have had their own experience.
Is there a lot of, I mean, the reason I brought up the three states, Nevada, obviously a lot
of activity, Alaska, a lot of activity, Hawaii, is there a lot of activity down there?
Well, there is some, I would, I don't, it's hard to say there's a lot.
So there's an issue with Hawaii.
It's population density and surface area.
So, Nevada, Alaska, lots of landmass, when you have people all around, so you get pretty
much a good persistent eye in the sky, maybe there's a farmer, maybe there's someone driving
a truck, maybe there's a military person, military bases, Hawaii is a much smaller landmass.
So you have fewer people in a smaller area looking up towards the sky.
So we don't really know if Hawaii is necessarily a hot spot.
We do have a military presence there, as we know, and we do have a couple sensitive facilities
there because of geographically where it's located.
And so it shouldn't be any surprise that we've had UAP activity there.
But whether or not it's as much or as consistent as some of these other areas, like we've seen
with, like, New Jersey, for example, with the drones, right, where they're being reported
everywhere, you don't have that type of population in Hawaii and you don't have the landmass.
So we really don't know.
We don't know if there's actually more activity occurring around the waters.
We don't know if there's actually an increase or a decrease, simply because we don't have
enough persistent, I guess, I hate to use the word persistent surveillance there, but
we just don't.
Remember, it's a couple, a few little islands in the middle of the Pacific Ocean, right?
And so unless you're right there at the time something's happening, you're not going to know.
You mentioned Skimwalker Ranch.
I'm just going, I don't want to lose anything.
No, no, no.
Have you done any work out there with Brandon or?
Well, so before Brandon, there was a gentleman named Bob Bigelow from Bigelow Aerospace.
By the way, this is a this is a gentleman who made his fortune in the hotel industry
and then decided to jump to aerospace and actually succeeded, right?
So this is a guy who put together these inhabitable inflatable type modules that
could hook on to the to the ISS space station, which, by the way, they're there right now.
He actually has them connected.
And he had these projects, Genesis one, Genesis two projects to create these inflatable habitats
for NASA as kind of NASA's future space program.
And he was very successful.
So he actually helped fund through his own money a lot of what OSAP originally did to
include Skimwalker Ranch.
He owned the ranch before Brandon Fugal owned it.
And there was a very robust research effort ongoing.
People don't know that.
Oh, it's just a bunch of hooey.
No, it wasn't a lot of real stuff going on, a lot of real research.
And I had access to a lot of those files.
That wasn't my portfolio specific.
So I don't usually talk about it.
There's other people that are far more qualified than me to talk about Skimwalker Ranch.
And by the way, there was more than one ranch.
People don't know that there are other facilities.
I mean, I would imagine there would be.
But yeah, I've been trying to get Bigelow on here for for a while.
He is an elusive guy.
And then at inauguration, I actually shared an elevator with him.
And I didn't say anything.
I don't want to bug him.
But, you know, I just he is a let him be.
He is I consider him an American hero.
And I don't say that lightly.
People can think what they want of individuals.
But I've seen what he's been able to contribute to our country.
And if you ask him whether he likes me or hates me, it's really irrelevant.
I've seen what he's been able to do and what he has done for our nation.
So, you know, I'm eternally grateful for what what he's done.
And and there's a part of that story that hasn't come out yet.
I think I think our country owes him a great deal of gratitude
for what he's been able to do for our nation.
So you were affiliated with it before when Bigelow owned it.
I was.
What was some of the stuff that you I mean, what was going on there?
Is it similar to what's going on with Skimwalker right now?
Very intense.
You know, again, I want to be careful not to speak for other people.
But I can tell you that there are some very strange things that occur
on that facility on that ranch that that certainly warrant additional investigation.
Either their national security implications.
Well, it depends what your definition of national security is.
But there's certainly enough going on there that warrants further inquiry.
So I applaud what they're doing with what Brandon Fugel and others are doing.
I think it's important.
Why do you think Bob never shared any of the research with Brandon?
I've interviewed Brandon.
He's a friend of mine now.
And, you know, he did not give over any of the prior research to Brandon
when he bought the ranch.
So they're starting from square one.
I don't want to speak on anybody else's behalf.
Certainly not Bob Bigelow or anybody else.
And that's probably one thing you'll notice during interviews.
I never speak for anybody else.
And I don't offer my opinion very often because that opinion could be wrong.
I'd rather stick to the facts.
But it could be one of two things.
Let's look at the full spectrum of why.
It could be that maybe Bob says, look, I don't want to predicate the science.
I don't want to prejudice, forgive me.
I don't want to prejudice the science with predicated information,
meaning here's access to all my data and you take it from there.
Start from scratch.
So we have a fresh set of eyes on it and remain objective.
Maybe that's why.
Or it could be, hey, you know what?
I paid a lot of money and put a lot of time into this.
I consider this information proprietary.
And, you know, you're going to have to figure this out yourself.
Maybe that's why.
Or maybe, I don't know, maybe because there was some government involvement,
maybe he can't.
Maybe he's like, look, it's proprietary to the US.
All this information we did is proprietary to the US government.
I can't release it without the US government's approval.
I mean, those are just some of the what ifs.
I don't know why.
I've never had a chance to ask Mr. Fugal that question directly.
But I do know Bob Bigelow and he never,
I don't think he'd ever do anything just out of spite or to be mean.
I'm sure he had a very good reason.
He's always very calculated.
I'm sure he had a very good reason for that.
I'm always on the lookout for ways to get healthier, especially now.
That's why I'm so glad I discovered Armora Colostrum.
Armora Colostrum has thousands of people reporting absolutely life-changing benefits,
tens of thousands of five-star reviews, and transformational stories.
Armora Colostrum is a proprietary, concentrated bovine colostrum
that harnesses over 400 living, bioactive nutrients
that can help strengthen the barriers of your body
and help fuel cellular health for thousands of research-backed health benefits.
Armora Colostrum can help strengthen immunity and gut health,
help improve fitness and metabolism, and enhance skin and hair radiance.
We've worked out a special offer for my audience.
Receive 15% off your first order.
Go to triarmora.com slash srs or enter srs to get 15% off your first order.
That's t-r-y-a-r-m-r-a dot com slash srs.
These statements and products have not been evaluated by the FDA.
These products are not intended to diagnose, treat, cure, or prevent any disease or condition.
These statements and information are not a substitute for
or alternative to seeking care from your health care providers.
Did you know that studies show that 80% of resolutions fail by February?
You can beat the odds with lumen and improve your wellness.
Lumen is the world's first handheld metabolic coach
that helps measure your metabolism through your breath.
On the app, it will tell you if it sees you're burning fat or carbs
and gives you tailored guidance to help improve your nutrition,
workout, sleep, and even stress management.
Just breathe into your lumen when you wake up
and lumen can tell you what's going on with your metabolism.
Then lumen gives you a personalized nutrition plan for the day based on your measurements.
You can also breathe into it before and after workouts and meals.
So lumen can tell you exactly what's going on in your body real time
and give you tips to keep you on top of your wellness game.
Take the next step to helping improve your health.
Go to lumen.me slash srs to get 20% off your lumen.
That's lumen.me slash srs for 20% off your purchase.
These statements and products have not been evaluated by the Food and Drug Administration.
These products are not intended to diagnose, treat, cure, or prevent any disease or condition.
So in your experience, are the things that they were experiencing, are they very similar?
Um, well, you mean compared to Brandon Fugel?
Yeah, yeah.
I think there's some overlap.
But again, I'm not really tracking now currently the Skinwalker stuff.
That's another group of folks.
It's not that I'm not interested.
I am.
I just don't have the bandwidth.
I'm simply, as I tell people, I am dancing as fast as I can.
I cannot turn the tempo up anymore.
As fast as these legs will move.
So to spend my time and energy now on yet another portfolio, I just simply, I'd have to clone myself.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, Lou, we have a Patreon account.
They're a subscription account.
They're our top supporters.
Good for you.
And they've been here with us since the beginning.
Fantastic.
It keeps growing.
It's a community now.
And I wouldn't be sitting here without them, and neither would you be.
So one thing I offer them is to ask each and every
guest a question that comes on the show.
Absolutely.
This one is from Jake Gillian.
Given your unique insight into the UAP phenomena and its potential implications for humanity,
what do you believe is the single most critical piece of information
the public should understand about UAPs right now?
And why do you think this information has been withheld for so long?
Wow, wow, Jake.
Great, great question.
So let me see if I can deconstruct this a little bit.
What is the one single aspect about the UAP topic that should be?
That the public should understand about UAPs.
The public should understand it, should be revealed now,
and understand its implications and the importance of it.
Wow.
There's not just one.
Let me see if I can break this down for Jake.
Um, there are fundamental reasons why you classify information by law,
by law, and then later on policy as well.
Usually it's to protect two things called sources and methods.
And then sometimes you can use it to protect some other things we won't go into here.
But those are the primary reasons.
What you can't do is classify information to cover up malfeasance or illegal activities
or something that might be embarrassing to the United States.
You can't do it.
We used to do it as a nation, and finally Congress stepped in
after all these nasty little things that we were doing,
like the syphilis experiments, for example,
or the CIA and the LSD experiments.
We did some pretty nasty things.
So Congress stepped in and said,
no, Moss, if you're going to classify information,
these are the reasons why you classify information.
And if you do it for any other reasons, you're wrong.
I don't believe that any organization,
any institution, any government, any religion has the right
to classify information that should be universally provided
to all the people of the world and all the citizens.
Now, what do I mean by that?
Galileo Galilei, when he first proposed,
looked through his telescope and first proposed
the heliocentric model for our solar system
was met with so much resistance
that the church almost burned him alive on the stake.
And he had to recant and say, no, I was wrong.
In fact, they even refused to look through the very telescope
to prove his observations.
Now we look back and we say, well, that's silly.
Why would anybody care that the sun is the center
of our solar system and not Earth, right?
Well, at the time, that information was thought
to be very threatening to the Judeo-Christian belief system
and the institutions at the time, primarily the church.
So in essence, they tried to classify that idea.
Don't tell the world that,
because this goes against what we've been telling people.
And I don't think, we look back hindsight being 2020,
realize that was dumb.
Why would you ever do that?
Why would you stop somebody from telling the truth?
I think this topic is very much the same thing.
Look, we tell everybody in modern terms every day
that North Korea has atomic capabilities
and that's not classified.
The fact that the Earth is not the center
of the solar system is not classified.
Now what is classified is the fact that maybe North Korea,
how those atomic weapons are delivered
and their flight characteristics and their targets, gotcha.
And you want to keep that classified.
But the fact that North Korea has atomic weapons
is not a classifiable fact.
Just like we're not alone in the cosmos.
These things are here.
It's becoming the worst kept secret.
It's now a liability.
There are two fundamental philosophies about secrets.
Some people believe secrets are like fine wine
and the longer you keep a cork on it,
the better it gets, the longer it ages.
I disagree with that.
I've told people all along since day one,
secrets are perishable.
They have a shelf life.
They're like vegetables in your refrigerator.
And if you leave them in there too long,
they're going to rot and they're going to stink.
And then you got a really big mess on your hands.
So if you allow a secret to go on longer
than what's necessary,
it actually will start working as a liability against you.
And ultimately, we've seen with the JFK files,
it will start to erode the faith and confidence
and public trust in the very institution
that that secret was there to try to protect.
This is no different with the UAP topic.
It is so obvious at this point
and our adversaries know it's real too,
to keep the mere fact of the existence of UAP
from the public knowledge I think is a disservice.
I don't think any organization, like I said,
or government has a right to keep that fundamental truth
away from the American people.
That's not their business to do that.
Now, if you want to say, well,
how these things actually work,
and because we obviously don't want North Korea
or some rogue nation having that capability to hurt us,
I got you.
But to deny the existence of it,
I think that's counterproductive.
I think it actually works against trying to
reinforce and instill faith and confidence in our government.
I don't think that's the way to do it.
I think ultimately, at the end of the day,
everything is going to come out anyways,
just like we see with the JFK files.
There's an old saying from Bob Marley,
you can fool some people sometimes,
but you can't fool all the people all the time.
And I think that's where we're at.
I think we now have to reconcile
and come back to the table and say,
yeah, it turns out we've been investigating things
for a long time, even though we haven't told you,
or maybe we didn't tell Congress,
and we didn't even tell presidents,
certain presidents what we were doing.
Now, is that a problem?
Yes, but we can figure that out.
We can get over that hill.
What we can't do is afford to erode any more faith
and confidence.
The faith and confidence right now in our government
at least was at an all-time low.
Most people do not trust their government.
That's a problem in a democracy.
I'm one of them.
Hey, brother, we both served our Uncle Sam.
I got you.
And sometimes, if you really love something
or love someone, you have to tell them
what they need to hear, not what they want to hear.
And this is a case, I think,
this is why I'm having this conversation.
The government needs to hear, look,
it's time for you to be honest with the American people.
I know what I was part of.
My colleagues know what they were part of.
We know what we've seen, and so do the pilots,
and so do the radar operators,
and so do the special operators,
and so do the CIA personnel.
The cat's out of the bag, guys.
The cat is out of the bag.
So back to the question here,
what is the one thing that should be revealed?
The fact that we are not alone in the cosmos.
In our 200,000 years of existence
as modern homo sapiens sapien as a species
and only really been the last 100 years
we had the technology to even begin to explore our cosmos.
Is it possible for our search for intelligent life
that in all that time,
Earth being four and a half billion years old approximately,
that intelligent life found us first?
Yeah, statistically, yeah.
And then when you look at the evidence
suggesting that and reinforcing that,
look, someone is flying these things around.
They are intelligently controlled.
They can outperform anything that we have.
So who's behind it?
That's fine if you don't want to consider that option.
It's either Russian, Chinese, or ours.
And it's not ours.
We've already said it's not ours.
We don't have that capability.
And we damn sure hope it's not Russian or Chinese
because then we're really screwed.
No, by the way, we've been dealing with this topic now
for the last, what, 70-some years.
Can you imagine?
Look, when these things, foo fighters,
we talked a little bit about Senator Ted Stevens
and allied pilots seeing these foo fighters
during World War II.
Let me ask you a question, Sean.
Right on the heels of World War II,
we have this rash of flying saucers being seen and UFOs
that were, in some cases, radar returns in the early 50s
doing 10,000 to 13,000 miles an hour, okay?
Where were we?
Well, we had just come out of World War II.
We became the world's premier superpower.
We had barely broken the sound barrier
and we hadn't been into space
and we were transitioning from propeller to jet,
to the jet age.
These things, we forget about 13,000 miles an hour,
we could barely break Mach 1, right?
Who had that capability at the time if we didn't?
Well, where was Russia?
They were just entering the atomic age themselves.
China, they're in the middle of a famine, right?
There's no one who had that capability.
I always use this analogy.
That would be like going back into the 40s.
That would be like going into King Tut's tomb
for the very first time
and as you're breaking down the rock wall
and peering into the vault,
all of a sudden seeing a fully assembled 747 jet
sitting in the tomb.
Temporarily, it doesn't make sense.
The Egyptians did not have that technology.
What is that aircraft doing in that tomb?
It doesn't make sense.
So, you know, there's the adage,
in the face, there's two types of people in the world.
In the face of new information,
you can change your opinion based upon new facts
or like some people, reject the facts
and stick with your own narrative
because it's more comfortable and convenient.
I think it's probably smarter and wiser
in the face of new facts,
we need to recalculate our thinking
and that's why I think back to this question here,
it's important that the people know
that the US government has been spending
your taxpayer dollars, a lot of it,
trying to research these things that are very real.
You don't spend millions and millions of dollars
and billions of dollars on a wild goose chase.
You don't do it.
And hiding black budgets and things,
you do it because something's real and legit.
And I think that's where we are.
Certainly my experience in the Pentagon
and the intelligence community,
this is substantiated.
Well, I mean, I think a lot of people think
maybe the Germans had some higher technology.
Well, they did though.
Well, they certainly did.
We know that, right?
The German Wunderwaffe program,
wonder weapon program,
had the Messerschmitt, right?
The ME, what was it, 108?
I mean, the first jet airplane, really,
that was the Germans that came up with it.
The V1 rocket, the V2 rocket, right?
The buzz bombs and the long range rockets.
Those were all German technologies.
In fact, with Operation Paperclip,
when World War II ended, what do we do?
We stole it all and brought it here, right?
Wernher von Braun and the Saturn V rocket.
That was just, I hate to say it,
but that was a glorified V2 rocket, you know?
So yes, the Germans did.
And then they had these other very interesting programs,
not too dissimilar to what the Pentagon had.
The Nazis had something called the Annernerva,
which really looked at some kind of far out stuff.
Now, some people will look and say,
oh, it was nothing but cult and witchcraft.
Okay, but there was enough there, there, enough data
to suggest that whatever they were doing worked
or could help them with the war effort.
So they invested a lot of time and money into that.
And that's not just, you know,
I was mentioning this because you said Germans,
but other countries did the same thing.
There's other countries that were always looking
for that strategic advantage.
What would it take for me to have a decisive advantage
on the battlefield, in the battle space?
So people say, well, why would they spend,
but look, our country did.
But one of my colleagues, Hal Pudoff,
the godfather of the US government,
the CIA's psychic espionage program.
That's right, I just said psychic espionage program.
Your tax dollars paid for programs like Stargate
and Grill Flame before that
and various other names before that.
Why? Because there was some information
to suggest that it worked.
And oh, by the way, the Russians were doing the same thing.
You know, so people look at things and say,
well, that's silly, that would never work.
And it turns out that sometimes it does work.
Look at the Navy SOC, your Navy guy,
the Navy SOCIS program back in the 50s.
Who would have ever thought, well,
I could just drop some microphones in the ocean
and maybe I can listen to Russian submarines.
It worked, right?
So is it really that, is it pseudoscience?
Well, it's pseudoscience until it works.
Now it's just science.
I mean, I also think that maybe as Americans,
we're a little arrogant thinking that we, you know,
that nobody else could have this kind of technology
because we're so advanced.
And, you know, maybe somebody else has it
and they're just not revealing it
because they don't want to play the fucking world police.
Right.
You know, we get ourselves involved in everything.
Well, why would you want to tell somebody,
look, like we're in this wonderful room here,
but if you're like me and sometimes paranoid,
I've always have contingencies
and I have contingencies for contingencies.
So if you were a country that has
some super secret technology,
would you want to advertise the world that you have it?
Well, it's kind of what I'm getting at.
Right.
So it is possible.
We think we're the smartest.
Right.
But this is why I say temporally,
I think now you're right because we know
that near peer adversaries
are absolutely ahead of us in certain areas.
I won't say what they are,
but we know that and it's a problem for us.
But if you go back to the end of World War II or really-
Who are some?
Who are some that are-
I can't say that.
I don't want to, you know, there's,
I want to let our folks in government do their job
and they don't need me spewing out vulnerabilities
that we might have where other countries are ahead of us.
But, you know, quantum computing, for example,
you know, certain type of capabilities maybe in space,
we have to maintain that competitive advantage.
But again, let's go back to what we originally said here.
If you look at this from a temporal perspective,
time perspective, at the end of World War II,
we really were the only world superpower at the time.
We had dropped the atomic bomb
and decisively ended World War II.
What was referred to as the greatest generation
then began to invest in the United States
and became the world superpower, dominant power.
There was no real near peer
other than the Russians at the time.
And they were still nowhere near what we were able to do.
So I can buy now, if you say that
there is a foreign adversary that has this capability,
okay, I doubt it, but maybe, but not 70 years ago.
And let's look at this because Marco Rubio,
the new Secretary of State when he was Senator,
said something very interesting.
He said, you know, I almost hope that these things
are not human because if they're human,
that's almost more scary who's created this technology.
And I think he's absolutely correct.
To put this into perspective,
we spend billions with a B, billions of dollars each year
to maintain a strategic advantage
from an intelligence perspective,
all 17 agencies of the intelligence community,
to know more than our enemies, right?
Now imagine if there was a country
that had the ability to develop a technology
and deploy this technology that could come into our country,
completely unimpeded, unchallenged, unseen,
be able to do whatever we wanted to do,
collect ISR on our military equities
and interfere with our nuclear strategic capabilities,
turn them off, right?
And then go back home, no sweat and nobody would ever know.
That would be, and by the way,
have been in development for the last 70 years
on this technology.
That would be the greatest intelligence failure
this country has ever experienced
eclipsing that of even 9-11
because despite the billions of dollars that we invest,
there wasn't a single indication or shred of information
over 70 years that some country
had managed to develop this technology.
Think of the resources and infrastructure required
to develop and deploy a technology like that, right?
And you didn't get one shred of evidence in 70 years
that Country X was doing that, right?
So choose your poison.
It's either someone else's or it's foreign adversarial.
If it's foreign adversarial,
you need to fire every single person right now
in national security and start from scratch.
And you better not provoke a war because we're going to lose.
So that's the other part of that argument.
If you say, okay, maybe some country
did develop this in secret.
Okay, well, how, when, where, right?
Under what circumstances?
And now China, you mean to tell me
it's going to be so brazen in 2004
to fly this right off the coast of California
and, oh, by the way, tangle with two F-18 Hornets?
That doesn't seem very smart.
That's certainly not where I test my secret stuff.
You know, we test our secret stuff at Area 51
in these places out of the prying eyes of people to see it.
Now, maybe it's some sort of red force probe, right?
Some provocation to see our response.
Sure, but there's also counter arguments to that as well.
So it simply doesn't make sense from a time perspective
that some country had this technology 70 years ago.
Now, sure, maybe, I doubt it, but I would buy that more.
That, okay, yeah, China, Russia in the last five years
has been able to develop this.
Not bad, look, 2004, how many people had quadcopters?
Drones didn't even really exist in 2004.
You had these fixed-wing remote-controlled airplanes
that you threw in combat maybe for 15 minutes
to get a sight picture on something.
You know, what type of drones did we have?
I mean, when I was in the Army, right before 2001,
we were dealing with model airplanes,
Hunter UAVs, Pioneer UAVs.
I mean, it could be us just now revealing it too,
because, I mean, if we are that technologically advanced,
you know, there's not really any money in that.
And I think we both know that a lot of these,
you know, the wars that we were in has to do a lot
with KBR, with the military.
Yeah, I mean, I'm gonna hold my comments to myself.
So for that advanced, and I mean,
we can end things that quickly,
there's not really a lot of money in that,
so they have to develop all this other shit that's,
you know, advanced.
The problem with that is that we,
when we test.
It's not really that advanced
so that we can spend all our fucking money,
you know what I mean?
Developing all this shit that's not at the top,
because if we just went straight to the top,
then it just ends immediately.
Well, we, I think, and it's certainly a possibility.
You're right, Sean.
It is something we have to consider,
but again, I go back to, how is the-
Nobody talks about that.
How, no, you're right.
How is the, well, because that gets into a very
uncomfortable part of the conversation, but-
But it's fucking real.
Oh, I don't disagree.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But, you know, that can, I'm not disagreeing.
But if you look at blue force capabilities
and how we test blue force capabilities,
especially sensitive capabilities.
What do you mean blue force capabilities?
US, good point, US capabilities.
So if you look at the way we test new types of capabilities,
right, for our military, for our intelligence,
we do it in places out of the prying eyes of eyewitnesses.
We do it in a place where it's gonna be safe,
and I don't have to worry about
potential midair collision, right?
I'm not gonna test this capability
without letting, let's say, the fleet commander know
that, hey, while you're out there in that range,
I'm gonna be testing my stuff there and see how you react.
You don't do that, because you could have midair collisions,
flight safety issues.
I mean, that's why you have a joint staff,
to coordinate these type of things,
and say, look, I'm gonna do an exercise,
and if I wanna test a new capability,
I'm gonna do that in area 51.
I'm gonna do it out of the prying eyes of anybody
in a place that's safe, and oh, by the way,
if it crashes, I don't have to have
a recovery issue on my hands, right?
Where, what is he gonna see, and I have a big profile.
So, I don't, and we've already set for the record,
and certainly when I was in the government,
we looked at Blue Force capabilities.
We've got some pretty cool stuff.
I'll tell you that.
I mean, even area 51, though,
it's not, you're talking right after World War II,
objects going 13,000 miles an hour.
In low Earth atmosphere, right?
That's not, area 51 isn't big enough to conceal some of it.
No, that's my point.
That's exactly my point.
If you're gonna test a capability like that,
you'll go to Antarctica if you really have to, right?
Or you're gonna drop it from the bottom of B-52
at an altitude of 60,000 feet and test what you gotta test,
which, by the way, we've done.
The X-15 is a perfect example.
But we do it in a way that is,
it's safe and out of the prying eyes of people
that are not right onto the program.
You don't test it right off the coast of California
in the middle of a fleet exercise
with an aircraft carrier, dozens of destroyers
and support vehicles and submarines and F-18s.
You don't do that.
That's not how you conduct a classified program
because too many people see it.
So I think there's an argument there to be made that,
obviously I would rather this technology be ours
than Russian or Chinese,
but I think we're pretty clear now as a government,
it's not our technology.
And our government has already said from the record,
very senior people, this is not our technology.
So if it's not ours, it's somebody's, whose is it?
What's the X-15?
X-15 is a rocket powered aircraft.
So right on the heels of the supersonic age,
we had just, I think it was the X-1,
was the experimental aircraft that Chuck Yeager used
to break the sound barrier for the first time,
roughly 763 miles an hour at sea level, plus or minus.
The X-15 was a hypersonic vehicle
that was to take people into space, believe it or not.
In fact, the pilots have astronaut wings.
It is a, think of a long skinny pencil
with stubby wings on it.
Doesn't even have landing gear, it has skids.
And it's dropped from the wing of a B-52 at high altitude
and then accelerates up to hypersonic speeds
and goes to the upper limits of our atmosphere
and into a low earth orbit.
In fact, if you look at that platform, the X-15,
not only does it have wings and control surfaces,
but because it flies so high, it has to have thrusters.
It's just like a rocket, just like a space shuttle.
And that was really, when you look at how we were testing,
I think there were only six of those ever built.
They started off with twin 500,000 horsepower engines.
Then they switch it to a general electric
one million horsepower engine.
And in fact, there was even a death associated
with the X-15 because apparently it had an issue
with telemetry and it flew so high
that when it was coming back down to earth, it burned up.
It didn't reenter properly and unfortunately
the test pilot was killed.
But the X-15 was really our first early attempts
and you're talking maybe 4,000 miles.
So Mach 5 is hypersonics.
The definition of Mach 5 is supersonic,
which is the speed of sound, faster than the speed of sound,
roughly 760 some miles an hour at sea level.
Mach 5 is defined as five times the speed of sound.
So five times that speed.
So the X-15 was one of those preliminary early efforts
to get into the area of hypersonics, it was manned.
And so the X-15 was, and so when you compare that
to objects that are doing 10,000, 13,000 miles an hour,
and we had barely broken 4,000 miles an hour with the X-15,
again, who had that technology?
And more importantly, who had that technology
to deploy it over the United States?
Because we were seeing these things
and they've been reported over and over again
since the late 1940s.
There's a very interesting document, Sean,
I'll share with you, that really I think emphasizes
and later on in the interview,
if you want me to read it to you, I will.
There's a very interesting document
and the date of that document that really is,
I think rather profound and really demonstrates
that we're now dealing with our technology
or foreign adversarial technology.
Let's read it right now.
It'll be cheap.
We don't forget.
Actually, you know what?
It's on my phone and I don't have my phone here.
Let's take a break.
This episode is sponsored by Roca.
Roca is a performance eyewear brand
for people who want to invest in themselves.
Roca manufactures premium sunglasses,
prescription eyeglasses, and readers,
and cuts all of their lenses here in the U.S.
at their headquarters in Austin, Texas.
Roca recently partnered with one of my favorite guests,
Dr. Andrew Huberman, to launch a new line of glasses
called the Wine Down Collection.
Guys, I've tried these.
You know I have problems sleeping.
I absolutely love, love, love these frames and lenses.
They're available with and without prescription
and have a proprietary red lens
that helps filter out short wavelength light.
Short wavelength light is in pretty much
all artificial light and it's terrible for your sleep.
Roca let me try a pair of these things
and I can feel the difference whenever I wear them.
I wear them in the evening after the sun goes down.
I pretty much started at dinner and I wear it until bed.
And let me tell you, these things work.
With so many options in eyewear
and wellness products out there,
it's a relief to know the glasses I'm wearing
help two things I really care about,
my vision and my sleep.
And as a business owner with all the decisions
I already need to make every day,
wearing a pair of Roca's glasses
is one of the best ones I've made.
Check them out for yourself at roca.com
and use code SRS for 20% off site-wide at checkout.
That's roca.com with code SRS.
One of the most important ways to stay healthy
is cooking your own food.
The best way to start the new year
is with a home cooked meal
and hex clad makes that easier than ever.
Hex clad are hands down the best pans I've ever used.
Hex clad makes cooking so much more convenient.
I get the performance of stainless steel
in the convenience of nonstick in a single pan.
They're easy to clean, dishwasher safe
and simple to wipe off after use.
They're even oven safe up to 500 degrees Fahrenheit.
The patented hexagon design is durable
and protects against scratches even from metal utensils.
Plus hex clad products come with a lifetime warranty.
They can literally last a lifetime.
For a limited time only,
our listeners get 10% off your order
with our exclusive link.
Just head to hexclad.com slash SRS.
Support our show and check them out
at h-e-x-c-l-a-d.com forward slash SRS
and tell them we sent you.
Bon appetit.
Let's eat with hex clad's revolutionary cookware.
So I think Sean, you'd be really surprised
to know that there's historical documentation
that substantiates what we've been dealing with
and we've been dealing with it for quite a while.
So if I have your permission,
I'd like to read something out loud.
Yeah, let's do it, let's do it.
You have to forgive me, I need my old man glasses
because I am old, this is gray, not blonde.
I'm an old timer.
I'm also a lot slower than I used to be.
Tell me about it.
I got my kid a trampoline.
I tried to burn some energy off.
I got on there thinking like,
oh yeah, this will be great.
It's terrifying, isn't it?
My knees and dislocated my shoulder again.
Exactly.
I'm like, oh, I don't remember.
I don't remember this happening.
So I'd like to read to you just briefly a very,
it's a two page official document
and it's the, when you look at the letterhead,
it's headquarters United States Air Force Washington DC.
With another header, the Inspector General US Air Force,
I think it's 17th District Office of Special Investigations.
Is this the, before you read,
is this the one you were telling me downstairs
that hasn't been released to the public yet?
It has, well, a lot of people don't know about it.
It has been officially released and downgraded
from its classified original form
through the Freedom of Information Act.
But it's been lost to a lot of people.
A lot of people don't even know where it exists
and I've got a whole bunch of these.
But let me just read you one if I can
to kind of emphasize what I'm saying.
The subject of this memorandum,
basically from the Pentagon, right?
Summary of operations of aerial phenomenon
in the New Mexico area.
And I'm not gonna tell you the date yet.
In the first paragraph, it was determined
that the frequency of unexplained aerial phenomenon
in the New Mexico area was such
that an organized plan of reporting these observations
should be undertaken, right?
So they're seeing so many of these,
they need to start an investigation.
The observers of those phenomena include scientists,
special agents of the Office of Special Investigations,
Air Force, OSI, airline pilots, so civilian pilots,
military pilots, Los Alamos security inspectors,
military personnel, and many other persons
of various occupations whose reliability is not questioned.
So these are the best of SB1 security clearances
and whatnot, trained observers.
And they talk about some of the morphology
of these phenomena to include disks or variations thereof.
And so in the conclusion sentence,
which is paragraph six,
this summary of observations of aerial phenomenon
has been prepared for the purposes of re-emphasizing,
so obviously they wrote reports before this one,
and reiterating the fact that phenomenon
have continuously occurred in the New Mexico skies
during the past 18 months and are continuing to occur.
And secondly, that these phenomenon are occurring
in the vicinity of sensitive military
and government installations.
Interesting.
Now, what's the date of this report?
25 May, 1950.
That's from 1950?
It is from 1950.
And there are a treasure trove of these things
that anybody can look at now and see.
And this is not world according to Lou Elizondo.
I'm not telling you this.
Your government's telling you this, not me.
The same government that later on told people,
oh, nothing to see here, folks.
In secret, they're saying there's a lot of things
to see here, folks, and we gotta pay attention.
Yeah, yeah.
So therein lies the phenomenon.
I wish we had recordings of people's reactions
instead of like these fucking typed up reports
that have to sound.
Well, you can see in that last paragraph where it says,
the purpose of this is to re-emphasize and restate, right?
So you can sense the frustration
that that action isn't being done.
There's CIA documents that talk about
how we're gonna go ahead and collect information
on these things.
There's radar reports, track reports,
multiple radar systems, tracking these things
to 13,000 miles an hour
in a low earth atmosphere environment
where the friction of air is,
so put it this way, the SR7,
the Lockheed YF-12A SR-71 Blackbird.
When that thing is doing about 3,200 miles an hour,
the entire aircraft had to be made out of titanium
to keep the plane from melting
because it gets so hot because it's flying at that speed.
And in fact, the coolest part of that engine on the SR-71
is that it's not just the engine,
on the SR-71, they played it in gold,
is 800 degrees Fahrenheit, right?
Those are the, that's the heat you're talking about.
Now, that's at 3,400 miles an hour.
Imagine 13,000 miles an hour.
And by the way, by the way, no signature.
No sonic boom, no acoustic signature,
no contrail like you see with a jet plane
when you're flying at 33,000 feet.
No signature at all.
I got a question for you, totally off.
You know, I was just thinking about the recording stuff
and you've obviously been involved
with a lot of the stuff.
I know you can't talk about everything,
but why is it always these fucking reports
that have been, you know, I mean,
what about the initial interview?
You know, somebody goes out there
and does the initial fucking interview.
Why, why don't we have, where are those recordings?
Rather than some bullshit, you know, typed up thing.
Hey, this came from the interviewer.
They got passed to the analyst.
They got passed to the, whoever reports to the, whoever.
You know, where are those initial recordings?
Are they recorded?
Well, sometimes, sometimes they're auto recordings.
Sometimes they're written reports.
Sometimes, so in this particular case,
as you probably already-
Because that would be the most descriptive account.
Right.
Well, from one person, keep in mind,
you want to get all the different perspectives, right?
So the idea of a report like this
isn't to just give you one compelling story.
It's to take all those reports
that you're getting from various different,
remember, pilots, OSI agents, military personnel, right?
It's in the report.
So obviously there's a lot of people reporting these things.
And so this type of report is really an amalgamation
of all those reports to send up to headquarters.
What you don't typically do,
and I can tell you this as a former special agent myself,
in the field, when you're taking notes
and you're writing reports,
you understand that the report that you're writing
isn't necessarily the one that's going to go to headquarters.
The one that's going to go to headquarters
is usually by the senior person
who's taking all the reports
and creates a comprehensive single report
and says, this is what we're doing.
So that two-page memorandum
that I just read portions of,
there's probably hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of pages
that are used to substantiate that one report.
So where are those documents?
Well, they're usually in the hands
of the investigative agency.
So for example, whether it's Army or Air Force OSI,
Army Counterintelligence, Air Force OSI,
or Navy NCIS, right?
They don't typically share those reports
because some of them are what they call
law enforcement sensitive.
Some of them are intelligence sensitive.
And a lot of them are very, very classified
because you're talking to people in key positions
who have key jobs.
Maybe they're working on special access programs.
So you've got to compartmentalize that information.
And then in order to distribute that information
up to the highest level,
you've got to start whittling away
some of the more sensitive information
and say, here's the salient facts, here you go.
It's just like when you go to court.
I mean, I'm aware of that, you know,
because of what I used to do.
Exactly.
But what I'm asking is, where do those go?
Most of them, I think that old are probably gone.
They're supposed to be archived.
I can tell you when I, and this is, you know,
God, I can't believe I'm gonna say this is
one of my greatest, greatest disappointments to myself,
professionally speaking.
So when I was a young, younger agent,
one of my jobs was to go to a particular military base
where they had all the old archives of classified reports
back to Korean War, Vietnam.
And there was this huge archive in the basement
of a particular office on Fort Meade,
I won't say where it is,
where the army and some other elements
kept all their old historical reports,
intelligence reports, talking to sources.
It became so big and so cumbersome
that there was an effort to try to digitize
all of that.
It couldn't be done, and this was in the day and age
where we didn't really have very good technology.
Everything had to be hand jammed into a machine
and scanned and cataloged and blah, blah, blah, blah.
So very labor intensive.
So the army decided, okay, anything over 25 years old,
unless it's obvious we need to keep it,
we want you to shred it.
And so one of my jobs was to go in to this place,
into this huge room and go through file after file
after file and shred stuff.
And now we look back and say, wait a minute,
that could be considered evidence.
You're right.
But that was what we were told to do.
And it wasn't that they're trying to cover their butts.
It's just too much.
You had room after room after room of file cabinet,
file after file cabinet of classified information
that's 25, 30, 35, 40, 45 years old.
And so-
All right, what the FBI's doing right now
before cash gets in.
Well.
God, I hope not.
I hope that they're not doing that.
But that's what was going on.
So I suspect a lot of this may have just been lost.
A lot of it may have been chewed up,
burned up over the years, shredded.
People that come and go,
they put something in a safe,
a five drawer security container with an XO10 lock on it.
Someone forgets a combination.
They drill it out.
Oh, there's some documents here.
Go ahead and shred the documents.
These are from 25 years ago.
Nobody cares.
They don't even bother to look at it.
Some of it just may be that incompetence.
Maybe some of it is not,
pretty sure a lot of it's not deliberate.
People just don't know what the hell they're looking at.
I see a project code name, Blue Phoenix.
Okay, so I don't know what that is.
Obviously, it's not that important.
It's 35 years old, shredded.
I mean, you're an investigative guy, right?
Well, they said I used to be.
I don't know if I could support it.
You had mentioned ancient Egypt earlier,
and it was just an analogy.
What if we wanted there,
and there was a 747 in one of the fucking pyramids?
Look, is any,
a lot of people think that the Egyptians,
the ancient, whatever the tribe was,
or the Peruvians,
all these Easter Island had some kind of,
that they were way more advanced
than what they've been made out to be.
I mean, they still can't explain
how the pyramids were made.
They got these underground caves
that Graham Hancock kind of brought to life.
I think they're in Turkey.
It's like entire cities under the underground.
I mean, is anybody looking back at that
and trying to piece any of this stuff together?
Great question.
I think there's a lot of people
on the outside of the government,
and there certainly are.
They see, they see.
Nobody within.
Well, let me get to that.
Okay. I can't say that.
So, you know, there's a lot of people
trying to find congruencies.
Can we see things in the old world
and make some sort of analysis
based upon what we know now
and make compare and contrast capabilities?
I can tell you when I was in ATIP program,
several of us spent a good deal of our time
looking at ancient script of human beings,
whether it's ancient Sumerian and Cuneiform
or hieroglyphics or runes
and looking at a lot of different things
because several of the UAP that we were investigating
were reported to have some sort of writing on the outside.
Now, that's very significant.
Writing, runes, some sort of symbols.
And so the idea was, is there a way to decipher these
by looking at ancient human writing
and see if there was any overlap?
Was there ever a time where maybe
some of that ancient script that we have
was actually influenced by an external source,
meaning someone saw something in the sky that landed
and it had these writing on it,
and therefore that inspired for them to write stuff.
Are there any stories like that?
Are there any cave paintings that maybe ancient humans
came into contact with something?
And if you look at the indigenous people
here in the United States,
they talk about the ant people,
and some of their Genesis stories
talks about things from out of there.
And same with the Aboriginal people in Australia,
some even in Africa,
a lot of them have very similar type Genesis stories.
So one of our efforts in ATIP
was to look at ancient human texts in all various forms
to see if there was any correlation.
Now, interestingly enough,
what the scientists that I was working with came up with,
which now looking back seems obvious,
but it wasn't obvious at the time,
the mere fact that there is writing
on some of these vehicles, whatever they are,
can allow you to formulate several conclusions.
One is, let me ask you, John,
what do we use as humans?
What is writing for?
What do we use writing to do?
Communication, documentation.
Non-verbal communication, right?
A thought, an idea, an order, something.
We give you an order, write it down, right?
I'm going to tell you something.
I'm going to write it down in a document
and give it to you, and it's indelible, it's there always.
What do we use, what are we communicating?
Well, it depends.
Sometimes we're communicating,
like if you go to a Jeep Jamboree
and you see a sign that says,
if you can read this, flip me over.
I've turned over, or if you can read this,
something went wrong, call home.
Or it could mean something else,
but it also means that whoever is using the writing,
that human eyes, the way we look at eyes
and the electro-optical spectrum,
the way we look at data, whether it's a magazine
or a report or whatever it might be,
dictionary or Bible, you have to have eyes.
That's why blind people use Braille,
because they can't see, they can't read.
So whoever wrote that, A, is smart enough to know that
they want to communicate a message,
and two, that whoever is going to read it
has to have eyes of some sort,
some sort of eye that can differentiate
and actually see that and then interpret that
as an actual message.
And so that's a huge deal, because that's fundamentally,
you're talking about a higher functioning brain,
because there is no animal right now on Earth
other than humans that use writing
to communicate information and knowledge.
That's a distinctly human thing
that's a very high brain functioning thing,
or at least for most people,
a high functioning brain capability.
And then it also means that whoever's reading it,
the audience has to have eyes.
So two fundamental things, whatever is behind these things,
they have eyes of some sort,
some way to visually see something,
recognize it and interpret that information,
and that they have a higher functioning part of the brain
that can take those symbols
and those symbols have a meaning.
And so that was kind of a pretty big moment for us in ATIP,
because we realized, hey,
there's maybe a lot more similarity here than we think, right?
There's some things that we share with something
that seem to be only humans can do,
and now it turns out that maybe something else can do too,
or someone else can do too.
So we do look at ancient,
I know your question is more like about ancient technology
and capability.
Not necessarily, I mean, there's even that other,
I can't, man, I'm gonna butcher her last name, Diana.
Pasulka.
Yes, Pasulka.
Just interviewed her not long ago,
we haven't released it yet,
but I mean, she talks about a lot of the stuff
within the Vatican and some of the, I mean.
I've seen some of it, yeah, it legit.
I had a senior academic share some information with me,
and it was in Latin and it was a communication
over 2,000 years old between a Roman soldier
and a Roman general.
And the Roman shield at the time,
they called eclipus, eclipus in Latin means like eclipse,
the sun, like the sun.
And they discussed there how these flaming Roman shields
in the sky were following them
from battle space to battle space, right?
Saucers, lenticular objects,
so think about that for a minute.
Going back to your point about ancient Egypt,
look, you're absolutely correct.
There's ancient knowledge
that we don't know how it was done.
Baghdad Battery, what the hell in Iraq
were they building ancient batteries for?
But that's exactly what it was.
What do you mean ancient batteries?
I don't know about that.
Oh yeah, using copper and stoneware
filled with a solution, probably orange juice,
they were creating electric currents.
You can look it up on your phone,
you look it up on your computer,
it's called the Baghdad Battery.
This is before electricity supposedly was invented
before we ever discovered something
called the electromagnetic spectrum, an electron.
And millennia ago, they were using it for something.
They were creating electricity.
It's called the Baghdad Battery.
That's a fact, right?
You can go, I just came back from England.
And in the museum there, the British Museum,
there's an entire Sumerian art collection there
and there's a wall and I have pictures of it
that depicts ancient Sumerian warriors doing what?
Being frogmen, scuba diving underwater.
They had this sack that they would hold
and there's actually depictions of these people
swimming underwater, breathing with these sacks.
So it's easy to look back and say,
oh, the ancient people that were basic,
but can you build a pyramid?
I can't.
How much resources would it take now to build a pyramid?
Yeah, you can go to Las Vegas
and see one that kind of looks like one,
but it's not a pyramid.
You're talking millions of stones
that are placed in an exact position,
cut precisely with tooling that even to this day,
we have a hard time replicating.
With all the tunnels inside of it.
With all the tunnels inside of that.
Look at some of the H blocks down in Latin America,
South America, in Pumapunku.
Look at, there is an ancient technology.
Look, go to Greece and at the base of the Parthenon,
you'll see these huge, huge, huge stones
that even today, we're not quite sure
even some of our largest cranes would have that capability.
The infrastructure required is enormous
and there's other places around the world
that are just like that.
So, we can turn around and say,
oh, ancient societies, they were primitive.
Well, don't be so quick.
I'll give you another case in point.
There was a discovery done talking about Egypt
about ancient mummies where they found traces
of what in their bodies?
Cocaine.
Now, cocaine doesn't grow on that continent.
It only grew in South America, the coca leaf, right?
How in the hell is our coca leaf and the derivative of,
the processing of, to create cocaine
found in some mummies thousands of years ago in Egypt?
So, you're saying these ancient mummies
were partying with cocaine?
I'm just kidding.
Yeah.
Careful.
I don't know if they were partying with it,
but anyways, my point is whether it was used
for medicinal purposes or whatnot, but yes.
So, that is a fact.
You can see it.
They pulled the traces up.
How did that happen if these ancient trade routes
didn't exist, right?
There was no crossing the Atlantic Ocean
or the Pacific Ocean.
So, there's a lot of mystery with our ancients
and our ancestors that I think it's foolhardy for us
to just be dismissive and say,
oh, they were primitive, they were savages.
No, they weren't.
Look at what the Aztecs were able to do with a calendar
to predict even lunar cycles and to include eclipses.
I couldn't do that now, but yet they were able to do it.
So, I am not as dismissive,
and this is why going back to ATIP
and looking for UFOs, it was important for us to see
if there was any context in which we could see
any similarity, any inspiration that might have existed
between ancient man and perhaps something else.
So, there is government officials
that are looking back at this stuff.
I'm pretty sure there still are.
I don't know if, I know we did.
I can't say they are right now,
but they'd be foolhardy not to.
You have to do proper research
if you really wanna solve a mystery.
Yeah, now keep in mind, let me also say though,
also in defense of some of the other folks who said
we weren't interested in that very much
because it didn't apply to today.
When you know as well as I do,
you're talking to a three or four-story general,
I can't show up and say, hey boss,
you need to see this document from 1950.
They don't care.
They wanna know what happened yesterday
and what's happening today.
Yeah, that's great, Lou,
but I don't really care what happened 70 years ago.
What happened to our F-18 yesterday
that came into contact with a bogey?
That's what I wanna know.
I don't give a crap about that stuff.
I care about this.
So there is also that, this sense of urgency
from an operational perspective,
to keep it full from a national security perspective,
you're really not gonna spend a whole lot of resources
looking in the past as you are gonna be looking
into the present and trying to predict the future
from a military and a national security perspective.
I don't care about Japan's use of a Mitsubishi Zero
back in World War II as much as I care about
maybe Chinese stealth technology being used today.
I mean, usually I wait till the end
to ask these kinds of questions,
but what is this stuff?
Is this nuts and bolts?
Is this, I mean, I didn't realize
that you were connected to how I put off.
I've talked to Skip Atwater, Joe McMonigle.
I've done a handful of these guys.
Edwin May, Angela Ford.
You know, I mean, I did not realize you were involved
or whatever your involvement was with that.
I mean, could this be,
and I don't know what you know that you can't say.
Is it nuts and bolts?
Or could this be some type of collective consciousness
that all of these experiencers are experiencing?
I mean, we got Neuralink coming online,
probably very soon.
And I interviewed Andrew Huberman
about we had a little bit of a talk about that
and how it would technically be possible
for with Neuralink to create an entire false reality.
An entire false reality.
Emotions, all of your senses, touch, taste, feel, feelings,
vision, you know what I mean?
That's one of the things Neuralink is gonna do
is hopefully help blind see.
I mean, is that a possibility?
Is that what this could be?
Or?
It can be everything and all of it together.
Then we've got Grush who's coming out saying
that they have crash retrievals where,
I mean, in everything so vague
where we've recovered non-human biologics,
is that the terminology that he used?
I mean, that could be a deer carcass
next to an airplane crash.
I mean, I'm not saying that's what it is,
but put a fancy term behind it,
behind non-human biologics.
Okay, well, is that a dead mouse?
I mean, that doesn't really mean it.
They're using non-human intelligence, NHI.
So it's not just non-human biologics.
It's non-human intelligence.
What does that mean?
Well, intelligence infers
that there's a higher functioning of the brain, right?
And there may even be,
so to answer your question thoroughly,
we first need to break down
and have an agreement on certain terminology.
So let's talk about, for example, consciousness.
You hear that term used a lot, human consciousness.
But what does that mean?
If you go to somewhere in California out by the beach,
and you hear someone say,
yeah, man, the world is about to,
the world is a bud about to blossom,
and, you know, human consciousness, we're all together.
Then you talk to a neuroscientist and they say,
no, it's actually a quantum process.
It's actually probably based in quantum entanglement,
and human consciousness is something
that is distinctly different
than human intellect and human physical sense.
There's another part of the human being,
another component that makes us human,
the size of brain and a body.
So we have to first agree what that means.
Secondly, we also have to understand
that the human being is an incredibly complex organism.
My background is micro, I went to school professionally
to be a microbiologist and an immunologist.
So I am a disciple of science.
Always have been, always will be.
I was never a science fiction kid.
I always tell people I was more of a GI Joe kid
than I was a Star Wars kid.
So I was trained in science and empirical data collection,
the scientific methods and principles.
And then I became an agent, right?
Which is just the facts man kind of guy.
Just give me the data.
I don't care what you think, I don't care how you feel.
Give me the data, let's see what the data suggests.
But I think we need to understand
the notion of human consciousness.
Our taxpayer dollars have been used to explore that idea
over and over and over again,
because there's enough information there
to suggest that there is something
to this human consciousness.
Like again, remote viewing program with Stargate, right?
We actually did that against the Russians
and they did it against us
and we did it against other targets.
And to some degree there was some real success there,
despite what some people may tell you.
It was successful, it may still be.
But with that said, let's take a quick exercise
on human consciousness and trying to decipher
what that means.
You said you have a daughter, right?
Mm-hmm.
Do you love your daughter?
Very much.
Absolutely, and so do I.
But what if I said to you, prove it.
Prove it to me you love your daughter.
How do you know what it is and what is love?
I mean we all feel it, right?
But how do you know you really love your daughter?
Well, you can't prove it,
because it's something that we all recognize as being real,
as part of us and our existence and our experience,
but it's really hard to define.
And you just know it.
And of course I love my daughter.
I'll do anything for my daughter.
I'll die for my daughter.
But prove it.
Well, dying for my daughter isn't proving I love her,
it's just proving that I'm dying.
So how do you do that?
How do you define something
that is inherently so hard to define?
And so right now, take that conversation
and apply it to all of human consciousness.
What is consciousness?
What is it even, right?
And is it possible that human beings
have something indelible beyond the body and the mind?
Something that lives beyond,
something that is greater than the physical sense
and the intellectual sense?
Look, you and I are, if you compare us to a banana,
I think we share like 75% of our DNA with a banana,
and like 99% of it with a chimpanzee.
But if you were to compare our DNA,
yeah, there's some differences,
but for the most part, we both have two arms, two legs,
and fingers, and two eyes, and bilateral symmetry.
So we're not really physically that different, you know?
And then if I asked you about your brain,
well, maybe it's a brain that makes Sean Ryan
who Sean Ryan is, well, okay,
but if you look at the neural pathways
and you go to a neurosurgeon,
they're kind of the same as mine,
and medulla oblongata, and the frontal cortex,
and the parts of the brain are pretty consistent
throughout other humans.
That's why we can do brain surgery.
You know how things are wired for the most part.
So that's not what separates us.
What makes Sean Ryan Sean Ryan?
What makes Sean Ryan willing to go to battle
and go to war and potentially die for his country?
Or Luis Elizondo to do what he does?
Well, that's the question.
Is that where human consciousness lies?
Is that where human sentience is?
And is that something that is shared
with other higher life forms,
or is it specifically humans?
I have five German shepherds, love them,
and they all have human names,
but let's face it, they're not really humans.
And I talk to them like babies,
because that's what we do,
oh, you such a cute little pie, right?
But in reality, it's a dog.
Now, it's not a human,
but because we are anthropomorphic creatures,
because everything we do,
we judge our entire sense of reality
based upon what we know and who we are.
So we superimpose that on other things that are alive.
And sometimes even not alive.
Why people refer to their boats as a her, right?
Oh, she's a beautiful boat.
Because that's what we do innately.
We are trying to ascribe something else
with our own values and attributes.
It's just what we do instinctually.
So when you're dealing with something
that is potentially truly non-human,
true potentially non-human and not earthly,
how do you deal with something like that?
Well, the only way you know how
is by ascribing human attributes to it.
You say, well, they're maybe motivated like us
and they're scared like us
and they have whatever biases they have.
We have those too.
And it's a way for us to relate to something
that is, it's a way for us to know the unknowable potentially.
And so when we talk about human consciousness
and is it possible that these things
are also part of a larger consciousness network?
Well, it's possible.
It's possible everything sentient has that.
You have societies that will refer to that
as a soul or a chi or an id
or whatever name you wanna put on a spirit.
But is that what really needs to be human?
Because this is not really any different than yours.
There's something else that makes Sean Ryan
who Sean Ryan is.
And it's not your physical self
and it's maybe not even your brain.
So that's part of the discussion.
And then, you talked about about
the five fundamental senses
in which we judge our environment in the universe.
And for millennia, look, Homo sapiens sapien
in modern format has been around,
thought to most anthropologists,
maybe the last two to 400,000 years.
Earth has been around for four and a half billion years.
So modern humans have only been here in a blink of an eye.
Really just poof, just say, I popped in and here we are.
We have five fundamental senses
by which we judge our environment.
And in fact, the way we process information.
And if you can't touch it, taste it here,
smell it, et cetera, we don't know it's there.
In fact, it's one of the reasons
why we use radio telescopes.
Where I live in Wyoming, beautiful,
unincluded night sky, so see all the stars in the heavens.
And yet when you look at that same part of the night sky
through a radio telescope, what do you see?
Oh, you see all sorts of new stuff.
You see Magellanic clouds and you see nebula,
things that you can't pick up with the human eye.
In fact, most of space lies beyond our ability
to directly perceive it.
If you look at the electro-optical spectrum
between red and blue, the way we see the universe,
that's only 0.0035% of the entire electromagnetic spectrum.
Again, 0.0035% of the entire electromagnetic spectrum.
That little narrow sliver of window,
that's how we perceive our reality.
So most of reality lies beyond that.
Imagine if you had cell phone signal or your cell phone
vision and now you could see in Wi-Fi and Bluetooth
and you could see in FM and AM and GPS,
your perception of reality would be different,
fundamentally different, and your awareness
would be different than what it is right now.
And then you have a scalability issue as human beings.
If you look, I tell people, if you really wanna
get your mind blown, type up on Google
or any search engine the words pale blue dot.
And what you're gonna see is this black inky blackness
and right in the middle about maybe two pixels large,
a little blue fuzzy dot.
What that dot is, is when we sent out the Voyager spacecraft
on one of its last commands, we told it,
turn around and take a picture of home, of Earth.
Everything you have ever known, you've ever learned,
everything you ever loved, everything you ever feared,
every person that ever lived in history,
every person that ever died, ever,
is all on that tiny little blue dot,
hurling through the vacuum in inky blackness of space.
Now, that's uncomfortable for some people to think about.
And then when you think about the size of the universe,
modern right now, most astrophysicists and cosmologists
agree that the visible horizon,
meaning as far as we can see in any direction,
from one end to the end of the universe,
is about 40 billion, B billion light years.
Now what's a light year?
It's the time it takes and the distance traveled
by a photon of light in one year.
So how fast does light actually travel?
186,000 miles per second.
That's seven and a half times around our planet
in one second.
Multiply that to a year and now multiply that
to 40 billion years, right?
That is an enormous distance.
And that's only 10% of the actual size of the universe
as predicted now by some scientists
because most of the universe is too big,
it's too far away, the light will never reach Earth.
So now you're talking about a universe
100 billion light years and human beings
is infinitesimally small, right in the middle, right?
As mind blowing as that is,
if you take one hydrogen atom,
Avogadro's number, 6.23 or 6.28 times 10
to the negative 23 in size,
that's roughly the same magnitude, order of magnitude
that atom is to us as we are to the universe.
Meaning we sit right in the middle
of the scale of the universe.
And mostly we can only interact as human beings
with one order of magnitude
or two orders of magnitude up or down.
Otherwise, simply the universe is too big or too small.
We will never know.
And that's where most of reality actually lies.
So for us to sit here and say,
well, you know, these things and they can't possibly be this
and we know nothing.
Our perception of the universe is so limited.
It's like trying to look at the Grand Canyon
through a soda straw.
It's incomprehensibly large and complex
and we're always learning something new
about our universe and our place in our universe.
And so when you talk about human consciousness,
I know this is a very long-winded way
to have the conversation, but it's important
because we don't understand consciousness.
We don't understand how it works, right?
If it's really part of quantum entanglement
and where space and time is irrelevant,
we live in a three-dimensional space with three axes, right?
X, Y, Z and axis plus time
as a function of the fourth dimension.
Well, we experience time linearly,
unlike space where we can experience it three-dimensionally.
For the most part, human beings experience time linearly,
meaning it's one way,
but is that really the way time works?
Well, we know time is relative
because GPS satellites that have an atomic cesium clock
on board, which is the exact same atomic cesium clock
we have at the ground station,
we started noticing something very weird.
We had something called atomic drift,
meaning depending how far the satellite was,
the GPS satellite was from the surface of the earth,
the more there was a deviation in the time
on that atomic cesium clock.
Now, how is that possible if the atomic decay,
your half-life is exactly the same
as the one on the ground?
The reason is because time,
the further you get away from a massive object,
time gets, time runs at a different rate,
literally at a different rate.
And so we now know that the very notion of time
isn't actually linear.
And so I've often explained human consciousness,
potentially, this is just, I don't know this for sure,
this is kind of the way I've experienced it,
and especially if you talk to some remote viewers.
You can imagine, if I were to ask you a question, Sean,
I say, Sean, give me your simplest and less than a sentence,
few words as possible.
If I were to ask you, Sean,
what's your definition of the past?
What would it be?
And it's not a trick question,
you can answer it any way you want.
As simply as possible.
Definition of the past.
What's your definition of the past?
Prior experience.
Right, something that already happened, right?
It already happened.
And by that same definition, if I ask you, Sean,
what's your definition of the future?
What would it be?
What's going to happen?
It hasn't happened yet, right?
So very simple, it already happened, it's going to happen.
So by those definitions,
if I say that I'll define for me the present, what is it?
Well, the present isn't a moment of time.
It's actually a transition process
where the future becomes the past.
And it happens so quickly and so fast
that it's probably measured better in playing time
than in actual human seconds.
And it's not really a point, it's a process.
And so if you look at, for example,
let's look at a cigar, where the ashes,
I've used this example before,
where the ashes of a cigar is the past.
It's already been burnt up, that's it.
You can't put it back together.
The future is that part of the cigar that hasn't burned yet.
And the present is the cherry.
It's that moment of ignition
where the tobacco is being consumed and turned into ash.
Now, if you had the ability to look very carefully
at the cherry of that cigar burning,
you'd notice something very strange.
Once you remove the glare and really focused in,
you'd notice that the cherry of that cigar, the cigarette,
is burning unevenly,
meaning if you could get in there and squeeze inside
and look, you would see that there are parts of that cigar
that are igniting and becoming ash before other parts.
And you can actually have parts
that have not yet been consumed
behind parts that have been consumed.
There's this weird fuzziness there,
and it's why some now, some physicists theorize
what they call the atomic,
I'm sorry, the electron cloud.
When you and I were in school,
we learned that an electron orbits an atom.
That's not actually what's happening.
We now realize it's a cloud.
It's the electron is both there
and not all at the same time.
It's this weird duality principle
because scientists believe that at that small of a level,
the electrons are so small
that they're actually able to zip in and out of reality.
The fabric itself of space-time,
they're so small they can zip in and out of.
And so they're everywhere and nowhere all at the same time.
This is kind of more into the more quantum physics models
of our understanding of the very, very small of our universe.
It may even apply to the very, very large,
but also may apply to human consciousness,
which may explain why we invested so much time and money
into things like remote viewing
because if my brain is quantumly connected to your brain,
then it doesn't matter how far away you are
or what time it is, we can always connect.
And maybe that is, as some neuroscientists have speculated
that human consciousness is actually a quantum process.
It's actually, your brain is like a quantum computer.
And that's where, that's the realm, that's the domain
in which human consciousness lives.
And if that's the case,
is it possible other higher forms of life
also have that ability
and that is actually not unique at all.
In fact, when you see two dogs enter a room,
as some have speculated,
there's some sort of nonverbal communication going on.
We don't understand it, but they do.
And is it possible that human consciousness
is really not that unique or special?
In fact, many forms of life share that consciousness,
a consciousness, and have the ability to communicate.
Maybe things like remote viewing
are actually vestigial capabilities,
meaning it's nothing new,
we're not evolving to become superhumans.
We've always had this, in fact,
before we had verbal communication
that is now global and virtually any language
I can look up and translate.
Perhaps it was a survival technique.
Perhaps we needed this type of ability to communicate
and transmit information for our very survival.
Well, Joe McMonigal talks about this a little bit
when I interviewed him.
He talks about before there was language,
before there was pointing and grunting,
that it was, that basically language
has made us a lot more, we're not as efficient.
As we used to be.
Correct.
And the communications, while there were no words,
it was a lot more efficient.
I knew what you were thinking, you knew what I was thinking.
People say, well, that's a bunch of hooey.
We're doing it now.
We can put on helmets and you can have an Air Force pilot
sitting in a room with his thoughts, be able to fly a drone.
Talk about video games and these people
that are really good gamers.
It was only a few months ago that a gentleman,
a quadriplegic, had a chip put in his brain
and now he can play Call of Duty, of all games,
better than most professional Call of Duty players.
Why?
Because it's a direct interface between thought to action.
There's no neurons and neural pathways
and having to translate electrical signals
into motor signals, right, which is inefficient.
It's just direct, boom, brain to the interface, to the game,
which is arguably much more efficient, much faster.
Would that not be the preferred way
if you had an ability of seeing this wonderful portrait
of you in a helicopter up there?
Imagine being able to fly that helicopter
without ever having to touch anything and it's instant.
That helicopter goes exactly where you want it to go,
when you want it to go and how you want it to go, right?
All with this.
Well, technology, don't look now,
but we're getting close to that now.
We can almost do that now.
You have technical interfaces that are helping people
do things now that were never even imaginable
five years ago.
So we're almost there now.
Here's something I'd love to tell us Americans
to get better at this year.
Something that our international friends beat us at in spades,
speaking more than one language.
And you can get fluent sooner than you think with Babel.
This year, find a whole new voice with Babel,
the language learning app that gets you talking.
Learning a new language is one of the best ways
to understand the world around you.
With a focus on conversation,
you'll be ready to talk wherever you go.
And if you watch my show,
you'll know I've spent a lot of time in dangerous places
all over the world.
Being able to speak the language was a lifesaver
more times than I can even begin to count.
With over 16 million subscriptions sold,
Babel's 14 award-winning language courses
are backed by a 20-day money-back guarantee.
Get up to 60% off at babel.com slash SRS.
Spelled B-A-B-B-E-L dot com slash SRS.
Babel dot com slash SRS.
This year, get talking with Babel.
January's almost over, and so is your chance
to save on a Helix mattress
while getting the very best sleep of your life.
If you're dealing with snoring, back pain, sleep apnea,
or if you sleep too hot,
Helix mattress can help with all of that.
So many of my listeners are getting
the most restful sleep of their lives,
me included, with their Helix mattresses.
You know, a good night's sleep is one of the best ways
to have a better quality of life.
I know that Helix helps me get plenty of rest every night.
It's really been a game changer for me.
Helix is dedicated to helping everyone sleep better
so they can live better.
And right now, my listeners can go to helixsleep.com
slash SRS for 20% off site-wide
plus two free dream pillows with a mattress purchase.
That's helixsleep.com slash SRS for 20% off site-wide
Helixsleep.com slash SRS.
So to say, well, that's a bunch of hooey.
That technology would never exist.
Hey, buddy, have you seen the news lately, right?
So I think you're right.
And I think going back to the original question you had,
which is, I know, forgive me, way, way, way around,
but it's important because we're talking about,
you asked me, is this technological?
Is it consciousness?
Could this all be related?
What do I think about when people say that?
You know, we have to, there's a lot we have to unpack here.
We have to discuss what is consciousness?
Is it something that is universal or is it just for humans?
And is it the thing that is mainly makes life life?
And those are all really relevant questions.
I can't answer that because I simply don't know.
All I can do is provide for you my own experiences
and some of the work that we did in ATIP
and some other efforts.
But I think the jury is still out.
And I think in order to have that conversation,
we first of all have to agree what it means.
Even terms like something like consciousness
because different people will interpret that word
to mean something else.
It's like love, right?
I love my job, I love my car.
Well, I love my kids.
Well, that's a different type of love.
Well, wait a minute, love is love.
No, it's not.
Love isn't love.
I love chocolate, but I don't love chocolate
like I love my kids, right?
And I love my wife differently than I love other folks
and other things.
So maybe consciousness is the same way.
Maybe there's not a single definition
for what consciousness is.
And I think that's part of it
because we're trying to talk the same language,
but in there, some of those words
don't have the same universal meaning for every one of us,
if that makes sense.
Does make sense.
How involved were you with the Stargate program?
What I'm comfortable to talk about
is that early in my career,
I was brought into a very interesting program.
The gentleman's name was Eugene Lesman.
He was probably the top, at the time,
the top remote viewer for the United States Army.
And that was my first experience.
I was brought into a very strange program
early in my career after getting out of the Army.
I didn't understand it.
I didn't know what they wanted from me.
Eugene had me do some things,
I guess, to testify I was a good candidate.
And then very shortly thereafter,
the program had the plug pulled,
the funding was pulled permanently,
and I wound up having a regular, normal job.
So you were gonna be a remote viewer?
Well, I got trained to do some of it, yeah.
I didn't say I was a good one.
There's guys out there a lot better,
and gals a lot better than I was,
but I can tell you it works.
And Hal Pudoff, I'm not gonna,
if you ever interview Hal Pudoff,
say, hey, Lou, wanted me to ask you
about the whole DC Metro incident on the Red Line,
and let him tell you the story.
Maybe you can connect me with him.
Absolutely, absolutely.
Yeah, he's an incredible human being.
Him, another person, if you ever could get,
Dr. Kit Green, Christopher Green, we call him Kit.
Kit worked with me, and Hal worked with me on A-Tip.
The US government has had a long interest in remote viewing.
I know some people find it funny,
but we didn't stop that.
I can't, I would not be able to elaborate
if there's any programs that exist or don't exist anymore.
But, look, it makes sense that if something works,
you don't stop.
I know, we didn't stop that.
But, I mean, where I was going is,
what do you make about, I mean, Edwin May said that,
I believe, don't quote me on this,
you can go back and look the interview up.
I believe Edwin May told me that
remote viewers are only correct less than 40% of the time.
Well, what's correct, right?
So, if you ask me to predict a lottery number.
He says what's correct is what can be verified,
which I would tend to agree with.
Sure.
You know, and Joe had two that stick out to me.
He remote viewed a mountain in Alaska.
I believe it was in Alaska where they said that there,
he remote viewed some kind of non-human beings
inside of a mountain.
Sounded like basically like some type of a space center.
How about this?
Let me ask you this, Sean, and we'll get back to that
because Joe McMongol and those guys
really know their shit, their stuff.
Let me ask you, let's say someone remote viewed you
and said, you got into a motorcycle accident
when you were younger.
It was a pretty bad motorcycle accident.
Total your motorcycle.
And it was an Enduro Yamaha motorcycle.
And you turned around and said,
no, actually it was a Honda or a Kawasaki.
Is that person right or wrong?
They didn't get Kawasaki right,
but they got everything else right
to include the injury that you sustained
and the fact that you total your little Enduro motorcycle.
So, this is my point when they say,
well, they weren't accurate.
Well, what's accurate?
That they got 90% of it right and 10% wrong?
So, again, it goes back to the metric
that's being used to say something's right.
I will tell you that in my experience,
some of this stuff was off target,
but some of the stuff was dead on.
And I mean, dead on to the point
where the United States actually successfully located
a down Russian supersonic test plane that was being flown
and it crashed over the Congo over in Africa.
And no matter what, all the satellites we used
and airplanes, we couldn't find it
and neither could the Russians.
Who found it?
Remote viewers.
Look at the story behind General Dozier
and Brigada Rosa, Red Brigade,
and the killing of Aldo Moro,
who was at the time the president of Italy.
And then they captured and they kidnapped General Dozier.
And they were gonna kill him.
And remote viewers got pretty close
to being able to locate him.
If you look at what they were doing,
they got damn close and some actually say
that's the reason why he was saved.
Remote viewing can be very effective.
But it's like any other collection data point.
There's bias.
There's collection bias.
And then you also have other issues.
You have interference.
You know, the human being,
that's why I say remote viewing should never be taken
as a single source intelligence capability.
It should be there as an additive capability, right?
So just like when you're collecting intelligence now,
you have a human source,
but you never just go with human.
You go with SIGINT, you go with ELINT,
you go with whatever other ints you need,
intelligence collection capabilities to bolster
or to negate pieces of information that you're receiving.
You never wanna take single source reporting.
You always wanna have a comprehensive capability
that has multiple sources of feeds of information.
And then you base your conclusions off of that data.
So what do you make of stuff like that mountain
or which I'm sure you know what I'm talking about.
I do know what you're talking about.
What do you make of that?
You know, I find it interesting.
There's people who remote viewed stuff in Antarctica.
People that have remote viewed stuff.
I mean, Joe remote viewed Mars.
I can't remember the years.
He's not the only one.
3000 BC, the pyramid, you know what I'm talking about.
Yeah, I mean, there's a book, really interesting book.
This really all kinda blew up
when there was a army captain, his ranger,
sustained a TBI in an exercise.
I think he went to a bright start in Egypt.
And he had a wound to his head.
I think it was caused by a graze bullet
that caused some damage.
And he was on his way to getting out of the army
because he said he saw things
and he thought there were hallucinations.
And long story short, he got actually recruited
into the Stargate program, into remote,
because he's actually a very good remote viewer.
And the name of the book is called Psychic Warrior.
I don't believe the gentleman is practicing anymore.
I think he had maybe had some complications
as a result of it.
But that was really the first book that came out
that really kind of revealed the Stargate program
and kind of the day-to-day operations
of what they were doing and what we were trying to find
and the type of things that were going on.
So if you want an interesting book to read
or anybody in your audience that listens,
pick up the book, Psychic Warrior.
I'm not promoting, by the way, let me just further.
I'm not promoting it's a good book or it's a bad book,
but it's an interesting way to kind of get a sneak peek
behind what some of the people in the government,
our government, our intelligence community were doing,
both CIA and DIA, Defense Intelligence Agency,
Central Intelligence Agency,
and even the Bureau to some degree, believe it or not,
were involved with regarding remote viewing.
It can be very effective.
I mean, the Mars thing, I mean, in the Alaska thing,
it didn't sound like there was a lot of follow-up on that.
So.
Well, so now you have, because now we have technology, right?
We can confirm by sending probes to the moon
and to Mars and other things
to substantiate if what the remote viewer is seeing
is accurate.
So again.
Was there any follow-up?
So that wasn't, if there was, I wasn't part of that.
Okay.
That was significantly before my time.
My folks, now there was a very interesting,
boy, how am I gonna get mad at me for this?
No, I can talk about this.
So as a result of remote viewing,
some of these reports were very classified.
There was one in particular incident with an individual,
it might've been with Ingo Swann, actually,
if I'm not mistaken.
I might be mistaken, so let me just caveat.
It was with a very good remote viewer,
where their target was a Russian submarine.
And they were providing the description on this new,
might've been a Typhoon class submarine, I don't know,
probably before that.
But it was one of the latest new submarines
that the Russians was deploying.
And this was Joe.
And you, well, did you find out
what was following the nuclear submarine?
No.
UAP.
And I said, well, that's it.
They're like, well, what else do you see?
Well, that's interesting,
but do you wanna know what's following it?
They're like, yeah.
And he goes, there's a UFO following the sub, yeah.
So people like Hal Pudoff,
who I consider national treasure, talk to him.
Talk to him if you can,
because he's not getting any younger.
He really is an American patriot
that did a lot for his country,
took a lot of crap for what he was doing.
He got accused of all sorts of nonsensical crap
from his haters,
something I think we both can appreciate quite a bit.
But in reality, he did a lot for his country.
And a lot of that was extremely, extremely successful.
And the fidelity of the information was right on the money.
Interesting.
It's a fascinating subject.
Quantum entanglement.
Well, look, I'm not a quantum physicist.
I didn't sleep at a Holiday Inn Express,
but I'm not a quantum physicist.
I would talk to folks like that,
talk to maybe Eric Davis, Dr. Eric Davis as well,
Hal Pudoff, Kit Green.
Kit Green is also a medical doctor
who understands things very, very well
from a biological and medical perspective.
And I'm sure he has his opinions on that as well.
What was Davis's name?
Eric Davis, Dr. Hal Pudoff, Dr. Eric Davis,
and Dr. Kit Green.
By the way, all of them patriots,
all of them great work for our country.
All right, let's get a little sidetracked there.
Maybe I'll actually hit this outline eventually.
But let's talk about your involvement
in Army Intelligence and how you got involved with ATIP.
How did that happen?
Well, they weren't the same.
It wasn't the same journey.
So I grew up, I think I kind of mentioned
I had a bit of a dysfunctional upbringing.
To tell you about how I got here,
I need to really tell you about who I was and how I started.
So my father was a revolutionary.
He was a revolutionary in Cuba.
At the time there was this dictator named Batista,
Batista in Cuba, and there was corruption issues.
So my father, with some other people,
people like Fidel Castro, Che Guevara,
realized that Batista wasn't good for the country.
So they trained in the mountains
and they overthrew the country in a coup.
And Castro had promised freedom and democracy in elections
and had a little bit of support
from the U.S. government to do that.
And he took over, and when he took over,
he very quickly turned and pronounced himself
pretty much president for life,
which is a dictator, not a president.
And he sided with the Russians, and that was a problem.
So my father basically telling his friends,
hey, this is not what I signed up for.
He said he was gonna offer freedom and democracy,
and instead he's just as bad as Batista.
So my father told his family
that he was going to the United States to study English,
instead went to Orlando, talked to some people in the CIA,
joined the revolution, Brigade 2506.
Brigada 2506.
And so he went to Guatemala,
trained in the jungles of Guatemala,
and then was on the USS Houston boat
that went from Guatemala for the invasion of Cuba.
They landed on the beach,
and my father was subsequently captured,
and for about two years spent his time in Castro's prisons.
The last one was called Isla de la Pinos, Isle of the Pines,
where my father had, he had a tooth that had,
I guess, become, it had erupted and he had an infection.
So they did surgery on him without anesthesia.
And for food, they ate boiled horse hoof, right?
So really bad experience.
Long story short, two years later,
he comes to the United States.
And my mom and him have what they call,
my dad always called it the romance of the century.
My mother was this beautiful bombshell model.
She worked as a Playboy bunny.
She was a model.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
While you were alive?
No, no, this is leading up to me.
And so they were, my mother was this beautiful bombshell.
Very free spirit.
And she had a really troubled past herself.
So never liked to talk about her family.
Met this young dashing Cuban revolutionary,
and they fell in love.
And although interestingly,
they never officially got married, I found out later.
Even though they said they were married,
they never were married.
So as a young kid, I remember living in a wonderful,
wonderful, loving family environment until it wasn't.
My father, for 30 minutes of the day,
they had, again, the romance of the century.
The other 23 and a half hours were hell.
My father and mother fought very violent.
And then when the marriage finally ended and they divorced,
my whole world went upside down.
The bank repossessed the house my mother and I
were living in.
I had to sell my clothes at a flea market
so my mom could pay rent.
She had various male figures in and out of her life.
She struggled, she struggled so much.
My father went from being very successful
entrepreneur and restaurateur
to now working in a wood factory.
And I was making more as a busboy at Red Lobster
than my father was making at the wood factory.
And they were living separately.
And I was caught in the middle.
I went to big public school.
Really bad for me, bullied bad, bad, bad, bad.
I was a pretty interesting kid.
So because of that, I got angry.
And one day I decided, if I'm gonna get beat up,
I might as well grab one of these guys with me
and take him down, I guess.
And I did, and I got in trouble at school for it.
But that was very empowering for me
because I never liked bullies.
I hated it, but I was too afraid to do anything about it.
And so one day I fought back.
And I fought back hard and I realized
I was pretty good at it and I started fighting a lot.
Too much.
And in my public school, I wasn't very popular.
Really rough, really dark times for me.
Bounced around a lot, many different homes.
I was angry and I joined JROTC.
Now JROTC at the time isn't what it is now.
I went to a big public school.
I went to a school that was still engaged
in the now controversial practice of called busing,
where they would take kids from different parts
of the social demographics and underprivileged kids
and they would bus them into a different school
to try to give them opportunities.
So ROTC was kind of a last-ditch effort.
If you were a bad kid getting in trouble all the time,
you were kind of forced into ROTC,
I guess for discipline reasons.
And so most people, if you weren't a popular kid
and you went to JROTC or you went to juvenile hall,
really it was kind of that way.
I had a different experience.
I all of a sudden met people that felt just like me
and we had this sense of comradery
and I found strength in that and I loved it.
And it was the military that I realized would save me
and it would teach me how not to be.
And so I went into college very poor.
So I had to pay for it.
So I became a bouncer at a lot of the various nightclubs.
I convinced myself I would take those jobs
because I could go to school during the day
and then I could make money at night cash under the table
and that was the way I was gonna support myself
through college.
The reality is it was an excuse to fight
and I didn't realize until I got older
and I got more mature and I realized
why I was doing what I was doing.
I was still very angry and I just wanted to teach bullies
a lesson, I had a lot of hurt inside.
So how did you come to that realization?
Oh, fatherhood, marriage, time.
I was an angry young man for a very good portion
of my younger years and anger can be like rocket fuel
it's very volatile and you can use it
to really propel yourself.
But also it's like rocket fuel is very caustic.
It can eat you up inside.
It's like acid and over time it can destroy yourself.
And I realized that that I needed to do so.
I needed to figure this out
because my motivation for doing things
while I would tell myself one thing
was really for some other reason.
Self delusion can really be a powerful thing
when you're younger.
So I went to college, studied microbiology and immunology
again, the wrong reasons.
I was told by my family who had at that point
kind of disowned me, extended family,
like, oh, he'll never make it to college
and if he does, he'll never make it
past his first semester.
So I chose the hardest major.
I said fine, I'm gonna go to the medical program.
They gave me a microbiologist and an immunologist.
You?
Yeah, that's what I'm gonna do.
And so I did.
Again, motivated for the wrong reasons.
Fortunately it worked out to my benefit.
I actually enjoyed it a lot
and used some of that later on in my life and my career.
So finishing college, I was in a lot of debt.
Really not a whole lot of options.
I didn't wanna spend the rest of my life
looking through a Petri dish and a microscope.
So I joined the army.
Now, what I didn't say is early on
when I was a young man in high school
and before that as a young, even seven years old,
my father had this idea that I would join the new revolution,
Alpha 66 and retake Cuba.
So me and myself and some other kids
were always taught weird paramilitary skills,
how to disassemble a Kalashnikov
and what's the difference between a 223 or a 5.6
and a 6.2 by 37 versus 39
and my dad when I was eight taught me how to fly a plane.
By 11, I was scuba diving.
How to build explosives and provide explosive devices
in the kitchen using household products.
Like really weird stuff
that's not healthy for a kid to learn
but my father had this desire, I guess,
for me to accomplish the mission that was his mission.
It was never really my mission
but I think he felt that somehow
that I would do it and help liberate Cuba.
That was his number one prerogative
for every syntactic member as a kid.
He was volatile man, he was volcanic.
When he blew up man, someone was going to jail
and it was usually my dad.
He was very intellectual and very smart
but he was also exceedingly volatile
and as a kid I was terrified of my father because of that,
because he was unpredictable
and I didn't wanna be like that.
I wanted to be like my father
but I didn't if that makes sense.
I wanted to be like the good parts of my father
but I didn't wanna be like that, like the anger
and I was turning out to be that way.
I was doing the same things.
Finding excuses to get into fights
and kick people's butts and it wasn't healthy
and all for the wrong reasons.
So after college, I went into the army,
had an opportunity to go in as an officer
because of my college degree
and my father's words were always ringing
in the back of my head and in my ears.
He said, look son, if you wanna be a leader,
you first must know what it means to follow.
So I enlisted, enlisted in the army
and had a chance to learn some stuff in the army.
Very short period of time, people will always go back
and say, oh, you're this hero.
No, I'm not a hero, I know I'm not a hero
because I know what a real hero is
and most of those heroes aren't here to tell their story.
I suffer from really bad imposter syndrome
because people see you in uniform,
they see the pictures of you in various situations
and they're like, oh my God, you're so brave.
No, there's people out there that had a hell of a lot worse
that did a lot more than me.
The real heroes are the guys and gals
that aren't here to tell their story.
It's the families that are left behind
that have to have the Christmases and birthdays
without the service member and going to PTA meetings
and cooking dinners every night and doing homework.
Those are the heroes.
What I did was easy, comparatively speaking.
The real hero is the female helicopter pilot
who's low on fuel but she's not gonna leave
her little ducklings behind so she continues to stay
on the LZ and stay and stay and stay
and takes round after round after round
until finally the helicopter gets shot down out of the sky.
Right?
That's the hero.
So all this other bullshit and people come by,
oh, you're a hero, save that shit for somebody
who actually believes it.
I'm not a hero.
I'm just a patriot doing his job.
So long story short, in the army for a little bit
and then I got recruited out of there
to a special program.
They call it special.
Maybe it was, but for different reasons.
I am proof you do not have to be intelligent
to be an intelligence.
Let me just say that.
But it was an opportunity that I relished.
So I joined a special activities program.
Did that for a while.
During that process of the recruitment
is when Gene Lesme came into my life
and I learned a little bit about the remote viewing program
you might say.
And then spent my time early in my career
doing counter insurgency, counter guerrilla operations
and some counter narcotics support
mostly against in Latin America
because my language being Spanish.
So think of FARC, right?
And ELN and Tupac Amaruz and Indero Luminoso
stuff like that.
You're probably too young for this
but we had something called Plan Colombia
that was arguably probably not so effective.
What was that?
Plan Colombia was a US government effort
usually with Charlie 3rd of the 7th Special Forces.
There was a DMZ area, Demilitarized Zone between Colombia
and the Fuerzas Armadas Revolucion de Colombia FARC.
It's terrorist organization.
They call themselves guerrillas
but they did bad stuff, kidnappings and dope
and stuff like that.
So there was this Demilitarized Zone
and you had these three areas,
Tres Esquinas, Apia y La Randia
were these cities where we had SF and Intel people
doing counter insurgency, counter narcotics missions
where we were trying to pump in a lot of American resources
and money and support to help the Colombian government
get rid of the FARC.
Again, this is back in the days.
So this is late 90s, stuff like that.
So we were involved in stuff like that.
Then long story short, little later, 9-11 happened.
And very shortly thereafter,
I found myself in some weird place in the middle of nowhere
in Uzbekistan called K2, Kashi Khanabad.
And yeah, you probably remember that place a bit.
It was crazy.
Spent a little time there and then-
What were you doing there?
Prepped him to go down south.
We were, I was only there for maybe four or five days
and then I was making things smoking into Kandahar
back in 2001.
Anyways, long story short, I digress.
Spent the next years and years after that as-
Who were you attached to back then?
Special agent.
So we were with J. Sotif Dagger.
Good.
So we had a small Intel.
That's where I met General Mattis for the first time.
Incredible human being.
Nice.
Yeah, but anyways, long story short,
found myself there in Middle East quite a bit
and then Iraq cooked off and I did some work
with that effort.
And then I wound up promoting myself to a desk job.
So I went from being a special agent in charge
and running counterintelligence, counterespionage,
counterterrorism operations,
some cross-border operations stuff
and to getting a job in D.C.
Kind of what happens, you get promoted to a point
where they pull you out of the field and it's like,
okay, now you're gonna manage budgets, right?
And stuff like that and personnel.
So I did that and then it was in 2008.
I was at the time with director of national intelligence
as a senior Intel official there
and the commute was killing me.
I lived on this little tiny island called Kent Island
in the middle of the Chesapeake Bay,
which was great to raise a family, right?
Having daughters, kind of give them the normal life.
They can ride their bikes.
You don't have to worry about crazy people in the town.
But my commute was terrible.
So if you know a little bit where the direct DNI is,
it's actually past the CIA, it's right past Langley.
And the commute was like three hours each way from me.
And so I was sometimes in the car coming from work
then I was actually at work.
It was brutal.
So I had an opportunity to come back to the Pentagon
for a one-year JDA joint duty assignment
and that's when Clapper's like,
I need somebody to run law enforcement
and intelligence integration.
We wanna get local law enforcement somehow figure
how do we get national level intelligence,
counter-terrorism information that's classified
down to a level where people can do something with it,
but they don't have a security clearance.
So how do you do it, right?
So you create this tear line and stuff like that.
So I was brought back for that
and very immediately there afterwards
is two people came in to my office.
I was in Crystal City at the time at a particular location.
They still don't want me to talk about so I won't
but beautiful corner office.
And two people come in, talk to me and say,
hey, you've got some background and this and that.
And early in my career, I forgot to tell you this,
I did some work on UASs, so unmanned aerial systems.
So drones, all the different types of drones
that we had at the time,
which were fundamentally pretty basic actually,
I did some advanced avionics protection and technology,
high energy laser technology, first stage, second stage,
solid and liquid rocket booster motor engines,
some space platforms.
So when they came and talked to me, they said,
hey, we know you have a CI background
and we'd like you to consider working with us
in a special project.
Didn't know at all what it was, had no idea.
And after several of those meetings, I said,
look, our director would like to meet you.
So I said, okay, sure, we set up a meeting
and I went to another undisclosed location
where they were, he was at.
I remember going up there and it was so bizarre.
The epitome of a true, whatever you think
a rocket scientist in your brain, that's who this guy was.
Kind of disheveled hair, tie a little crooked, glasses.
And he happened to be at the time,
the US government's premier rocket scientist.
Like for real, real, like the best rocket scientist
in the US government, super, super, super smart.
And we had our conversation, then he looked at me
towards the very end, he says, so I gotta ask you.
Yeah, he says, what do you think about UFOs?
So I thought about him, I looked at him,
I told him the truth, I don't.
He says, well, what do you mean, you don't believe in them?
I didn't say that.
You asked me, what do I think about UFOs?
My response is, I don't think about them
because I don't have the time, I don't have the luxury.
I'm too busy doing other stuff and chasing bad guys
and stuff like that, I don't think about them.
And he looked at me and he said, that's fair enough.
I said, but let me give you some advice.
Actually, he might have even said, let me warn you.
He says, don't let your analytic bias get the best of you
because what you learn here may challenge that.
And at this point, I still didn't know
what they were looking at, I had no idea.
But he just said UFO out of the blue, I'm like, what?
And this whole time, the two people that had come
to my office were telling me, this is very sensitive,
we can't tell you what it's about, but our boss can.
And they needed somebody with counterintelligence
experience to run the counterintelligence
and security aspect for their portfolio
because they were worried that the Russians
and Chinese were trying to expose them, which I get it.
America's running a secret UFO program,
yeah, the Russians would want to know.
So very shortly thereafter,
I realized the true focus of ATIP.
And it was to look at, I realized at that point,
the US government was taking very, very seriously
encounters of UAP over controlled military airspace
and over our sensitive facilities.
And the more we looked into it, the more we realized
not only was it real, but it's a real national security issue.
Like we got real stuff happening where these,
I've got another document here.
These things actually interfered with our ability
for nuclear strike capability.
I mean, think about that, right?
Restrict our ability to launch
if we're attacked by the Russians.
The UAP was able to turn off an entire flight of nukes.
Now what's a flight of nukes?
Think of a Christmas tree light
where each light is a military, is a nuclear silo
and you've got this kind of central command post.
Well, they were all taken offline by a UAP.
And by the way, one of the intelligence reports I have,
and I can say, I can read it to you.
It's not conjecture, it's like, oh, well, maybe, no.
They saw the UAP and all of a sudden, boom,
the entire flight goes down.
And only when the UFO left did the nukes come back online.
And if that's not scary enough,
we had intelligence reports
that the same thing happened in Russia,
but there, they were turned onto a ready position.
Like where ours were turned off, theirs were turned on.
So yeah, so we had serious concerns.
And while Alsop was looking at other stuff as well
regarding the ranch,
my focus was really the national security issue
of look, it's very simple.
We have a capability of technology
that's been demonstrated that can enter our airspace
completely unchallenged, of unknown origin,
and who seems to be interested in our military equities,
our military capabilities, and oh, by the way,
has demonstrated an ability
to interfere with our nuclear technologies.
Now, if that's not a national security issue
or a Department of Defense mission
or an intelligence mission is,
then I don't know what is, right?
That's the very definition of a national security threat.
So that was what, that was the impetus,
I think, for a lot of my colleagues and mine.
And now, being the new kid on the block,
I'm kind of walking around with like,
oh my gosh, wow, wow, wow, that's real?
Wait a minute, Roswell's real?
And my scientists that have been there forever
and part of other, or the efforts with the US government,
kind of putting their hand on my shoulder,
be like, yeah, you're gonna learn a lot here, buddy.
Buckle up, it's gonna be a wild ride.
And boy, were they right.
I worked with some of America's finest in that capacity,
really, really good people.
And then in 2017, on October 4th,
I resigned from my beloved department.
Why did you resign?
So, boy, I have to backtrack here.
There was an aerospace defense contractor
that had agreed to surrender
their crash retrieval material to us
because we were the government, we're running the program.
We had a facility specially built at a SAPF level,
SAPF facility level.
And so they said, here's a catch,
you just need, because we have this existing memorandum
from the Secretary of the Air Force saying we can't,
we have to possess this stuff.
If you can get another memo
from the Secretary of the Air Force saying,
we can give it to you, we'll give it to you.
Because this is a lie, at this point,
we're keeping the lights on, it's very expensive,
we don't want to deal with this anymore,
you can have the material.
We've exploited what we can exploit from it.
The problem is Secretary of the Air Force
didn't want to play ball.
So along comes Mattis and thank God Trump gets there,
brings Mattis in, I'm like, man, my old friend's back.
If we can't get a memorandum of approval
from the Secretary of the Air Force,
I'll just go above him and I'll just go straight to SecDef.
I'll just go to Daddy Mattis and say,
hey, Jim, I need some help.
But you know, too, how command and control works
and we understand chain of command.
So I was always very careful never to just
intercept the boss and be like, hey, boss,
I need to talk to you.
He's had many levels above me
that I would have to go through.
The problem is one of my direct supervisors at the time,
I knew this but nobody else did,
had several IG investigations against him.
So I couldn't trust him.
And so what I did is I went around him
and I was briefing with the concurrence
of the Secretary's front office,
I was briefing the Secretary's staff,
his direct, the White House advisor,
National Security Council advisor,
and another advisor who I'm not allowed to say
who they worked for.
I say they worked for the CIA, I can't say who they were.
There were the three head people for the Secretary.
They're up in the Secretary's suite.
If you've been there, you know what I'm talking about
right there on the E-ring and on the river entrance.
And so I was briefing them on a weekly basis.
Weekly basis, yeah, this is important.
I got the pilots coming in,
I have the radar operators coming in,
I have the reports, I've got the documents,
I've got the photographs, I've got the videos,
I've got the briefings, I've got a stack of crap
this big every time coming in.
And they're like, yeah, this is important.
The problem is we can't brief
the Secretary of Defense just yet.
Like, well, you can't wait, he has to know
because if something happened, we were already getting,
we have these ships, the Roosevelt,
that's being literally stalked by UAP on a daily basis.
I mean, I have these emails on CIPRNET saying,
hey, Lou, I can't keep people below deck forever.
What do you want me to do?
They're all over the ship, right?
So I'm like, okay, don't worry, the Calvary's coming,
we're working this, we're gonna get you the relief
you're looking for, I gotcha.
The problem is that people in the head shed
didn't wanna do anything until the boss,
until we had a, at the time, our Undersecretary of Defense
for Intelligence, the USDAI,
the head senior principal staff assistant
for the secretary for all things intelligence,
wasn't a Senate confirmed person.
So they wanted to wait and wait and wait
until they got somebody in there, Senate confirmed,
brief the USDAI, who then we would brief Secretary Mattis.
I kept telling him, guys, don't let bureaucracy
get in your way, don't do it.
We cannot afford the weight, he needs to know now
that what's happening in the field,
I can't keep a lid on it anymore.
I can't, it's gonna be, everybody's gonna know this.
And I also think there may have been some,
and to protect the boss, which I totally get,
nobody wants to be the one to tell the boss,
hey, look, we got a problem, boss.
There's something in our skies, we don't know what it is,
we don't know how it works, we don't know where it's from,
we don't know who's buying the wheel,
we don't know, by the way, it's interested in our stuff.
It's not a great conversation to have with somebody,
especially like mad dog Mattis, or others call him chaos.
He wants answers, and if you ever worked with a guy
in the field, General Mattis is a very serious guy,
very learned, he's a guy who wants more information,
not less, and then last but not least,
I suspect what they didn't want to do
is give the boss some information only to be asked
a week later by the media, have you ever been briefed
on UFOs, and you would have to say for the record,
yeah, I've been briefed on UFOs, right?
There's many reasons for it, and looking back,
I can understand it, but at the time,
I was very frustrated, and so I knew that the only way
I'd be able to get the secretary's attention
without breaking that chain of command,
I could have walked in any time I wanted to
into his front office, and I have,
but you and I both know you don't break the chain of command,
you can't break the rules to enforce the rules.
You can't do it, it doesn't work that way.
You can't break the law to enforce the law,
and so I was very cognizant of that,
and so I did what most people do in my situation.
I resigned, and I knew that my resignation,
I addressed my resignation memo directly to him,
knowing that they would not be able to stop that,
and they tried, by the way, even that they tried,
but I told him very point blank in my resignation memo,
I said, sir, you need to be aware, this is real,
and this has the ability to impact our nuclear capabilities,
our military readiness, and it's a problem
that we're gonna have to deal with, and-
Had you been in touch with him since then?
I have not, no, I think he lives overseas right now
with his lady, but there's some back-channel discussions
that occurred, it's for him to say, not me,
I respect him tremendously, he was a great leader
in the military, politically, I don't know,
I'm not talking politics, right, I'm not a politician,
but he was a very effective leader, and let's not forget,
almost a year later today, he resigned too, right,
that's what you do, when you can't fix something internally,
you don't become a problem inside, you leave,
you do what you're supposed to do and say,
okay, aye, aye, sir, and you roll out,
and then if you wanna speak your piece outside, fine,
but don't cause problems inside the chain of command,
that is unforgivable, and I agree with that,
I know some people differ with me on that perspective,
but it's the way I feel.
We keep talking about UFOs and UAPs
interfering with our nuclear arsenal,
what are we doing to combat that?
Well, I think this new administration's gonna do a lot.
Like what?
Well, let me let the administration first get a handle
on what's going on and decide what they wanna do,
a nuclear facility isn't just Department of Defense,
it's not just Air Force, you have Department of Energy there,
you have all sorts of different organizations there
that are part of the calculus, right?
So you've got a lot of equities.
First of all, they need to get a handle on what's going on,
and by the way, for the record,
I am extremely optimistic about this administration.
I think this is the best thing
that could have happened to this country.
I get a lot of shit for it,
but this is something I know several individuals
on the cabinet, I'm not gonna say who,
that are very interested in transparency
for the American people, like sincerely,
really want transparency,
while also understanding we have
to protect national secrets, right?
So I think there is going to be some things done
that will prevent any type of,
hopefully any type of interference
in the future of our nuclear equities.
Now, that's not to say,
I mean, if something is super highly advanced
and they're using a capability we don't understand,
then how do you defend against that, right?
Well, I mean, now they have this,
I interviewed Joe Lonsdale,
EPROS, the direct EMP weapon
that can take out 100 drones plus at once.
I mean, is that something we could implement?
Yeah, and we already should have implemented it.
This last administration dragged their feet,
no, we can't do anything about it.
Which, hell, you can't, yes, you can, and you should.
This is my frustration.
When we allow politics to drive
national level decisions involving security
without having the expertise in-house or resident,
then everything becomes a political calculus.
And that's fine until you talk about national security.
There has to be an emphasis on national security,
especially with our nuclear equities.
I mean, what do you make of this,
it was that video, the whistleblower, the saw,
I think it was an Air Force special operations guy
that came out recently, the whistleblower that came out
about the egg-shaped craft that we picked up.
There's a little video on night vision,
we're gonna overlay it right now on the video,
but I mean, what do you make of this?
He says it's an alien craft or troll.
First of all, any time a veteran comes out,
I always give them deference.
Why, because they earned it.
I don't care if they're wrong or not,
they earned that privilege to speak their mind.
Secondly, he is who he says he is,
he is a former special operator.
That is fact.
So whether you are a Navy SEAL, or you're an Air Force PJ,
or you're an Army special operator,
these are folks that are not just trained observers,
as you know, but they're highly skilled, right?
And you go through a battery of psychological evaluations
and sometimes polygraphs and drug testing,
and these are really representing
the best of the best tip of the spear,
and that's why they're the tip of the spear.
Where was that retrieved?
You know what, I'm gonna let him,
I don't wanna talk too much about his story
because it's really up to me.
You asked me about him as a person.
I believe he is speaking his truth.
I believe he is doing what he believes is correct,
and for that I support him.
I was not there for that recovery.
I was not there when he decided to come out.
Did you see anything like that before?
There's reports of a vehicle shaped exactly like,
Lonnie Zamora, I mean, read the case.
He was a cop, and he talked about an egg-shaped craft.
Just like that, back in the 60s, right?
So the morphology of this is not anything new.
The question is, is that what it was,
or was it something else?
I don't know, but the fact that he's willing
to come out publicly and tell this conversation,
I think is important,
and I hope that other people do too,
and people come out and start poo-pooing him.
Well, you wonder why more whistleblowers don't come out.
Look at the way I was treated.
Look at the way he was treated.
I'm not poo-pooing him, I'm just asking.
No, no, no, no, no, of course,
that'll mean you, I mean, I mean that rhetorically.
People in general will say,
well, how come we don't have more whistleblowers?
Well, look when the whistleblowers come out,
how they're treated.
Look at poor Dave Grouch.
Here's a guy who I served with.
We were at Space Force together, working the UFO topic,
working for the UAP task force.
That's what we were doing, that was our job, right?
He comes out 24 hours after testifying at Congress.
What happens?
Two guys from the CIA apparently leak his information,
medical information, and try to use his PTSD against him.
You know what?
F you.
Low life piece of crap person
that would use somebody's combat PTSD against him.
That is, you know, you who never done nothing,
never popped nothing, never served nobody,
you don't deserve, get your ass in the corner
because that guy was a hero.
He actually did the right thing.
I saw him every day, and by the way,
everything he said was absolutely,
everything he told Congress was correct.
And a lot more he knows that he hasn't said.
And so what's his reward for speaking his truth?
What happened?
Oh, this guy, alcoholic, oh, this guy, PTSD.
I mean, that is the reaction by certain elements
within a corrupt system.
And by the way, that's my real issue.
That's what motivates me every single day to come out.
It's not just the UAP topic.
We've got a very significant issue on our hands right now.
And it's been there for a while.
It's become a cancer in our government.
And that concerns me,
because that threatens everything.
That threatens everybody.
And, you know, unless you ask me,
I won't go down that road,
but that to me is a much greater national security issue
than UAPs ever were.
What do you think he's opened by coming out with us?
Do you think he's trying to force the government
to reveal something?
Yeah, he's trying to do what I did
and other colleagues of mine.
Let America know the truth without getting in trouble
and without being thrown into jail
and wearing an orange jumpsuit.
You know, the problem is
that there's a very sophisticated capability
to try to smear people like that.
I've been saying, wait till the real truth starts to hit.
People are gonna go crazy.
When people find out the length that some individuals
in this system were willing to go to to keep us quiet,
you wait till that shoe drops.
That's coming out.
You think it's gonna come out?
Oh, I know it's coming out, absolutely.
Yes, sir.
Is there any relationship between that
and, I mean, did you watch my interview
with Sam Shoemate, the Matthews-Libelsberger?
You have to forgive me, Chris.
It's okay.
You know about Matthews-Libelsberger
is the cyber truck.
He's former Green Beret.
Yes.
Blew up the cyber truck.
I know the story very well.
Okay.
And I know what you did.
I didn't see the interview.
I apologize.
It's fine.
But I know very well that scenario
and the email you received and the information you received.
In the email, he talks about gravitic propulsion systems.
Is there any relationship between that
and what the soft veteran just revealed
in the short night vision video?
There is a relationship to the story.
If it turns out that that video is authentic
and legitimate, then the answer is an absolute yes.
But first, that video, again,
I wasn't there to shoot the video.
So I wanna be very careful.
I know what I say.
But anti-gravitics has always been the holy grail for us.
And there's several reasons for it.
But if you can understand
and somehow control and master anti-gravitics,
then that is going, whoever figures that out
is gonna put you about 200 years ahead of everybody else.
And that's big.
That's big.
We kinda talked about this at the beginning.
Yeah, yeah.
Anti-gravitics is the holy grail.
All sorts of, it's not just being able to fly
without any obvious signs of propulsion
or without wings and control surfaces.
Again, space-time, if you understand anti-gravity
and the warping of space-time,
then distance doesn't mean so much to you.
Time is a little more flexible.
And so there's a reason why the US government
doesn't even like to talk about it.
Or any other government.
Yeah, we looked into it.
It's just a science fiction term.
Is it?
It's all we could find.
Couldn't find anything.
Yeah.
It's an interesting world we live in.
I mean, it sounds like you know about this.
Do you know about this?
You know, when it comes to certain capabilities,
I'm not gonna go there.
People just have to see.
I don't wanna be,
look, I'm trying to do this in a constructive way,
not a destructive way.
I'm extremely loyal.
People think I left the department out of disloyalty.
No, I left the department out of loyalty.
But I wanna do the right thing without,
I wanna have the conversation without being destructive.
And the reason why I left the Pentagon
was really just to finish the mission
they gave me in the first place.
What about the New Jersey drones?
Yeah.
You know, that came out, what, about a month ago,
whenever they had it.
No, it wasn't just New Jersey.
It was New York, Massachusetts, Florida, California,
Oregon, Washington, even in the UK,
when I was there.
And I think it kind of spun out of control.
I mean, every asshole with a drone
was throwing it up and taking videos of it.
Sure, and I'm not worried about those.
My concern is when you have some that have been reported
to be the size of an SUV, or more importantly,
aren't blinking, first of all, they're not squawking.
There's no transponder on them,
which if there's a large enough commercial drone
they're supposed to.
Then secondly, the light patterns were not consistent
with, in some cases, with navigational aviation lights.
And then third, they were silent.
And fourth, when we actually deployed drones
to try to intercept individuals trying to do that,
there seemed to be an anti-drone capability on board,
meaning some drones were disabled and fell out of the sky,
the ones that were flown to try to intercept
these other drones.
Now, let's talk about drones for a second in New Jersey.
Most people are familiar with the quadcopters.
Commercially available hobbyists have quadcopters.
They fly for about 15 minutes, maybe a mile or two,
and then they have to be recovered.
Now imagine what it takes to fly a drone
that's the size of an SUV.
Let's look at it technologically just for a second.
Most drones are line of sight, RF, radio frequency,
line of sight, fly the drone, it sees me, I see it,
and it's getting my signal, I can control it.
If you wanna go beyond the horizon, beyond line of sight,
you now need infrastructure to do that.
You need a repeating capability,
meaning an airborne capability
or a land-based capability that will take that signal
and then retransmit it out to your drone,
because you're now over the horizon
where these signals are gonna reach.
So you need an artificial way,
whether it's a balloon or a satellite or a tower,
to relay that signal.
Otherwise, the thing doesn't fly, the little crash.
You gotta transmit that.
That takes infrastructure.
Then if you're gonna have a drone
that flies more than 15 minutes,
in some case, five, six, seven hours,
and not fly two miles, but fly over 100 miles,
think about that.
There's only two types of fuel we use for drones.
One is internal combustion engine,
like jetty fuel maybe you use,
or gasoline for a propeller,
internal combustion engine, or battery.
Now batteries don't last that long,
and they're heavy as hell.
And the fuel is even more expensive.
One liquid fuel, that's even heavier.
So loiter capabilities, the reason why our drones now,
like a Reaper or something like that, are fixed wing,
because they gotta stay flying for a long time.
And so a helicopter, a rotary blade drone can't do that.
You don't have that loiter capability,
so you have a fixed wing capability.
That's not what these were.
They weren't fixed wing capabilities.
And so if you wanna fly a drone, even one of those,
you have to have someone to launch it,
someone to control it, someone to recover it,
someone to maintain it, someone to refuel it
or reenergize it, right?
So now you're talking a group of individuals
that have to be on flying just a single drone
with that type of capability.
Where are you gonna launch it from
without being seen or detected?
Where are you gonna recover it from
not a single one being recovered, right?
Completely in the dark.
Now you're talking about, okay,
well, maybe I can launch it from a boat.
Okay, well, how far are you gonna be
in international waters?
And are you sure the coast guard's not gonna see you
and your ship identifier and all these other things?
I mean, as some people reported having
a quote unquote mothership,
that's a big profile in the water.
Okay, well, maybe they're launching some submarines.
Okay, great.
But then there's another challenge with that too.
Is a submarine surfacing to launch them?
Or are these things being launched subsurface?
Meaning like the old Polaris missile, right?
Bows out of a tube and flies.
Now what about when it lands?
And what about if one crashes?
Because it's technology, right?
It could be interfered with electronic jamming capabilities.
Are you willing to take that risk
and all of a sudden now you've lost a drone
and it's paraded like the Russians did
with the U-2 back in the 1960s
when we were flying the U-2 over Mother Russia?
No, that's a PR disaster.
So there's a lot of things that are inconsistent
with some of the descriptions of some of these UAP
or some of these UASs or drones.
And I think the fact that we don't know
is proof positive why we need to know.
For the government to come out this last administration,
I mean, this is embarrassing to say to the American people,
yeah, y'all are seeing stuff.
Every single one of these are being flown in a legal way.
And they're all the heaviest drones or manned aircraft.
First of all, you don't shut down a military air base
because something's being flown over your base legally.
Get the hell out of town.
We're not that stupid, right?
And when you have all these people that are reporting
to include members of Congress,
don't tell me that these are all legitimately,
because if they were, then where's the paperwork from the FAA?
Where's the squat code on this?
How come they're not showing up on flight aware, right?
Nothing.
And then they'll say, oh, these are all being flown legally,
but we don't know whose they are.
Wait a minute.
Then how can you say they're being flown legally
if you don't know who they belong to, right?
It's even the statement itself is contradictory
and saying, no, no, folks, just don't worry about it.
Nothing to see here.
That's the same kind of crap they tried to pull
with other things, like with the Afghanistan withdrawal.
Don't get me started.
I mean, you keep feeding a bunch of crap to people.
You think that they're gonna get used to eating crap, no.
They're gonna get pissed off
and throw the plate in your face.
And that's what we saw with this last election.
The people got tired of being lied to
and constantly being told something
that was exact opposite of what was happening.
Politics aside, I don't care if you're Democrat
or Republican, nobody needs to do that.
Just tell the American the truth.
And look, if you don't have an answer, say that too.
But don't lie, don't insult the American public.
Come on, that's not why we put people in office.
I mean, what are they?
What are they?
What do you think they are?
Well, I think there may be multiple things.
It might be a combination of things.
So in the old days, if you had like, for example,
if you breach the perimeter of a military base,
you would have some jeeps come out
and maybe a helicopter to try to find what's going on.
But we're more sophisticated than that.
We now have drone capability ourselves.
And so if we detect something on the perimeter,
breaking a perimeter, we can just launch drones like that.
Automatic, we can geofence the whole place
and automatically have drones take off
without even a human being involved
to figure out what's going on.
And by the way, it's a lot cheaper.
You can cover a lot more area using a drone
than you can with one or two helicopters.
So imagine a scenario where maybe some people reporting
some sort of really anomalous issue, a UAP perhaps.
And then the response by us is to launch drones
to try to figure out what's going on.
And so you have some people reporting something
that doesn't look like a drone,
size of an SUV that disappears,
comes in and out of the water potentially,
stocks postcard boats in the middle of the ocean, right?
Up to 20 at a time.
And then our response is to launch drones
to figure out what these are.
And then people report, no, I was worrying.
I could hear it making sound.
It was blinking lights like a plane.
It was definitely a drone.
They both could be right.
Both could actually be happening.
Now, I'm not saying for the record,
I'm not saying that's what's occurring,
but that could explain why you have this varying degrees
of explanation between eyewitnesses.
Someone says it's huge.
It's been loiting for hours and hours.
It doesn't look like anything I've ever seen before.
And then someone says, oh, no, a little tiny thing
with warring blades and blinking lights.
So to answer your question, what is it?
And is it one or the other?
It actually could be both.
And it could also be other options.
It's not something that we haven't yet considered.
But again, this is why it's so important.
This is why I've been trying to emphasize
with the new administration to get a handle on this,
because this will be a PR disaster.
It will be, it already has been,
if we don't get a handle on it.
So there's been several recommendations
that have been floated up to the new administration
to help President Trump get a handle on this
and do exactly like he said he's going to do.
And I full faith in Congress.
What are some of the other possibilities
that we haven't considered?
Foreign adversarial capability.
Is there a new threat force technology
that's being used to assess our reaction to certain things?
I mean, I think that was brought up.
There was a lot of chatter that it might be Iranian drones.
I mean, there have been reports
that that's why the inauguration was moved indoors
was an Iranian drone threat.
Yeah, could be Chinese.
Then there's also the other alternative which you discussed.
Maybe it's a blue force response to a threat
and we don't want to panic the public.
We've got a broken arrow situation on our hands.
We've got a lost nuke, right?
Maybe some bad guy figured out how to do something
and put something together under our noses.
That's a scary thought.
Or it could be someone trying to figure out,
look, let's see the response.
If I was a bad guy and I wanted to use a drone
to spray some sort of chemical or biological agent, right?
How do we defend against that?
Could we detect it?
An airborne aerosol attack.
And so how do we detect it?
Well, we'll send some drones out to spray something,
nothing bad, just something, a tracer,
that we can pick up with other drones
and send other drones out to say,
yeah, we can actually pick this up
and this technology works, right?
So there's lots of different possibilities
and we really need to consider them all.
I don't understand why we wouldn't have used
one of those directed AMP weapons.
Rather, we could have and we should have and we did it.
And this is my point, it is so ridiculous
and all it takes is someone in the administration say,
I will tell you, when I was in Pentagon,
I was part of a working group,
the US Air Domain Working Group
and it was co-sponsored by the FAA
and Department of Homeland Security, DHS.
And even when I was there like 2013 and 2014,
they were still arguing who was responsible for what?
When you say, okay, who's responsible for drones?
No one wanted to accept it.
It's ridiculous and this is why I think
the president you're gonna see
is probably some maybe executive orders come out
saying from now on, okay, you're gonna do this.
And if there's a drone in the sky, the buck stops with you
and yes, you can shoot it down.
Now, if it's not ours and we're not squawking,
then shame on you, zap it.
If it turns out to be a government contractor,
well, you should have listed your flight path.
Sorry, your million dollar capability crash,
that was your fault, not mine.
Yes, we do have the capability.
Very easy to do that, but we don't.
Yeah, yeah.
Just like the Chinese spy balloon, right?
How many have went over the northern continental
United States before we actually saw one and shot it down?
Oh, I was really upset about that.
It did turn out that we did extract
some type of intelligence out of that balloon.
Well, you know, the story is now, right,
that we've been known about these flights for a long time
and it never got reported up.
So that's a break in the chain of command too.
And who had the unilateral authority to make that decision?
Yeah.
I guarantee you, they did not have that authority.
Yeah, yeah.
How close are, I mean, what is,
how concerned are you that China, Russia, Iran, name,
enemy of us has this type of technology?
This type, as in the drone technology or the UAP technology?
The UAP.
Oh, Sean, I am worried.
I'm worried particularly with the two big guys,
Russia and China.
China has already announced
through the Five Continents Initiative
to run the entire,
be in charge of the entire United Nations effort
for UAP investigations.
They announced what?
Can you say that again?
I think it was the South China Morning Sun.
They announced through what they call
the Five Continents Initiative,
China has proposed to the United Nations
that they set up and run
the UAP investigation for the United Nations.
Russia has had a long history in this.
In fact, right after the Berlin Wall fell down
and there was this brief romance period,
this marriage kind of honeymoon
between the United States and Russia.
And when that happened, the ball came down.
Actually, you might have been too young.
There was this brief period for a few years
where we were working with KGB.
KGB was working with us
and they were giving us all their files.
And we gained a lot of insight into their UAP program
into the, well, better not say it.
There's some names, program names
that the Russians were involved with involving UAP
and it was very precise.
They were sharing a lot of intel with us.
There was a lot of it.
And even at ATIP, we had a lot of that intel
available to us.
So we know for a fact, Russia and China.
We also know for a fact that there were several key allies,
five eye partners.
I won't say which ones they are
because they might get mad.
But they were interested
and we had actually an information
sharing agreement with them.
In fact, Japan two and a half, two years ago,
two and a half years ago,
came to the United States, two and a half years ago,
came to, actually about three years ago now,
came to the Pentagon and asked to enter
into a bilateral intelligence information sharing agreement
with the United States for the sole purposes
of sharing UAP related information.
Interesting.
Is there any overlap with this information and intel?
When you say overlap, I'm trying to understand what.
What I'm asking, are we seeing any similarities?
Oh yeah, all similarities.
That's what ATIP did.
That's what the five observables were.
Yeah, there's similarities.
They don't have totally different shit than we have.
It's a little bit different.
When you say they don't have different,
are you talking about other nations?
I'm sorry, forgive me.
When we're sharing files with Russia or Japan or China,
whoever the hell it is,
are we seeing similarities in the intel?
Absolutely, yes.
The morphology, the velocity,
the performance characteristics, the capabilities,
absolutely we are.
Absolutely we are.
What the Italian fighter pilot saw
three weeks ago over the Adriatic Sea,
we saw four years ago with a Navy Super Hornet pilot.
Absolutely.
Okay, okay.
Wow.
How much do you think they know that we don't know?
That's my fear.
That's why this is a problem.
I don't fear the UAP or the UAP technology.
I fear some other country having that technology
and using it against us.
And here we are, we're not even willing
to have a conversation with our own people.
They're totally open about it, they don't give shit.
But they're spending lots of money into this topic.
So that is part of my concern.
Well, I hope you're right.
I hope we start getting some answers.
Well, the good news is I think we actually know
a lot more than we've admitted, fortunately.
Is that good news?
I guess it probably is.
Well, what it is, it's at least I think encouraging
that we've been looking at UFOs for a long time, brother.
This is not new.
We have been involved in this topic
since well before Blue Book.
I just read you a document, they're from 1950.
There's stuff from the National Security Council,
the president, from J. Edgar Hoover,
the director of the CIA.
It's all in writing, it's all there.
I just sent you a small little, tiny little snapshot
of some of the reporting.
There's a bunch of it.
So when people say, well, our government doesn't know
anything, hello, yes, they do.
That's just been a recent part of the narrative
so you don't look over there.
We've known about it for a long time.
We've been investigating.
There's documents on official investigations
all the way to the White House on this topic.
We got it.
So I would tell people, I think, look, here's the good news
because I don't want to be all doom and gloom
and go, oh, you're fear-mongering
and you're trying to say that things are a threat.
No, I'm not.
The threat is our lack of knowledge.
The threat is our lack of knowledge on this topic
and our threat is not being transparent
with the American people.
You can't fix a problem, right?
You can't recover from a problem
if you don't identify it in the first place.
I think we're at the point now,
there was a fear for a very long time
why our government didn't share this information
with the American public.
And I understand, I don't agree with it, for the record,
but I can respect it and understand it.
At the height of the Cold War, what was going on?
Well, you had this winner-takes-all approach
to a chess match between then Soviet Union
and the United States.
And we had a lot of things going on.
We had civil unrest and we had conflicts over here
in Vietnam and other places, and we had a nuke,
real nuke issue.
Russians had nukes, we had nukes,
and we're building more and more and more and more
and possibly go to war.
And there was this concern that, you know,
here's this real threat from Russia
and then you've got this other thing going on here
that is interesting, but doesn't show any obvious signs
of being a threat yet.
So why don't we focus on this issue here
and then we'll kind of maybe at some point
address that issue.
Then there's also the notion of you don't admit
there's a problem until you have a solution.
Look, governments are solution-oriented.
That's what we pay them to do, to have solutions.
And let me give you a real case in point to this.
In the 1960s, it's actually started in the 50s,
the CIA and Lockheed at the time
developed the U-2 spy plane.
And the idea of this plane was to fly faster and higher
than any other plane we ever had
and fly in contravention to what?
The Russian agreement we had, the treaty with the Russians
that we would not fly manned reconnaissance missions
over mainland Russia.
And what did we do?
We did the exact opposite.
We actually flew manned reconnaissance missions,
but we did it in a way where we didn't think
they would ever, ever see it.
And what happened the first couple of missions?
We succeeded.
They didn't, Russians didn't respond.
Mission success.
They didn't even know we were there or did they?
It wasn't until the Russians were able to develop the
and deploy the SA-2 surface to air missile
and successfully shoot one down and parade powers,
who was the pilot and show the wreckage
in front of the United Nations,
did the Russians ever admit
that they were tracking every single flight.
It wasn't until they could neutralize the threat
that they ever admit even to the Russian people
that there was a problem
because that's what governments do.
And so is it possible that some people in our government
said, look, this is just too much
for most people to absorb right now.
We don't know how to deal with it.
Let's not cause panic.
There were some studies that were done
by the United States government
commissioned to some think tanks by the US government.
And in those studies, I said,
what would happen with the American people
if we disclose the presence of UFOs?
And the answer was, you can't.
You will cause civil unrest throughout our population.
And people say, no, that's silly.
You're not gonna cause panic and civil unrest.
Well, look, it's happened before
where people got freaked out
when the Dead Sea Scrolls were first,
I think it was 1947, right?
They were discovered, the Dead Sea Scrolls.
It was like years and years and years later
before the translation of those Dead Sea Scrolls
were publicly released.
Now why is that?
Because they were afraid it was gonna contradict
the current understanding
of the Judeo-Christian belief system.
We don't want, this will upset people too much, right?
Cause panic, cause anxiety, hysteria at a mass scale.
I can understand that.
I can understand that mentality,
but the reality is the American people can handle the truth.
In fact, the American people deserve the truth.
This generation, new generation of young men and women
are different than mine.
They are different.
They have access to the entire world on their cell phones
in virtually any language instantly.
If I wanted to go learn something in school,
I had to go to the school library,
grab an encyclopedia that's probably 20 years old
and read a paragraph on something, right?
If the page was even there
so that some kid didn't rip it out
and put it as part of his book report.
Now, you've got the entire world history
in the palm of your hands.
So I think this new generation is much more willing
and readily able to accept some of these more profound ideas
about humans and our existence and our place in this cosmos.
They're not causing panic.
Most of the people, young people I talk to,
they go, meh, yeah, we know aliens are real.
You do?
Yeah, why not?
Well, okay.
I mean, that's different than when I grew up
and people thought you were crazy.
In fact, the American Psychological Association
once considered the study or research or belief in UFOs
as being an extreme form of deviance.
Think about that.
Same with tattoos, by the way, right?
So I think our mentality of our society is changing.
I think we're not, you know, the old saying,
I'm not your father, this is not your father's oldsmobile.
I don't think we're in the same place,
mentally, psychologically, sociologically, theologically
than we were in my generation.
I think with where we are as a society,
things have fundamentally changed, you know,
the way we deal with new information and new ideas.
Let's not forget that in the words of Arthur C. Clarke,
any sufficient technology, advanced technology,
appears like magic, right?
But it's not, it's just technology.
I often tell people, you know, a little exercise.
I say, if I tell you the word parachute,
para being a prefix, Latin prefix,
meaning above or beside.
So if I say parachute, what do you think of?
Well, I think of about a device that deploys over my head
and helps me get to ground with a thump
and not a thud, hopefully, right?
And if I say parachute, I mean, paramedic,
what do you think?
Well, I think of first responders, something positive,
people there to save a life, you know?
So paramedic, parachute.
But then when I say paranormal, what happens?
You just did it.
You did exactly what most people do, they go, hmm, right?
The reason why is because we have been conditioned
that word paranormal is spooky, it's weird.
When in reality, everything in science,
everything in science is paranormal
until it becomes normal.
The cell phones that we use and Wi-Fi signals
and the laptop computer and all that at one point
would have been considered paranormal.
And now it's routine, it's not normal.
It's just advanced technology.
And so I think with this new generation of young people,
they realize that.
They understand that a lot of things
that we grew up thinking strange and weird are,
I was at a time, you probably remember this probably,
well, yeah, you're in the military for this.
Do you remember the whole policy of don't ask, don't tell?
And people's lives were ruined,
and if they suspected you of being homosexual,
that you could lose your entire career and be discharged.
Oh, that's silly, who gives a crap if someone's gay?
I mean, right?
But that was the mentality back then.
And man, people were, you lose your career over that shit.
Now we look back and say being patriotic
has nothing to do with your sexual orientation.
Who gives a shit, right?
But that was real back then,
and it affected a lot of people's lives.
This new generation, I think, realizes that.
They're like, hey, man, you guys are really kind of stuck
in this old paradigm of doing things.
Maybe you should reconsider and reevaluate.
Because at the end of the day,
the topic of UFOs and the UAP,
UAP aren't gonna change, it's here, whatever it is.
The only thing that changes the way that we deal with it,
the way we look at it, the way we think about it,
the way we handle it, right?
We can't change that fact that something exists.
I can't change the fact that there's a lion or a tiger
or a hippopotamus on that side of the wall.
What I can do is change the way that I view that.
Is it a threat or is it an opportunity?
Can it hurt me?
Well, yeah, but if it's behind the case, then probably not.
And can I learn something from it and things like that?
That's my perspective.
I don't have all the answers.
I have some answers that hopefully will continue
to be developed and come out in a legal way.
I'm not a leaker.
I've never disclosed classified information.
I still maintain my top secret security clearance
with SCI eligibility.
I'm not gonna jeopardize it.
I took an oath to defend this country
from all enemies, foreign and domestic,
and that's what I'm gonna do.
And I don't think I need to compromise national security
to have this conversation.
We've come a long way in the last seven years.
And I've said before to people,
there's a difference between doing things right
and doing things right now.
I prefer to do things right.
We have one opportunity to do it right.
And I think we are making significant headway.
If someone like me were to just come out full Monty
and say everything I know, you'll know more information,
but you'll never get any more
because I'll go to jail and that's it.
And so I think there's a balance.
I think we can continue to have this conversation,
get the members of Congress engaged,
support our new administration
in their pursuit, dogged pursuit of the truth,
while increasing the aperture of transparency
and disclosure in a manner that is constructive,
not destructive.
In a manner that gives the American people
what they deserve, the information they deserve,
but without compromising any type of national security,
equity or capability.
We can do it.
Yeah, it's harder.
Yeah, it's a lot harder.
I know, ask me how I know,
but we're succeeding.
We're doing it.
We're able to do it.
We just gotta have a little bit of patience
and a little bit of courage.
I think we're doing it.
Look, the fact you and I are having this conversation,
you are one of the biggest media personalities
on the planet.
Now think about that.
You now have more people listening to you
and your voice on a weekly basis
than the major networks of our country
for the last 70 years, like ABC, the CBS, and NBC.
So your voice matters and we're having this conversation.
There was a time that people in the media
would never talk about this
because it was suicide, just like politicians.
This topic would be considered political suicide
because when you mention UFOs,
people think tinfoil hats and Elvis on the mothership
and nonsense like that.
No, what we're talking about is national security.
And we're also talking about the human condition,
the way we process information,
the way we handle new paradigms.
I've used this before.
And I think to its effect,
my wife will kill me for saying this
because she hates this analogy,
but I will submit to you that there are moments
in our evolution as a species
where these paradigm moments occur,
where we change fundamentally
our understanding of our reality.
And so one may argue that when we were first coming out
of the cave for the very first time
and gazing upon the heavens,
we realized at that moment
that our world has got a lot bigger.
Another paradigm moment may be
when two people were striking a rock together
and all of a sudden a spark flew and they created fire.
And for the first time,
mankind could illuminate the darkness.
And now the monsters hiding behind the trees,
well, they were just bushes, right?
Another paradigm moment may have been
when mankind was standing on a stony beach
and one fisherman says to the other,
you're not going to sail over the horizon.
And he says to him, you can't do that.
You're going to fall off the edge.
You know, by the way, there's sea monsters out there,
giant cracking and you're going to get ripped apart.
And of course people laugh about it now,
but you know what, it turns out they were right.
There are sea monsters.
They're just called giant squid of the Pacific
and great white sharks and blue whales.
And they're really not monsters, really.
They're part of our nature.
They're part of our understanding.
And so maybe this topic of UAP,
this is just yet another stony beach
we're about to sail over the horizon.
Yeah, but we already are with AI.
Oh, absolutely.
I could not agree more.
I think you're absolutely correct.
Well, Lou.
How have we got to any of the questions
you wanted to ask?
I'm sorry.
It's been a fascinating interview.
And I just, it was a real pleasure to have you here
and I hope to see you again.
Sean, it's my honor and privilege.
You always have a home out in Wyoming.
I mean it sincerely.
Listen, you're doing great work for our country.
You don't need to hear that from me.
I know you hear it all the time,
but truly, truly from somebody who's spent
a little bit of time in the media,
you are providing a great service to our nation.
And even if it has nothing to do with the UFO topic,
the fact that you're willing to put yourself out there,
have these meaningful conversations
and allow your audience to be part of that,
history will remember you very kindly.
You are setting a new tone
for how America gets its information
without a filter by the way,
before with the networks, remember,
you had all sorts of people coming up
and putting spins on things.
And what you are doing is a tremendous service
for our nation and humanity.
So thank you sincerely.
My wife is a big fan of yours.
Really appreciate what you're doing.
And I appreciate all the guests you've had in the past
and all the guests you're having in the future.
Even if some of those guests in the past
don't like me very much,
thank you for doing what you're doing.
Thank you for saying that.
You got it.
Honor and privilege.
No matter where you're watching Sean Ryan show from,
if you get anything out of this,
please like, comment, subscribe,
and most importantly, share this everywhere you possibly can.
And if you're feeling extra generous,
please leave us a review on Apple and Spotify podcasts.
Thank you.