Hello, so the myth has long been that in order to stay young and beautiful looking, we need
special wrinkle creams.
According to Dr John Lakey, the world renowned Beverly Hills beauty expert, most of those
wrinkle fixes on the market are nothing more than glorified moisturizers.
So recently Dr Lakey has focused his attention away from mainstream cosmetic practice to
pursue a revolutionary anti-aging technology breakthrough, one that some experts say could
empty the wallets of the cosmetics industry.
His personal clients have dubbed his new do-it-yourself technique the age rewinder method because
it can take years or even decades off your appearance in under two minutes, I could do
with some of this stuff.
Dr Lakey has released a step-by-step video to the public, free and uninterrupted, where
he outlines exactly how to use this simple solution from home.
The video's racked up over 2.3 million views and counting.
So far thousands of women, what about the men, are reporting they look decades younger.
So you can find out more about this yourself right now, go to BHMDNUMERAL1.COM slash ROS
or click on the link in the description box below, that's BHMDNUMERAL1.COM slash ROS.
There is one thing that Dr Lakey asks from his viewers, if watching this video helps
you look and feel younger than you have in years, then please share this video with your
friends and loved ones.
Together we have the power to make as many women reclaim a youthful look as possible.
Go watch the video at BHMDNUMERAL1.COM slash ROS right now or just click on the link in
the description box below.
Hello and welcome back to Reality Check.
So I've had a long interest in the northwest of Australia.
I start my book In Plain Sight at the place called the Harold E. Holt Naval Communication
Station, which is a very mysterious former United States facility, now an Australian
run facility that actually communicates with American nuclear attack submarines in the
Indian and Pacific Oceans using VLF, very low frequency radio waves.
And the thing about this whole area is that it's been a hotspot for a very long time of,
how does one say this politely, anomalous objects.
And adjacent just to the east of the Northwest Cape is a place called the Pilbara Desert,
a gigantic squave of Western Australia, rolling red desert country that to the Aboriginal people
there is beautiful and also deeply mysterious.
When the first settlers came to as colonists to Australia in the 18th century, they were
puzzled by what became known as Min Min lights, orbs, glowing spherical orbs drifting through
the art black.
And the fascinating thing about it is that a hundred and something years on,
we still have no answer to that mystery.
Well, our guest today is Dr. Andrew Morgan, and he's a Kiwi like myself.
And he's also a person who's got extraordinary scientific qualifications.
And he's taken a very, very close interest in the whole subject of UAP's anomalous phenomena
across that part of Western Australia.
And what is uncovered is actually quite fascinating.
It's a poke in the eye for those people who constantly say, oh, yeah, yeah, yeah,
if there really are UFOs and NHI, why do they only ever show themselves over cities in America?
And that's not true at all.
I just don't think we've been properly looking.
And I often think the only way we're ever going to crack this mystery is by scienceing it.
And that's what Andrew is doing.
He's a scientist.
He's a teacher in science at a school in Western Australia.
But he's got a very illustrious background in studying of science.
He went to the University of Auckland, did an undergraduate degree in zoology.
Completed his paddy dive master qualifications.
Moved to Queensland in Australia in 1995.
And did a master's in marine science at the University of Queensland in Brisbane.
Returned to New Zealand at the end of 1998.
And did a PhD in environmental and marine science at the University of Auckland.
He was commissioned as an officer in the New Zealand Navy.
Did his basic training, bridge watchkeeping and vessel safety over two years.
Joined the active reserves in 2007.
Taught marine studies at the Bay of Plenty Polytechnic in Tauranga in New Zealand for
five years.
While also consulting to the fisheries and aquaculture industry.
And he moved very sensibly to Australia in 2012 with his family.
And he consulted in the offshore oil and gas industry for five years.
As an environmental advisor in exploration, drilling, planning and approvals.
And he's now the honorable profession of teaching in science.
Presume Andrew, is that correct?
Yes, thanks Ross.
Yes, career science teacher.
So I've been 30 years in science now and back into the teaching profession again.
Now, the thing I find very brave of you to admit because it's very controversial for
a scientist is that as well as being a scientist who's endeavouring to study anomalous phenomenon.
Ever since you were a child, you've been what is politely called an experiencer.
You believe that you have had encounters with NHI with a non-human intelligence.
Can you tell me about that?
Yeah, that's a lifetime experience.
And I'm very careful about the vocabulary I use as a scientist.
And I've written a book on it now too, which has made me go back through my life and look
at all these patterns and occurrences with entity interactions and all the common vocabulary.
Dreams, visions, astral projection, by location, and that sort of phenomena that no one ever talks
about because of the stigma attached to it.
What I wanted to do was say, look, here's a career scientist, 30 years in science, wants
to understand more about how this has impacted his life.
I mean, look at Professor Gary Nolan, for example.
He's an experiencer as well.
So there's a lot of these people very high up in their professions coming out and talking
about this now.
And I think we need to have a conversation about understanding how this impacts people's
lives and what it all means.
So what does it all mean?
What were the kind of experiences you had?
Take me back to some of the earliest experiences you had as a child.
As a child, I'd say at seven and nine years old, I had, I suppose it's a typical childhood
experience of what they call little people in your bedroom that I had twice when I was
seven and when I was nine.
And back then, I've got no concept of what UAP is, what NHI is.
As a child, you don't.
It's just a novel experience, unusual, and then you put it in the back of your mind
through your life.
And it's only later on as a teenager where I have these really vivid experiences in my room.
And I've always been able to remember what I do when I'm asleep.
I suppose it's a little bit unusual because I've been able to go back and recount and
remember these experiences of being conscious while asleep and out of your body taking places.
When I got older and more recently, that turned into even craft entity interactions as well.
So you've actually, you believe, you believe you're a classic abductee.
You've been taken from your bedroom at night and taken somewhere else to a craft, perhaps.
Yeah, because I did a bit of research on this, because I didn't understand it myself,
because there's the physical phenomenon of that, that you read a lot about.
But then there seemed to be some connection with consciousness, and people are talking
about how consciousness is not your character, and that can be separated from your body physically.
So I've gone more down that avenue in researching and talking to people about how that works.
So that part of you can be taken places and then you come back.
So science it for me.
You're the scientist.
You're the guy who works on the kind of empirical scientific method.
You believe clearly that what you've experienced ever since you were a child
is real, that it's not some kind of hallucination, some kind of psychosis.
Why do you believe it's real?
What is it that has given you that confidence that you're dealing with something that is,
in fact, non-human intelligence, NHI?
I suppose the confidence comes from much maturity in thinking over 30 years in science
and understanding the science of consciousness, because it's repeatable.
The thing is, is it measurable?
Yes, it's repeatable, and there are common themes through your life around the types
of experiences and visions, and even places that you seem to be in, and circumstances,
whether that's, they call it flying dreams, and they can often be in the same place or
the same circumstances.
There's interaction with, sometimes that can be interaction with a craft.
And I kind of, in my book, I classify them into different experiences.
Normal dream processing, which I've read about.
You're processing what happens during the day.
You may or may not remember that.
Then there's visions, which they can be precognition of something that hasn't happened.
Then you've got your outer body and astral projection, which is going places.
And then from there, the other one that I've come across is the interaction in your room at night,
where you seem to be, I suppose they call it paralysis, sleep paralysis,
and something's going on.
There's a presence in the room.
You can't move.
And what I tried to understand is fear.
There's a lot of talk in consciousness studies about overcoming the fear of something that
you don't know, and that once you can seek to understand it, you have more freedom to interact.
And I've found that in my older years, I've got more freedom in these circumstances to question,
to interact, and to ask what's going on.
Is it hard to speak about it?
I mean, there's a lot of stigma associated with saying that you've been abducted,
or that you've had interactions with NHI.
Are you concerned about blowback for talking like that?
Yes and no, but I think we need to develop the vocabulary because there's so much pop culture
around UFOs and UAP, even the word anti-gravity that was coined, because they didn't understand
what they were looking at.
So I try to avoid the pop culture terminology and facilitate a discussion about the science
behind it all, because I believe there's a science that connects all of this from UAPs to UFOs
to consciousness studies to experiences and what they experience.
And if you go back to ancient history, the ancients certainly document a lot of this
stuff and had a deep knowledge of it from what I can gather.
So we need to have these conversations.
You know, the thing I love most of all is that your mission, if you like,
took you to one of my favorite bits of desert.
It's beautiful country, the Pilbara Desert.
And I think this all started to really happen for you, didn't it?
When you were at a place called Newman, which is a mining town in the middle of the Pilbara Desert.
Yeah, that's right.
About five years ago, I took the opportunity to teach up there in science in that town.
And that's when things did take off by myself up there coming back to Perth and the holidays
to family.
But I had the opportunity to go camping out there and also talk to Indigenous people
and locals at the pub and all that.
And once you get to know people, they say, oh, some strange things happened up here.
And there's some very interesting Dreamtime stories as well.
And because at the time I was writing a novel series, which places reverse engineered UFO
technology in the deep sea mining industry, I was researching the topic.
And I went camping in Karajini with a telescope.
And I was looking around at the night sky.
And I just had the sense that there's a lot more to see than just the light spectrum,
the visual light spectrum.
And I need some more gear.
So I went and thought, I'm going to invest in some infrared digital camera.
And then so round two of my camping trip, I set up to do what I was going to do at night
and tested my film and that.
And then after dusk, I was filming the sky and then the horizon.
And what do you know?
As you've said, orbs appeared in my field of view.
So let's talk to one of those images.
There's a beautiful image that you've sent me on video that you captured of.
It almost looks like a sun.
It's a solid white spherical object moving very slowly, tracking past trees,
presumably right in front of your campsite.
And it moves across open sky, across trees again, and then disappears out of sight.
Was that one of your first classic sightings of the spherical orbs that you see in the outback?
Yes, that was before I developed all the field methodology to apply the scientific method.
I was just scanning.
And that was one of the first ones I saw that came right past me where I was filming
on my first trip with those digital binoculars.
And that's what inspired me to get other gear.
So I went and got an electric magnetic field intensity meter, a Geiger counter, and another gear.
And you'll probably talk about this soon, but I got in contact with someone I could trust
to talk about how we develop the methodology in the field
to collect reliable and repeatable data and have a data-driven program of research up there.
So that's what I really like about your work.
You remind me a lot of my friends, John and Jerry Tedesco over in Long Island,
New Jersey, who are currently dealing with a plague of a swarm of drone UAPs of some kind
hovering over the East Coast of the United States.
But they decided in their retirement years that they would science the subject of UAPs.
And boy, did they find some interesting stuff.
And what I love about you is you've done the same and you've teamed up with a guy
called Brian Tyson. What can you tell me about Brian and what role does he serve in your research?
Yeah, that's right. So several years ago, when I had this first field trip, I was hunting around
for someone I could liaise with that didn't have an agenda, was not interested in owning any of
what I was doing, but would help out in the capacity that they could.
And in his particular role, he had a personal interest in UAP.
And I hooked up with him through my social media channels because I saw him commenting on UAP.
And I just mentioned that I had this project going on in the Pilbara and was he interested
in looking at a little bit of footage and some images.
And he said, yeah, happy to help or have a look.
And then the relationship involved from there professionally and personally.
And he became a key advisor on scientific methods, interpretation, a bit of speculation,
what we need to do to develop the research into the future.
Because I only had a self-funded budget.
So we came up with proposals and funding proposals for how we might expand that into the future.
So he's been quite key in the background and wants to remain in the background due to the nature of
his job and his work, which is fine. But yeah, he's been a key player.
And so one of the things, you've had papers published, haven't you?
We self-published on ResearchGate. That's an interesting story because we did submit to a
journal and waited the six to eight weeks for the first lab paper to be reviewed, double blind
review. So one reviewer came back positive, published with minimal corrections.
And the other reviewer just focused on one thing.
And that was the cameras only filming at 30 frames per second. I can demonstrate they're
all artifacts of filming. And so the journal rejected the paper, which means the other two
papers we didn't even get to have reviewed. So what we did is we published them as research
papers through ResearchGate attached to our lab, which we just call EnergyScape.
So they're self-published on ResearchGate now.
Let's deal with that. Firstly, is 30 frames per second filming a
liability for you scientifically improving your thesis?
Yes and no, because we should have a frame rate of about a thousand.
Tedesco and Tedesco will tell you that as well. But to compensate, and I even say this in my
research paper, to compensate, we looked at reliable, repeatable, measurable,
data-driven approaches over multiple times. So going back, doing the same thing over and
over and over again. And so your point is, is that if this was a camera artifact,
it would occur, incidentally, it wouldn't occur pretty much all the time. How often are you seeing
these objects that you call orbs and rods? Every time we go to the same site and do the same
standard pattern of data collection, the intensity and the numbers of them might vary,
but they're always at that site. We think, talking to Dr. Tyson, that it's connected to
some sort of temporal or interdimensional anomaly at the site as well. But to measure that, we need
more gear. I mean, we've looked at electric magnetic field intensity. We've made correlations
between the manifestation and the EM intensity. Let's deal with that because you've mentioned
a Geiger counter and you've also mentioned an EM detector. Let's talk about electromagnetic energy.
Did you notice anything anomalous about the electromagnetic energy in the area where you were?
Yeah. So there are naturally occurring EM anomalies and there is with the Hestaden lights as well
in Norway. And we found that there was a buildup during the day in the middle of nowhere. There's
nothing around. There's no high voltage power lines. We're away from anything that could
generate the voltmeters and microteslas that you would associate with suburbia. And that would
build up to late afternoon. And then we found that the intensity of the manifestation of orbs and
rods had a correlation between zero and one with the intensity of the electric and magnetic field
buildup during the day. Now I'd like to get more data on that because we had four data plots on a
linear regression graph to get a strong correlation. So we've got more work to do, but there's certainly
an indication that there is something anomalous going on there.
So can you say that the electromagnetic radiation that was anomalous, was it causative
or correlative to the appearance of the orbs and rods, do you believe?
We post a number of different theories on that. So the key at the moment is not to
say it's this or it's this or it's this. We post several different theories and one in particular
was to do with energy coupling or energy cascades in the area because we've got,
I think it's called piezoelectric naturally occurring phenomena as well, where you can get
really small natural orbs from the buildup of electric and magnetic intensity in the atmosphere.
So there's that as well, but we think that masks this other UAP phenomena as well, which could be
a life form extension, it could be technological, it could be hiding there. We simply can't know.
Before we get into the life form issue, you also mentioned you had a radiation detector.
Did you pick up any anomalous radiation?
No, the gamma radiation was on the same meter and I tested for that and it was always
baseline background levels. And I think it's because you'd need to be right near an actual
object or an imprint or a physical trace for that to register. So in terms of background levels,
not above them. So paint me a word picture. I mean, I love the Pilbara. It's a beautiful
part of Australia. And the funny thing is the great mythology about Australia is we all walk
around with big hats on and walk around the outback, but very few Australians ever get out there.
And it is wild country. Paint me a word picture of where you are. It's big red hills covered with
scrub and blooming hot during the day. Yes, yes. You go in the dry season between April and September
because it simply gets walking around in 40 degrees. It's very difficult. It's barren. So
Karajini National Park is where we are for the field work. So it's red rock and dirt,
lots of termite mounds, short bush and shrubs and grasses, lots of canyons. It gets down to freezing
at night. So you've got gorges and canyons with water. Beautiful landscape during the day. And
that night I found in the area I was working and I did some field work at night time, getting up in
the middle of the night, quite creepy because it's deathly silent, almost not normal. There's no
insects, no birds, extremely quiet and a little bit creepy when you're sampling and recording
the stuff going on around you because you're ready for something to pop up in front of you and go,
oh my God, where did that come from? So I found that quite unusual as well when I've been out
tonight at night in other areas where you've got background insects, not the odd bird fluttering.
We did debunk some of this. We looked at camera blurring. We've looked at and I've filmed and
recorded four different types of organisms in infrared. And we know that they are organisms
because we did some background research on nocturnal flyers up there. So yeah,
very, very desolate place. So do the Aboriginal people in that area, do they talk about anomalous
portals or objects themselves? Is there anything in their mythology or their dreamtime stories
about this kind of object? Yeah, that's interesting. There's a couple of things there
because Newman Township, the swimming pool there is built on top of a dreamtime story
because the Aboriginals, to make it rain up there, they had a rain dance and apparently
where the swimming pool is, there used to be some big huge rocks in their dreamtime story
and they would dance around them. And apparently these rocks would split open and a light would
shoot up into the sky and then it would rain. And to me, that was a UAP story. You'd probably
have to ask the elders about their interpretation of that now from their dreamtime. But that's just
one. And then I had an anomalous experience up there with an elder that had passed on when we
went camping somewhere overnight and I asked an Indigenous person about this experience of my
sleep being interrupted in my consciousness by an Indigenous elder. He said, oh, they probably
didn't want you there and you shouldn't have been there. So I took that as advice not to go camping
back there without actually asking to be there. So let's go into the detail of the orbs and rods.
You've written, you and Brian, a fascinating paper that in my view presents pretty compelling
evidence that you're seeing something that is actually intelligent and responding to you.
Can you explain why you think these orbs and rods are intelligently responding to you?
Yeah, because we've got a huge archive of video footage and done extensive analysis
in frame-by-frame analysis and video clip analysis in a radial manner around the cardinal
directions. And we found that they demonstrated object avoidance. So that's whether that was an
obstacle. They would turn on a dime, instantaneous acceleration as well. So some of the five
observables are camera recognition or being filmed in infrared. They would come into the
field of view and then turn and try and move out of it pretty quickly as well. And same with the
observers. Can I just for a moment just interrupt you there? Okay, let's just try and think about
that. An infrared camera itself is not emitting any energy, is it, to try and capture the images
that it's capturing, is it? Yeah, we have in the 850 nanometer spectra. So there must be something
about that spectra that interrupts some of the, I think it was orbs. Orbs did it, not rods. The
orbs would do that. And then I found in one very interesting one where I was filming an orb and
trying to track it as it moved up into the sky. It would try, I would, I would try to look at it
move to the left or right or up and down with it. And then it would move
very quickly backwards and forwards as if it was making fun of me trying to track it.
So there's a trickster quality to this phenomenon. Yeah, there's a trickster. And that's been
mentioned in other studies as well. So there was that. So there's object avoidance. There was
some of the five observables. There's avoiding the camera, avoiding the observer as well.
So in your own words, you think this is intelligent? Can you explain to me,
you believe that this is intelligent? We think, yeah, we think there's some form of intelligence
now. Now, what Dr. Tyson and I came up with was a little table that looked at that as to whether
that represented a life form extension or an extension of an ecosystem phenomenon that's not
in the visible spectrum, whether there's some sort of mixture there of naturally occurring
and technological, because we've been speculating that these places with magnetic anomalies are
good places to hide if you're NHI as well. So whether there's some biomimicry there.
So there's a technology that mimics natural phenomena. And I talk about that in my papers
as well and how that can be, because these rods had counter rotating spindles around them.
There's no airframe like ailerons fuselage. There's no wings like organisms, but there
were these counter rotating spindles in our digital analysis going around them. And some
of the orbs had bisected rings as well. And so it's very interesting.
So you saw differences between the orbs and the rods. They don't behave the same, do they? What
are the differences? So the rods have extreme velocity instantaneous acceleration, turn with
no inertia. And the orbs, and predominantly the rods move in straight lines. We did see them
avoid objects, but the orbs were more erratic. So they were slower, still quite fast, slower,
turned without inertia. But they tended to investigate more. So there was different
types of orbs. There were orbs that had seemed to investigate what was around them. And there
were orbs that just moved through the field of view. And the ones that investigated were able
to turn instantaneously, no inertia. So all of these objects were able to overcome inertia
and demonstrate some of the five observables. What I find amazing about this, Andrew, is
if what you're saying is right, and if you can exclude the probability that these are artifacts
inside your camera that are doing these effects, you've found another form of life.
Yeah, I did talk to Dr. Tyson about that, about because one of the things of the life form
extension, and I said, well, do you think it's sentient as an intelligent organism, and not just
like an animal as intelligent, but actually capable of thought or thinking or some level
of consciousness. But what he did say and what I thought was, if this is a temporal anomaly,
it could also be a silhouette of something that we don't have the full manifestation of in our
own dimension. So we've been looking at that as well. So this is doing my head in. So
you guys are theorizing that where you were filming in the Pilbara Desert, Karangini National
Park, there might be some kind of interdimensional portal that this life form, these orbs and rods
are coming through. And just to get my understanding of what you've just said,
the reason why sometimes they appear translucent rather than solid is because they might only be
partially in this dimension. There might be shadows of themselves from the other dimension.
Yeah, that's one of the theories, one of the several theories we've got. And I called it
the looking glass effect, because when I was filming, there was this perfectly still night,
there was no wind, no breeze, no fog, no clouds, no fog coming up from the ground. But there was
this haze quite a few times through the footage. And it's not there when you're looking around.
And then it was what I call ghosting orbs. Yeah, it was sort of translucent. And then
there were the solid ones that would come out of that and be moving off and around.
You say solid. Were they solid objects? Do you think you can say definitively that they were
solid objects? Yeah, that's no, no, I wouldn't say that we've come to that conclusion because
we don't know whether they're plasma, whether they've got a structure to them underneath that.
Because I said to Brian, what if they're actually harnessing the energy that's around them
and not creating it themselves? But plasma itself is a solid because it shows up on radar sometimes,
doesn't it? Yeah, and if we had the technology and some more instrumentation, because that's
one of the things brought up about our research papers is understanding more about not just the
morphology of these objects, but the underlying structure and how that plasma is generated. So
whether they're generating it internally or externally, yes, it's still a fourth state of
matter as a light or a rod with a plasma around it. Now, the thing I find really shocking about
this is because you can't afford a camera that can shoot 1000 frames per second, that's the only
reason that you didn't get published in a peer reviewed journal that would give you the opportunity
to publish your good science in a journal that might give you the approval, if you like, of the
scientific community for what sounds like a potential discovery of a non-human intelligence.
Yeah, I think, yeah, that's, um. I find that incredible, really, when you think about it,
the implications are extraordinary. I mean, we're spending hundreds of millions of dollars on SETI,
you know, trying to communicate with radio signals across the universe. From what you're saying,
you are hypothesizing and still working, obviously, on trying to prove it, but you've
got a pretty solid basis for a hypothesis that what you are exploring is another form of life.
Yeah, I think we have the beginnings and the groundwork to do that, and I think
the key is application of the scientific method, and yes, cheap, yes, cheap gear,
but cheap gear done well, cheap gear done well is better than expensive gear given to someone that
has no idea what they're doing and just films and there's no methodology. I think the key here is
methodology, scientific methodology and hypothesis-driven research, and yes,
we need funding to prove or validate more what we're doing, but being rejected from a journal for,
I mean, I have to stay professional. I can understand from this physicist's perspective that
he has concerns, but there was another reviewer that said, we should publish this as something
here and move forward, because we're not, I think when you get a reviewer looking at one journal
article, they don't see the other two papers that are coming after it. They don't see the
hundreds of hours of video footage and stills, and they just get a summary. So in staying
professional, I understand that, and there are ways to self-publish now, and I think this whole
publish or perish thing needs to be discussed more at universities as well, because it's all
tied to funding models as well, of course, as a university scientist.
Well, let me be the ultimate skeptic. I feel the obligation to be the voice of debunking skepticism
just for a moment here. The scientific community, would you agree, broadly takes the view that
UAPs, UFOs, they're not capable of being proved in material science, that essentially it's never
been verified, and that these things can't be, you know, you can't gather data on them,
you can't measure them, you can't sense them, therefore it's not real. What do you think of
that suggestion, that hypothesis? I think it's antiquated, because technology's changed,
and our thinking has changed, and if the scientific or academia is still thinking like that,
I think very quickly and very soon, as you're probably well aware, they're going to get left
behind if they don't get on board, and yes, some of us have taken a risk professionally stepping
up, you know, Gary, Avi, Loewe, myself, I'm a little bit lower down the ladder professionally,
because I'm not an academic, but I have an academic background, and I'm an educator and a
scientist, so I think if they don't change their mindset when this all starts to accelerate,
as it is already, they're going to miss the boat on all this. Yeah, the technology's there to do
it now, I don't understand why they would still, I think it's entrenched, it's an entrenched mindset
within academia, it can't be, therefore it isn't, I mean that's talked about a lot as well, and we
know historically, well for me personally, I've written another book coming out next year on our
missing science, which we could discuss, and I've looked at the whole UFO UAP thing since World War
II, and some key figures that have come afoul scientifically of the powers that be, including
Otis Carr, Douglas Tor, Dr Ning Li, Victor Shaw, Berger, all these guys seem to be talking about
the same science of field repulsion, field repulsion technology, I'm wondering whether if some of the
stigma is facilitated by counterintelligence over those eight decades of legacy programs
and all of this, and that that's distilled into the university system and into their mindset,
so it's a minefield as you know of counterintelligence, personal agendas, you know,
blue book, project sign, project grudge, there's a whole history behind this in terms of academia
that I think we need to overcome the stigma of to move forward. Now you and I have got a mutual
friend Josh, Josh York, who's an anthropologist who operates in that part of the world, and
he's in touch with a lot of the Aboriginal communities across that desert area. I was
fascinated when I first spoke to Josh, he told me that it is a big thing in the Aboriginal communities
that they frequently see what they describe as structured craft hovering over the landscape at
times, black triangles, and it fascinated me because I start my book in plain sight with an
account of a young woman who was at the Harold E. Holt Naval Communication Station when it was an
American base, and there was a gigantic triangular craft that hovered adjacent to the base over a
road leading up to the base, and she told this chilling story about how when she was asked to
come into the base to talk to officials about what had happened that night when she and two
police officers had seen this gigantic hovering craft, it was quite obvious to her that the
base personnel and more importantly, the people who'd been flown in from overseas from American
military overseas, and civilian personnel, they knew full well about these objects and the whole
intention was to try and cover it up and shut it down. Is it a plausible possibility that what
we're seeing is some kind of American testing of prototypes? I mean, the thing that fascinates me
about her story is a lot of the accounts from the Aboriginal community in that part of the Western
Australia desert, and over the Northwest Cape, they started when our good friend George Knapp
started reporting on Area 51, Groom Lake, the Nevada test range, and all of a sudden the
cover of Groom Lake was blown as a place where you could safely test military prototype vehicles.
Is it possible that what you're seeing and what the Aboriginal community is seeing
are some kind of secret military technology perhaps being tested in the Australian outback by the
Americans? I think there's a lot of speculation in there. Yes, the Indigenous communities have had
a long history, as I've talked to Josh myself, and I've met with him, and a couple of Indigenous
people up there talk about objects, and even around mine sites up there, we've got conversations and
pubs about objects and lights and unusual lights at night, and a particular person at a mine site
up there sent me some photos of physical, what I think is physical craft as well in terms of discs
and cylinders. Can we see those photographs? That was one thing you hadn't sent me just yet,
but can we see those images? I'm trying to get the high res ones because they were low res
off the phone, so when they were sent it reduced the file size, so I didn't want to send those
because they're too pixelated, so I'm still waiting to liaise and get more of the high res
versions of those. So in anticipation of us getting them, can you talk to those photographs
and tell me what you see? Yeah, because I got a little bit of video sent to me as well. Around
this mine site, because I don't want to talk about companies and naming mine sites,
that wouldn't be professional, but around a particular mine site there's an increasing
occurrence of objects in the night sky and during the day. There's the typical rainbow coloured one
that's been filmed at night that I've got a bit of footage of that just changes flashes a whole
lot of different colours and moves up and below the horizon. There was another footage of a large
cylinder, one that people talk about. I've got some footage of that just hovering in the night sky
and there was another one in the mine pit during the day and off in the distance up against or
close to one of the walls of the pit that had more of a jellyfish-like structure to it. But
what this person did say was that they, I don't know whether it's they're more aware of them now,
so they're seeing them more or mine workers reporting an increased presence or activity
around that area because it's around the area outside of these mines as well. So they might
be seeing objects that are a few miles away from where they're looking. There are actually
quite a few fans of reality check way out there in that West Australian desert because they send
me their own images of what they're seeing over their remote Aboriginal communities and a lot of
what they're describing is what you're describing. Spheres, silver spheres, silver tubes. What on
earth are they, Andrew? If you do your research historically and you go back to pre and post-World
War II, there is what I call the pop culture narrative and then there's the scientific
narrative. So in the pop culture narrative they talk about flying saucers and cylinders. I think
there's a couple of books. David Childress has written books about that whole Nazi Germany
narrative for flying saucers and cylinders. So there's a potential there for a technology
that's already been seconded away in the private aerospace sector, proved and tested. So there could
be that as well and that's why we've had these hearings in the US and Congress about all this
as well about who's got this technology and why aren't we aware of it? Have our adversaries
got hold of it and are they doing better than us? So there's that. Maybe the Australia, maybe there
isn't a presence up there that's a bit of both, NHI and human engineered technology that with or
without the help of NHI. The triangles, they're up there because I've been, like you, I've been
sent a photo of triangle lights in the skies by community members up there in the clouds as well
and I've seen a couple of objects myself, one at night, one during the day that were of a different
structure. So and I think there's a difference too because obviously the engineered ones,
you know, rivets, a structure that's been assembled and it tends to be the NHI ones
have no external features that show that they've somehow been assembled.
Let's talk about what you referred to earlier, the piezoelectric effects in the rocks. I'm
searching here for prosaic explanations and one of the things that really struck me when I was
in Egypt was there was a lot of talk about the quartzite in granite and the piezoelectric effects
of granite carrying a lot of quartzite that they are in many ways conductive or attractive
of electrical energy. Can you develop that hypothesis for me? How might a piezoelectric
effect in rocks help or assist in an understanding of the UAPs we're talking about?
Yeah we took, and I think it was in the third paper that we've published to ResearchGate,
we talk about energy cascades enhancing the phenomena up there through natural accumulation
of electrical energy. So with the quartzite you've got high-grade magnetite there
which has a magnetic field, you've got quartzite which has a under pressure, quartz under pressure
generates an electric field and the pillar is a craton so it's one of the oldest rock
formations on the planet. So in terms of pressure and movement you've got the excess electrical
and magnetic energy in that whole area anyway and combine that with freezing and thawing of water
deep in the rock formations because it's a desert climate that generates pressure friction and
electrical energy as well. So that all comes up out of the ground and it can coalesce and that's
why they talk about these naturally occurring spheres, small spheres that can form from
concentrated EM energy. Well that's what I was going to ask, I mean is it possible that the
orbs and rods that you're seeing are something caused by the piezoelectric effect of rocks
simply rubbing together, that we don't need an NHI explanation for this, that it could just be
a geological explanation as I know they're looking for at Hesteland in Norway as well,
you know everybody's still looking for a possible geological explanation to explain the phenomenon
that occurs in this valley in Norway called Hesteland. Yeah and I compare and contrast
Hesteland lights in the papers that Brian and I have written and I think even in
Teodorani and his papers talks about the potential for that naturally occurring
phenomena to mask the presence of any technological phenomena as well. The same
could well apply and we need more research to look at that but there is the potential for that
up there but what I found is some of these the kinematics and morphologies of some of
some of these orbs and rods don't demonstrate a random pattern of movement that you could
associate with a naturally occurring phenomena which applies that there must be some form of
intelligence that is connected to some of these orbs and rods and I think Teodorani in his papers
in his work poses that question as well is that do the kinematics in Hesteland demonstrate
an intelligence is there a mixture of both in there and we simply don't know at the moment we
need more more field work and more instrumentation to separate the two if they are mixed together
in this in this area. It's one of the things that you would cite as evidence of intelligence
that when you point your infrared camera at these objects and start detecting them
I think you've described it as a phase shift they appear to change phase and change shape or form
in some way. Yeah the phase shifting was interesting because if they were just going on
in and out of the field of view you couldn't say much about it but when I went back through
and looked at the frame capture analysis and at some of the videography they would manifest in
physical space in the field of view and we and in my third paper we show some frame capture of that
of an infrared this all just appears and coalesces as a light as a light ball out from out of nowhere
so it's not coming through the field of view it's actually manifesting in the field of view
the rods are too fast to do that because I don't even mind again we talk about high speed
cameras to do that but the orbits were moving slow enough and manifesting slow enough that we
did capture that on film and so if that was but again is that a naturally occurring
light ball was that a form of intelligence so that's what we can't separate the two at the
moment because you know the light the large light the larger that you've got video of moving
through the field of view when I first went up there that's a lot bigger and it has a completely
different morphology to a smaller one as well so they're not all the same can I just ask just
for a bear with a very small brain if light is light those orbs are clearly some kind of
light or energy or plasma do you agree yeah yeah there are some kind of energy there
light ball plasma some form of energy why can't we see them on anything other than infrared
this is where I put forward to dr tyson the energy cascade hypothesis within an
interdimensional anomaly is that to go from invisible to infrared to the visible spectrum
requires a certain amount of of energy to manifest in physical space so I put for that
as a theory is that and I think teotirani talks about this too that the level of energy required
to be in the infrared spectrum and the visible spectrum is different so and if they're harnessing
energy externally which is another model we put forward not generating it themselves then they're
totally dependent within that temporal anomaly on available energy and energy cascades as to how
how intensely they manifest so I'm recording them in the 850 spectra nanometer spectra
and it may simply be that the the intensity of energy required to manifest
and the light visible visible spectrum is not enough so so do you need more or less energy
to show in infrared than you do in visible light I'm still researching this but
I think in terms of energy cascades it's more so I think I think because yeah I'll have to
go and do some more research on this but because I'm still talking to dr tyson about about plasma
and light ball and energy cascades within this anomaly if it is a temporal anomaly because
it appears the more the more you move away from the site the less of these objects there are
they still have the same intensity but there's less of them so where where's the energy coming
from for that for that number to manifest and concentrate radially around a certain area
and is that energy intensity like you said related to their ability to manifest
is it are they choosing or are they just choosing not to manifest visibly is there a
dr tyson even talked about what he called consciousness or the observer effect in
quantum mechanics is that you observe something and therefore it's matter and when you're not
observing it it's a waveform so there's that whole area of physics as well as it is the observer
having an impact on the manifestation and and one of the final questions andrew do the things you
see the orbs and rods do you only see them at night yeah but that's mainly because of the gear
i've got i do electric and magnetic field density right through day and night but the infrared camera
i'm standing up to film an infrared at night so daytime yeah well is it possible that they are
showing themselves in the daytime it's just you don't have the type of camera that could pick
them up because the infrared would be lost against the daytime heat yeah exactly yep and i think
that's where if we get into more field work and a proposal to develop this further with with better
technology that we can set up sensor arrays 24 seven and look at others the full spectrum
because we're very limited with 850 nanometer spectra and em field intensity just what about
the rest of the infrared spectrum the visible spectrum even the ultraviolet spectrum
what would you need to be able to measure them during the day high speed cameras hyperspectral
cameras what would you need yeah we need hyperspectral cameras so we can do day and
night alongside em field intensity and also the radar arrays as well to see if there is a signature
from an actual object so you've got the hyperspectral cameras you've got your em
field intensity you've got your radar array i think we'd be getting a lot further along the track
in terms of what is going on there all we can say definitely is something is going on here it's
anomalous it may or may not be naturally occurring and there seems to be some form of intelligence
attached to it so we've written three papers on that put forward our theories behind the data
suggested a way forward and put place it in the context of the scientific literature
literature globally and in particular the Hestad and light research with the exception of
Hestelin and the work of Massimo Teodorani the Italian scientist that you've mentioned
a couple of times is anyone else researching these orbs and rods around the world
i've had uh there's this anecdotal evidence on from youtubers and there's also there's also
historically i found on the internet people have written books on and called them spirits that
have passed over and there's this whole uh that whole side of it too and i i stayed away from
that i said look this there's a science to all this uh some people have connected these orbs to
spirits or passed over spirits or the spiritual side of things and i think yeah there's a
consciousness consciousness connection but let's let's let's be scientific and you know it's just
because we don't understand something let's not turn it into religion and let's keep with the
science and and find out what the sciences are behind it all and i again i allude to the fact
that there is there's a missing branch of science in the public arena and i think that there's a
science in the public arena that i think other people are well aware of what do you think that
missing branch of science is dr andrew morgan yeah we had a discussion about this the book the book
i my book on my life is an experience of the book on uap coming out next year and all my background
research and one word actually three words i could sum it up as field repulsion science
uh everything seems to be connected to to that and if it's so highly coveted why and we had the
conversation about okay scalar weapons technology uh even to go back to maxwell's original quaternion
notation where time is a scalar fourth dimension and that's all been taken offline and modified
as well so there's there's something missing across all of this so do you think some science
is being actively suppressed by some in the scientific establishment or is that too big a
call no i i think yes and no i think there's there's a naivety about it because you don't
know what you don't know and the ones that do know uh it's maybe career ending or not a good idea
and then there's counterintelligence as well so because if you go back through and look at all
the stuff that's been taken offline and there's a stigma around it people's careers have been
altered changed or they've disappeared or not working on it anymore and they're all in that
area of research is is this rotating this technology counter rotation field repulsion
and and go to i've gone into russian work and even um torsion fields a lot of torsion field
research is is by russian scientists in nature uh and in terms of technology application and that's
all connected to field repulsion science as well so where is all the science why is it not
universities in high schools are connected to special relativity and quantum mechanics so where
is it because the big thing that fascinates me is even physicists like eric weinstein admit
that there's a huge hole in modern physics that string theory doesn't work it doesn't explain the
known universe we've got a huge problem with modern physics and for much of the last 60 to 70
years it's struggled to explain a unified physics theory that actually explains the
whole universe um what do you think this field propulsion technology is exactly can you explain
that to a lay person without making our heads explode yep yeah it's key it's key to to make
sure we call it field repulsion not propulsion so field repulsion uh and it's all to do with um
um uh go back to maxwell's electromagnetic atom and spin a subatomic spin an electron spin
and and everything spins and when when you generate an electric field from that
you generate a repulsion so if you look at dr dingley's disk technology same sort of thing
getting that that that spin technology to generate a repulsive field uh you go to um
victor victor schorberg's uh implosion drive spinning disc uh again generating a field around
it which allows it to shoot up in the air uh at instant instantaneously uh and then otis car same
sort of thing uh with uh with with uh uh field repulsion so generating a spin and a repulsive
field so that's that seems to be where this gap is but i go i think we need to have a conversation
about the relationship between einstein and maxwell because i've been researching this
and what happened to maxwell's petunian notation uh and scale of time so i think it all started
from there uh whether that was on purpose or inadvertently because heavyside turned it into
vector calculus and then einstein that got a special relativity from from all of that
but maxwell and einstein knew each other so einstein must have known about maxwell's
petunian mathematics because he was a genius mathematician and helped einstein so has that
been taken offline what happened to it why is why are we not talking about scale of time
and field repulsion since then and every time it has been brought up it's it's disappeared
so whether by design or oversight a science is being suppressed
i i think so and and and maybe there's good reason for that but we're at a stage now where
we can acknowledge that yes you can hold on to the technology but give us our science back please
because we need to understand how how the universe works and i think uh understanding the fourth
dimension is gonna uh in terms of what i've just talked about is gonna unravel or bring back
what eric weinstein was talking about in terms of our missing science and understanding deep space
travel and hopping around space and and not moving through physical space to get to somewhere that
takes hundreds of years to get to because that's never going to happen i think people are well
aware well dr andrew morgan i think your little adventures in the pilbara desert
examining mysterious orbs and rods may one day provide us with an answer to that big question
and i sincerely hope it does dr andrew morgan thank you so much for joining reality check
um i think all of us would like to see your research continue it'd be great to see your
um work better funded so that you can get the equipment you need to do the kind of research
that's needed to definitively get a result and hopefully get you published in a peer review
journal yeah thanks thanks a lot ross i think we have more questions and answers at the moment
but i look forward to what the future holds so thank you very much
thanks for watching go to join nn.com to find news nation on your television provider and please
don't forget to click that red subscribe button to ensure you get more of news nations unbiased
and fact-driven news coverage