Hello everybody, welcome to the second part of my conversation with Colm Kelleher,
author of Brain Trust, Hunt for the Skinwalker and Skinwalkers at the Pentagon. We're now
segueing from our conversation on the connection between Alzheimer's, mad cow disease, and cow
mutilations to discuss the topic of the paranormal and of course the paranormal investigations my
guest was involved with at a remote ranch in Utah's Uinta Basin. On with the conversation.
The scientific method,
and I had initially asked you about it on the email too, because it doesn't seem like a lot of
what went down there and what happens with other in other places is it doesn't really lend itself
to repeats and it seems like with SETI for example they want the wow signal to repeat for
it to matter and right now so far the wow signal hasn't repeated and so it does certain concessions
need to be made for this subject matter to be investigated? Yeah that's a very good point
and that is something we wrestled with you know throughout this whole program
and you know it was an exercise in frustration trying to get repeatability and reproducibility
because whatever was doing this and we still to this day have really no firm idea of what was
behind all of these cattle mutilations, cattle disappearances, UFO activity,
discarnate voices, poltergeist activity, bizarre creatures showing up. I mean the list goes on and
on but we had no fixed idea on who was behind this or what was behind this so we were tasked
with sticking to scientific methodology and we deployed a lot of sophisticated sensors
in different areas of the property and one example is we would have a whole bunch of sensors
deployed around a specific area that had activity in the previous nights or the previous weeks
and then we would deploy a lot of focus and then find the next day or two that a whole bunch of
activity had happened on the very end of the the opposite end of the ranch outside the sphere of
where the humans and the people were focused so it was almost like we were playing cat and mouse
with something that knew what we were doing and that was very evasive and very deceptive and very
sort of very well skilled in being able to camouflage itself and if it didn't want to be
discovered it wouldn't be discovered but there was quite a lot of occasions when we actually
came face to face with stuff that we couldn't explain so you know I mean but that was always
outside our control and also outside our ability to repeat things usually happen very quickly
unexpectedly and in areas that we you know we were not sort of prepared at all times and
we did you know train to be more prepared as time went on it was kind of like
scientific method was shown to be sort of inadequate in terms of fully describing what
was on the property I mean one of the things that I had done in my previous career in mainstream
science was publish a lot of papers and peer-reviewed scientific journals so I knew
how the system worked and you know you gathered the data you reproduce it you get the the best
possible data and then you present it to a peer-reviewed journal and they critique it
and you resubmit and then the paper is published well there was nothing that we got
in the sort of six years of boots on the ground on skin marker ranch that could have been
gone through the process of peer-reviewed publication in a refereed scientific journal
it just that the data were too sporadic they were not reproducible so we were kind of left
with a lot of sporadic data but nothing that could be published well I feel like there's
some instances and all across all these texts where I feel like
you could apply some level of reason and say okay well if this many people who are unrelated are
seeing this certainly there's something to that so for example going all the way back to the
Gorman family and that crazy wolf
it's reminiscent of something I read you know in a more recent in the more recent text where
a hitchhiker made its way onto someone's property and I think it was described also as a wolf
or having little flight features exactly I mean that's that's the sort of strange part of this
whole thing I mean what really separated skinwalkers at the Pentagon from the previous
studies we've done was that here we had an official United States government program
the Department of Defense Defense Intelligence Agency 22 million dollars were allocated through
the Defense Intelligence Agency for this program so we had a lot of resources and we were we were
able to hire a lot of people and some of the people that were on this skinwalker ranch were
actually sent from the Defense Intelligence Agencies kind of like a field trip in order
to investigate to see if this you know what this was going on in this ranch had any validity if it
had any intelligence value or if there was anything you know properly associated with it
it was kind of like standard operating procedure for the United States government is is to deploy
people to the area so you know to to look into what was actually going on so on during the
the program which was a two-year contract with the Defense Intelligence Agency there were five
separate United States government people who were deployed onto the property from different
different departments somewhere from the Navy somewhere from the Marine Corps
somewhere were from the intelligence agencies but what was remarkable about this was that
all five people who were deployed on Skinwalker Ranch had really bizarre in-your-face phenomena
happening to them right on the property and secondly as you allude to all five of them brought
weird stuff home to their families so what happened was they you know they would have
a an experience on the property and then fly back to Maryland or Washington or somewhere on the East
Coast from which they from whence they are originally deployed and then a couple of weeks
later their wives or their spouses or their kids would suddenly start encountering these black
human-eyed shadows that would would would appear over their beds in their bedrooms there would be
orbs of light sort of you know moving through the walls and moving into their their bedrooms
sometimes blue sometimes red sometimes white these things were the size of of baseballs
they moved silently and sometimes you know they caused injuries on on people you know they actually
caused injuries but part of this effect that these people seem to have brought back to their families
included sightings of these bizarre creatures and remember we're talking about what are called
TSSCI cleared and these are top secret special compartmented information cleared people who
were high level people in the United States government and in the military these were very
very highly qualified people who had been in Afghanistan who had been in Iraq who were used to
confronting fear and so some of the the stuff that erupted in their homes caused them to really
fear of what was going on one example was you know after that the guy who we call Axelrod in
the book in in in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon book went home to his family a few weeks later
his wife was just shutting up shutting the all the lights down it was like 11 30 at night
and she was just about to turn the lights in the backyard down when she saw this creature
that was standing beside a tree looking at her and she looked at it closely she kind of leaned
forward and focused on it and this thing was looked like a wolf standing on two legs leaning
against the the tree and it was like she just couldn't believe her eyes I mean this was in
suburban Virginia and you know she didn't say anything about it it completely freaked her out
it unnerved her she looked away and then she looked back and the the creature was still there
and it was obviously staring at her in a unfriendly way so at that stage it turned around
and just walked back into the tree line and vanished and she just literally couldn't believe
her eyes didn't say anything to the rest of our family she did not want to freak them out
but then three days later her two teenage sons were in the in the living room
of their same house when one of them noticed movement out the backyard this was on a Saturday
morning 10 a.m broad daylight and standing in the backyard was this bizarre looking wolf like
creature again standing on two legs staring at the at the kids and the other kids sort of
also saw it and once they locked eyes again this creature looked very unfriendly hostile
it began running towards the tree line on two legs which is anatomically impossible I mean
if you look if you put a German shepherd on two legs it can at best totter one or two steps
so it's anatomically impossible for a large wolf like creature to run on two legs but that's
exactly what this creature did and not only that it blew up a whole bunch of leaves that were on
the ground so this was not sort of some kind of you know sort of apparition it was having a
physical effect on the leaves on the ground and so it ran towards the tree the tree line and vanished
so the teenagers called out to the family you know they were kind of panicked they didn't know
what to make of what this was and so the mother came in and you know what they described was very
very similar to what she had seen three nights before so they the family then walked out into
the backyard down to where the she showed exactly where this creature was standing by the tree
and on the tree bark there were these obvious claw marks on the bark of the tree I mean the
the implication was that this creature had made you know strong deep claw marks on the tree so
again this was evidence that this wasn't sort of some kind of weird human perception thing
it wasn't an apparition there was something physical about what had happened in their
backyard and so this was one of dozens of examples that this family and this this guy who was
you know promoted up the ranks because obviously he didn't talk about any of this stuff
at work because it was so bizarre and so so outside what had happened but this guy was very high level
in the in the navy department of the navy you know we're not talking about somebody who was
I mean he was very high level had top secret security clearances all five out of five people
who were on the skinwalker ranch property during that government program they all had dramatic
effects and they all brought this quote-unquote hitchhiker behind to their homes and so not only
the kids saw it but also neighbors of this family started reporting weird stuff happening all these
blue orbs flying around their their house and even school kids who were friends with these two kids
who did not talk about what they had seen but their school friends started talking about that
they were starting to see your see weird stuff outside their homes so we speculate in the book
in skinwalkers at the pentagon that you know this thing is behaving like some kind of an infectious
entity the the guy you know gets infected on the property brings it home to his family his family
starts seeing weird stuff and then their neighbors start seeing weird stuff and then the the school
kids start seeing weird stuff so it's almost like an infectious organism is moving out into the
neighborhoods and that's not the only time we saw that we saw that multiple times of of this infectious
behavior of something that originated on skinwalker wrench and then moving out into the into the
neighborhoods can you talk about the black triangles for a little bit because
i gotta tell you bro i have been obsessed with these things since i was in high school
actually probably middle school is when the unsolved mysteries episode came out about it
it was in the 90s yeah and sometimes they're depending on the source that
the they're different from the chevrons that were seen in the hudson river valley but some people
say they're the same things and i was one i just wanted to get your take on it because
you have a whole chapter dedicated to the black triangles right there's a whole chapter in the
skinwalkers of the pentagon devoted to the black triangles yeah well you know the organization that
i was talking about that looked into anomalies that looked into calumni relations nids we also
looked at black triangles and you know we were very very fortunate that um you know in 2001
we we had this sort of illinois it was a very famous case of of four separate police officers
had witnessed this black black triangle going over their their heads so some of them took
photographs and the photographs weren't weren't particularly good but we deployed a team of
including a a retired fbi agent a retired air force office of special investigations agent
out to illinois we interviewed all the witnesses and there were over a dozen witnesses that had
seen the progress of this low-flying black triangle that had appeared um and then actually
it was about 4 a.m that it started and then the last sighting was after 6 a.m so it was it was
in the air for over two hours different police precincts there were four different police
precincts who had seen it had tracked it had had driven their vehicles in pursuit of it
so this was a really good case and and it became kind of legendary in the in the black triangle
sort of investigations um but you know so nids became a sort of a central
data clearing house for this whole phenomenon we got literally hundreds of cases and reports
of these black triangles from all over the country from the united states and also from europe there
was a a lot of famous cases that had erupted in in europe particularly in belgium and in in
in france so we were privy to a lot of this data and the the sort of the central feature of this
this phenomenon was that these enormous triangular shaped objects that were silent
usually brightly lit would be flying at very very low speed sometimes 30 40 miles an hour
very low over these populated neighborhoods over interstate highways and when i say low altitude
we're talking sometimes just over treetop level i mean we're not talking sort of a couple thousand
feet up talking about really low i mean we had multiple witnesses who told us that this thing
was so low as it was coming towards them that they started running because they were sure it was so
low it was going to crash into you know the neighborhood they thought it was it was just
so so bizarre so over the years we accumulated like i said hundreds of these cases they were
all very very similar and they were all sort of overload the populated neighborhoods flying
dangerously low silent and and then they would be capable of extreme levels of acceleration
where they could accelerate from a practically standing position to vanish within a second or two
so they had these really high level performance characteristics and so that you know the big
question was always in everybody's minds from the start of the 1980s all the way through to about
2010 when these triangles were flying everywhere was this a united states special access program
or was this some sort of you know was this from somewhere else quote unquote and you know throughout
all of the the time that we investigated these cases and all of the we literally interviewed
hundreds of witnesses to these these things we came to the conclusion that there was really
very little chance that the united states government would be so foolhardy as to you know
fly these extremely large experimental aircraft very low very brightly lit over highly populated
neighborhoods and highly highly populated interstate highways for what purpose i mean there was i mean
this this was not a single flight of a of a top secret aircraft this was hundreds of different
flights all over the united states and over europe so we came to the conclusion that these were not
ours you know these were these were not ours and one of the chapters in skinwalkers of the pentagon
we specifically specifically talk about this case where you know guys in in a small town in
georgia rural georgia comes out because his son and their friends are are are sleeping in a tent
overnight he has a 10 year old son and friends and you know the dog is barking crazily so he
walks out and he sees one of these huge triangular things that that's literally parked over his
his property and it's moving very very slowly but it's gigantic it's the size of a football field
and so he tries taking you know video camera of using a cell phone
his cell phone doesn't work all of the electronics die in the in the cell phone which is very
usual behavior for this stuff bottom line is he he goes inside grabs a high-powered flashlight
runs back out of it and illuminates that the the object with the flashlight
instantly he turns on the flashlight he gets this beam from the underside of the of this gigantic
craft hits him with this blue light he feels burning on his skin almost immediately turns around
crouches to get away from the thing he feels the back of his neck burning so he he ducks inside it
i mean he he you know he's really scared but whatever this blue beam that comes from this
object is really hurting him so you know he uh he he spent the rest of the the time in his house
this this object then eventually took off at a fantastic speed but you know he he woke up the
following day with a really severe headache and he had burns on the back of his neck sunburn on the
back of his neck he started losing his hair over time we our organization with the defense
intelligence agency contract had two contract physician scientists who were md phd so they were
well versed in investigation of medical injuries so we dispatched one of these guys
who spent a lot of time with interviewing this guy this guy had metallic taste in his mouth
his hair started falling out he you know the physician scientist took photographs of him
we had other investigators take photographs of him i mean he was losing his hair he had multiple
blood tests at at the local hospital he had really low red cell counts and white cell counts
um you know if we didn't know better he was suffering from some kind of radiation injury
non-ionizing radiation industry injuries so we had the the fortune to have these medical people
md phd's were able to follow this kind of medical injury case over weeks and months over the weeks
and months this guy developed a whole bunch of weird tumors he got really sick and then slowly
after about a year he started recovering but we were able to take multiple blood samples over time
and we were able to document in extensive detail and all of this you know all this medical data was
protected by the HIPAA laws which is you know the privacy laws and our our physician scientists
operated strictly under HIPAA so this guy's identity can never be revealed but you know the
fact is we were able to track his the health status and his health deteriorated dramatically
after this encounter with this huge triangle over his house when he got hit by this weird blue beam
now again was this one of ours or was it you know one of theirs i mean why would a united states
um experimental aircraft be radiating a united states citizen on their own property for no other
reason than they shone a flashlight at it i mean what's the purpose of that there was you know
again we went through this whole exercise of what is the agenda of of something like this and again
we concluded that the chances are united states government deployed aircraft would never be as
foolhardy as to deploy something like this over some guy's property irradiate cause a medical injury
you know non-ionizing radiation the guy's hair falls out and he eventually recovers but he gets
very sick for a long time as a result of this encounter so again that's sort of a codex to the
black triangle phenomenon it's not always healthy you know it's not always good for
your health when you have encounters like this well you know well i mean the the thing about the
it seems and i i can't buy into the idea that it's government either because it just seems
overkill for pointing a flashlight yeah you know it's just like that's something that somebody who
doesn't think on our level would do exactly i mean if if you had a drone or a robot that was
programmed to react a certain way maybe you could you know maybe you could sort of get your head
around that that that kind of dramatic overreaction that it was some sort of pre-programmed response
but it makes absolutely no sense it defies common sense for somebody if that was a manned
aircraft and it was an experimental aircraft from the united states government
to react in that way is just it's just defies common sense blue seems to be a recurring
horrible color for people encountering these things whether it's an orb or a beam
i mean those blue orbs that that people encounter and we have several instances
in in skin markers of the pentagon where we describe these encounters with blue orbs
pretty well universally they are not good for your health i mean if you know if you see a blue orb i
would say run the other way because we we document a number of times in in the book where
um blue orbs cause medical injuries you know if they get too close and we've we've had instances
of blue orbs going all the way back to skinwalker wrench where they injured you know killed killed
three three dogs um that were getting too close to them we also had instances at you know skin
worker of the pentagon where we described this biotechnologist who was driving with his daughter
towards bend oregon and sees these three blue ufos in the field next to next to them as they're
driving and they start moving towards the car pretty quickly two of them actually come into the
car one of them goes right across the dashboard in front of of the two of them but one of them
comes in through the window and enters this guy's left shoulder as he's driving goes through the top
of his body and exits his right shoulder right in front of his daughter his daughter is in the
passenger seat and it goes right out the window but you know it goes right through this guy's
body and and and exits the right shoulder and so again we have this sort of uh we we deployed the
mdphd medical investigators that we had on on this case too and they you know these these two
were followed for several months and actually the main person the main guy was followed for years
medically we had serial blood samples but bottom line is this this guy almost immediately
after this event you know when he got got got to his place in bend oregon started having these
symptoms and um you know his uh the left side of his uh of his face had had this sunburn effect
uh he lost the use of his eye it started watering and his eye left eye started going bad his left
ear started going bad uh hair started falling out from the left side of his head after this
thing had gone through his body he came down with a rare form of ductile cancer which luckily did
not metastasize but you know within a few months this guy was really sick so we were able to monitor
him with the the aid of his uh with the these medical positions and we collaborated with the
physicians that were treating him you know in in oregon and we documented sort of a vast amount of
changes in the immune system uh changes in the and the guy's physical health eventually recovered
from the ductile form of cancer luckily it was not metastatic and so um you know a few years later
was feeling a lot better but the weird thing about his daughter who had you know had a close
encounter she did not have any ill effects but you know she was in college and then she went back to
the east coast to um you know to be with uh her her roommates and the same kind of hitchhiker effect
erupted in her household she had never been anywhere close to skinwalker ranch but all she
had was this close encounter with these weird blue orbs but um all of her roommates back in
on the east coast in connecticut where she was going to college uh started reporting you know
waking up with these creatures that were standing over them in their bedrooms and sort of these loud
footsteps on the stairs outside their rooms uh orbs of light sort of moving through the house
again the same kind of thing the so-called hitchhiker effect um she went back from oregon
to the east coast and brought something with her but it was nothing to do with skinwalker ranch so
we figured out eventually that in terms of methodology you've got to follow these people
for months or years in order to really document what the effects of these phenomena are
as opposed to you know you go out you take their testimony for a weekend and then you move on to
the next case you'll miss all of that those kinds of effects and so we were lucky to have the
22 million dollars through the defense intelligence agency to investigate all of this uh all of these
phenomena because we were able to deploy these kinds of resources for a couple of years
and so that made a huge effect i think on the on the overall program
yeah it sounds a lot like um i mean i've heard for years that uh people who have
experiences as as young people will often have them again as adults and
it's almost as if they get the sense that they're recognized like they know who saw what at what
point in their life and return and it's almost feels like it's the same i mean you use the word
methodology that whatever this is has the same mechanism or methodology to be able to track
who's who and who are they related to and who are their friends away where they go and
who are they related to and who are their friends away where they go and it's so spooky
yeah i agree with that i mean i i think there's lots of evidence for people having these kinds
of experiences as kids and then yeah they they they also have experiences during their teens and
all the way into adulthood and it's almost um in a lot of cases it seems to occur in families too
you know the grandparents have you know have these strange activities in their lives their
their offspring have same kinds of phenomena and then attracts even into a third generation and
you can see that the same thing happened in the grant in the grandkids that has been documented
lots of different times it's it's almost like as you say um you know some kind of tracking
mechanism is happening where people who have these effects seem to be predisposed to have more
more of them and also their family members seem to have um it's almost like it transmits genetically
yeah and i'm predisposed to that uh idea because um
um me plus two other people in my family tend to have pre-cognitive dreams
and i've made a conscious effort to track how the hell that has ended up in our our family and
unfortunately i don't have a solid uh sort of family tree to lean in on but i know it comes from
my mother's side and i find that interesting and i think there's something to that too
yeah um i i definitely think that um a lot of a lot of what we've come across
is maternally transferred from grand grandmother to uh daughter you know granddaughter or daughter
granddaughter so um it does seem to to transmit maternally not always but but um it's very common
for a long time i thought there were rules it seemed like it was okay for these things to kill
animals they could mess with humans all they want they could destroy their economic system they could
destroy their psycho their psychology but then i i read about the brazilian black boxes
and now i'm i no longer comfortable in in these sort of false rules i had for myself
so that i could sleep at night uh and i was wondering if you could talk a little bit about
what do you think that there are rules or do you think that like maybe the black boxes aren't
i mean i've never even heard of the black boxes till i read one of your books
the the black boxes you're referring to were called chupas um by the the local hunters and
a lot of this activity happened in in calaris island off the northeast coast of brazil
back in the late 1970s um but and and i would say there were people who died as a result of
these interactions getting zapped by these uh beams from from craft that used to show up
um tremendously frequently but if you look at the entire sort of scope of this phenomenon this ufo
phenomena if you want to use that word um since say 1947 when kenneth kenneth arnold first saw
these things um and it became sort of into public awareness so 75 years it's been going on
um out of out of that 75 years um it's really the exception rather than the rule that people are
killed um people are killed uh there are a lot of people who get too close to these things
and have medical injuries but you rarely come across except for that calaris island series
of incidents where people are so badly injured they get killed um and you know the question is
over time um is is uh we we have a lot of data on what the performance characteristics
of these objects are we've accumulated a lot of data in the last 75 years everything from radar
tracks to ground traces performances but we have almost no data in terms of what their agenda or
intent is and you know it may be that if people get too close to these objects for example the
the guys the guy and his daughter that i just talked about in oregon um and they medical injuries
happen is that as a result of them being in the wrong place at the wrong time or is there some
kind of intent there and um i don't think there's enough data even in 75 years to say that these are
deliberately attacking people i i would tend to say um that we don't have enough data on the agenda
quote unquote of these objects it's it's so i think it's an open question i think it may be that a lot
of these people are in the wrong place at the wrong time and that you know whatever is interacting
with humanity may not mean it harm necessarily um it's just that you know people who get too
close to some of these things um end up injured yeah that's that's the impression i guess so like
the black boxes i think it was it was a sentence in there about how maybe the he was too close to
a beam that was set for stun or something like that yeah or um there was one instance i remember
reading about i don't remember which one it was in where some woman was driving on on a road and
it looked like the ship was malfunctioning and she thought jesus was going to come out of the light
so she stayed and looked at it and um they could don't jesus isn't coming out don't stay and look
at it and uh she ended up with cancer right yeah that's right that was that happened in texas
yeah so and i think also with that i forget his name it was a very famous case they made a movie
on with the logger who got abducted uh travels walton he later came to the conclusion that um
they were trying to help him because he was too close to the ship so even though it was
horrifying for him he now thinks that they were trying to restore his health
yeah and and i i think there are a lot of instances um of that kind of um you know where
where there's there's evidence that you know the upshot of some of these people you know they
they have healings for example um as a result of interacting with uh with some of these things so
it's not all doom and gloom and and so it there seems to be a variety of interactions with these
objects that uh can cause you know people's life lives to change in sometimes a good way you know
sometimes that you know people are so overcome by shock and horror at sort of experiencing something
that should never never be real um that you know they can't handle it and that that's obviously
another set of um you know occurrences and consequences that happen but you know i don't
see any evidence that there's a deliberate attempt to harm humans um in any consistent way how
important are stories in all this um what what do they play any kind of role in
creating your own methodologies uh for example the skinwalker goes all the way back to
to legend uh and then then you have your local local myths oh well i heard that you know this
thing happened on this property at that time or whatever are stories an important role in helping
you figure out kind of a what's going on um in terms of a continuity there's a a guy called
Jacques Ballet who has written some very influential books in this um in this field and by by this
field i mean the general topic of anomalies and ufos and sort of things that should not happen
you know the sort of uh what jeffrey crypal from rice university calls the impossible
you know the impossible happens but you know one of the books that Jacques Ballet wrote was was
one called messengers of deception was written in the 1970s was pretty influential and essentially
his whole um premise was that the ufo topic does operate at the cultural level and it operates
via um you know having having dramatic effects on people's lives in different ways you've got
different manifestations of these objects you've even got people who are claiming to be
contactees quote unquote who can um have charisma and form you know religious cults and so um i you
know to use your terminology the stories of these sort of encounters can permeate into um you know
small groups of people and then ever larger groups of people like the raelian the so-called raelian
movement that happened in france from this guy who originally was um contacted by quote unquote
aliens i mean there are thousands of people in the raelian movement and it's a global movement
but it's a quasi religious movement that's based on the original contact experience of
of a single person um so these kinds of stories do generate myths and um they can transmit to
through populations and one of the premises of valet's books is is that you know you can form
you can have new religions formed as a result of contact experiences and the the way these
experiences are promulgated is mostly verbally and it is through through stories you know
there was a famous um for instance fatima portugal where where these kids who allegedly
saw the virgin mary repetitively the crowds got bigger every time they reported seeing these
uh that these visions of the virgin mary and so the final episode sort of the culmination of
many many weeks of this thing was this gigantic crowd formed in fatima portugal and um you know
a ufo appeared and this object it was like sort of it looked like um a gigantic disc and it was
brightly lit and that all sorts of weird light phenomena happened but like five to ten thousand
people were witness to this in 1917 and you know it all got mixed in with the appearance of of the
blessed virgin mary and so there was a sort of a religious connotation i mean the fatima um fatima
you know visions were were sort of i think they were um counted as miracles in the uh in the in
the catholic church but this is an example of a of a sort of a borderline phenomenon that looks
like a ufo that was sort of layered over a religious visitation and so promulgation of that
i mean for the fatima 1970 sightings were seen as a you know a dramatic occurrence of um a quasi
religious phenomenon and you can see you know a lot of that of the original biblical stories
have been you know interpreted by some people as as you know the original contact experience
had some sort of narratives that were very very parallel to what people see now
i have some closing questions for you
i meant to write just a few and i ended up with the whole page really
um have you been following the current proceedings on the ranch after the acquisition by brandon
fugal yeah to an extent um yeah i've interacted with brandon fugal quite a few times and and
you know it's interesting the team that he deployed on the on the property were extremely
skeptical at the very beginning and this is in march of 2016 they took over so it's been five
years now there's been at least two seasons of the secrets of skinwalker ranch on the history
channel tv but much of what was experienced by the uh the original gorman family back in the early
90s subsequently experienced by all of the nids investigators they're technical people
and all of the people who visited the ranch followed by the government investigators that
were deployed as part of the ossoff program in in skinwalkers of the pentagon and then finally
brandon fugal's team on the skinwalker ranch the the reproducibility of of all of these phenomena
is staggering over a 25 year year period i mean there it's almost like um instead of getting
reproducibility in the short term the kinds of phenomena that have been seen um by brandon
fugal's team is are similar to what have been seen by the defense intelligence agency investigators
and also by the national institute for discovery science investigators and also by the the gorman
family back in the 1994 period and you know we we've tracked the previous owners of the property
that that had skinwalker ranch before the gorman family was was on the property and there's a lot
of evidence that these same phenomena go all the way back into the 50s the 40s and it goes all the
way back even into the 1930s so you know we're looking at sort of something that has happened
continuously brandon fugal's team you know have have been pretty innovative and pretty uh you know
pretty um i would say they've deployed a lot of new technology they've been creative um and but
they're they're experiencing some very very similar phenomena they have not got explanations
for those phenomena there's a lot of hypotheses just like the allsoft program under the defense
intelligence agency generated a number of hypotheses nids generated a number of hypotheses but you know
in terms of testability um nothing is definitive you know but they are consistent i mean there's
been a 25 year documented history on skin marker ranch that is reproducible and consistent
prior to buying it he was warned that um the government wouldn't release some of their findings
to him and as there's some some of it's still classified and
for aspects of the studies that are still classified why why do you think this is and
what is the purpose of withholding information about about this well you know that the original
contract with the defense intelligence agency that started in 2008 and terminated in 2010
i mean that there are really three aspects to this that are that are sort of make it more
difficult to release the information you know just automatically and that is number one the
um the defense intelligence agency contracted a um a private contractor to do this this work
private contractor delivered you know over a hundred reports to the defense intelligence agency
on the activity and not only on skin marker ranch but also elsewhere
um and so all of that is subject to contractor um proprietary contractor language in the in the
original contract that's item number one item number two is that in order to release all of
this data especially the databases that were accumulated you would have to go through them
and remove all of the medically sensitive information the HIPAA related uh information
the personal identity protection protected information that's item number three so um you
know prior to us uh releasing the book uh skin walkers of the pentagon um we had to submit this
to the pentagon for review so four separate agencies within the pentagon reviewed it
including intelligence agencies and they um stipulated that a lot of these names of active
duty military people active duty government people had to be changed there were offices that the
names of offices had to be removed so the department of the defense of defense
went through a line-by-line review of skin walkers of the pentagon before it was released
so they stipulated a lot of removals a lot of information that was sensitive and or classified
was removed from the from the book prior to its publication so those same stipulations also
um hold for release of this information um you know provided a team of people went through every
one of those hundred reports many of which are over 100 pages and also the uh the large database
went through every case in that database again all of the personally protected information
uh would have to be removed all of the medically sensitive information would have to be removed
um but if that was done which would be a long process but if that was done then that information
probably could be released as a taxpayer i 100 support going through this process and releasing
it's difficult but it's doable yeah someday
okay okay so i posted on my facebook hey i'm going to be interviewing author of these books
who was on skinwalker ranch and if anybody has any questions and some people had some questions
and so one of them is um it's about disclosure some say full disclosure on the ufo matter has begun
so do you think it's a big it's begun or do you think that the the release of that navy video is
just a fluke and if it has begun what are the socio-political and economic ramifications
of this becoming a normally accepted thing in our culture well i i think you know june 25th 2021
when the office of of department national intelligence odni
released this report to the public involving 144 cases of interactions between military pilots and
f-18 pilots and and also their carrier strike groups on either end of the both east coast and
west coast that was a a turning point in the history of how the united states government
treats this phenomenon because before that i mean they basically said in that report that
number one ufos are real they're not fantasies they're not people who are on drugs or mentally
ill they are real number two they constitute an air air safety concern that was new and three
they they potentially constitute a national security issue so the fact that the united
states government came forward and and said this to the public was a complete departure from the
previous 75 years where witnesses were regularly sort of labeled as drunks and mental incompetence
and sort of people have to be crazy to you know talk about ufos the other thing is that the united
states government admitted that they had been studying ufos even though um the the standard
line from the united states air force and from other departments had been we lost interest in
ufos in 1969 when we stopped project blue book and the um you know the the condon ufo report
put an end to all of our interest in ufos that was not true i mean they've been studying ufos
all along and the program the 22 million dollar program that we were part of is one of those
programs and so the fact that they actually released for the public record that ufos are real
is a form of confirmation i wouldn't call it disclosure but it was confirmation that what a
lot of people are seeing and have been seeing for 75 years plus um is real so it's not a it's not
some kind of fantasy and they're not mentally ill but it's real so that's about as far i think as
the united states government is going to go i don't see them going beyond that because um you know
what are they going to disclose um that they've already disclosed sort of a short version that
ufos are real um they have no idea who these are what these are who these are or they have no idea
of a lot of the details of what would follow in quote on quote disclosure plus there's uh there's
an enormous body of classified work behind which this whole topic has hidden for decades that is
never going to see the light of day and so the united states government coming forward and saying
ufos are real i think that is probably you know as far as they will go
sorry about the cat by the way i know you can be distracting
yeah i'm allergic to cats so that's probably why i'm coughing he just keeps
i'm just psychological psychological yeah that's right um the hypothetical part the part of your
brain that comes up with you know could hypothetically be this or that has that
changed in any kind of ways from before you were with nids to after i guess i guess the person
wants to know if you're more open-minded that's the impression i get from the question you know
i i think my um my view on this phenomenon has evolved over time i think when i first sort of
started with nids and this is 25 years ago um back in 1996 i guess i had a pretty simplistic
view that you know extraterrestrials were flying in spaceships to um to earth they were taking
samples and they were conducting scientific expeditions um i think the ufo phenomenon is
way more complex than that and i think um my view at this time is that there is um there's a lot more
to be done in in investigating the ufo phenomenon than i had realized because i think what what we
really sort of pioneered during the um the defense intelligence agency funded program was the idea
that um not only could you just look at ufo performance you could also look at ufo effects
on humans and you could you could document physiological effects you could document medical
injuries you could document psychological effects and then all the way out to paranormal effects so
that was a departure that had never been done before and so that has really opened the doors
because um that you know i mean sporadic data had been taken but nothing as comprehensive
and as meticulous as had happened under that government program and they have all the data
on this they own over 100 reports some of which were over 100 pages so thousands upon
thousands of pages of reports are owned by the defense intelligence agency on these not only the
ufo performance and how electromagnetic spectra were monitored magnetic fields were changed and
electromagnetic effects but also medical injuries and physiological psychological paranormal effects
so it's a very rich information source that was begun with this program and you may be aware that
um the national defense authorization act just got past the senate and there's a particular
amendment in that ndaa written by new york senator christian gilibrand which is almost a carbon copy
of the uh the ossa program uh the defense intelligence agency program in other words
it's whoever wrote that language i don't know if it was senator gilibrand or one of her staffers
i think there was a lot of in the of what's in our book skin workers of the pentagon that showed up
in the in the gilibrand amendment it makes me think that they want to get serious about ufos
and they also want to go beyond just sort of documenting um the physics and the engineering
behind the ufos they're also interested in documenting effects on humans because they
specifically use the language in the amendment like monitoring adverse physical effects
we're going to deploy feel the field investigation teams we're going to have
you know effects on on medic medical injuries so it makes me think that you know and obviously
the devil is going to be in the details if it actually turns out that the gilibrand amendment
becomes law and is actually adopted within the pentagon then it stands a good chance
that some kind of repeat of the ossa program is possible and that's that's something that would
that i would never have imagined 25 years ago in terms of my thinking the idea that the united
states government in 20 june 25 2021 would actually say to the public ufos are real
i mean that's something i would never have imagined 25 years ago
some part of me was this past year even i was just like i wish heineck was alive to see this
shit yeah i mean i mean he would have really he would have celebrated i think i mean again
nobody would have expected this do you think that we're this is another facebook question
this is the last facebook question and then i'll have one more for you from me
are humans interfered with or are we just interacted with
well interference and interaction is in the eye of the beholder right i mean there there's an
there's still a lot of people who are having a lot of very intense experiences
with ufo phenomena and with so-called entities associated with ufo phenomena if you ask those
people their answer is we're being interfered with if you ask the people who are having interactions
with ufos from say 100 yards away they see a brightly lit craft they you know they may or
may not have physiological effects i would say they would answer interacted with but i
i guess that the short answer to that question is all of the above i think there are people who are
being profoundly affected you know john mack who was a harvard psychiatry you know head of the
psychiatry department at harvard who spent a lot of time looking at these quote-unquote abductions
and came to the conclusion that these people were not mentally ill they were actually reporting
something real in their lives well if you believe those people and he looked at hundreds of people
you know people are undergoing intrusive procedures that are extracting you know
sperm and eggs from their from their physical bodies against their will so these people are
definitely having intrusive procedures performed on them so that's beyond interaction interactions
if you believe those people you know i mean it's a very intense interaction
what do you what would you like to see from people in the ufo community it and the reason
i'm asking this is the final question is because it seems to me like people are just waiting for
more document releases or somebody somebody else to make a four-year request you know people in the
ufo community have had a long it's been a long time and i think it's almost like the dam has
broken now as of june 25th 2021 we're now in a different era and i guess their expectations
are a lot higher than they were you know a few years ago especially you know prior to the new
york times article that broke the history on our program
you know their expectations are a lot higher so i think a lot of them are wanting the release
of a lot of information but you know you've got to realize that or they have got to realize that
the government works very slowly it is very very careful and beyond releasing non-classified
unclassified versions of some of the interactions with that are ongoing and and activity that's
ongoing but on the eastern west coast and all over the world actually with these objects
there's not a lot that the united states government is probably going to release
so i i i think expectations are very very high i think what needs to happen is that the also
program instead of being a two-year program needs to be reinvigorated into a five-year program
because uh when when when the department of defense program was terminated after two years
we had 50 full-time people that are working on this on this program and out of nowhere this
this project was terminated because of political reasons and because people were realizing that
this data is gonna you know they were afraid it was going to show up on the front pages of the
new york times sometime and that's exactly what happened eight years later so it was shut down
very abruptly this program needs to be uh reinvigorated data needs to be collected for
at least five years and then there needs to be a sort of a a release of all possible information
to the public that's not classified and doesn't interact with you know the national security
situation i would agree with that that's the only way the taxpayers are gonna be okay continuing to
finance it i agree um let's say they reinvigorate this thing uh and it's five years and this question
also applies to i guess the formation of nids it could be any one of these organizations how do
you go about recruiting for something like this like what are you looking for kind of people
it's uh it is a very good question um you know i i personally interviewed um both by phone
by telephone and face-to-face in about a four and a half month period in 2008 about 300 people
when we were doing this massive recruitment drive to populate uh we we we recruited phd level
scientists we recruited um md phds we recruited technicians uh translators data analysts military
intelligence people security officers retired police officers we recruited 50 people in about
four and a half months we trained them and we then we started conducting field research
and probably and we got them security clearances probably in in the space of what would normally
take a contractor two to three years to accomplish we accomplished in about five months because we
had to get this program up and running and get start getting data um in order to deliver what
we were we had promised so it was a really i mean it was a rocket ship um taking off in terms of
but the recruitment process was um luckily that the program itself was not compromised because
we recruited the the normal channels but we were looking for professional people and during the
interviews we had a sort of a weeding out process where we weeded out people who were you know this
was against their religion this was against their their belief system they were they thought all
this was fantasy and this kind of thing so we we we had a screening process that we went through
and out of the over 300 people i interviewed we hired about 50 people and uh i mean we were like
a well-oiled machine after 24 months we were really rocking and rolling on this program
and suddenly it was terminated like i said out of nowhere so the same kind of recruitment process
the same kind of professionals recruit people if possible with security clearances because
that saves a lot of time in terms of um you know reinventing the wheel so um that's what we did
and i think that's what should be done again all right okay thanks it was great and uh you're
welcome back anytime i love the way you talk thank you i appreciate it i enjoyed it too