Hello everybody, welcome back to the podcast. Before I begin, I just wanted to
talk to you about the subject matters of this episode. This episode isn't about
finding answers, but about having conversations that can establish new
pathways to thinking about subjects that don't have easy answers. My guest is the
author of three books, Hunt for the Skinwalker, Skinwalkers at the Pentagon,
and Brain Trust. All three of these books tackle difficult subject matters. My goal
going into this is to have a transparent open-minded discourse, not disrupted by
dogmatic narratives or corrupted by mainstream expectations, and to do so
without worrying about stigma on the subjects herein. I desire to embrace a
truth of reality that doesn't conform to our natural desires for a well-defined
binary reality, and to accept the truth that actual reality is gray. It is blurred
and existing in a quantum field of information that we don't yet fully
understand. On the podcast and in my life, I do not doubt the experiences of others,
and I urge you to adopt a similar philosophy. It is in this that we will be
able to truly listen and maybe eventually find the answers we so
desperately desire. When I talk about the paranormal in this episode, it's the
full spectrum. Ghosts, cryptids, UFOs, precognition, whatever isn't normal to
our everyday lives. Some of the descriptions of paranormal anomalies will
overlap with stories that exist in some religious beliefs, but it's important to
view these concepts as part of the natural world and not concepts to fear
out of religious taboo. If we're going to get an accurate idea of what it is
we're actually looking at, experiencing, and responding to, then we must grow up
and out of our fear-based preconceptions of what is or isn't off-limits to
scientific study. Due to the complexity of the subject matters herein, I decided
to separate the conversation into two episodes. The first part goes live
January 3rd, and the second part goes live January 10th. With that said, please
share this conversation with your friends who might be interested in the
subject. Additionally, I'll be clipping the episode and including these clips on
my YouTube channel, so if there are specific parts of the conversation you
prefer to share, please consider sharing the clips. And please, don't forget to
subscribe and participate in the discourse by leaving a comment on the
YouTube version of this episode or any of the clips. Thanks, and on with the
conversation.
I reached out to you because I had never made the hypothetical connection between
mutilations and our food supply, and so I was thinking maybe we could have a
conversation where we kind of start with your book from 2004, Brain Trust, right,
and then progress to mutilations and then go into the Pentagon. Yeah, yeah,
Skinwalkers. Well, you know, the name is unfortunate. Well, it's not really
unfortunate because, you know, the Skinwalker legend was totally
non-existent until the publication of that first book, Hunt for the Skinwalker,
and sort of put the whole thing on the map. And the idea that Department of
Defense officials were actually getting face-to-face with a lot of weird stuff,
that's where the title came from. But I think outside the small UFO community,
it's almost meaningless to a lot of people, but actually a lot of people have
been affected at the Department of Defense. That's interesting. And yeah, I
definitely want to go there. And I'm thinking, too, like, some of my questions
you might not have a direct experience with, but certainly you probably have
thoughts on. You probably heard some of the same stuff. And so I figured, you
know, you just let me know. Or if you want to skip them, that's fine, too.
But yeah, I just kind of take a loosey-goosey conversational approach.
And I am being informed that I have to talk to you now. I'm gonna shut my phone
off. Yeah, this is, uh, this is my annotations for Hunt.
Wow. That's Hunt for the Skinwalker. That's not even the recent one.
Yeah, I do all of them. And I did, Brain Traps was only available through Kindle,
so I can't show that to you. I think we should do a one-on-one, if that's okay
with you, on kind of how you got your research into Alzheimer's going and just
making some of those basic connections between cows, Alzheimer's. People aren't
going to know what prions are or prions. I don't know if I'm pronouncing it right,
but I think it's protein, right? Yeah, they're essentially infectious proteins,
which is a real kind of strange anomaly, because all infectious organisms usually
are associated with either viruses or bacteria or some kind of combination of
both. But the fact that proteins can display infectious behavior really came
out of Stanley Prusner's research, who got a Nobel Prize. And the previous sort of
assumptions about this infectious entity that was associated with transmission of
these weird neurodegenerative diseases that became known as mad cow disease in cows
and chronic wasting disease in deer. Well, there was a sort of an assumption that there was some
kind of virus involved. I mean, that was the original assumption until sort of Stanley
Prusner really started putting the idea of infectious proteins on the map. And I mean,
everybody carries prions. And when prions are in a particular conformation shape,
then they do a lot of good in the cell. But it's when they flip to this alternative conformation
is when they start really wreaking havoc on the cell. And then as time goes on, on the larger
tissue, which is the brain. And the standard way of looking at the brain after
infectious prions is almost like Swiss cheese. I mean, there's big holes punched in the brain
over a few years of this alternative conformation working its way through.
Just so that we're getting the vocabulary down. Can you describe the difference between a downer
and a walker? In terms of cows? Yeah, it's a downer cow is basically a cow who has lost the use
of his or her nervous system and muscles. In other words, they can't get up and walk.
A walker is a cow that is displaying preliminary symptoms, but is not actually
sort of at the stage where it's becoming terminal. And the downer cows are usually
well on the way to death. And walkers, they may be staggering, they may be shaking, they may have
sort of uncontrollable twitches and all of that, but they're still able to walk. So it's just a
kind of a progression of symptoms. In some of the old interviews I saw of you,
you had talked a little bit about how the research didn't include walkers or the testing
didn't include walkers. Do you know if the USDA has changed their approach in testing?
Well, you know, brain trust was written back in 2003 when the whole mad cow was sort of a real
issue because the first case had been discovered in Washington state and multiple cases had been
discovered in Canada. And we were just at the sort of the latter end of a wave of
cases of mad cow disease in the United Kingdom and Europe. And people had eaten infected,
tainted meat in the United Kingdom and Europe and a lot of young people had died. So,
you know, brain trust was written in 2003. So USDA really slammed on the brakes in terms of testing
with the idea being that, you know, they were doing quote unquote statistical sampling.
But actually what they were doing was a lot less testing than they should have been. And in fact,
there was a famous case that might be in the brain trust book where a private company decided to go
ahead and do testing. Sorry, my cell phone just went off there. So they decided to do testing
and the USDA shut them down because they were testing outside of what the USDA considered
acceptable. And the idea was that they were opening their doors towards private ranchers
who wanted to know whether or not this infectious entity was in their cattle. So a lot of people
wanted testing to accelerate, but the USDA slammed on the brakes. So in the interim period,
there has not been an increase in testing. There's actually been a decrease in testing over time.
So if there was sort of low levels of this, you know, mad cow disease, BSE,
being transmitted in the United States cattle herds, then the chances are it would not be
detected these days. Oh, interesting. I was hoping for better news.
Yeah, well, you know, it's kind of gone off the radar for a lot of people. And, you know,
since brain trust was written, the science has progressed tremendously. And, you know,
after the National Institute for Discovery Science program ended in 2003, 2004, I actually
took a job in San Francisco, California. I was working as a laboratory director at a biotechnology
company in San Francisco. And just by sort of coincidence, actually, one of the research arms
that was being conducted at this company was looking exactly at the kinds of alternative
prion confirmations that were possible. And, you know, the sort of the, I guess, the Holy Grail of
this research or part of the Holy Grail of this research was to develop really good monoclonal
antibodies that were directed against the alternative confirmations, because that would
have been a very good way of being able to distinguish preferentially between the different
confirmations of the prions. And by analogy, the pathology, you could actually investigate the
pathology. So I was part of this biotechnology company in San Francisco that was doing this kind
of prion research. And one of the things that has come out in the interim is that a lot of these
so-called neurodegenerative diseases, including Alzheimer's disease, and a lot of the dementias
also have these prion-like characteristics. They're not prion proteins, but some of the
proteins that are involved in Alzheimer's disease display prion-like characteristics. In other words,
they can change confirmations. And once those confirmations are changed, they can induce other
proteins to change confirmations. So there is that sort of large scale umbrella effect where
all of the dementias and the neurodegenerative diseases share this characteristic in common.
When I wrote Brain Trust back in 2003, none of that was known. All of the research that was
being done or has been done on that has really been done in the last 10, 12 years. So it's got
to the stage now where there is a lot of overlap in the thinking with the large Alzheimer's epidemic
that we're in the middle of. And the fact that the proteins in Alzheimer's display prion-like
characteristics in terms of quote unquote infectious behavior. So that's a dimension that was not there
12 years ago. Well, I know I can't even hear a conversation about Alzheimer's now without
somebody mentioning beef. So I would like to think that you get the credit for that.
Well, I know that there's a lot of people that are involved in the research. And
it is surprising. A lot of people have sort of come up to me in the interim and talked about
Brain Trust. So quite a few people seem to have read the book, which kind of surprised me because
the book is bad news. I mean, there's not a lot of joy and happiness in that book. So
I was not expecting a large number of people to be sort of reading it. But for example,
South Korea, there was a lot of interest in South Korea because they had an uptick in BSC
maybe 10 years ago. So a lot of people in South Korea bought the book. And I believe actually
Brain Trust was translated into Korean. Well, I think a lot of people,
despite what some powers that be think, they want the truth even if it's painful.
People want to know how to be healthy. Yeah, I agree. I mean, that especially these days,
I think is becoming more and more the case. I think a lot of young people do tend to
be much more focused on what they eat than, say, the older generations.
You'd suggested, I think it might have been on a podcast you did with George where it might be
that there are others who are interested in our food supply. And I think that that's fascinating.
And I was wondering if you could talk about why you think that is.
Yeah. So the whole cattle mutilation thing came out. I joined an organization in 1996,
which is way back in history, called the National Institute for Discovery Science. And the purpose
of that organization was a privately funded organization by billionaire Robert Bigelow,
who tends to put a lot of money into areas that are controversial and anomalies. So
one of the anomalies that the National Institute for Discovery Science was tasked with investigating
was this so-called cattle mutilation phenomenon that really erupted in the late 1960s
throughout the western part of the United States. Pretty well every state was hit. And
even in the 1970s, 1980s, there was hundreds if not thousands of cattle that were
found by farmers and ranchers and veterinarians. They were perfectly healthy the day before,
and they would be found dead with these weird incisions that happened where the lips
were cut out. Sometimes the genitals were cut out. Sometimes there were holes that were made
in the abdomen of the cattle. Sometimes there were holes in the head. But it all looked like
somebody had killed these animals, and it was definitely not the work of predators or coyotes
or whatever. So this was a mystery. And actually in late 1979, 1980, the FBI actually got involved
with investigating these phenomena because the entire western part of the United States was
suffering an epidemic of these cattle mutilations. And essentially nobody has been ever caught or
charged with a crime in terms of killing thousands of these cattle. So the National Institute for
Discovery Science was formed. We had a full-time veterinarian on staff. My background is biological
sciences. So we formed sort of a task force within NIDS, which is the acronym for National
Institute for Discovery Science. And we connected with a lot of veterinarians in the western part
of the United States and also law enforcement, sheriff's departments throughout the Montana and
Washington, Nevada, Arizona, New Mexico, Colorado. So we established a network so that we could get
a call when these animals went down. And so we were able to get our act together so that we would have
veterinarian, a qualified veterinarian on the spot within 24 hours of the animal dying.
The rancher would find the animal and would immediately know who to call because we sent a
lot of these telephone numbers out. We had a toll-free telephone number. So we would get calls. We
would dispatch a team to these cattle mutilations. And we looked at several, probably 50, 60 cattle
mutilations in different states over a period of maybe four or five years. So it was a really
successful sort of endeavor. And the idea was that we would be on the spot. The veterinarian
would do what's called a necropsy, which is the equivalent of an autopsy on these animals. It
would take samples. If there did look like there were cuts around the hide, samples were taken
from and we would dispatch those samples to a variety of labs for histopathology and for
biochemical analysis, blood analysis and all of that. So we did have the resources because
Robert Bigelow was funding all of this out of his own pocket. So the way we approached this was a
very sort of forensic sort of scientific approach as opposed to kind of standing over the animal
and taking photographs and sort of speculating. So what ended up happening was that we accumulated
a lot of data over four or five years. And it became obvious that there were really two sort of
separate patterns of cattle mutilations. One was the most common and that was that the lips or the
eyes or the reproductive organs were usually removed in some kind of a really well-orchestrated
surgical manner. It was obviously, whoever was doing this had some sort of surgical skill.
In fact, some of the veterinarians that we talked to because we also enlisted
local veterinarians in this whole thing, some of these people that we talked to actually said,
you know, this is really skillful. What's being done here is not sort of some hack arriving with
a scalpel. It's somebody who knows what they're doing. So there was that sort of series of
mutilations but there was a small number of mutilations including one or two that we looked
at on Skinwalker Ranch which were obviously much weirder and much more difficult to explain. In
other words, you know, it was beyond somebody with surgical expertise. You know, one example of that
is we came upon a mutilated animal in Northern California and the intact eye of the animal had
been removed and it had been placed on the grass. I mean, with the vitreous fluid in the eye, all
the fluid in the eye was still intact and it was looking at the animal. I mean, this was sort of
weird. It was not the sort of business-like, you know, the standard pattern was pretty business-like.
It looked like a sampling exercise. So there was this small number that we sort of labelled as
quote-unquote paranormal linked calculations but the majority of them looked like a business-like
sampling exercise that was going on. Now layered on top of that, over the course of
the several years that we looked into it, there were medical devices sometimes found
either beneath these animals or on these animals. I'm talking about hypodermic syringes. Some of the
chemical analysis that we conducted on these animals seemed to show that there were levels of
sedatives in the animals. So it began to look like some kind of a sampling exercise
and it was around this time that the whole prion protein was sort of gaining prominence
as a sort of a really lethal disease. So we put out the hypothesis that this may have been a
food supply sampling exercise by a small expert team that may have been contracted by,
you know, might have been contracted by a pharmaceutical company, might have been
contracted by one of the arms of the United States government. We didn't know but it would not be
a very, very sort of sophisticated exercise to have a helicopter, a couple of trained
veterinarian surgeons, a couple of technicians to land at night and start sampling animals in the
wild. Now why would this be necessary? The reason it's necessary is that if you try to do the same
thing in a sort of a slaughterhouse, if you go to a slaughterhouse and you try to get samples of
animals, people start talking and you do not have the same sort of freedom of movement or latitude
than if you're sampling the food supply in the field in the wild. And if you're tracking
movement of an infectious organism or an infectious prion across a food supply,
you want to do it in multiple states, multiple herds, multiple locations and that's the kind
of pattern that we began to see. So it's the result of all of the above that we started
formulating this hypothesis that, you know, there was the majority of these sample, you know,
samples were being taken from cattle, probably legally, but it was a sampling of the food supply
as opposed to, you know, UFOs coming down and mutilating cattle, this kind of thing. But,
you know, the beauty of this whole thing was that there was enough legend and enough lore out in the
sort of the newspapers and all of that, all talked about mutilations sort of being associated with
aliens. So that means that no self-respecting veterinarian would waste a lot of time doing
this. No serious scientific study would ever happen. A law enforcement would usually not touch
it. So, you know, we also hypothesized that this organization, whoever it was, that was sampling
the food supply, was doing it on the undercover of the so-called UFO alien thing. So they knew
they would never get caught because nobody would essentially bother to get into such a controversial
investigation. And so, you know, this thing went on for decades. There are very, very occasional
cases now, but there were, you know, countries in South America had a lot of this cattle mutilation
phenomenon occurring in the same way. You know, I mean, if I had to speculate, I would say the same
group that was doing it in the United States also probably got a contract to go down to Argentina
because Argentina were obviously very concerned about the quality of their beef, especially with
the export markets. They were exporting a lot to the United States and Europe. So they were very
concerned about making sure that the food supply in Argentina was not contaminated.
Hmm. Is there, have you ever attempted to figure out, like, based on the parts that have been
removed, what sort of information they were looking for, like with the tongue or whatever?
Well, again, one of the reasons that we started looking at the, you know, at the prion as a
possibility is that, you know, there were primarily prions, once they infect, they do
replicate very rapidly in the tongue and in the lymph nodes around the neck of the animal.
So, and in the brain and the spinal cord tends to also get a lot of activity. The eye, there's a lot
of prion activity in the eye of an infected animal. So a lot of the organs that were being
removed and the tongue is a very good example because of the high levels of replication
of prions in the tongue that we kind of put two and two together and we formulated this. Now,
I emphasize this is not a fact. This was a testable hypothesis. So, you know, NIDS was
disbanded in 2004. After that, I'm not aware of any organization that through the kind of resources
at this problem that Robert Bigelow and National Institute for Discovery Science
and our teams that were on the ground, I'm not aware of anything that has been done
since 2004 on this problem. I think things have actually regressed back to the original situation
where you get people who are sort of they quote unquote investigate calumelations by going there,
taking photographs and then posting them online. But, you know, in terms of actual information,
analytical information, forensic analysis, I'm not aware of anything that's been done since 2004.
Well, later on, I'm going to ask you about
investigations and what people should be doing. But I have a couple more questions about the
calumelations. You had said something earlier about how there was sort of almost a parallel
between the discovery of the prions and when they started. And I was wondering if
there's also a correlation. I don't know how far back Alzheimer's research goes into, but
was there an increase in Alzheimer's at around the time that this started as well?
Well, you know, the timing Alzheimer's obviously is known that there were some cases of dementia
documented all the way back in the early 1900s. In fact, the guy all was Alzheimer was operating
back in those days and the disease, you know, got his name. But it's not really until the 1970s
that the numbers of Alzheimer's cases started to really escalate. I mean, you can actually track
it because the CDC has a lot of data now in terms of the escalation of Alzheimer's that really
started. The curve started going up and it got steeper and steeper by the late 1970s, 1980s,
1990s. So it has continued going very, very sharply up. But pre 1970, Alzheimer's disease
was not that common. I mean, it was common. Now, you know, if you talk to somebody at the CDC,
they'll say, OK, well, we did change the definition of what constitutes Alzheimer's
around that time. You know, that possibly is one of the reasons. But it goes way,
way beyond that because we're talking, you know, hundreds and hundreds of percent increases
and escalating over time. Also, the aging of the population, you'll hear these explanations that
aging of the population, people are living older, longer now. But that's still, even if you factor
all of those factors in, you still get dramatic increases of this phenomenon,
Alzheimer's phenomenon, starting the 1970s. Now, I should mention that, you know, one of the things
that I tracked in brain trust was that there was really sort of some remarkable
experiments being done by the National Institutes of Health in the 1950s. And
there was a guy called Carlton Gajuszek, who actually won the Nobel Prize for his discoveries.
But what he figured out was that there was a tribe in Papua New Guinea called the Foray.
They were cannibals. And one of the ways they sort of marked the rituals that they marked the death
of one of their tribe's people was by eating them. And Carlton Gajuszek discovered that there was,
this tribe had come down with a bizarre brain disease that they call kuru. And so he actually
was kind of like a cowboy out there. I mean, nobody was regulating or overseeing him,
but he was an NIH scientist. So he started carving up these people and essentially getting their
brains of these cannibals who were dying from this mysterious disease, shipping the brains back to
the National Institutes of Health. And actually, the brains were shipped to Fort Detrick in
Maryland, which is still the center of biological warfare investigations in the United States.
And so these brains were accumulating in Fort Detrick. So throughout the, this all happened
in the late 1950s. So throughout the 1960s, they were trying to figure out what this infectious
entity that was killing these tribe's people, because it was obvious something infectious.
They were eating and the people, the cannibals who ate the dead people would all in turn come
down with this mysterious brain degenerative disease that we now know as mad cow disease.
But bottom line is the scientists at the NIH, they got this facility in Patuxent, Maryland,
and began injecting a whole bunch of different animals, chimpanzees, deer, cattle, mice,
rats, you name it, to see if this disease was transmissible. So bottom line is that over time,
to put it mildly, all of the security, all of the sort of biosafety level, none of that existed back
in the early 60s. So a lot of these animals escaped. And so one of the hypothesis is by the
sort of late 1960s, early 1970s, these prions had transmitted through the food chain,
especially to deer, because chronic wasting disease in deer is a highly infectious form of
this aberrant protein that goes right through the herds. So bottom line is that it transmitted
through the country. And so the escalation of all of this stuff, including cannabinoidations
beginning in the late 1960s, the rise of dementia that happened in North America
in the 1970s, all of these kind of co-located in time around the same time. So again, we were,
we went through the exercise of joining the dots. One of the parts I found interesting in Brain Trust
is this sort of recurring, it seemed like a scene that recurred again and again and again, where
some authority with the state would go and investigate the cannabinoidation, be like,
it's a predator, see ya. And do you think that, and this could just be your opinion based on
all the time you spent up there doing that. Do you think they knew better?
This is a pretty complex, you know, it's a pretty complex research program. And I think some people
may have known better. I think the people who contracted, who may have contracted this small
outfit to do some food source sampling throughout the western part of the United States may have
known better. But the vast majority of the people who were working at the state level,
you know, sort of who were aligned with the CDC or the USDA, I really don't think that those people
were privy to what was going on. I think it was kind of like they didn't have the full picture
and there was too many separate data points in different areas. I don't think, you know,
necessarily people had the full picture. And the other thing is, you know, I've worked with
a lot of state governments, but particularly federal government in the last 25 years,
including Department of Defense and NASA and other organizations and multiple departments in the
Department of Defense. And so what some people may ascribe to, you know, some kind of a conspiracy,
I think usually can be explained by people making mistakes or some sort of incompetence going on.
I would tend to put that out as the first explanation as opposed to some kind of organized
cabal doing some something nefarious, because again and again, I've seen these sort of mistakes
being made. You know, people get transferred out of departments and all of their expertise
goes with them. And this new person has no idea what to do with this whole thing. That happens
with incredible regularity in the federal government. I would agree with that. When I
was in my early 20s, before I moved to New York, I used to be a conspiracy theorist. Then I came
here and I started meeting people. And I changed my mind. Once you start having
dinner with a congressman, you realize nobody can keep a secret. Exactly. And yeah.
So the business as usual mutilations, then there's the other ones. Can you talk about the other ones?
The other ones, I'll give you an example of the other ones. There was a ranch in Northeastern Utah,
which has since become known as Skinwalker Ranch. That National Institute for Discovery Science was
kind of, it owned the property. And it was like a living laboratory, because one of the reasons
the property was purchased was that this property had a history of cattle mutilations going back
into the 60s and 50s. So the property was purchased and there was a herd of cattle on the property.
And so we had surveillance on the property. We had sensors on the property to detect anything
weird. But I was sitting in Las Vegas in 1997 when we got a call from the ranch manager
of Skinwalker Ranch saying that one of their calves had gone down and they had just found it.
And the weird thing was this was calving season. It was March of 1997. All these newborn calves were
you know, getting born around the property. And the rancher and his wife, the ranch manager and
his wife had gone through the process of putting ear tags, these bright yellow plastic ear tags on
the cattle, on the calves after they've been born. So this was happening, but sort of 10 o'clock
in the morning, they had just tagged this newborn calf. It weighed about 84 pounds.
And they had walked about 100 yards down to the next one where they were proceeding to tag the
next one when the dog next to them started freaking out. And it was obviously focused on
where they had just come from before. So they went back to figure out what was going on and
they found this calf that they had tagged like 45 minutes earlier. And this was like 10 o'clock
in the morning, bright sunny morning in March. And they found the calf completely spread eagle
on the ground. All of its internal organs were gone. It was open as if it had been sort of
spread-eagled and carefully spread on the ground. And the really spooky part of this thing was that
there was not a drop of blood on the animal, in the animal. So it's not like a coyote came out
from the tree line and attacked the calf. This calf had been completely stripped of all internal
organs. And so I got a call when I was in Las Vegas and we had our veterinarian on staff,
we had a couple of people. So luckily Robert Bigelow had a private jet. So we jumped on the
private jet. We were standing over the animal about two and a half, three hours after the call.
And I mean, this was one of the weirdest things I've ever seen. I mean, this calf was lying on
its back in the pasture. All four legs are spread-eagled and the flesh was pink. The ribs were
just jutting up. All of the hide had been cut away. And like the rancher had talked to us,
there was not a drop of blood on the animal. So we actually did this experiment to see if maybe
a whole bunch of blood had sort of seeped from the animal onto the ground and disappear that way.
So we actually did that experiment, went to the local slaughterhouse, got a couple of litres of
blood and poured it on the grass in different locations and photographed it over time. The fact
is, if any of that blood had been spilled from the calf, it would have stained the grass badly.
But this animal in broad daylight with the two people no more than sort of 100 yards,
maybe 150 yards away, they never heard anything. They never saw anything. The only thing that
alerted them was their dog went crazy at this particular time and alerted them that something
was happening over there. But this happened essentially in broad daylight under their noses.
So that's an example of the kind of spooky sort of quote unquote paranormal associated because we
actually got a tracker, a professional tracker, to start looking around the animal and he kind
of boarded the area for several days looking for tracks, looking for any tracks of any perpetrators
that could have done this. We had all of these gaming exercises. We wargamed the whole thing of
a group of special forces people that had broken cover from the fence line and done it. But the
fact is there were no tracks. There was no blood at all. There was no sign of the organs.
And this animal, the bright yellow ear tag from the ear of the animal had been really
cleanly sliced off by what looked like a scalpel very, very cleanly. So this was not a coyote attack.
It was not somebody or something had done this using sharp instruments. So we took a necropsy
of the animal. We sampled the animal and from two independent labs we got, forensically,
we got that sharp instruments had definitively been used on this animal.
It was not sort of a predator attack. It was not a coyote attack. So that was an example of the kind
of the spooky and this was not characteristic of the animals that we investigated. Your involvement
with the ranch pretty much started with the mutilations? It started with, it was a combination
of the cattle mutilations plus a lot of unusual activity including these quote unquote nuts and
bolts, UFOs that used to reportedly fly over the property. So that was one of the reasons that the
ranch was purchased. It's a 500-acre ranch in Northeastern Utah, about 40, 50 miles from the
Colorado border. It's along the Wasatch Front, pretty out of the way place. But that was the
reason it was purchased because of these, we were tasked with investigating all of these anomalies
utilizing the scientific method. I mean, that's the bottom line. We had PhD-level scientists on
staff. We actually had a science advisory board that were pretty, they held our feet to the fire
and they made sure that nothing that we did was deviated from the scientific method. And these
people were sort of world-class scientists from national laboratories, from universities. We
actually had two scientists or two astronauts who had walked on the moon on the board of National
Institute for Discovery Science. That's like Harrison Schmidt and Edgar Mitchell. So two out
of the 12 people in history that walked on the moon, they were part of our National Institute
for Discovery Science, science advisory board. So it was a pretty prestigious board and they were
not into sloppiness or methodology that was outside the scientific method. So I mean,
I think it was a good thing because it really kept us really focused on trying to apply the
scientific method to these anomalies. But one of the problems was we were constantly one foot behind
whatever was doing this, we were always behind the curve.
And that was the first part of my conversation with Colin Kelleher. Please tune in next week
for the second part in which we discussed almost exclusively his work at Skinwonka Ranch. Thanks,
everybody.