Hello and welcome to Reality Check. Before we start I want to tell you a
little bit about our sponsor for this week. It's the iconic Chuck Norris, a guy
I used to have on my bedroom wall. The martial artist hero who's still in his
80s and still kicking butt and still staying active. What's even more shocking
is he's stronger, he can work out longer and he even has plenty of energy left
over for his grandkids. He did this by making just one change and he says he
still feels like he's in his 50s. His wife even started doing this one thing
too and she's never felt better. She says she feels 10 years younger, her body
looks leaner and she has energy all day. Chuck made a special video that explains
everything. Make sure you watch it by going to chuckdefense.com slash Ross.
That's this link below this video. It will change the way you think about your
health. Once again that's chuckdefense.com slash Ross. Now let's get on and enjoy the show.
G'day and welcome to Reality Check. So you've seen the full NewsNation special
investigation Hunting UFOs where we detailed the allegations of a first-hand whistleblower
for the very first time telling the inside story of the retrieval of non-human craft.
I know it's an extraordinary allegation to make and there's millions of armchair experts out there
who think they know everything about this story. Well today for the first time the bloke who told
that story to me on NewsNation is telling his full account, the full interview for the first time.
Jacob Barber is a guy I first met two years ago and he's not used to the limelight. He's
fundamentally somebody who's been trained in intelligence. He's been trained in how to operate
in the covert world and the only reason he's going overt is because he thinks you, the public,
have a right to know about the illegal and criminal and improper things that he believes
are going on inside what he calls the program. But be aware that, I think as George Herbert once said,
the life of a spy is to know, not be known. It's difficult for any person to make the decision to
step out into the limelight, let alone the excoriating glare of many hostile people who
are looking for any excuse to pull Jake down from his pedestal. And the interesting thing is
he wants to be investigated. He wants the government, the congress, to tackle this story
and begin the slow exposition of what he knows. And it's a difficult story I think for a lot of
people to grasp because the scale of it and the implications of it are immense. Not only does it
mean that there is a non-human intelligence that's been engaging with this planet and
contrary to what the Pentagon says, we've known about it for decades. It also means, of course,
that the government or sections of the government have been lying to us and continue to lie to us.
And that's an egregious breach of public faith and at some stage there is going to be a reckoning.
But ultimately the big decision now for congress and for the new Trump administration is whether
they take the allegations of Jacob Barber seriously. So he wants and we've always intended
for his full story to be told. So here today for the very first time is the full interview
with Jake Barber, a great and loyal American who wants you to know the truth. Hey Ross,
my name is Jacob Barber and for the last 30 years I've worked for the US government and
its private partners in both an official capacity as an enlisted man in the United States Air Force
and in a non-official capacity for the broader intelligence community as a contractor. Over
the last three decades my work has been very diverse and has included the recovery of downed
UAP of non-human origin. I am pleased to share that as of a couple weeks ago I have fulfilled
a promise to our friend David Grush by getting myself into a skiff with congress and I have
provided top secret SCI testimony on the subject matter of UAP. With this behind us I'm pleased to
be at a place where I can share information with the public. The type of information I can share
will be limited by my DOPSR restrictions and personal restrictions I have set in order to
protect the privacy and quality of life of my friends family and colleagues. So with that
let's talk. So Jake, you've just made an historic revelation that we are not alone. How did it feel?
Felt pretty good actually. Get that off my chest. You've lived with this secret for how long?
You could say more than a decade. So let's roll back. Let's tell the story of Jake Barber.
Okay. You say you were an enlisted man and then you ended up working for the intelligence community
as a contractor. Tell me that story. How did that happen? Well in high school I was 17 years old.
I was prospected into a program, an enlistment program. It was a guaranteed enlistment or
guaranteed training enlistment program contract for a specific career field at the time called
Combat Control. Career field is still called that. The contract was unique at the time.
It was a 10-year commitment to Air Force Special Operations. I finished my screening for that
program in September of 1994. I shipped off to Air Force Basic Training. Upon completion of that
I went to a place known as Operating Location Hotel. This was Air Force Special Operations
selection. I completed selection roughly four months later and then entered into what is known
as the pipeline. The pipeline is approximately a two-year specialized training schedule where
you go to a number of schools. At a certain point in my pipeline I was approached by some individuals
who had a discussion with me and convinced me it might be a good idea to consider becoming an
airplane mechanic. Was that to be your cover? Yes, yes. Because I noticed your DD214 which is
your release discharge document from the U.S. Air Force which you've provided us. It says you're
an aerospace mechanic. I was. I was a mechanic. I spent a lot of time on the flight line at Pope
Air Force Base and an obscure maintenance shop known as the Dash 21 dual rail shop and I spent
a lot of time there in my cover capacity and I worked hard. You're constrained very heavily
aren't you by what's called a defense office pre-publication security review. Correct. And
that's called ADOPSA for short. Yes. And if you accidentally or deliberately reveal information
that they've told you that you're not allowed to reveal you can go to jail for the rest of your life.
Yeah they've created quite a landmine of words to avoid. So there are certain agency names,
certain designations in the military that you're not allowed to reveal or use. Yes and for good
reason. Let me clarify something though. You were trained as a top special operations soldier. Upon
completing that I was given orders to Pope Air Force Base where I spent a lot of time actually
working in a maintenance capacity in an obscure maintenance shop known as the Dash 21 dual rail
shop. My time outside of that was spent in any number of clubs you could say. I was a member
of many clubs where I got an opportunity to do a lot of interesting training. You were given
extensive special operations training. I trained in things like survival. I was in parachute club.
I was in scuba club. I was in weapons club. I was in pilot club. I even was in Spanish club.
I was in entrepreneur club, paramedic club. So they were fully training you for whatever that
covert role was going to be. Nobody was training me. I was there on my own free will out of my own
interest and trained in a number of clubs. A mechanic but you were training yourself in a
whole range of different skills and I noticed your DD214 document it actually shows that you've got a
sharpshooter's achievement. Yes, yeah. So how many mechanics have a sharpshooter's achievement?
Not many. I will say that the standard for marksmanship in the Air Force is pretty low
but I did qualify as expert marksman in a number of small arms. Right and you've also I noticed
you're able to talk about the fact that you earned a commendation for the use of
combat medical skills to help save the lives of two men in a horrible accident.
Yeah that's the interesting thing is every once in a while my club skills would show up
in the ordinary Air Force. Part of what goes on when things are heavily compartmentalized is often
the left hand doesn't know what the right hand is doing and so serving in my capacity is what is
known as an OPFOR, an oppositional force. By the time I was deeply immersed in my club training
I soon began to be deployed as what's known as a red team member. I became a red team expert.
So an opposition force person what do they do? Just explain to me what you do.
So OPFOR is the bad guys. So an OPFOR is a utility team and that team's utility as in
pressure testing or stress testing the effectiveness of blue what are known as
blue forces which are the good guys. So OPFOR is trained to deploy their own intuition
and innovation in order to make the regular soldier's lives hell and that was where I was
uniquely qualified and was deployed in that fashion in a number of real world scenarios
and training scenarios. Now it's a very useful set of skills that you acquired in the Air Force.
Yes. You've essentially had the training of a top tier one operator at if you like Delta Force or
STS-24 level which is the top US Air Force elite group but you were not a top tier one operator.
That is correct. There's no evidence that I was ever assigned to any task force that was associated
with those teams you just mentioned. What were you? What was I? Ross I was a highly talented
airplane mechanic who got to deploy on a number of presidential support missions. I was a security
escort for what are known as HVTs all over the world. I also worked I deployed in Bosnia in
support of the hunt for war criminals. So why do countries like America have covert people like
yourself? What's the purpose of it? Well there's a lot of utility in what you could call a hidden
hand. For better or for worse the US government and its agencies tend to paint themselves into
a corner and they're bound by their own regulations and rules of play which makes it extremely
valuable to be able to outsource to folks who don't have to follow those same rules.
So you were operating outside of the normal rule book but to be clear there's nothing wrong with a
covert role. The US government uses covert operators all the time. Absolutely it's 100%
in the best interest of everyone in this country and to maintain superiority from a national
security standpoint that we play the game that way. And do you regard yourself as a patriot?
Absolutely first and foremost before anything else and I'd like to be clear let's do this
right now. I'd like you to know exactly what side I'm on. Firstly I'm on the side of my family and
my friends. Second I'm on the side of the American people and I'm on the side of the government and
the military. Third and only as long as they're taking care of the first two. In that time when
you were being trained learning all these skills did you have any idea about aliens? No not at all.
One way you can validate that you were doing special work is that you were actually recommended
for a heroism medal weren't you? The US Air Force? I was. And you're not allowed to talk about that
operation are you? No there was a classified missions that took place in Bosnia and but every
once in a while things showed up in my record and at some point I had the presence of mind to start
making copies of certain things which was a little nerve-racking because it may have been illegal
that I was in possession of certain things but this was a letter recommendation that
that calls out my particular act of heroism. Were you awarded that medal? No it was squashed by my
case officer. And do you think it was squashed because they didn't want you to be conspicuous?
Yeah because what the hell would an aircraft mechanic be doing chasing war criminals in Bosnia
and doing so to the extent that he would find himself in a situation that would be worthy of
a medal of heroism. Now you can't name the agency the organization that you were working for can
you? No. You're forbidden by your DOPSA? Forbidden. At any stage during any of the training that you
received was anyone ever telling you that you were part of a government that was aware of the
existence of non-human intelligence? No not at that time and I'll have to tell you that
that everything changed for me right around 9-11 and I left the Air Force and basically made a left
turn at Albuquerque never part of the global war on terror and quite literally made a left turn
at Albuquerque and was sent out to California at that time to begin establishing my cover basis
for an independent as an independent contractor so that I can serve what was coming down the
line next for me and that is the path which led to the UAP subject. In your time in deployment
you met certain people from an aerospace company didn't you? Yes I did. Now it's also part of the
constraints you operate under that you can't name that aerospace company? Correct there's no good
reason to name them even if I wasn't constrained. What were they doing there? Well they were
supporting us with some new weapons technology that could be used to
disable vehicles and aircraft. I can disclose this my understanding is that they were essentially
using it was actually I think it's a meta republic record that microwave weapons,
pulse microwave weapons were being used at that time. Correct there were some early prototypes
that were being used at that time and I met individuals that were there representing the
companies that were providing that service to the government made some friends and those
relationships led to opportunities later in the California desert where I began my journey. Before
we go any further had you ever as a child experienced any kind of anomalous phenomena yourself?
No. This was completely off the books for you it was complete revelation to you. I mean I was born
in the 70s I grew up a fan of Star Wars and Star Trek and Back to the Future and it certainly was
a pleasant and fun idea but during that same time it was also very clear that the culture
it was clearly nostalgic like the subject matter of UAP and non-human intelligence which wasn't
an acronym we used back then aliens let's say that it was 100% a fictional story so while I
was interested in it it was purely as a adolescent from being interested by any other fictional
subject. Before we get into the nitty-gritty of what happened after 2001 let's talk about
what you perceive are the rights and responsibilities of American citizens under
your constitution. As an enlisted man did you swear an oath to the constitution? I sure did
How much do you care about the ideas and the principles that are espoused in the U.S.
Constitution? Those ideas are absolutely paramount they come above everything else even though I
mentioned my family and my friends are whose side I'm on first I cannot facilitate protecting them
without the fundamental nature of the U.S. Constitution so it is paramount to everything
else. Is it fair to say that the reason why you're speaking to us here today is because you
think it's important that the American people be told about what we're going to disclose in
accordance with the constitution? Article 1 of the U.S. Constitution enshrines the idea that all
arms of government must be transparent and accountable to the congress. Is that happening?
You know I can't really speak to that from what we're being told there is no evidence
of extraterrestrial presence here there is no evidence of non-human intelligence
there's a little bit of admittance and evidence that there's something anomalous in the sky
flying around and we don't know what it is so the bad news is I can't really help further that
question that everyone wants answered the good news is I'm going to begin to be able to start
answering that question and that's the primary reason I'm here to speak to you today. Do you
think congress is being misled, deceived about what is secretly known about non-human intelligence
alien life? It's clear they don't have the full story. What's being held back?
Just about everything but there's another problem I don't even know that they're giving it a proper
attention to begin with so unfortunately congress is very ignorant when it comes to the subject.
So very recently the pentagon spokesman assured press reporters in a pentagon briefing
that there is no evidence of extraterrestrial engagement with planet earth. Is that true?
Is that true? No that's not true. Now they like to hang their hat on some key words there
extraterrestrial so that means outside of the planet earth and that is yet to be determined
by my best understanding. So you're saying you know for a fact there are aliens? Yes 100%.
There are alien craft? 100%. Have you been involved in the recovery of those
alien craft? Well Ross yes I have. How does it feel to say that? I'm kind of over it like this
has been a fact I had to get over it wasn't easy when it when it first hit you but that was years
ago and it's actually quite therapeutic to get to talk about it and I'm encouraged that it's becoming
commonplace because that's where it needs to be for us to move forward and start gathering some
evidence which we intend to do. So you're building up a cover in California shortly after 9-11 what
are you doing? Well I'm doing a number of things one trying to fill out a sensible explanation for
my backstory I mentioned one of the clubs I was in was pilot club and you'll speak to my good friend
Don Paul here shortly who I met during that time but there's no record of that so I actually
one of the first things I did is I had to go to commercial pilot school in order to create a
legitimate training record so that I could operate in an official capacity this time as a
helicopter pilot. So you'd learned how to fly as a covert operator but they didn't give you a
license for it in the military no because you weren't allowed to have that qualification
because that would undermine your cover I suppose correct so you had to go and pretend to not be a
pilot in order to get your commercial yeah that was loads of fun actually I was I found it quite
challenging to pretend I didn't know how to fly so it's amusing yeah you must have blitzed it
well pretending to be bad was quite easy in the beginning the hardest part was faking a natural
learning curve so how to show that I'm getting better in a progression that they've seen before
so that was fun a few times I took the liberty to mess with my flight instructor but he just thought
I got got lucky so this happened for what a couple of years yeah a number of things were done so
one of the rules we go by is that legitimacy is the best cover so in order to provide a certain
utility to the government by way of a contractor I have to go and establish a lot of legitimate
businesses I have to function in a legitimate way under existing contracts to build a cover a cover
is not a hollow shell it has to be layers deep and the best way to have many layers of cover
is to just go do something genuine to begin with so let's be clear about this you're a very
financially successful businessman in your own right you've done well in business yes you are
not being paid by us or anyone to do this interview no no in fact you're deriving no
financial benefit or in kind benefit at all from doing this interview no why are you speaking to
us today well because I've got some good news okay so I know everyone's been waiting for people
like me to speak out and we haven't been doing nothing the past several years there's been a
lot going on and I'm very pleased to share that we are moving forward in an official and transparent
capacity to explore the answer to these questions that there appears to be no evidence for and our
number one goal now is to function in a private capacity with the backing of venture capitalists
and in coordination with some of the most key departments in the government in order to start
answering these questions in a transparent way related to the UAP topic are you a front
am I a front yeah I mean you've worked obviously in counterintelligence
you're a trained intelligence operative is this some kind of disinformation proper
propaganda operation no and I'm going to say no and I'm going to tell you I'm not lying to you
but unfortunately there's no way that I can convince you of that if if that's what you're
thinking a lot of people watching this will be thinking oh you can never trust a spook
you know there's obviously wheels within wheels this is part of some official government disclosure
operation yeah is it no it's not and again I'm not going to be able to make you believe that
but what I can invite you to do is I'll paraphrase the book of Matthew you will know us by our fruits
so I'd like to invite you to stay tuned in and watch what our new project is about to do and
prepare to be dazzled so you're proposing you're part of a team that is proposing
to do private retrievals of alien technology yes yes and you've got the backing for it
yes wow so let's talk about now what you do know okay when you finally secured your pilots training
in the commercial world what happened while I was getting my pilots training I was also working
to set up a number of businesses in order to pursue government contracts for from the doi
the dod and all their all the organizations and departments within those and mostly what we did
a lot like in the 90s you know the cover capacity takes up the the most most of your time is spent
operating in the cover capacity so you were working in legitimate businesses
earning a living like everybody else like everyone else you're just waiting for the call
waiting for the call the you know the incidental benefits of the the capabilities of the companies
you set up are those benefits that are on standby to be deployed in the subject matter of uaps
so you've set up all those legitimate businesses when did you get the call so as an helicopter
operator we provide a number of services to a number of departments within the military
industrial complex and that includes the department of the interior as well as the doi
the department of the interior has a number of other departments within it and we worked
mostly in those for our conus or within the continental united states those operations
include things like firefighting long haul short haul which is our external loads for helicopters
working for the bia bureau of indian affairs anything you could do to provide utility
anything that you could do with the utility of a helicopter we were put to task on now at this
stage there was no indication of any anomalous phenomena at all no when did you first start
becoming aware of strange objects in the sky during your work well a lot of the work we did
on was on what i call the range and the range is a particular geographical area where
the u.s government and its private partners use to test all kinds of things
weapon systems and resilience to weapon systems of certain craft and so you see a lot of exciting
things and i have to remind you that my particular role is very basic security and
transportation it gets a little broad as you drill down but i'm a security and transportation
expert and that's the service we provided broadly provided to the to the government and its partners
so you start seeing at the range yes interesting objects well yeah it's always interesting out
there you know my it was a process for me getting to the point until we had our first
experience with something that was obviously non-human in origin but up until that time
there's lots of interesting things in the sky i can tell you that our technology and by our i
mean anything that lies within the inventory of the united states government its private partners
is pretty spectacular there are some cool things and from an observer's standpoint on the ground
it's it's hard to tell exactly what's going on things come in and out of sight things disappear
for a moment and reappear things to seem things seem to move very quickly things change color they
change shape and a good reference for this is i'm sure we've all seen these drone shows like they
could put on at the super bowl halftime or other places and those are pretty amazing to see visually
amazing but we all know that's human tech and we accept it but if you kind of think about that and
think about perhaps what we might be doing privately in the interest of national security
your imagination could fill in the blanks on what you might see on a test range that's being used
by the u.s government its partners i mean i guess we all expect that this technology that we don't
know about that's being kept confidential for very good reasons because the united states doesn't
want foreign adversaries to know that it has an aerospace advantage or a weapons advantage over
a potential rival and were you telling yourself that for a long time when you started seeing
anomalous objects on the range yeah because just like it is now you kind of have to train yourself
even once you become a believer in the uap subject and you take some folks outside who
are believers and they look up they get really excited and falsely identify a satellite as a uap
or something else in the sky an airplane that has you might not be able to see its
position lights or its strobe so you know what lou elizondo has described as the five observables
instantaneous speed incredible hypersonic speeds transmedium travel water to air air to water
positive lift some kind of propulsion system that isn't explained by conventional systems
and stealth so you were seeing objects that complied with those weird observables yes
um and at that time you would also see things when you talk about the uh i'm sorry the trans
transmedium so um one of those that that would raise your eyebrows more of the transmedium
characteristics because things would come from the ground like from the earth from a ridge from a
mountain or it could pass through so they'd come out of the ridge out of a ridge yeah now that is
clearly technology that is certainly not known now again that is the that is the visual understanding
of what what you're seeing and was that human technology you just don't know i just don't know
yeah that i do not so there came a time though where you began to realize that this was something
else well let me let me add to we also know of circumstances and you'll speak to some of my
teammates here where we did recover things that were that were exotic in nature in the sky and
we know they were classified craft and we recovered them and took them back to where they go and that
was a that was a regular thing so there are things that we're trying to protect that are far beyond
what we know about publicly yeah much like everything in my story that we're talking about
80 to 90 percent of the time it's very ordinary and boring once you get acclimated to the to
the lifestyle it's but for a five or ten percent that is the most outrageous and exciting time
of your life but the majority of what we see and do is explainable and is ordinary and is known
by many people and is not not classified but there is a certain percentage which is extremely
sensitive and that extremely sensitive bit does include what we know is our own man-made advanced
technology and we we work we work to our our recovery efforts if this is where we're going
with the conversation when we look at a recovery mission or a crash recovery team you don't put
together a team like that with the intent of recovering non-human craft that that team is
trained and provided the training and tools and technology to conduct a recovery mission
for a number of objects and craft but in the rare occasion or let's say the hypothetical occasion
something of a non-human origin or source were to interface with the ground you would deploy that
same team and that is the segue and how we got involved with this particular subject so tell me
about the moment when you realized that you were involved in a retrieval of non-human technology
alien tech so it became very clear the first time we recovered something that was non-human
in origin that it was precisely what we were dealing with our communications changed our
communication process and procedure was modified it was also clear to everyone on the team that
what we were dealing with was something that was unexpected versus expected and then just visually
looking at the object on the ground you could tell that it was extraordinary and anomalous it
was it was not human how close did you get well i was a helicopter pilot and i operate with a 150
foot to 200 foot long line so i got within 150 feet of this object what did you see i saw an egg
a white egg how large was the object i would say approximately 20 feet plus or minus a little bit
about the size of a large suv did it have any seams no what and it was pure pure white it was
like pearly white like a metallic pearly white the best i could i could assess i mean what you're
describing sounds something like something out of a tv show yeah well fortune i'm going to share
some images with you and you can see one of these flying in the sky if you like in broad daylight
so you actually saw it in the sky before no not this one but in our new venture we've already
begun work and we're capturing since the data of the exact same craft flying in the sky how did you
know that that egg-shaped object was non-human in origin well visually after seeing all kinds of
things in my past it was clearly something that was ridiculously looking it's inconsistent with
anything i'd ever seen before i can also tell you that the reaction by my team who was very
experienced was was not was atypical we changed our our we modified our entire process for recovery
that night our communication process changed we all knew we were dealing with something
extraordinary and in addition to that it has also been verified by me by high ranking members of
the uip uap task force that what we recovered that night was in fact known in hi craft so the
implications of that are actually quite shocking it it means the government's lying to us which
shouldn't come as any surprise to us but we're being lied to i don't i can't comment on that
because i don't know what the government knows this this operation yeah i just can't comment
to that because uh do you think it's possible that there are even senior people in the pentagon
who aren't aware of what you know absolutely there are senior people in all branches of
government that are unaware what's going on at the bottom so when general air force general pat
rider speaks at a press briefing in the pentagon and says there is no evidence of extraterrestrial
visitation or engagement with planet earth he might actually be telling the truth because he
hasn't been read in like you correct now you have what's called i understand a top secret
sci clearance you have compartmented intelligence clearance to certain programs my clearance is
given like on as a as like an as needed basis so like when i go it's not like i go there's no
record of me having top secret clearance anywhere but i get well there is because in the documents
that you've showed us there is one document that shows a nato top secret clearance and what does
that mean uh that means you are cleared to the highest level that you that you need to be in
order to function in the capacity that you've been assigned on a particular mission and it's
quite a high clearance it's very high clearance and so the best effort was done to secure your
cover and as part of protecting that cover it wasn't allowed to be known that you had high
clearances but what you have been able to demonstrate to us is that you were in fact
given high clearances as part of your role yeah the clearances kind of accompanied me like a
shadow if i got deployed on a particular mission let's use an aircraft an hvt mission for example
high value target high value target i spent a lot of time in the 90s living out of a hotel room at
pope air force base with a pager that that was our technology back then so i'll give you a short
story that'll tie this together so a typical situation for me would be told to go stay at
the lodging on base and i could travel to the chow hall i could travel to the gym but i had
to stay within that response area we would have a sealed aircraft a sealed aircraft is an aircraft
that has been configured and swept and then a metal seal goes on the door to where if that
door is open or broken we know someone has entered that aircraft in an unauthorized capacity so
we'd have a sealed aircraft there if we got dispatched i would go to an aircraft there
would be manifests that go with that aircraft that would list all the crew members their security
clearances and a rough description as to the mission at those times we would the crew would
be briefed security clearances would be issued to that crew and anytime i was on a hvt mission that
was highly sensitive i would operate under what is known as a nato top secret security clearance
and there are documents a few documents that i was able to make copies of that show that and indeed
the document that you've showed us shows very clearly that you and the pilot were the only
people on board the plane that had a nato top secret clearance yeah probably the reason he
was assigned is because i was there so not to sound arrogant but the fact that i was being
deployed on that mission meant that the aircraft commander also needed to be read into a certain
degree which would require that clearance it's part of the reason why they keep your clearances
secret in that covert role so that they have plausible deniability if you ever did decide
to speak publicly yeah here's the funny thing like the u.s government can make a bunch of rules
in order to create a scaffolding that keeps things intact but they make a bunch of rules so
that they can break them and hack the system and get around them it provides great obscurity to
create the rules that separate the known from the unknown and i want to add one comment here is
when we're talking about circumstances like the first time we recovered a uap which was the flying
egg that immediately regardless of where you were or what level of security you're operating under
at the time when that shows up you're instantly now in a top secret classified situation
regardless of people's clearance so before you flew out that day to go and do the recovery of
the egg yeah what were you told i was told that we were going out to do our normal thing we're
going to provide range security and we transport crew and we're doing our normal range work you
weren't told that this was an anomalous craft that was clearly of non-human origin and i genuinely
believe no one else knew this was going to happen either i think it was a shock to everyone
and at no stage were you ever subsequently told that the craft was of non-human origin no so how
do you know it wasn't human how do you know that we don't have top secret tech that is shaped like
an egg right well i'll tell you that because of the reaction of my leadership structure and because
of my experience working in that capacity everyone involved was convinced that what
we were seeing and dealing with was in fact exotic in its origin i will also tell you that
during this process over the last couple years it's been confirmed to me by ranking members of
the uap task force that what we were working with that night was in fact an hi and it was not a
unique experience the egg as we're referring to is known by and there have been many others that
have encountered this type of craft in our atmosphere outside of our atmosphere broad day
night time all over the place you got a good look at this object didn't you yeah was there any
visible propulsion system on it no not what we would know there's no engine there was no thermal
signature i was operating at night when i finally came in to pick it up so i'm working under
night vision goggles at the time and it was quite clear i flipped them up flipped them down and
looked at it a couple of different ways was there a thermal signature there was not a thermal
signature it wasn't hot no no you know general laws of thermodynamics you know if an object's
been flying or driving an engine it's going to show heat isn't it yeah yes yeah so how do you
think that object was being propelled well that's a great question that we're looking forward to
exploring with our new venture so when you went back to base was it the sort of job where you
could go to your bosses and say hey listen what was that object that i picked up that strange
looking egg thing no that's not quite how it works when i go back to what you would call my base when
i go back to our facility that's back to my my normal working business and the people that
are involved there have really no idea what's going on when i'm holding myself out for work
for the government so this is this is how the compartmentalization system works it's a need to
know there was no need for the people that were you were working with to know so they weren't
briefed in yes and you only found out incidentally because you saw it on the range right so let's
keep on going that's twigged your interest for the first time you've seen something that does appear
genuinely anomalous when was the next occasion when you became aware of anomalous non-human
technology there's another craft that we recovered that i'm i can talk about and that craft was what
we referred to as an 8-gon an 8-gon is basically a disc shaped object that when viewed from the top
has eight different symmetrical sections that are delineated by some form of ridge so it's an octagon
shaped disc yes what by by any chance was there a name a nickname for the egg yeah the egg we
actually called nanus like from the morgue and mindy show from the 70s because it's ridiculous
that's exactly what it looked like and so it's funny when you look back at the what may have
been the motivation for the 1970s because what where else would that egg is a ridiculous idea
for a guy from mort from orc right so you have mort from orc who flew to earth in an egg
it surely gives credit to the idea that some like to think that perhaps there was a pr program
that utilized our fascination with hollywood and television to paint pictures of actual fact as
fiction making it now some weird hybrid you could call faction so what time of day or night was it
when you came across the octagonal object the 8-gon we did recovery on that both day and night
so talk me through it what happens
you're in your chopper yeah i'm in my i'm in my chopper what sort of chopper
at the time is a bell 212 which is the same as a uh uh uh in one it's a twin engine twin bladed
bell helicopter you're flying at night flying at night yeah what time at night oh god i don't
remember like after midnight have you been given any pre-flight briefing
i would i'm the one who would be given the briefing but we are given a loadout on the
particular uh object that when you're flying an external load um we designate two different
sites one's called the drop site one's called the pick site you could say the pick site is where
the payload is that you're flying in to pick up um as you're making your first trip into the pick
site the payloads are already rigged and manifested for you and to prepare them for flight
when you're in route to that object uh you're given some basic information like weight estimates
size estimates and there's two objects that i'm here to talk about one was the egg the other is
what we called an 8-gon the 8-gon was a uh essentially a flying disc with what looked
like eight uh delineated sections when looking down and i can tell you what it looked like
from looking down because that's primarily how i saw it because i'm a helicopter pilot
we did recoveries with the eight gons there was more than one that was that made its way to the
ground on this particular operation and the recovery was done at night and then more was
done in the day because of where we operate sometimes things can make their way into the
terrain the terrain where we operate is the highest mountain range in the whole
united's continental united states and so the decision was made to wait till daylight
to recover some of the object or some of the material that was brought down or made its way
to the ground that night during the recovery of the object at night time i make my way in the
helicopter from where we configure the line and we fly to where what we call the pick site there's
two locations we designate them pick site drop site drop site at the delivery location we have
a crew both at the pick site and the uh the drop site on the ground the the pick team configures
the cargo for flight so whatever it is the craft is sitting in a sling waiting for your helicopter
yeah it's saying we have this these things called pumpkins which are like rubberized bags or
containers and from my point of view that it was covered in a pumpkin at least from the bottom
and the sides this is one of the most profound experiences i've ever had in my life i'm about
to share with you so bear with me um this is for me when it became clear as i get closer to this
pick site i start feeling odd i start feeling extremely emotional
and the closer i get the more the emotion starts to overwhelm me and
what do you feel what's the emotion i feel
i feel
a sense of my mother i don't know how else to explain it i feel
this intense hybrid of sadness and happiness and beauty um and song and it was very disruptive
to me because i had a very practical responsibility at the time to operate a helicopter in the
night and i began wondering what was wrong with me it was late am i am i just stressed am i tired
am i marinating in a in in cortisol and estrogen i don't know um but as i came over this object
for the pick there was this overwhelming sense of emotion what's it saying the object
tell me what you're feeling
like i said it was an overwhelming sense of sadness happiness is it your feeling are you
suddenly having a mental breakdown on the job no i felt like something connected with me
connected with me i felt like something had tuned in to me and my soul and was
providing me some sense of guidance on what to do and how profound what i was doing was
um and it was so overwhelming that i began to cry and uh i can't imagine crying at night time with
night vision goggles is the healthiest way to fly a chopper no it is not and then i'm confused as
to why i'm crying at the same time and then i'm do i abort the mission do i and so i just did my
best to focus on my particular cues when doing this type of work and i got the load hooked up
and i began flying away and once it was just me and that object in between the pick and the drop
side there's about 20 miles in between i felt like something was inside of me i felt like i
was possessed by the most beautiful spirit i've ever been possessed by and was it loving it was
loving um but there was a sense of sadness at the same time and um
had you ever had an experience like this before no no it was a very feminine energy i'll tell you
that i it felt like felt like the spirit of god but not in any masculine sense that i had ever
felt it was like again the feeling of my mother um and
my daughter and beauty uh and it wasn't like a soul it was like a frequency that i was
connected with was it scared i don't know if it is a thing i'm still trying to figure out
why that happened i well i don't want to say that because i have a pretty good idea of what's going
on now and whatever that force was since that night it has stayed with me and as crazy as this
sounds it's what's guiding me now and it's what's providing protection for me it's changed your life
it's changed my life do you think it's made you a better person that experience it has made me a
more sensitive and aware person which i think all of us would be better people
so that was a moment when you became aware of at the very least a technology that had the
capacity to touch you remotely remotely telepathically telepathically now telepathy we are told
is a nonsense it's a fiction and what happened after you flew the object in the sling to presumably
the drop-off zone once i made the drop uh before i got there i was really scared that i was going
to have to stop flying and punch this thing off uh because i was so distracted but then i was like
well crap now we've got another recovery site now we're going to have to recover this i'm going to
have to burn chile and i don't know so it took everything i had in me at the time to get to my
drop site and i delivered this oddly enough no one in my crew reported having similar effects
from this i do not believe there was a being in that craft i've come to understand now after being
involved with other parts of the programs that are tested on the range that there is a there is
a known and researched and implemented emotional or psychic or what we call a psionic component
to the research and development of the uap program now jack i know it's going to be very
confronting for our audience to hear this but you think that you've discovered something
potentially about yourself as a result of that experience that you might in fact have abilities
that you were never aware of i know when i in my childhood if we look back to when i was a kid
i i sincerely believe that the screening i went through in high school um you know my grandparents
are when i was a kid i there's the reason i joined the military is real simple i wanted to
jump out of airplanes and kill bad guys and make my my grandparents proud and my grandparents were
the most amazing people i've ever met you know they grew up during the great depression dealt
with world war ii and my grandfathers particularly were the strongest and the most sensitive men
i've ever met all wrapped up in into one person we can call them navy grandpa and army grandpa
let's say so you know navy grandpa was a very influential naval officer who's actually a member
of the seals predecessors the scouts and raiders army grandpa was a was an army captain and a
salesman they both founded our neighborhood church and literally set the cornerstone to our church
together unfortunately you know their children my parents were very loving people but made a
lot of bad decisions and this led to step families for me at a very young age and to get away from
the abusive environment i spent a lot of time outside i would tell my my mom i'm going to my
dad's house i'd tell my dad i'm going to my mom's house and i would i'd bug out and just go live
outside you were living in the bush somewhere yeah essentially i was homeless but you know i
just told myself i was a a wild commando survivalist and uh that gave me pride in what i was doing
instead of shame um and so that i ref i refined a pretty in um a pretty high level of independence
at a young age but my grandparents were still always there um making sure i had some outlet
for certain things and so they got me involved with uh an art program and a music program
i'll have to tell you so my navy grandfather he uh he was the superintendent he got his
doctorate in education and by the time i had graduated high school he had retired as a
superintendent of our school district so he was a very influential man and i understand he ran
the gifted and talented education program for that school district yeah you could say he was
the ambassador for this area for the gait program which was a program for gifted and talented kids
and my personal experience with that was was great it was uh i just got pulled out of normal class
a couple of times a day at least twice and got to go to a private classroom where
i had one-on-one time with um a staff member there who played a lot of games with me inside
and outside and we ran a number of creative classes together and outside of that i also
after school i would attend i had a private art teacher i learned music um and so i felt
like i had a unique education experience as a kid my grandfather also got me involved in water
polo and swimming he was a diver and a swimmer um and water polo became a great outlet for me i
found the um the competition and the physical exhaustion was like great medicine for me looking
back though now do you think there might have been something special about your selection into the
gait program well if we we look into my high school years you know unfortunately my senior
year i i got a lot of trouble when i did show up to school i was a bit disruptive in class i had
a smart mouth i liked being a class clown um and i got a lot of fights and by the time my senior
year came around i was the varsity goalie on our water polo team and five weeks into my senior year
i got expelled for fighting again and on at that time i was on a disciplinary contract so
my accumulation of bad behavior throughout high school resulted in a contract which was interesting
and it was a one and done fail situation and five weeks into my senior year i was expelled
at this time my my grandparents decided to hold an intervention and i don't even think my parents
or step parents know but the two men got together and met with me and
decided to research military programs that would be available at that time and so we made several
trips down to uh ucla to an office near there and i began going through a series of tests
of all kinds there were physical physiological psychological creative tests
and we assumed that you know all of this was pretty typical you know now don't you that the
u.s air force has been secretly testing people through the gait program for certain psychic
abilities yes were you tested yes do you think that might have played a part in what happened
to you that night when you were recovering that craft yeah and i don't know that the air force
realized that i'll tell you i know others that i've come to meet through the program that we'll talk
about that we're in a psionic program that have a very similar backstory but for whatever reason
i was not used in that way again my creativity and intuition resulted in as i've shared with
you before being used for creative war games being very creative in war games but
what i used as intuition if we make a spectrum and we put intuition on the conservative side
let's say the right side of the scale on the more far outside that might be something that
looks a lot like telepathy or telekinesis and we call this psionics which we can talk about
and so i knew i was intuitive i knew i was creative and i also know i had good imagination and so
looking back it was clear that becoming a red team expert those are the tools that i would deploy
my intuition and creativity is what made me successful in that capacity i'm quite
struck by how many very senior elite soldiers special operations soldiers when they admit
what they do in a combat situation where they're facing imminent harm there's often a moment where
they talk about intuition yeah precognition they knew something was about to happen does it happen
to you yeah i would i would say that i have a keen ability to make good decisions short term
and long term i also find comfort in chaos you could say and i actually see things more clearly
in chaos and tend to make very wise decisions and is that a quality that you recognize in a
lot of your colleagues in special operations yeah you might be interested to know that people
at an elite operator level there's a lot of them that are left-handed a lot of them that were
artists as kids or still are very good drawers illustrators musicians they're also if you were
to describe their personalities you might have you might find yourself using some some oxymorons like
peaceful warriors sensitive savages you could say that's a real thing and i'll add one more
we're a bunch of dead serious goofballs so there's this this dichotomy between feminine
and masculine at the extremes that i don't know if you could go as far as to say is the big blue
air force and the big black department of defense knows what they're doing and they're prospecting
for these kids at a level and they're planning this long-term well-thought-out path but what you
will find is that we end up making our way there something made you connect with that machine that
night yes i it chose to connect with me and reportedly no one else on my crew so when you
got back to base did you report the fact that you'd had that extraordinary no no why not
i was because i didn't know what happened and i don't want you know you carry a lot of responsibility
as a pilot you know in this process i've moved from being a very pragmatic person with a
tremendous amount of responsibility in day-to-day grind in this dimension to a place where i've had
to take into account and incorporate things that are basically metaphysical and find a balance
between the two all while maintaining the trust that i could do my very pragmatic work so the this
was something pretty new to me this night the last thing i'm going to do is go back and tell my team
that i almost had to pop the load off because i was connected with a goddess that was making me cry
so you've had those two anomalous incidents with craft yeah clearly
these are objects that are being recovered that do not appear to be human technology
so this is a good thing to talk about because what we're dealing with is either non-human
intelligence if we want to use those words or that phrase or that acronym it's either that or we need
to dramatically redefine what we think human intelligence is because this object whatever
it was was capable of communicating with you in your mind that object or whatever was controlling
that object was also connecting to me through the mind through my mind now you learned
didn't you that this was the tip of an iceberg it wasn't just you correct what did you learn
well my work coincidentally shortly after that led me in support of another particular part
of the program which deals directly with looking at this piece right here which is
is there a component on the summoning side that we call and the operation side of
these non-human craft that has to do with consciousness or at least a field of consciousness
that perhaps humans can tap into and maybe all beings in the universe can can tap into
what is a psionic a psionic person is someone with the predisposition for
extral temporal you could say abilities and sensitivities someone who is
is has a fantastic intuition what did you discover with the psionics were being used for
in the program in the program there was certainly a desire to explore the idea
that perhaps uap could be summoned could be communicated with could be controlled
and could be persuaded to land all by deploying people with psionic abilities to interface
and communicate with the uap and did you see that happen yes i did so there were people who were
purportedly psionically gifted who were brought into the program yes there were where did they
come from they come from all over they're not and all over i mean from outside the united
states as well as in and how are they detected how are they picked uh you know i don't really
know you'd have to ask somebody else i'm told that there are particular indigenous communities
around the world native americans people in different third world countries who apparently
have enhanced psychic abilities that are really sure i think um i think most people could grasp
the idea that perhaps people that are from other cultures you know our our culture has
uh leaves a lot to be desired when we look at the contaminants that exist in our food
contaminants that exist in our drugs and contaminants in our culture some of these contaminants
it turns out aren't great for your spirituality or your consciousness or
your psionic abilities and so those who live a particular lifestyle or live in a culture
where they have a more natural or direct way of life with nature and their surroundings
seem to um that within those groups of people there's a little bit higher demographic than
there typically is for those with a psionic ability so these people are sought out and are
are used to contribute to the research that that might be going on with with the psionic i want
to put something to you i've spoken myself you haven't told me this but i've spoken myself to
people of native american background indigenous americans who say that this is a particularly
popular thing for recruitment from the program to happen in indigenous american communities yes i
know that for a fact there are also people from countries in the third world where these abilities
are recognized and not treated with stigma as we do in the western world yeah there is no stigma
in fact if there's any stigma if you're the one who's not playing along you might be the outcast
in those cultures so the irony is that part of your discovery inside the program is that there
genuinely are people who can actually make a mental spiritual connection to a technology
yes 100 percent was that a revelation to you it was fun it was actually fun to learn uh it's one
of the things in our work that was like oh my gosh there's more to life it answered certain
questions and intuitions if you will that we have going back to your childhood and if anything that
were most present in your childhood which is very satisfying because um you know something as a child
you have this this particular feeling and it kind of dies out as you become more mature and have to
take on more responsibility and so to be able to uh nurture that and accept that that might be the
case and to see organizations as serious as those who we worked with um taking this seriously was
actually a heck of a lot of fun see this is an ontological shock i think for many people watching
this because we're all being told firstly there's no such thing as aliens visiting this planet yeah
and secondly we're all being told there's no such thing as telepathy or psychic abilities it's
rubbish yeah you know i don't think there is going to be an ontological shock i think people are
going to react to it the same way i did i think it's going to be an ontological relief because
i think everyone deep down knows that that there is more to life than what we are being told and
experiencing and to know that there might be something like a sixth seventh eighth sense
that has a spiritual spiritual connection and that that might actually have a good
nature and application behind it like not only is it not shocking but it should be welcomed i would
think well i'd go further jake it's beautiful it's beautiful and isn't that the message you
got from whatever that was overwhelming sense of beauty overwhelming and love and love and it's
funny hearing an elite soldier talking about love yeah and benevolence you know what fuels every
elite soldier is a preservation of love or something that they love that's what's behind
all the strength so let's go through the psionic program when a psionic operator engages with
technology how do they do it using their mind something like meditation and i need to preface
this by saying this is stuff that i've come to know recently the night that i had this experience
there was another team involved come to find out was a psionics team and they were also working
that night and do you think it was them that had attracted the object in the first place
yeah i do and so how did the object come to land um i think it was invited to land
by the psionics team is that always how they make the objects land no there's a number of other ways
so i have to tell you that you know weapon systems are tested out there i know this from other
sources i know that high pulse microwave weapons are being used to bring down some of these craft
yes now how often was it done where the objects would land on their own accord and how often was
it done that weapons would be used yeah i can't tell you how often i could tell you they are
brought down both ways that they are invited to land by the psionics team other times they are
invited in by the psionics team but then um hpms which are high powered microwave weapons
are deployed and they have an effect where they can disrupt the uh the flight pattern of the object
and when it is an object sometimes it's not and it can result in that aircraft being forcibly brought
down when they did the attraction of the objects was it purely psychic or was the machinery that
was used as well so we there's five components to our operation which might answer a lot of
your questions so the first component is a calling phase calling is either through man or machine
based summoning systems we have man-based systems which are our psionic assets which make a psych
a connection through intuition or consciousness with the object and can invite it in the other
is a machine based calling system which uses um many systems which i'm not going to go into detail
about you could refer to them as a dog whistle or a lure and uap certain types seem to be
specifically attracted or responsive to our machine based calling systems and then from there once
they're brought in we communicate with them now the psionics can have a dual role because in this
communication phase we do a lot of data collection so it's verifying that what we are seeing is
something tangible also that it is responding to our efforts so we might invite it to move
left or right or to position our particular mean base machine based systems in a particular
direction and then measure the response the implication of what you're saying is that
this intelligence that's behind these objects whatever it is seems willing to share yeah
yeah i think it ultimately is working for us and um it is it is commonly talked about that what
we are getting even when we weaponize it is a donation a gift and even when we deploy equipment
when when there's a combined operation where the psionics team and a machine based team all the
equipment kind of has to be blessed and brought in when it's a psionically led operation for
summoning a lot of people watching this jake are going i'm sure this is crazy this guy's making
this up this can't possibly be true alien vehicles psychic techniques to engage with technology
this is disinformation fabrication yeah well we intend to prove that's not the case which has a
lot to do with the timing as to why i'm coming out now we plan to produce that evidence in our
new venture with our teams that we've used for years in the legacy program we've now gotten out
we've pulled our resources and we're backed by venture capital we're also working in coordination
with the most forefront government agencies that you would want involved with us on this subject
matter and we're going to start producing evidence on all of this and we're going to share it with
but Krishna you you know it works because you've seen it done yes yeah and so have your colleagues
that's correct what would you say to people who might say there's no way a secret like this could
have been kept for so long i mean you're describing an operation that in your experience has been
going for at least 10 20 years yeah yeah do you know how long the program's been doing the
psionics i would say i'm sorry did over it i don't know what else to tell you
so it can be kept a secret can be kept oh yeah secrets uh there are lots of secrets
some kept for good reasons so let me briefly summarize the implications of what you're saying
aliens are real so i would like to know unfortunately we got to get really specific
with the semantics okay so what do you mean by alien something non-human and intelligent built
craft that you have been involved in recovery yes something that is inconsistent with our idea of
what a human is uh is involved with these craft are these intelligences whatever they are are they
extra terrestrial are they from somewhere else or could they possibly be living on this planet
i gotta remind you i'm a security and transportation guy that has been involved in this program
really within the purview of those two categories so you're gonna have to ask someone else i
presume you got a chance to talk to the psionics yeah when they mentally telepathically engaged
with whatever this intelligence was what did they tell you about it well that uh they refer to it
as a they in a very spiritual nature something like angels uh angels and demons uh let's say
there's certainly good energies and bad energies but it's talked of in a very um in a very nebulous
way like this because no one really knows what it is no one especially on the psionic side we're
still trying to figure that out we're still trying to figure out exactly what it is and there's
probably a number of things going on there might be biological entities and we use the word
biological for a very specific reason biological we don't need we we limit it to that because we
aren't here to imply that it is sentient or has a consciousness we really don't know that
there is some evidence that that shows it might be the case that these are something like soft
tissue drones or lab meat that was programmed in order to operate craft meat robots meat robots
yeah okay so it really begs the question but ironically while some of the biological
cargo that comes with these craft is not conscious consciousness itself is how you
interact and pilot the craft which is ironic because for the first time ever the biological
creatures inside are not conscious but the craft is the other implication too from what your
experience shows is that whatever and wherever the intelligence is that's behind those craft
it seems friendly benevolent benevolent yeah in fact loving loving it's if you want to connect
with it if you want to have a relationship and if you want to see stuff flying in the sky
you need to be channeling a loving energy that's just the way it works beautiful yeah it is
in fact there can be individuals in the group that throw off that vibe that can mess up the vibration
of the psionics work and their communication with the beings and then you aren't as successful
have you in any of the work that you've done and i know you're being very limited in what
incidents you're prepared to talk about have you ever come across malevolent intelligence that's
non-human i have not i personally have not have any of your colleagues you'll have to ask them okay
okay the implications though of what you're telling us
are incredible we are not alone we are not alone there is a non-human intelligence that has been
engaging with this planet yes to your knowledge is it just the united states that is having these
encounters no no i can tell you for a fact that my team has been sought after for our unique
service that we provide by organizations outside the united states but let's to be clear i don't
want to put you in the position of imputing that you might have been helping unfriendly countries
neither of the countries or none of the countries that you worked with foreign adversaries no not
and when i say that i use the word organizations instead of governments because there are there are
there are many other folks that may be operating in a private capacity that so let me let me say
this this situation is not unique to the u.s. to your knowledge are russia and china doing
retrievals of non-human i have no idea i imagine they are why would you say that well because
uh this particular activity is not unique to the united states i know for a fact that
members of my team have been asked to provide our expertise and service
for organizations outside the u.s. not china and russia but um you know the u.s. government
does not have a monopoly on the uap subject matter i mean the skies are not classified
your conscience can't be redacted so i the nhi can connect with whoever the hell they want and
whoever the hell they are can connect with nhi and this lends itself to a particular situation
or formula that you can imagine exists which is if you have a belief that this is a worthwhile
venture which ironically the government has made extremely clear like there are many people myself
and our new organization included that is not waiting on the government to say this is something
you should invest time and energy on and that's become abundantly clear in the last two years
but prior to that anyone that had the will to believe that and the money to invest and the
tools and techniques and talent in order to do it could set up their own communication crash
recovery and reverse engineering problem program anywhere in the world the nhi is not hold itself
out exclusively for the united states why has this been kept secret from all of us oh god i don't
know i really don't know um i imagine you know i have to trust that be careful what you wish for
there might be very good reasons i imagine that um some of what we see i know that some of what we
see is our own advanced tech um and it's absolutely imperative that we keep a competitive advantage
over our adversaries as a patriot that's paramount we need to be able to defend ourselves
and unfortunately you can't tell the public things without telling your adversaries so therefore the
public for their own good is going to be kept um they're going to be kept out of the know on
certain subjects and so there's this there's this difference between secrecy and privacy
and i will lay this out because we need to be able to flip back and forth between the two
privacy is something that protects responsibilities and the dignity of whoever
needs that privacy secrecy is something that typically hides vices uh
amoral intentions and crimes let's say i know for the most part that what we're dealing with when
it comes to our government the subject matter is a matter of privacy not secrecy if you want
to look at it that way somebody you discovered was recording these operations in secret there are
videos of these operations that were captured illegally during these operations that are out
there you became aware didn't you while you were doing these retrieval operations that there was
concern from a private aerospace company that certain computers had gone missing
yes and those computers were panasonic toughbooks correct five panasonic toughbook six six
six what happened well um we were deployed on a particular task to recover what we call hvt's or
high value targets those high value targets were panasonic toughbooks um and whatever was on these
toughbooks was highly sensitive material and this this came about i have to tell you after 2018
um it is quite possible i will say that the sensitive material that is on these panasonic
toughbooks uh has to do with sensor data video um that was illegally captured during some of
these operations some of which may be incriminating or classified now i can understand a lot of people
may watching this may be indignant but there are good reasons why some things are classified
in the u.s military absolutely so you were tasked to get these laptops back yes because the concern
was they could break the secrecy of the whole program um i can't speak to what the implications
were of this sensitive information getting out you know my job is pretty simple i get tasked on
something i get given a pretty narrow scope you know and after doing this for 20 years that's
enough for me because everything that i've done up until now is i've been very well taken care
of and everything i trust the process by which we operate so uh i'm only pre pre-loading it that
way because that wasn't the case by the end of this operation for the first time in my career
by the end of this operation we began asking questions we've never asked which is who are
we working for what is going on and why did it turn out to be that there were two
seemingly adversarial parties trying to employ us to go after these hvt's so what happened so
my team and i worked in coordination with our contact for this particular task there was
obviously another team involved which is an intelligence team most of our intelligence
came by way of human which is human intelligence which is essentially the reporting of information
by a human by their own observation and experience and uh we recovered our first two uh tough books
they were um they were in the high sierras i'll tell you that and uh we had first deployed began
recon on that on that particular target for the first two in the winter time and there was tons
of snow so we continued to just observe that location in order to keep tabs on who might be
coming and going it's very remote there's no way there the only way to get there would be by foot
or horse or helicopter so um we did a couple snow surveys and at the time the snow was over nine
feet so we had waited to for the fall before we would deploy to get these first two are you and
your men armed yeah we're always armed yeah because whoever this was is potentially very
dangerous i'm armed when i go to starbucks so that's not saying much but we were armed yeah
so what happened so we recovered our first two tough books um we got back to our our base location
and then went through them and took photographs discovered that the hard drives were missing which
is something we expected could be the case we then took pictures and detailed reports of the
tough books and the and the contents of the the casing that we found them in and we delivered them
to um a very familiar facility which is consistent with the company we are working for and then we
went back to task and waited for more instructions on um on where to look next for the missing
components of these computers as well as the other tough books that were thought to have been out
there um the next piece of intelligence that came through led us to uh a lake and high altitude
lake and we found um the hard drives in a sealed steel container 25 feet underwater
wow yeah so someone's going through a lot of effort in order to hide these things
but you can you can't blame them i mean this is worth a lot of money if you sell it to the right
buyer yeah depending upon what's on there it was clear that again this is this it was clear that
whatever was hidden was highly sensitive to the employer of the task we were on and to whoever
was in possession of these at the time they were being hidden yeah at any stage did you find
yourself under threat yeah so um we didn't get much past that mission we never recovered anymore
the very next time we went out things got strange um for me and my spidey senses my intuition was
on high alert because our intel contact changed the rhythm and style of our intel
changed i'll leave it at that and um when we deployed to the next location to begin our
reconnaissance and um in preparation for going to have a look around uh the intelligence became
began to change last minute also we were given a partnered air asset instead of using our own
and we took it in good faith and as we got closer to the day in which we were going to deploy
intelligence kept changing and so that that raised my concern um we ended up going anyway
and when we got there the hvt's were gone and it was clear that shots had been fired and i'm going
to leave it at that so when i got back to our home base after that i made contact with our
with our dispatcher let's say and said we're out we're done and i needed space to breathe
we then deployed our own air assets and we got the hell out of there
um you felt you were in significant danger yeah and i was concerned that we were being set up
we were being prepared for the one thing that we've always offered employers and that is
possible deniability and that we were perhaps going to be the hidden hand that gets severed
and that perhaps we were the ones who may be responsible for capturing that sensitive
material on the front end do you think that you and your team had come under suspicion for
the videos is it a simple i think that's very likely or we were a suitable patsy i do have
to put one thing to you yeah because it's an incident that i've been told about from
2004 and i've been told about it by multiple people i've been told that
a private aerospace company was testing one of its own vehicles what's referred to as an alien
reproduction vehicle an arv in the colloquialism that vehicle crashed somewhere south of new
mexico possibly in mexico and i'm told that a team from that private aerospace contractor was
deployed and while they were there another team arrived from the u.s military and they had
innocently been deployed by their government to intercept what they thought was a potentially
anomalous craft and in the course of that encounter i am told two men were killed
can you comment on that insert yeah there's nothing i can add to that story or comment on
if i did have something to add if i had knowledge of that it would certainly be something i would
expect to get squashed by dot sir and quite possibly if i was involved in something like
that i probably wouldn't share it for one of my other reasons which is maintaining the privacy
and quality of life of my friends and family it's too dangerous for you to talk about potentially
it certainly it would be yeah can you speak more broadly without referring to that particular
incident speaking broadly about the implications from the program do you believe people have been
hurt or killed as a result of attempts to protect the secrecy of this whole venture yeah it is my
understanding and belief that unfortunately that is true people have been murdered that seems to be
the case you were in a situation where what you were doing was plausibly deniable you felt under
threat you were asking who you were working for who were you working for yeah for the first time
in my career i let me start by saying that for my entire career both in the air force and as a
contractor afterwards i've been very well taken care of i was given time off to get my head right
when i needed to i was given time to take care of my family when my wife had twins
i've been very well compensated i've been trusted and everything that needed to be laid out before
me when put on certain tasks was as advertised and as promised that all changed in 2018 and i
cut ties and built had to get rid of every one of my team and built a brand new team from scratch
the same way i always had but we cleaned house and i went back and recruited through very reliable
sources the type of team members i always have from the places i always have and we set out
to try and figure out exactly who the adversarial parties were that were both interested in these
laptops and again it was obvious to us at least who the employer was but they were now in question
in my mind as being part of the problem we ran into and it became clear to me after working
in this world that perhaps it wasn't this company perhaps there was someone in mid-level management
or someone completely external that was masquerading as representatives of this
company and they liked wearing their merchandise okay so we came up with a plan and i decided
we're not going to ask questions down here we're going to go to the top so i reached out to the
director of security for the particular organization and a sister organization
and set up a meeting with them and went and spoke to them directly about our operation to find out
which was true because there was only two truths in my minds either they were complicit or they
were compromised so either their company and their chain of command was compromised meaning the top
had no idea what was going on at the bottom or they were complicit this mission that we were
asked to do was directed from the top down so the question in your mind was was this a rogue
operation what did you find what did you find out well i found out that the people at the top
claimed to know nothing about it and they didn't want to touch it with a 10-foot pole
and they advised me to leave it alone so this leads you to the possibility that this was a
rogue operation somebody was tasking you to do things dangerous things where your life had been
in danger and your team members had been in danger this is a good example for everyone watching as to
how something like this could be kept secret because you could think of me as again i'm just
a security and transportation specialist everything else i'm speaking to and that i know about
i gained just from my own knowledge and interest of being in the environment but i speak to a lot
of things that aren't necessarily my specialty i'm on the very fingertips of this thing which is part
of why you haven't heard from me before i am i operate in the shadows by design i'm the fingertips
of this thing i have firsthand accounts of working with these crafts and in these organizations
they're up here at the shoulder like our friend david grush has worked at a very high administrative
level he didn't know who i was he had to find me through the process and so there are things that
the shoulder is intending to do if we're going to use a joint analogy that ends up being facilitated
by individuals on the fingertips there's another joint in between that's the elbow this is that
mid-level something could be dramatically redesigned and repurposed at the elbow joint
to where the mission of the fingertips is not consistent with the mission of the shoulder
when you confronted the head of security for that unnamed private aerospace company what was his
reaction was he nervous oh he was nervous i mean it's quite unusual for you to go and knock on
the door of a very very senior person in such a huge organization yeah no he welcomed me and
this is something that we had we had made arrangements for right but was he perhaps
freaked out frightened when you confronted him about what you told him i know i'd like to think
i know how to make myself come across disarming and so he told you to forget it we had a lovely
talk actually it was very personable um very congenial and he shared concerns maybe he i
like i would go as far as say he had more concerns than i did and and he was at a point in his career
where he didn't want to deal with this anymore he was making changes in his career to try and think
distance himself if he had any knowledge at all it was clear he's trying to distance himself from it
he didn't want to get involved but he did provide some advice on who where we should go if you look
at the inspector general function of any organization that is certainly a place that he recommended we
go but he he uh he made it clear that there were some inspector generals that may be
a better place to go than others and is that what you did no i didn't do that why didn't you go to
the inspector general um because these are the oversight agencies that the u.s government has
set up to properly investigate these kind of abuses of power it wasn't at that point you got
to remember like i had lost all faith in everything i was starting at ground zero i even
fired my whole team and was rebuilding my own network from the ground up um so at this top of
i'm a fingertips guy so my knowledge of the shoulder i was not going to go i didn't know
who to trust so even going to an inspector general the expectation would be for me to just spill all
so um i hadn't done my homework enough to where i felt comfortable going to an inspector general
and i wasn't necessarily wasn't sure that that was going to provide me the outcome i wanted
so what did you do so the first thing i did is i began expanding the list of people whose opinion
i was going to ask and uh through that process uh i found myself reaching out to the one thing
that was always my get out of jail free card which was i knew if anything got bad i could go to
members of congress particularly the senate intelligence committee the monitor for the cia
and plead my case and ask for help so we started there and unfortunately that was a very
disheartening experience because me going there asking for their help very quickly turned in
to them asking for my help you're kidding no no um which was extremely disappointing to say the
least but they were scared they were scared and they were running into their own problems of
being in fear of they were being harassed and they were afraid for their own personal safety
so people investigating this uap legacy program for congress were feeling threatened they were
feeling threatened and other people they were speaking to as sources were being threatened
and so they very quickly after learning who i was
began asking me for personal protection um and for strategies to mitigate threat
but you're not getting the help you need no i'm like i came to you so
that pretty much was a devastating moment where i'm like shoot we're all alone
um and it was unfortunately
a much more grave situation because what it indicated was that our congress was not only
ignorant to the subject they were neutered they were neutered by what they could do about it why
how i mean it's in your constitution jake the constitution enshrines the idea that that congress
rules everything is accountable to congress congress needs an enforcement arm so laws without
enforcement don't exist so jake hearing your story about a psionic program inside the legacy uap
retrieval program makes me think back to cases like the 1980 bent waters incident where at an
raf base a royal air force base in the united kingdom christmas 1980 a craft allegedly landed
in an adjacent forest the rendlesham forest yeah what do you think happened there man that's one
of my favorite cases once i began looking into the history of this thing that's one of the ones that
stood out to me especially when you think about where we are now i i'll tell you this i if bent
waters happen tomorrow like this thing would be over with and because they couldn't conceal it
like well you couldn't conceal it but it's just everything we're looking for has already happened
like your book for example in plain sight if you just look it's it's so obvious but that one case
has everything we need and i don't know how anyone can say there's no evidence of extraterrestrial
and maybe they're hanging their hat on the that's why we have non-human intelligence maybe they're
trying to hang their hat on this one little narrow place they can slip through which is
things are not from outside the planet i don't know how they're doing that but whatever the
case what went on at bent waters has everything we need it has uh firsthand experiencers people
that have made physical contact with the craft um the most reputable people um in the air force
at that time working on a nuclear facility um osi shows up immediately of the office of special
investigation office of special investigation that's a us air force office yes people are
sworn to secrecy um people it happened on multiple occasions there's multiple uh sensor data in that
goes with the the firsthand witness what do you say the money what do you speculate brought that
craft down well i'm certainly speculating but after my experience i think uh what may have
happened in that case is it may have been a craft that was attracted to a psionic asset or was being
operated by a son if that craft was ours and it was being operated psionically um there's this
thing called link loss link losses it's it's a common phrase used with drone operation drones are
or uavs as we call them unmanned aerial vehicles um or uas they're also called that unmanned aerial
systems are operated remotely in the off chance that there's a disconnect between the operating
system or the transmitting side and the receiving side within these craft um it's called a link
loss and when that happens um our man-made systems are designed to rtb or return to base
or they can go to designated landing sites in a link loss so that same system would be deployed
because commonly what happens with a with a psionic asset who is using a form of intuition and
consciousness to connect with a craft uh there's a disconnect we call it which is like link loss
i can tell you when we run exercises using the psionic assets in an intentional environment to
get samples to the ground we intentionally disconnect the psionic asset so that the
hpm systems can be energized because there are some potential issues that can happen if the
psionic asset is still connected to the craft when it's hit with an emp or other hpm i'm told i'm
told part of their consciousness can stay in the craft yeah it seems to be the case that um
the human being um can suffer some form of cognitive injury by still being connected to
that craft when that craft is de-energized there is a case at the ref bentwaters during the ref
bentwaters incident in the united kingdom there was an airman called john burrows who was exposed
to what we now know was an extraordinary amount of gamma radiation dangerous radiation yeah and
he suffered quite terrible injuries but had a terrible time persuading veterans affairs that
he deserved medical assistance because he couldn't prove that this was an occupational exposure to
radiation well i can tell you i came to know the name john burrows because uh i've been seen by
the same doctor as him dr gary nolan for the exact same reason so what happened to you
we're not quite sure but the first time i got exposed to what in hindsight uh is obviously a
radiation exposure of some kind is uh we were transporting hvt's high value targets high value
target which are at this time was a large sealed container um i'll tell you i was in near the
continent of africa and uh after this particular mission me and everyone on my team got extremely
sick how sick like physically ill in the hospital um within you know weeks after this i lost every
hair on my body which they call a an alopecia uh migrating alopecia um and i also lost the
skin on my arms so the skin's actually falling off your body yeah like not just falling away
it was lopping off within a couple of days like a severe sunburn this led to a series of all kinds
of other what i have learned since being with dr nolan is uh autoimmune issues um i ended up
developing a severe heart murmur that i never had before which is the same thing that john burrows
had um and throughout my career i would have reoccurring uh autoimmune dysfunction when exposed
to other things i ended up recovering from that at the time and because of the nature my work was
classified the va was only dealing with symptomology not causation in the treatment of my injuries and
i didn't even really understand that it was radiation so were you treated for radiation
poisoning no i was not are you being now no i'm not being treated now for radiation poisoning
but you're being what you're being investigated for what sounds like a radiation exposure yeah
because i had other occurrences later in my career after 9 11 when i left my enlisted capacity and
went to work as a contractor i've had other episodes where um i've had other illnesses and
i've had i've lost the hair on my body and patched out several times and to me i don't know if this
my fear is that there's something permanently broken that might show up in the form of cancer
god knows what later in life and we're going to be way behind in trying to figure out how to deal
with it so i am i did leave the service with the service uh service service connected disability
through the va and so i'm i'm getting treatment through the palo alto va under the supervision
of dr gary nolan right now and he's dedicating his expertise and his clout to get me um the best
treatment i can get now professor gary nolan is one of the world's top immunologists hugely
respected scientist who has as i understand it he's spoken publicly that he's been involved
in a program for an intelligence agency investigating havana syndrome yes so does it
give you some comfort that you're now getting the medical help that you should have got all those
years ago hell yeah it does and plus he's got the best bedside manner i've ever experienced
but clearly because of the covert nature of the job you were doing you weren't told what you'd
been exposed to no no we we transported what we called mystery boxes all the time i have no
idea it could have been empty it probably wasn't empty but we don't know what was inside the boxes
and what were you told if somebody tried to seize that box what was i told no we what were your
orders we we maintained the authority to use lethal force if anyone tried to seize those boxes
so whatever that box was it was extremely valuable to the u.s government that's correct i have to say
jake the the idea that you would be so recklessly exposed you know a person who's clearly patriotic
somebody who's clearly been a highly trained operator at the elite levels of special
operations in the u.s military it offends my sense of decency that employers would expose
you to something so recklessly can i put on my speculative hat for a minute sure okay so
if if the air force let's say knew that what we were working with that night had any type of
radiological signature or could turn on or turn off there's a whole set of process that we are
we're trained in on how to deal with that from a hazmat perspective and a containment perspective
and a measurement perspective on our person to detect the level of risk that might be associated
and the fact that none of that was was apparent that night tells me they didn't know what was in
the box and it got turned on or turned off which leads me to believe in hindsight all these years
that it may have been something of non-human origin or exotic let's just say exotic it may
have been something exotic that activated or still had some fallout let's say that they
were unaware of you know are you the only person that you're aware of inside the program who's
suffering health effects no no not at all how many are there uh more than me and probably
51 percent or greater i would say are suffering some form of health effects yeah i'll just say
just so you know it's it's more common than it's not that's heartbreaking i mean we ask our men
and women in service to do so many things the idea that because a program is secret
you wouldn't get the help you need i'm going to push back on that a little bit i don't think this
is uh this is something that's unique to the program as we keep saying i would say 51 percent
of more the people that come out of the military have and they sacrifice their bodies for for good
reason that's part of what we're willing to do i mean the ultimate sacrifice they say is death
which we've all agreed to do is to give up our life so anything less than death goes in with that
obligation that we gave up voluntarily so the military at large or anyone that works in this
capacity in the broader service of our nation they you get injured especially doing it 30 years
in the course of your high value target investigation you met dr steven greer yeah yeah i
did what was the purpose of meeting dr steven greer um well first of all i'd like to say that
you know you can say what you want about dr greer but the guy's been 30 years ahead of everyone else
on a lot of the details of this subject um so a lot of what he says is correct he to me he's like
the bent waters like we had everything we needed in 1980 and now we're fishing around for morsels
of that this guy he's he's been ahead of everyone and what i find quite funny is the one thing he
gets the most shit for is the one thing he's probably most right about and that is his ce5
protocol so ce5 is when he uses meditation and he claims it engages telepathically with the
phenomenon yeah that's his term for it like we don't use ce5 we don't use dr grige protocol
nodor or other people in the in the program or subsequent programs so ce5 is real
yeah if we're going to use his term i'll tell you what is real is is the ability to go into
something like a meditative state and summon uap and pilot uap that is real that's 100 real
wow i have to process that for a moment because that is just the most extraordinary claim
yeah well we hope to prove it soon on what basis did you approach dr greer my understanding was
that whoever was in a legal position whoever was in illegal possession of these hvt's may have the
intention to expose that sensitive material as a whistleblower you were concerned he might take it
to dr greer i was still working in my official capacity of protecting the sensitive data that
was on these hvt's that was my job at the time so dr greer was scheduling here a whistleblower
conference in dc and was holding a large event at the press club in washington dc
and so we reached out to him one of my teammates made a bump with him in the virginia area
and shared with him some information to pique his curiosity and to also bonafide ourselves as
someone he should maybe consider listening to and we set up a meeting and i explained to him
um upfront what our intentions were that we believed that there were whistleblowers that
might come forward was something that is sensitive and it may not be appropriate to disclose and i
asked to become um asked to be put in a position of authority with him where i could vet his
whistleblowers so we offered our service to help vet whistleblowers at the time thinking our guys
whoever was uh whoever had these hvt's might show up with the did that nope they never did but
it was on this trip that we were what was interesting at the time is we were contemplating
our own whistleblower path forward because of what had happened because of what had happened
it was happening at this time and so what surprised me is during this event a young marine
named michael Herrera came forward with a very particular story and spoke of a particular
operation that we were aware was taking place or operations like it let's say were going on and
i saw this young guy get up there and it just spoke to me call it my intuition that was blessed
i was blessed with that night i made contact with non-human intelligence for the first time but
my intuition was on you know was on high alert that night and when he spoke i knew what he was
saying was true and no one else was believing him and he was wrong about a few key things that he
was speculating on and so i made the decision after he spoke to go to dr gurir and ask to
speak with him privately so let me summarize very quickly what michael Herrera alleged he was on a
relief mission in Sumatra Indonesia they were deployed he and his small patrol to a particular
area and they were helping find people who needed help yeah in the course of that patrol they were
carrying weapons that's something that's been vigorously disputed by some of his colleagues
but he's adamant that he was carrying weapons and they stumbled across a craft a gigantic craft
yeah many many many meters wide hovering in the air and below that craft there was a platform
with trucks ford 150s and there were containers that he described that pushed buttons with you
what he described didn't he he was told he told he told the greer disclosure conference which
was in 2023 that the paramilitaries pointed their weapons and threatened to kill the marines that
they were american they took their guns off them and they basically threatened that they were going
to be killed yeah that's that's exactly what he talked about basically they were told eventually
they were released they were told to walk away their weapons were unchambered there were no
rounds in the weapons and they were told to walk away they allowed them to leave but they were told
not to look back yeah i can't speak to all that and let me be clear um that is never that is not
the type of group i would ever volunteer to be a part of but i know that uh there are guys like
that out there that get shopped out and become part of these programs the particular part that
that struck me were two things one the description of his craft although the size was enormous i have
i have no experience with a craft that size but the craft he designed was precisely the same craft
that we had come in contact with in our operations within the united states and that is it was a disc
with the eight gun construction when viewed from above the other thing was he spoke of the
containers and his initial uh speculation was that they made they must have been moving drugs
because they had something on the top that looked like some sort of h vac system of some kind
um and i knew right away those were the same type of containers we used for the site team
when they're operating and being transported so what are the containers used for the containers
are used for transportation of the side team and also just as a an operating base it's a
it's a mobile operating base um and so this quickly went off the rails because
it for some reason the term human trafficking got put into the story after or got put into the
minds of the people that were hearing his story after i got involved so what did michael harrera
think he thought they were either gun running or drug running didn't yeah he thought they were
that's what he assumed they were running drugs and uh i knew that those type of containers when
associated with that craft were used for the side team that's why they had many split h vac units
on the top provide comfortable environments inside for humans for either transportation
or for operation you can operate inside those containers and they're sealed they're kind of
like a faraday cage in that regard where it allows you to concentrate if you're going to
operate from those you can concentrate on your work as a si asset or they're used to mobilize
so clearly whoever those men were they were american they were private military contractors
and they weren't very friendly no are they the people that you feel pose a threat at times to
the legitimate operations of the program yeah i think uh it doesn't take many bad apples to
ruin the batch because to make the point you're at pains aren't you to emphasize that generally
this is a well-run operation that runs on ethical boundaries yeah my primary messages my primary
message that i want to get across is that this mass vilifying of what's referred to as the
military industrial complex is a very bad idea and there are very good people that work over here
not just good the best the best and brightest that america has to offer and the goods and
service that are provided by those organizations which fall under the military industrial complex
are the goods and services that make our country the greatest in the world
and we benefit from those on a daily basis and so to mass vilify it on mass is not only i mean
that's a crime in itself but it's a shame and we're so hungry to people are so eager to quantify
where their threat is coming from we want a bad guy and this this is not an entire cabal of bad
guys there are a few bad guys like it everywhere that operate within the military industrial
complex and unfortunately um their operations get get the spotlight so you but you you decided
that michael Herrera his account made sense to you from what you knew about the program what did you
do um i told him i told him what i believed was going on and that it that i knew that there were
operations going on oh konus in third world countries to recruit and train psionic assets
and whether or not this was an opportunity to recruit or provide job opportunities to new people
or he stumbled upon an operation in which they were currently being deployed and maybe they
had to evacuate themselves from that area because of the natural disaster who knows but that's all
speculation there's two applications that come out of that firstly we're recruiting psionics from
indonesia a foreign country yeah are those people given are they voluntarily going are they are they
yeah that's my understanding they're very well taken care of um you have you have to think and
this is where the human trafficking idea was a was a very unfortunate turn in in michael's story
especially after my involvement with it because now oh great now we got this guy that is at least
somewhat indirectly informed that there's a human trafficking operation and when we talk about human
trafficking we think of sex trade and all kinds of other things and this is not it at all i
there's my understanding that the programs that are conducted to recruit psionic assets in third
world countries these people come willingly and if you were to go down there and try and liberate
them with any type of you know liberation army um you would be liberating people that don't want to
be liberated they get very well taken care of they get fed there's actually a sense of pride
especially within the native american communities that have been involved in this program that
do cooperate outside of konus as well um there's a sense of pride with this skill and ability
and so again this is another example of it's almost like we want there to be darkness in this area
and there is not darkness and i'll tell you by nature of my experience as i shared non-human
intelligence itself does not operate that way and so these people that that are whose um skills
are nurtured are basking in a glow of light i would assume most of the time when they're
doing doing their work for them it's a very positive experience very engaging spiritually
with this phenomenon yeah so you say they're basking in some divinely beautiful uh frequency
in order to do the work properly the implications from what you're saying are that if Michael
Herrera is telling the truth if he really did see a gigantic octagonal craft floating in mid-air
with no visible means of propulsion in indonesia in sumatra in i think 2009 yeah it suggests that
a private military contractor working for an aerospace company was operating some kind of
reverse engineered vehicle yeah it's certainly possible i would say especially based on what i
saw i dealt with a much smaller version of an octagonal saucer this was a bigger one i could
certainly see that being possible can you answer me this question have you seen any alien reproduction
vehicles any replica vehicles made from non-human technology i honestly can't tell you with um with
certainty once we get into the space but i can tell you what i know has been human what has been
non-human when it gets into the hybrids i just don't know can you tell me how many retrievals
you've been involved in no you that's a classified thing yes can you tell me were the remaining i
think four hard disks ever recovered the four tough books to my knowledge no we stopped at
two so there are still four hard disks containing containing potentially incriminating material
at large or somebody else was hired and they recovered them is it a question mark in your
mind that maybe it was a foreign adversary power that was trying to procure this incredibly sensitive
yeah that's certainly possible was there a a name for the psionics was there a term that you used
for uh there's a term we used which is what a p3 program why the p3 there's three p's it's the
psionic predisposition potential p3 yeah now that's not an official program name i
think you'll find anywhere that's why i'm able to say that from your understanding of the kind of
people obviously who were capable of psionic ability obviously there's people of native
american background people from third world countries that are deeply spiritual that appear
to have this capacity to engage with the phenomenon was there any other group that was especially
susceptible to being able to engage with this technology yeah kids children children it's been
suggested to me that left-handed gay men are particularly good at it yeah that certainly
seems to be the case that there is a larger distribution of the predisposition amongst
children and gay men for whatever reason the demographic when compared to normal society
within the program that gay men and kids and females are more more often seen
as having the predisposition for the psionic ability i'm again exploring the boundaries of
where i can go and you you might want to say no comment to this but i'm going to put it to you
anyway i have another source inside the program who has told me that one of the aerospace companies
holding this tech at one stage relinquished a craft to the u.s government saying that they hadn't
been able to successfully reverse engineer it and it has been put to me that this was a lie
and that they have in fact got a fully flying intact reverse engineered craft i've heard the
very same thing from a very reputable source so i would i would believe that's true the implications
of this are that there's a whole secret program involving potentially energy technologies
anti-gravity technologies that are mind-blowing yeah it's fun isn't it it is fun yeah i mean i
guess the the message that i'm getting from you is one of kind of optimism yeah i'm i'm very pleased
to be at a place where this is becoming fun again you know when i when i started this journey 30
years ago in a 17 year old kid as i shared with you my intentions were very simple and clear i
wanted to jump out of airplanes kill bad guys and make my grandparents proud somewhere along the way
things got very confusing and very complex we're now at a point where things are very simple for
me again and i see clearly what i want to do with the rest of my life and i have my why
and fortunately because of my experience i have the how i have the capability and we over the
last two years while we've been hiding out we've been working to find a way to bring this operation
out of the shadows and into an open environment where we could build a public private partnership
with full transparency and explore all of these things that have been explored in secret
in a way that we can start from scratch but we may be 60 70 years behind what everyone calls
the legacy program but i'm telling you we're going to catch up very quickly and the reason
it's going to work is because we have all of the people like me that have been working there
we've i call it the league of extraordinary gentlemen but we have been recruiting guys
from within the program and women and those who are associated with the program
in a very open way and have formed and are forming a new team in coordination with
government agencies the two we would want the most coordination with are are coming on board with us
and we also have the funding through venture capital can you name those agencies
um not at this time but i hope to very soon you know we have some really important meetings next
week and uh i hope that after that time i'm going to need to ask permission out of just
good faith with those folks to see how how much they want to be i guess a lot of people watching
this might be worried that you're getting sucked into say an intelligence agency or a military
agency that is going to try and shut you down yeah well um or it could be where we're just the
we're just the legacy program 2.0 and this all goes underground again i'm giving you my promise
right now our organization is called sky watcher we are part of what has been defined as the
explorer's club and it is full of people who have the best intentions in mind and there's going to
be accountability with there there's not going to be transparency and i know that sounds like a lot
coming or sounds like could be a load coming from a guy like me with my background but you know i'm
not going to be able to prove it to you in this conversation but i'll say pay attention and
i'll paraphrase a quote from the book of matthew and say you will know them by their fruits so
stand by and judge us for our fruits you've been really touched haven't you by this experience
it's touched you spiritually yes it has there was a gathering at esalen okay and a lot of very high
net worth individuals who were interested in suppression of non-human intelligence attended
what happened i think something epic happened i think something happened that
if it was fully documented and understood would go in the history books
i had a feeling last week that that was historical it felt absolutely historic what you had was a
combination of the world's leading like most frontier scientists you had people that were
top experts in all their fields and then you had a variety of fields that was
outrageous we had neurosurgeons doctors and neurosurgeon we had physicists we had
high net worth individuals in the billions that were extremely open-minded and had a
frontier attitude towards all this we had mystics we had psychic kids we had children from germany
that could harness and actually showcase their ability to perform telekinesis their ability to
psychically see things with their mind and were able to prove that to all of us we also deployed
some of our psionic assets that we've used and are part of our new team with skywatcher
and we summoned uap we had the uap come and fly around and visit hang out with us and take off
and i have to say i saw it too yeah and it was profound
it's a spiritual experience and what you're trying to do now is replicate in the private sphere
what's being suppressed in the public sphere yeah you know we we're not looking back you know we
could we can leave the bad actors of the past we can leave them with their lies we have no need
for that we're looking forward i am absolutely confident that we are capable of generating the
type of high quality sensor data and photography and film evidence that everyone is wanting i'm
also confident that if we continue on the path with our with our government agencies that we're
going to get a craft we're going to get material in hand i know it's possible it's just a matter
of working out the logistics i'm just i'm just exploring this with you the implications are that
that this one part of the black world of the u.s government that is being hidden from congress
hidden from some presidents i know yeah working on retrieved alien non-human technology
yeah it's being kept from the knowledge of the american public and yet there's they're being
funded with taxpayer dollars billions of taxpayers dollars if you believe it yeah
yeah what do you think of that
well it doesn't sound right does it but you you could probably
tell that same story around a number of other things that have nothing to do with aliens and
unfortunately that's the government and the world we live in but the exciting thing is
the thing i find breathtaking from what you're saying is you're saying as somebody who's come
from that black world yeah screw the secrecy i'm going to say it a little differently
the u.s the monopoly the u.s government has on the subject matter is not respected by the non-human
intelligence spirits again the skies are not classified and your conscience cannot be redacted
and ultimately why i feel safe and why i feel optimum optimistic about the future is i know
that the nhi is guiding us that way can you explain how it is that you're not authorized
to do this interview but you ended up applying for a dopsa i think our audience might be confused
they might think that this is somehow an authorized interview and that there are people in the defense
department pulling the strings telling you what to say and that this is some kind of
disinformation operation yeah that's uh that makes a lot of sense to me but you know for what
it's worth i can tell you that's not the case i mean the dopser processes is very interesting
it's way more casual especially on the onset than you might think
when you take into account the ramifications for for violating the mandates that come out of it
and the subject matter that it's supposedly protecting but you know they get put in a really
tough spot and this is part of something we aimed to take advantage of i guess you could say by
interrogating the dopser system one of the things i haven't shared yet is in our effort to find out
who we were looking for one of the ways we came up with on how to do that was to query for who
might want to redact statements we intended to go public with through dopser so you filed i think a
fictionalized account of some of your experiences to dopser yeah so um any author or anybody that's
going to be contributing to an author to put something in writing or to share it orally like this
has to go through the dopser process if you ever held a security clearance
working for a government agency in the subject matter that you are intending to go public on so
right off the bat there's a tell right there the fact that i had to go through dopser tells you i
had a security clearance on the subject matter right there so there's their first failure of
poker face and that's exactly what we set out to exploit and so we came up with a reconnaissance
mission the reconnaissance mission looked like this we were going to write a detailed manuscript
as fiction through a ghostwriter when we completed that it was about 120 000 word
manuscript we broke that manuscript into actual sections that we called episodes
because dopser wants you to complete or submit the entire document we submitted our first 20 000
words our first 10 000 words which was 20 pages and within that first chunk of information we
included four types of information and that information's purpose again was to inform us
as to what they considered sensitive and the smes which stands for subject matter experts
that they were outsourcing the information to because what they do in the dopser process is
they send it out to all of the agencies that might be affected by you going public on something
even in a fictionalized manuscript and they say to them is there anything in here that needs to
be redacted to protect national security that's correct and it could be it could be you could
present it to them as fact or fiction it doesn't matter the context but more importantly if it's
protecting national security and it's redacted it has to be a legally authorized program doesn't
it yes it does so this this is what we use to set up our four categories of information that
i want to get through with you category one we included in that manuscript information we knew
was classified that we were privy to and we knew that was patently classified on a very high level
information category number two was information that was classified but we knew only existed
within the hearts and minds of the operators that were at the fingertips of that operation
um information category number three was information that was classified but you
may be surprised to learn was already in the public domain and open source source because
of the nature of the internet there are things that the dod and its partners would say that
shouldn't be out there but but it is anyway so we put some of that in there and then we had our
fourth category information which was the most fun which was where we took a little liberty
and went fishing we took our information that we knew was compartmentalized connected it with
other information that were these fact islands we were aware of because of our i won't say how
and then we took our own creative liberty at connecting those two dots through a particular
pathway as to why that might exist and filled that space with other fictional classified information
what happened six months later took six months we came back with seven pages of redactions
of all four categories wow so one that confirms there is a classified program relating to this
information yes wow now there was a counterplay here so although that was informative i have to
tell you when they came back our intention was now that reconnaissance mission having
bared fruits was now going to inform how we went back and edited remember this was the first 20
pages of a of a multi-page i would say the first 10 000 words of 120 000 word manuscript we were
then going to take that information and write around it in order to extract more intel through
the dobser process so you were running a counter counter surveillance operation against the very
organizations that's a red team's best tool right there you were doing op four opposition
play three four five dimensional test yeah chess so you play multi-dimensional chess
so even though they know you and your team were thinking about publishing something they don't
know that you're speaking publicly on national television about the legacy program that's a good
question no they don't but it doesn't mean i was limited to do that because i have to tell you
about the counterplay so there is a although they have no poker face they're in a really tough spot
because not redacting information means that if they just if they just chose hey this is sensitive
but we're not going to redact it well now obviously that makes it into the public domain
but by redacting it they prove that it's sensitive so they have no idea as to
they have no idea as to how you acquired the information they know based on your security
clearance and your background because it had to be submitted under my official name it's a
social security number and my record in order to get triggered and that's how they know what sms
to send it to the sms who i worked for squashed all kinds of stuff then it went to one of the
other sms i worked for they squashed their stuff and it came back with all these squashings in the
form of black ink now let me keep going because the counterplay for them would have been to let
certain information go so that it could be formally categorized as not sensitive and the
fictional liberties taken by an author of a fictional book so they could do that they could
have done that but we didn't really see that what they did do however was they got a sense they were
they got on to us they figured out what we were doing and they said stop you cannot submit anything
else you have to submit the whole manuscript and we told them well that is the whole book we're
going to release this like episodes of a special this is the whole season but we're going to release
it an episode so we have to send it to you 10 000 words at a time because that's how it's going to
be released and they they were kind of caught there and they didn't quite know how to respond
so i can tell you that since then and this was a 2000 correction this was 2022 i think believe in
january when we first submitted the manuscript and they they haven't gotten back to us on the
rest of it still sitting there do you think that there are people in private aerospace who think
that it's inevitable that eventually this story is going to be yeah i know there there are and
we have a lot of people in private aerospace that are part of our sky sky watcher program
that have come on because just echoing the point that you made earlier that the military industrial
complex is not one big monolithic organization that says the same thing and has the same view
there are people i know inside the military inside the intelligence community and you've
been one of them who basically think it's implausible to try and keep this secret and
moreover that the public has a right to know yeah it's it's going to come out it's all coming out
it's coming out probably like this year so you think yourself the public has a right to know
this information not all of it no what sort of things need to be protected do you think
let's um anything that affects national security like we have to be careful of
what we wish for like we don't know what we don't know even me i don't know what i don't know
and if we're at the point where we have so little trust in our government that we're just going to
there's a reason it's called catastrophic disclosure catastrophic is not good
for those calling for heads any more than it's good for those whose heads are being called for
like we as a public do not want catastrophic disclosure we what we need again there's a few
bad apples we need to maintain our institutions we don't get rid of them we need to find a way
to get the right people promoted to positions of power and trust and we already have that
it's called the gang of eight in congress they're a big part of that right now it's not functioning
that way but we're not going to change we can't change the structure we need to get the right
people into power into positions start looking into it um and again you don't need to rely on
the government it's already there like what we need to know is this we need to know that we're
not alone we need to know that there's a profound spiritual component to our existence and that's
just for the sake of our own fellowship is creatures sharing this planet but also there
it's there's an extreme amount of utility in our ability that has been suppressed forever so if
if we could learn how to use that um and also for those that are keeping the secrets keeping
it secret is a bad way to try and study something we need an open source we need all hands on deck
all brains on deck all consciences on deck in order to find out how we can exploit this in the
best of ways in order to come up with things like zero point energy let's say until we do so we're
going to be stuck with the same problem we have been for all the civilization and that's a battling
for limited resources and if we could solve that problem by something that might come out of
disclosure that would be something i say should be disclosed things relative to national security
no and we can't trust ourselves we can't say give us all of it because we don't trust you we have to
put trustworthy people in position and let them make that decision okay let me ask you this way
then do you think the public have the right to know that we are not alone yes i'll say yes to that
and the thing i find shocking though is that the most beautiful thing that you've described to me
the most exciting thing is what i think our audience is going to have the biggest trouble with
is believing the idea that human beings have the capacity to do things with their minds
that have been suppressed yeah i've just kind of smiled because that makes it more entertaining
for me because they're going to be shocked but you know what they i think i don't think that's
necessarily the case i think there's more people that believe it they're just not talking about it
and i can tell you for a fact even within our world of hardened operators at the highest level
of guys that are still in behind closed doors we all know it's true and we have the most emotional
talks like we're part of oprah's book club i mean it's it's true and right now we're in a moment
where the truth is being obfuscated and twisted but the truth i'll tell you is our weapon and
when we're willing to accept the truth no matter how profound or earth shaking is when we move
into a position of power and it's going to liberate this subject and you know what how fun
would it be if we're right i'm not telling you it'd be different if the government
and what was being hid behind this subject matter was the fact that there was an asteroid on course
for earth that we there is no way we could we could redirect it or there's no way we could
defend against it and we were all going to die in the year 2020x or whatever it is that's not
what's being hidden what's being hidden here is something extremely positive and it's something
we've all hoped for it's the one thing we've all looked for in all of our religions that we celebrate
across the world it's the one thing that we want to be true of our religion and it's the one thing
that um the one common thread amongst all religions and so that's what's being hidden
and that's what we're going to find out and you can't bottle it up the implications of what you're
saying also are that potentially there is some kind of capacity to draw incredible amounts of
energy from the quantum back end you've seen it i've seen it there's also obviously the capacity
to use propulsion systems that are far beyond what we're describing yeah that seems to be the case
as well anti-gravity anti-gravity they know about it anti-gravity zero point energy those
secrets are being suppressed from our knowledge i've seen demonstrations recently that again
proves that the government doesn't have a monopoly on this they have while they have we know that
they have been working on it they've seemed to have been doing a good job in keeping others
from making their own independent progress but that time is changing independent progress is
happening right now and it's coming out that's why i'm so confident we don't need to rely on their
body of lack of evidence let's say we don't need to rely on that like it's here like the the shift
has already happened there's people in silicone valley and around the world that are so financially
independent so intellectually independent and yes so emotionally and psionically independent
that they don't need the government to tell us those things but we still have to work through
do you think the aliens the non-human intelligence wants us humanity to know
about their existence yeah i do believe that that's the message that that we're getting
so you felt that yourself when you connected and there are others that i know of
that are being sent that message directly and they are extremely confident so jake in early
october you made the decision on the invitation of the senate select committee for intelligence
to go to congress and give evidence yes i did how was that day um it was great it was a it was nice
to finally get it done and it seemed like by the time i went i held out so long that by the time
i got there there are a lot of people had already done the heavy lifting like dave and others and so
they were like okay we know we don't know and we know that we haven't proven to be the most
they know that they don't have they can't offer whistleblowers the protection we know they need
which was my primary objection the entire time is that they offer protection they have no way
of providing it they've got no enforcement they've got no enforcement they can't protect me
um and so things had certainly changed what was the reception in the room what kind of comments
did you hear well for the most part it was fantastic you know there was eight or nine people
i'm not going to say versus me but it was a one v nine situation where it was me in there and then
i had at times seven to ten people a few had to come and go because we went for four and a half
hours but um it was all ears it was listening david grush and commander david fravor gave
evidence to the congress along with ryan graves the two f-18 pilots sat with david grush and gave
evidence to the congress last year under oath and they insisted on doing it under oath to emphasize
the veracity the truthfulness of what they were saying if you were asked would you be prepared
to do the same 100 and i told them that i told congress that during our time in the skiff now
what impact do you think you had on the people listening in the room at the senate select
committee for intelligence well we laughed we cried we had a lot of serious talk so if anything i
i would think i came across sincere keep in mind we were scheduled for a two-hour block we went
four and a half so they were definitely engaged they seemed like they were
sincere sincere in their effort to find out what's going on why hasn't somebody like you
with first-hand knowledge of the program come forward so definitively before that's a good
question and that's what i kept waiting for more to come forward i feel uniquely qualified to come
forward at this time because i know we have this private venture coming and i've already been
begun negotiating with those government agencies who i thought may have come after me let's say
if they had ill will and it's been proven to me that they don't so there are government agencies
that don't know about this program that are aware of the obvious illegality of parts of it yeah
i don't know if it's that it's every department has within it a responsibility to deal with
in the sky flying around that we don't know what it is i mean just start in the faa for example
which is ryan graves's particular case he's he's trying to advance is that you know there is a
safety of flight here there is an aircraft separation issue a collision avoidance issue
in the air if there are things flying around in the sky and the faa doesn't have a way of managing
that or producing safety reports on it we've got a big problem and the problem gets much bigger from
there and so while we like to speak of the government is the government it is not one big
cohesive machine that works together and so every department like the fbi like department of homeland
security like border patrol department of defense you know they have their own niche responsibilities
in order to make sure things in the sky aren't our adversaries aren't carrying payloads aren't
causing safety of flight issue and yeah aren't they also have a responsibility to figure out
whether or not aliens are visiting the planet and you think they are yeah i do so the truth
is out the truth has been out for a long time what would you like to see happen like what's
your dream you've seen this technology yeah you've felt the sincerity of the intelligence
that you were engaging with what would you dream of what's your aspiration for the future
you know what'd be really cool is to be driving down the highway look up and see a billboard
advertisement for the united states air force recruiting kids into a career field for uap
research and study for psionic exploration for piloting technology to other galaxies like
that would tell me we've arrived and we are at a place where clearly
the public and the government are working together because the suppression of this secret it's not
just suppressing technology and weapons which i can you know as much as i don't like the idea of it
i can understand why somebody might have made the decision to do that it's suppressing spiritual
knowledge that you think the public's got a right to know well and here's where i would say we need
to respect the fact that we don't know if we don't know imagine weaponizing consciousness
we don't think of in this story we're telling we're assuming consciousness is the good benevolent
harmless thing that should be disclosed everything we've researched and understood
imagine if it is the case that consciousness could be weaponized and that people like the
president of the united states could have could be under mind control that's a huge problem and
imagine if someone could independently develop we already see this problem with drones we are so out
of control with the drone issue that drones can fly around with a payload and cause mash casualties
because we don't have it under control the fa doesn't we just unfortunately we don't have the
cfrs the code of federal regulations and the people hired to deal with something like drones
imagine if we had to manage and police the malevolent use or the weaponization of consciousness
that could be a really big problem have you done any operations yourself retrievals or operations
involving the legacy program in arizona no have you seen the rubber duck video which was shot by
border patrol from a surveillance plane over parts of the arizona desert yes do you know
anything about that object i don't i don't know anything about it are you aware of any underground
bases yes have you visited any yes so they exist they do can you tell me anymore no ross
you can't blame me for trying no i don't blame you do you know anything about the phoenix lights
i'm very yeah i'm familiar with that story i remember hearing about it when i was a kid
and going oh you know that's interesting but not believing it but now knowing what i know it seems
very clear to me that that was a legitimate non-human intelligence that had flown some
sort of craft over phoenix which raises the question all over the united states right now
us air force bases are being buzzed by what they call drones yeah and funnily enough nobody's seen
one of these and been able to recover one because so-called electromagnetic pulse weapons don't work
on these objects whatever they are not all uap respond to the same weapon systems it raises the
question is the phenomenon making itself more overt do you think is it trying to wake us up
certainly is to me in my experience but you know it's hard to say i don't know how to
how to look at that from a completely objective i don't know i don't know how much it's shown
itself over the decades and centuries because a lot of people watching this said to say
you're pushing them up against a barrier of doubt indecision stigma and taboo that's been attached
to the subject for 80 years a lot of people aren't going to believe this what do you say to those
people i'm not here to make anyone believe anything it's exhausting like either you're
going to get it or you're not going to get it like we have we honor in our own capacity
we've operated sky watcher already me and my team on the very first outing summoned a white egg in
broad daylight and while i have pictures of it i'm happy to share with you we calculated this object
to be traveling depending upon the slack range distance anywhere between 3 000 and 11 000 miles
per hour based on this size we're still analyzing the data we collected from the range and we're
happy to show that to you and so what else could that be there's this there's this other way of
looking at this like we can put all this information before you and you could say it's not this it's
not this it's not this we're at a point now where the amount of information is so overwhelming the
probability that any alternate alternate explanation for its existence is there is so much
less than the probability that what i'm telling you is exactly what is going on you want this
investigated don't you yeah i wanted i want to do the investigating that's what we're doing i want
but would you quite like to see as a result of this story would you like to see yourself questioned
and held to account for evidence and and tested your allegations yeah we have an opportunity
right now to work with the u.s government and as a private partner the place where we operate
right now we've been successful before in conducting our whole operation all five phases of it
the u.s government has shown an interest they know we're capable they know what we've pulled out of
the sky it's consistent with the egg and everything else i've told you about and what they're offering
to do now is give us exclusive use access to facilities because they don't know what's going
on departments there there are departments within the broader branches of the three-letter agencies
that aren't being read into what other sections are so they want us to help and because we're one
of the few groups of people that have experience and we provide them a path to redemption so there's
a real there's a real message here from you of incredible optimism about what this could represent
yeah this is why i know disclosure is coming and guess what it's going to come out in the most
beautiful way i believe the united states government in the next 12 months is going to use me
and my team as a peaceful non-judgmental path forward to disclosure they're going to help us
conduct our operations
and gather evidence in order to present this subject matter to the public so that these
questions can be answered once and for all and all the questions i'm talking about what do the
craft look like how do they operate who is operating them how are they being operated
and where are they coming from we should be able to answer those questions
probably entirely in the next 12 months can i put to you there is a dark state
there are people who don't have good intentions who want this secret to remain suppressed aren't
there it seems that way yeah are they going to win no they're not going to win they're not going
to win there we've we've passed a tipping point there like i said when you're talking about these
people they aren't organized you become a dark person by having by being filled with more vice
than virtue virtuous people win people full of vice they lose and they're dividing amongst
themselves they're on a sinking ship all of the good people that are in these organizations
realize they're in a position they need to make a decision as to which side they're on
and despite having all this leverage and threat that they have that's being held against them
they're making the decision to move forward are there people inside the program who you know
will come forward when you speak up yes um i know i'm going to serve as a huge catalyst and that's
going to be an exciting day the things i'm talking about are going to be you know dave did a great
job of paving a path i'm going to come along and try and improve upon that path and widen the road
i expect the next uh people that are the next groups of folks are going to be coming down this
path are going to blow it wide open do you worry for your safety for your family's safety no i
don't i don't i think i'm being protected believe it or not by the nhi and also i don't i don't put
up with harassment i don't believe in the boogeyman i am the boogeyman you know how to help yourself
yes yep so if somebody comes after you they'd better watch out it'd probably be the worst
decision they ever made in their life i would intend to make it that way clearly
at the heart of all of this there's been an 80 year cover-up where we've all outside in the
the normal world been told that this is nonsense aliens aren't real telepathy is nonsense
how do you deal with that how do we reverse decades of stigma and taboo you inform yourself
why are we relying on these people that have been keeping the secrets to let us in on the secret
why don't we make their secrets obsolete by capturing the evidence ourself and becoming
all firsthand experiencers of the phenomenon and the technology because that's possible
and from what you're saying jake barber that's a beautiful experience
yeah it was the most beautiful experience i've had in my life
would you like to see your kids one day doing that work my kids already are believe it or not