You have this amazing blue being experience that prompts you to get into quantum physics.
Because of what this being had showed me, I started looking into this notion of
longitudinal scalar waves. Now, these were shown to me by this being as slinky, so to speak,
that exists all around us. You can use the potentials that exist all around us right now
in the quantum vacuum to surveil an entire room.
How would you do that?
I don't want to say because it starts to overlap into stuff that's sensitive.
I know a group that is working in the government that has been working on this since the 90s
and they've had massive success. There are things that I've seen in private laboratories
that are undeniable and verified by people other than myself in those facilities.
A UAP was hovering near some plants and as an individual approached the UAP,
the UAP shot off as many people have experienced. However, when the plants that were close to the
analyzed, they had aged 10 years within X amount of hours. We're dealing with multiple
factions or elements of both government and private industry that have vast influence on
what could or could not be revealed and no one really knows what to do. If you reveal some,
then people are going to take it and run with it and then that's going to open up a whole other
avenue of research that can be weaponized pretty easily if someone has a nefarious mindset. We have
mutual friends that are privately working on some of these things where six, seven months worth of
work in the lab, all of a sudden it's a weapon now and if someone gets a hold of that weapon,
it's game over.
This interview was one of the most baffling and intriguing I've ever done on this show. Today,
we will talk to a former construction worker. He was down and out and just scraping by. He then
developed an interest in UFOs. Then, he had an interaction with a blue alien being that according
to him caused him to do a deep dive into quantum physics. All of this sounded pretty crazy when I
first heard about it, but since meeting this next guest, I've introduced him to a Navy scientist
who's worked at the highest levels of government. Even he was extremely impressed and intrigued by
this former construction worker's findings. I know all of this sounds insane, but it's true.
Our next guest was also spotted by the legendary Hal Putoff and Eric Davis, who have also noted
his impressive knowledge in areas of unorthodox science. Dr. Davis, thank you so very much for
being here today. Oh, thank you for inviting me. I'm happy to be here. A lot of this guest's
interests in physics are in a special branch of it called Extended Electrodynamics. We recorded
this interview in early December of 24 and at the time of its recording, Extended Electrodynamics
was considered quackery. Something you might hear at a zero point energy conference somewhere
in the southwest from a crystal healer. But right after we recorded this podcast, the National
Science Foundation and NASA co-sponsored a podcast with some elite scientists and engineers
with serious credentials claiming to investigate, you guessed it, Extended Electrodynamics. I've
also heard from multiple other Navy whistleblowers that this framework is very, very real and useful.
When you introduce the scalar field, you now have the possibility of at least three completely new
kinds of waves. Okay, so a construction worker with no formal schooling downloads exotic physics
from a blue alien being and that physics is now being vindicated at the highest levels of
government in aerospace. Sounds about right for 2025. But this former construction worker hasn't
only agreed to come on my show, he's agreed to speak with any scientist at any level about his
theories on my show as a follow-up. I thought that was a pretty decent show of confidence.
So without further ado, please enjoy this special sit down with this week's American Alchemist,
the scientific savant himself, David Rossi. I'm here with Dave Rossi and I couldn't be more
excited to have this conversation because we've had a lot of offline conversations over the last
couple of years or year or so. And I'm always wildly impressed at your knowledge of physics,
experimentally and theoretically. And you kind of came out of the blue and had like this extremely
interesting origin story when it came to how you acquired such esoteric knowledge of physics. And
so it's an honor to have you here, man. Well, thank you so much for having me. I really
appreciate it. It's an honor to be here. Like you said, we've spoken for quite a while over the
years and I'm very excited to be on the show. I really appreciate it. Oh, absolutely, man.
Know that the honor is mine and you have a really great podcast everybody should check out as well.
It's called Generation Zed. And so we're going to go to the limits of my knowledge and ability
to understand this stuff. But if we ever exceed that, you can just go watch Zed's channel and it's
great. Thank you. I appreciate it. Yeah, man, of course. So I know you to be somebody extremely
knowledgeable, not only about UFOs from like an investigative lens, which, you know, a lot of
journalists out there know a lot about like, you know, UFOs and the history of the government
vis-a-vis UFOs. You know about it from a scientific perspective. And I think a lot of what you get
into is actually just man-made prosaic human exotic technology. Correct. That sort of mimics
UFOs. Maybe it's inspired by UFOs. I don't know. Right. But yeah. If I can give a little background
as to how I got into this basically. So it was around the time that COVID had hit and I decided
to start a small podcast and I didn't think at the time, you know, about four years ago that I would
be where I am currently. And so what happened essentially was I decided to start looking into
the UFO topic in general, UAPs and all that. But then after a couple of years of doing the show,
I started to say to myself, well, I'm very interested in learning about it and making videos
on it. And I was gracious enough to have a small audience that supported me. But I said to myself,
well, what if I can actually try and build something? And so I tried to first dive into
the theory of things like, you know, Maxwell's equations and so on and so forth. And throughout
that process, I recall a very spiritual experience. I'm going to sleep one evening and
it felt like I don't want to use the word abducted because I think that implies that there was some
negative connotation to the experience, which in this case for me, graciously there wasn't.
But I remember essentially being, I guess you could say taken by a blue energy type humanoid,
if you will. There were no physical characteristics. It was just pure blue energy.
And I really couldn't tell- Why do you say humanoid? When do you say?
Well, because it had two arms, two legs. It was just significantly taller than
you or I, for example, height wise. And so- And when you say no physical characteristics,
it was like you could move right through it with your hand or something.
Essentially, yes. Like a plasma being or something.
Basically, very, very not really dense whatsoever. Sort of like, right, a plasma,
electric plasma type being. And I recall, again, I can't say for certain because I don't know if
it was a physical experience or a purely energetic or spiritual one, but I recall opening my eyes
and I saw all this basically white light around me, but it seemed like it was a very convex type
structure. And then I recall seeing, I felt like I was very drowsy and I recalled seeing this blue
being basically standing very close to my head. And then next thing I knew, I basically closed
my eyes and I woke up the next morning and I had all of a sudden this extreme drive and inclination
to study electrical engineering and quantum physics in particular. And I knew absolutely
nothing about it. I failed math, I think almost every year of high school. And so I spent the
first two years from there basically learning, learning, learning. I had made some videos where
I had discussed these type of concepts on my channel without getting into specifics name wise.
I was noticed by a handful of very nice gentlemen that seemingly saw some potential to what I was
saying from a physics and engineering perspective, gave some presentations to those individuals and
since then continue to learn, learn. Many, many cups of coffees later, many late nights spent just
reading papers, the Soviet papers, the older North American papers, which is I think in terms of
zero point energy tech. A lot of stuff is in the older literature, more so than the modern
literature. And then from there I built a handful of different devices that had some interesting
effects that seemed to substantiate what a lot of the theory that people like Dr. Pudoff, Dr. Davis
and others have discussed. However, I must say that there were people going all the way back to
the early 1900s, going back to Nikola Tesla, people for example like Gabriel Krone and E.T.
Whitaker and so on that seemed to substantiate certain experiments that I was doing with a
partner of mine using things like for example ring superconductors and looking into the notion of
magnetism and so on. And then from there I continued to network and meet more people both
in the defense industry as well as in the private sector. And there seemed to be more and more
validity to what I was looking into. And I don't claim I was the first one to discover this by any
stretch. What were you before you had your experience? You had a podcast where you're
covering UFOs, is that right? Correct, correct. And so you were already somewhat interested in
kind of out there subjects, but nothing from a scientific perspective? Nothing. Since I was
young I always had an interest in you know the paranormal and things like that. But right,
nothing from the scientific aspect. Before the podcast I was in construction. It was pretty
straightforward. There was no, I don't have any formal degrees. So what inspired you to start a
UFO podcast as a construction worker? Well what happened was COVID had hit and this was during
the time when people had you know two three months off where they were staying home. And I said to
myself I looked around at the time at the UFO podcasting field from what I could find at least
and I could, with all due respect to the shows out there, I couldn't find a show that seemed to
be very unbiased and neutral and just looked at evidence rather than implementing a certain biased
perspective. And I thought maybe I could contribute to the field by just taking applying an open mind
to it. Now granted with that said that has significantly changed because of fantastic
shows like yourself and some others. But at the time that's what I was doing and so there came a
point where I just kind of got bored and I said I want to try and you know make something and
see what I could do dealing with electromagnetism in particular, what that could potentially lead
to. And how far into doing the podcast do you have this amazing blue being experience that prompts
you to get into quantum physics? Probably about just over a year in, maybe a year and a half.
So going to 2021 now give or take. Is there anything that happened before that experience
or just seemed like out of the blue and no pun intended? Literally no pun intended,
out of the blue entirely. Nothing preliminary that was before that. That's amazing. Okay so
you're prompted to look into both electrical engineering and kind of some more experimental
stuff but also some of the theory behind some of these more exotic lineages in science if you will.
And you say you get noticed, can you say anything more about that and no worries if you can?
Certain individuals that you've interviewed on your show noticed me and asked me to present
a couple of times over and they were very interested in what I had to say and that told me well
if you know if I'm on to something I clearly must be on to something semi-feasible at least
because if not why would there be this show of interest? And then from there essentially I began
networking more and more, meeting with different groups of people in the private military contractor
field, meeting with people inside the defense department and officially there was no way that
they could support me but privately they were encouraging me significantly to continue pursuing
what I was doing and so at this point in time now what I essentially do is I consult for private
groups as well as for in some cases other we'll just say private groups for different aspects
of physics and I don't claim to know a lot by any means compared to certain individuals out there
with regards to zero point energy but I think in a certain capacity I could probably hold my own
and so that's led me to where I am now and I'm very very fortunate and very grateful so.
Well I'll just say the reason we're even doing this is because I don't feel super equipped. I
mean we had an initial conversation a lot of what you said resonated on some instinctive level with
me and so I was like okay this guy seems you know pretty legit like this seems awesome like
what he's into seems directionally exactly aligned with a lot of intuitions I've had or even stuff
I've discovered just from a historical perspective when it comes to Townsend Brown or high energy
physics or certain anomalies with consciousness or whatever you were kind of saying a lot of
this stuff but taking it a little deeper as far as the math and theory of it but really what convinced
me is I don't know if you remember this but I was like okay I appreciate you know meeting you said
this is amazing but like you're a construction worker four years ago and you just got prompted
by a blue being to get into this. I will say that this will be controversial however I know
that you're not afraid of any of that. I started looking into because of what this being had
showed me during that one evening experience in a visual sense I started looking into this notion of
what people call longitudinal waves or longitudinal scalar waves now I know there's a lot of
misinformation and disinformation out there about it I know that we have mutual friends that are
currently conducting experiments looking into basically proving its feasibility and what it
could lead to and so on. And just for the audience so this is this idea of you know sometimes it's
called scalar physics other times it's called extended electrodynamics it's the idea that
classical electrodynamics as we currently hold it which only allows for the you know your typical
transverse hertzian electromagnetic wave which attenuates over spacetime electrons pair off
that sort of thing. You actually have this other thing called the scalar field which allows for
all sorts of exotic wave types where in the transverse hertzian wave you have you know
a electric field a magnetic field and wave propagation and all three are perpendicular
to one another and in this case you could have you know a magnetic field and you know wave
propagation they're parallel and so it could do you know all the you know attenuation over normal
distances in spacetime that sort of thing might get kind of negated by these exotic wave types.
Correct and so to your point very well said by the way these longitudinal waves were shown to me by
this being basically as slinky so to speak that that exists all around us but because of the way
that quantum theory explains it there or would explain it if there was any official way to that
would be allowed through the system to explain it they exist all around us in what we call I
guess you could say the quantum vacuum or what was once called the luminiferous ether many years ago
I think over a hundred years ago they exist all around us but they also don't simultaneously so
you need to in other words curve spacetime itself in order to tap in order to tap these type of
waves so you use the traditional um hertzian transverse waves that we're used to and accustomed
to but you apply certain conditions um in an engineering sense to them in which will allow
spacetime to curve now how do you do that this is where it's interesting and I will get into that
so essentially if I may start with a very basic foundation here everything that we that is taught
to my understanding within particle physics electrical engineering on a basic level are
have to do with what are called u1 models that essentially assume a flat spacetime so in other
words in the condition of a flat spacetime you cannot get these effects and if you begin to
curve spacetime itself which I'll explain practically you can start to see this certain
type of phenomenology that you otherwise would not see so what do I mean by that for example
the Aronoff-Bohm effect shows essentially that they're that potentials themselves
more formally called the four vector potentials are actually more fundamental than physical fields
and I don't think a lot I know there's a lot of people privately that grasp it even better than
I do but I think publicly there are a lot of people that truly don't see that because it
maybe seems too esoteric or too magical or what have you but the idea here is that essentially
the electromagnetic vector potential can allow for the uh essentially the curving of spacetime
in a topological sense so in the laboratory you energetically start to get these caduceus
like waves that occur longitudinally that don't that are initially start off in a transverse sense
now in a very simple regard one way that spacetime itself could be curved would be having to do with
spinning for example a capacitor if you will because what you're doing from a mechanical
perspective is you're inducing curvature within that local vicinity of spacetime now
I'm paraphrasing here and forgive me for those that are watching this later on where if you look
up the actual quote I may be a little bit wrong here but Feynman said something peculiar which
is that when you are charging a capacitor you start to see the sparks come in on the edges of
the gap of the actual capacitor instead of where you're charging it from which implies that there's
some type of kinetic momentum if you will within the quantum vacuum or the ether that is right in
front of us that we don't have take a certain perspective to in order to be able to see it for
what it could be or what it could lead to so for example people look at the Aronoff-Bohm effect and
they think well what does this mean well it's possible that by implementing a vector and scalar
potentials electromagnetically you can start to induce curved spacetime phenomenologies topologically
that otherwise you could not do with a flat spacetime metric so from a if I may say from a
chemistry perspective say you have an acid and a hydroxide and you neutralize the two in the
laboratory but what happens is you don't get any exothermic reaction in other words you don't get
any heat the standard u1 model that assumes a flat spacetime says you will always get heat
there's nothing wrong with that standard model under the assumption that spacetime is always flat
but if spacetime is curved it's possible that you may start to deal with negative entropy or
neg entropy rather than entropy or linear forward moving entropy as we now know it to be so what
that means is we start getting these waves and phenomena that would otherwise not be realizable
because when you curve spacetime you start to induce a a caduceus like effect what's caduceus
a caduceus meaning essentially like two waves like the the serpent the medical symbol the serpent
moving around the yeah uh a staff yeah so the the actual serpent itself would be representative
of the waves or the same way if you think of our our dna double helix yep so to speak um and so
what happens is is that when you're in the uh when you see these effects with this acid and
hydroxide it's possible that there may be a negative energy aspect that is occurring which
means that you may have electrical effects in that experiment where the electricity is cold
instead of hot and this start this this also overlaps directly in the uh to the field with
low energy nuclear reactions cold fusion and so it gets very interesting because you start
to realize that there are these vortex like geometries in the laboratory whether it's with
chemistry whether it's with electrical engineering or so on or particle physics that otherwise you
would not get if you assumed a flat spacetime so what happens is if somebody says a scientist
may come in and say oh that's just sulfuric acid i would beg to differ they it would be sulfuric
acid if you unkinked the spacetime topology that the curvature of spacetime itself allowed you to
induce now if you unkinked it if you think of basically just two you know chains locking into
each other if you unkink those those chains or those fields if you will now you're back to a flat
spacetime but if you're dealing with curving spacetime you start to get these phenomena
that otherwise you would not you would not expect and to my knowledge at least are not um are not
taught within within uh you know certain schools um and institutions and so ideally so as far as
producing these effects are you saying that spacetime itself is actually curved or are you
saying that uh you can use high electromagnetism to curve spacetime spacetime um it wants to be
curved it so in other words you have to um mechanically or artificially induce curvature
in it and you do that through electromagnetism you can i was talking to uh you know a scientist
named bob maguire do you know him i've heard of him and and you know he was talking about um
the stress energy tensor right in einstein's equations right and you know how sort of
conventionally in uh you know physics if you have enough electromagnetism you should be able to
curve spacetime but we really just know that that occurs through mass because you have like
you know planetary cosmology where there's sort of this inward gravitational force right but it
doesn't really feel like from an engineering perspective we have the ability to create
you know the enormous amount of electromagnetism in order to curve spacetime
what do you think i this is a great question i appreciate it so i would say that we actually
can and we have privately um as humans without even needing to look at any type of reverse
engineered programs although i'm sure you know if one is working on a project and they're given
access to reverse engineered legacy programs they'd be able to you know cross reference
and make vast advancements let's talk about a guilt-free alternative to alcohol that's
perfect for your dry january or any time you want to unwind cornbread's organic cbd gummies these
gummies are an absolute lifesaver for my evening routine they're a natural way to relax celebrate
or wind down without the hangover i've cut back a lot on my alcohol consumption over the last few
years for a lot of you trying out dry january or cutting back generally it's not always easy but
swapping that glass of wine for cornbread cbd gummies is a total game changer it's a simple
upgrade to your evening routine that leaves you feeling great the next day without sacrificing
the fun plus with all natural ingredients they're the perfect way to stay balanced cornbread hemp
isn't just a product it's a small way to bring balance into your life whether you're journaling
meditating or simply enjoying some downtime these gummies elevate the experience without
any of the guilt it's like having a moment of calm in your pocket ready whenever you need it
alcohol doesn't have to be the default anymore whether you're cutting back for dry january
or just looking for a healthier way to relax you've got to try cornbread cbd gummies right now
american alchemy listeners can save 30% on their first order just head to cornbreadhemp.com
slash jesse and use code jesse at checkout again that's cornbreadhemp.com slash jesse code jesse
cornbread hemp this is the good life fellow alchemists it's a new year and that means it's
time to get organized and take control of our financial wellness for me rocket money has been
an absolute game changer it helped me uncover all sorts of subscriptions i totally forgot about
like a few i had no idea i was paying for months after i stopped using the services with rocket
money i canceled these in just a few clicks saving money instantly rocket money is a personal finance
app that helps find and cancel your unwanted subscriptions monitors your spending and helps
lower your bills so you can grow your savings seeing all your subscriptions in one place is
such a relief you know exactly where your money is going for the ones you don't want anymore
rocket money can help you cancel them no awkward phone calls no hassle just savings rocket money
also gives you a clear view of your expenses across all your accounts you can create personalized
budgets track your monthly spending trends and even set goals to save automatically for big
purchases paying off debt or just building your savings it makes staying on top of your finances
easy and stress-free rocket money has over five million users and has saved a total of 500 million
in canceled subscriptions saving members up to 740 a year when using all of the app's premium
features cancel your unwanted subscriptions and reach your financial goals faster with rocket
money go to rocketmoney.com slash jesse today that's rocketmoney.com slash jesse with that said i
believe that if you look at the work of salvatore paez so real quick when you say legacy so you
think that we do have ufos in our possession and we've like that's inspired a lot of modern
science i'm certain that we that there have been discoveries going back to the 50s that
humans have conducted from an experimental standpoint that have at the very least given
provided a proof of concept that show that we can induce these effects without and so do you not
believe like you know whistleblowers like david grush lou alazando who say that we have like
reverse engineering efforts within the government i i also believe that as well okay i believe that
as well i believe we're dealing with a mixed bag okay so to speak yeah i don't i don't take one
avenue i'm not a narrow-minded with regards to what i believe versus don't believe okay i think
we're dealing with a mixed bag and and and um so you're getting into sal paiz sal paiz for the
audience is a navy engineer who holds patents three extremely interesting patents
involving inertial mass reduction and you know exotic flight principles and that sort of thing
yes yes and i just interviewed him actually and so oh that's amazing yeah that's awesome that's
awesome he's he's a great guy he's a really good guy awesome guy i like him a lot yeah sensitive
oh he's a very very sweet guy very sweet guy um i think that to your question that we as humans
have made advancements um with regards to things like inertial mass reduction uh with regards to
things like the emission of high frequency gravitational waves um and if i could say very
quickly for the audience inertial mass reduction means you're basically reducing the mass of an
object so it begins to essentially fall up instead of the way that you would drop an object it begins
to essentially fall upwards because you're biasing the potentials of the mass of that object itself
and this is something that's been reported by you gain plakletin off and it's also and that goes
back to victor schauberger because his dad was actually a soviet agent that retrieved victor
schauberger's files yes and and but that also connects with this modern anti-gravity conspiracy
you have this woman named ning li who's at you know university of alabama huntsville and she
claims to have a mass reduction effect over a spinning superconductor and so you do you
basically believe both of those accounts i think there's there may be something there
with plakletin off um forgive me i have to be careful with regards to what i say about ning
li but what i can say about that is that um there is evidence of which i'd be happy to provide to
you afterwards where in the early 2000s she had sent an email to i i forgot who it was exactly
someone in the alternative propulsion community where she claimed she had generated about 11
kilowatts of high frequency gravitational waves well um the email messaging was then
intercepted by an ip address from west point and then from there you never heard from her again
um i know from there she wins this you know top secret military contract she gets a clearance
correct and yeah she she kind of falls off the face of the earth she leaves the university of
alabama huntsville yep you could just say oh her work fell off she was a quack or whatever but then
we found out since that larry smalley who was the head of the physics department at university of
alabama huntsville yep goes and joins her and larry smalley his name is on a patent in 2004
that basically involves uh an asymmetric barrel shaped capacitor and it's for nasa right and it
connects all the way back to towns and browns work and that was like the original kind of
anti-gravity guy who was using capacitors to exactly maybe manipulate space top exactly i
believe if i'm not mistaken ning lee was actually more focused on superconductors in a solid state
sense i know initially in the 90s she was collecting data on ring superconductors but i believe the
issue with spinning it after a certain threshold was that the the disks the the rings would begin
to break so i know she was looking into a more solid state aspect however there is a paper
that was released by bob baker under the miter corporation for one of the high frequency
gravitational wave conferences where you cannot actually access the entire paper just the abstract
introduction where i'm paraphrasing but bob baker talks about he's now since deceased but
he talked about how ning lee was able to generate up to 11 kilowatts of gravitational waves and
essentially there were two types of gravity that she had discovered which was ac gravity and dc
gravity so a static type of gravity and then an alternating current type of gravity under the notion
that gravity comes from the topological displacement of of matter topologies meaning essentially
you can use electromagnetism in a certain format in which would then at the next level above through
the curving of space time allow you to control gravity electromagnetically whoa wait explain
that and it's interesting you say two types of gravity because that comes up a lot
well you can also correlate that too and this is for your viewers and yourself to decide for
yourself to mr lazarez gravity a wave and b wave that's what i was going to bring up ac
ac gravity dc gravity it's possible my take on lazarez he was kind of a you know it's bob lazar
is but i mean the audience is definitely going to know who he is but like he claimed to have
worked at s4 area 51 reverse engineering ufos right and he also came out saying some interesting
things about the flight principles that these you know crafts used right and he talks about
two forms of gravity gravity a and gravity b right and i kind of have come to the conclusion
after researching lazar for a while that he was a limited hangout of a person right so like i think
this guy john lear who was cia affiliated right pushed him out to george napp and that for
whatever reason the powers that be wanted lazar out right but they wanted him out because i don't
think he had a super sophisticated theoretical physics understanding i think he had like more
of like a engineering topological physics i agree and so you have these you know it's almost like
gravity gravity a gravity b that's not saying too much right but if you're smart enough right
maybe you can get initiated or something figure that out right and that's why i say again i myself
am still uh 50 50 as to where i stand with the entire story of mr lazar um but i do think that
there are interesting correlations between what he claimed was the a and b wave and then
ning lee's ac and dc gravity waves so what are these two forms of gravity how do they work
so uh basically you have dc gravity that allegedly at least according to the the very
general abstract of her report and forgive me because um i can't really expand past this point
however the idea is that there's a static type of gravitational wave that does not depend on the
square root of the electric permittivity but rather depends on the strength of the source of
the magneto static field in which it's coming from and then there's ac gravity which is far
stronger and is is not static in any capacity it is it is something that you would utilize in a
pulsed base scenario in which would actually if you were to view its geometry would emit um the
same way that are uh in the same geometry that are uh that a caduceus or double helix would
interesting and then what gravitons gravitons correct for gravity particles right now i say
that because i think the term gravitons is still controversial in mainstream science however
there are papers that have since that were funded by the miter corporation going back 20 25 years
that show that gravitons were both very high frequency and extremely low frequency gravitons
were detectable near the earth's atmosphere now where why that hasn't been more publicly stated i
don't know i'd be happy to provide you the documents privately i also know that the soviets
before the soviet union fell were looking into uh essentially the notion that einstein's general
relativity was a very rudimentary static um uh understanding of space time itself um i know
einstein himself flip-flopped on the notion of the quantum vacuum or the ether yeah he first i think
he was for it then he was against it then for it then against it and i i'm not sure you know there's
rumors that he worked with nicola tesla before he passed as to whether that could be substantiated
or not i i don't know i wasn't around at the time well he definitely i think early on with special
relativity you know he was like relativity is not compatible with the ether and then i think in 1921
ish time frame right right he then says actually general relativity is compatible with the ether
but it was sort of silent people forgot about it correct and then you have quantum electrodynamics
and Feynman later and like the you know the vacuum of space is filled with energy and so he's kind
of like reinstantiating the ether sort of i think so i think so yeah but i want i want to get back
to gravitons sure because there's a really interesting article from 1956 called the g
engines are coming or something like that by this guy michael gladich and yes you know it's it's
all about how we have all these vital anti-gravity programs those anti-gravity programs are kind of
analogous to our atomic programs right and we're going to beat gravity and it's right around the
bend and uh in it is quoted i believe two scientists at princeton stanley desser and
okay it says these guys are working with we figured out g particles gravity particles
right and i find that to be such an interesting part of the article that like nobody really talks
about is like these guys are talking about gravity particles right exactly the all these um all these
publications and and whether it was in the literature or newspapers uh going back to the
1950s all the way to the 70s i've always said as i said to privately once the late 1970s hit there
are some papers still that came out in the 80s dealing with spinning gyroscopes with certain
electrical and other components applied to them where the spinning gyroscope would lose its uh
would lose some of its mass and then when the gyroscope was turned towards the earth's axis
or against the earth's axis depending which way you pointed it it would gain some of the mass back
so in other words it was conducted in magnetically shielded laboratories it was shown for example
that certain effects would occur that were that were not artifacts experimentally that could not
be ruled out um wow yeah so yeah how does doing all this stuff yeah how how did how does doing
these experiments allow for mass reduction the ideas that you can exchange now this is where
it becomes very esoteric but the idea is that you can exchange the internal mass of an object
um with the local environment or the local space time itself so the notion that energy cannot be
created or destroyed would be correct you're just basically cycling that energy in and out from the
object because of spin coupled to an electromagnetic induction field combined with uh something else
that i'll tell you off the air that that would that would allegedly prove this to or show at
least proof of concept that there would be mass reduction um and this is the work of salvatore
where he's saying that like if you couple spin with these specific electromagnetic charges
you can break the swinger limit you get this runaway the right now the idea is with regard
the the the swinger limit is essentially a very simply put the notion that after a certain um
threshold of uh electromagnetically uh the vacuum becomes non-linear yes so to speak i think it was
i forgot what it was 10 to the power of eight i don't want to say and hal putoff talks about
electrically polarizable vacuums as well so it's like i'm a big proponent of that and and then
you have this speech from jim rider who's a lockheed martin space systems guy who we now know tried to
transfer a quote unquote ufo to bigelow aerospace in 2008 according to lou alzano a bunch of other
people right and he's he talks about an electrically polarizable vacuum as well and maybe an interesting
analogy for the audience if you're like me and an idiot when it comes to this stuff uh like if you
had like a bat like a plastic bag with water in it right and you were to like press down on one side
that would be sort of electrically polarizing the vacuum and maybe you could surf space time as
right the same way a surfer surfs on water yeah water waves correct if we say there's a little
surfer figurine on the bag or whatever it surfs down exactly exactly and now that would be using
that would be using vacuum polarization as dr putoff i believe has a fantastic paper on
space time metric engineering excuse me that shows that now if i could clarify
as i understand it that is a little bit different than actually having a device that would emit
through pulsed based uh systems um high frequency gravitational waves however the physics are are
indeed interconnected uh very much so and and how do you get to a thing that emits high frequency
gravitational waves well there's there's speculation that very intense lasers could do it in um in
what's considered like a hall room array uh there's speculation that um uh you can use this is very
controversial but you can use superconductors to do it um there are speculation for example that
you could use certain geometrical setup of superconductors that could induce these effects
let's put it that way yeah interesting yeah so what useful stuff can you do it because we're
speaking really abstractly right now sure what can you do that changes the world with any of these
things you can essentially this is forgive me because this is where i'm going to have to be
careful but you can essentially do things for example from an energy perspective where maybe
and i say this speculatively it's possible that you can output more energy in a device than you're
inputting okay um which would imply coefficient of performance over one um which would violate the
second law of thermodynamics and there would need to be a readjustment to the law of conservation
of energy uh because you're dealing with a larger open system so if you implement the vacuum and the
vector and scalar potentials into your equations you could it would actually be feasible um the
second law of thermodynamics uh it would be completely violated because again it's possible
in these cases we would be dealing in some cases with electrical currents that are cold instead of
hot which is very controversial to say um that would be one aspect another aspect would be for
example the ability if for example as we see with dr halpudov's uh invention um where he had he's
using vector and scalar potentials to communicate that would be an extreme that is an extreme uh
breakthrough in revolution um another example would be the work of salpaez for example in which
you see that you could have craft that could basically be a a transmedium type of craft that
could go through water air etc without as if the water air didn't exist because the field around
the craft itself is voiding the the reality of space time itself as controversial as that is
so free energy uh building real ufos basically like exotic propulsion to the limit right and
then exotic communications as well correct that traverses space time and and even even healing
medical aspects that are again for example sorry to cut you off but um luke montagnier
his dna water teleportation uh paper do you believe that because i i've always found that
so this is by the way french nobel prize winner who discovered uh the genome for hiv right and
so he was lauded for that after that in his career he started getting this really interesting trippy
ideas one of which was that there are these aqueous nanostructures in dna that involve
communication semantic communication transfer and and um storage basically of information
right and he was kind of laughed out of the room from a conventional science perspective but you
think there's something i i strongly i would i'm not a gambler but i would bet money there's
something there you know i've always been sympathetic to it why why do you think there's
money there and then i can tell you why i'm interested um experiments i've witnessed
interesting yeah can you say anything more um unfortunately no one forgive me because i don't
mean to be like i i don't want to be overly vague well i can speak for you have you ever
heard of constantin mile i have okay so he's in the black forest in germany and he deals with
extended electrodynamics but from a kind of biological systems perspective right right and
he writes about dna resonance with you know specific longitudinal scalar longitudinal waves
actually one of the scalar waves is called heliochoidal right and so you might think you
know uh if if form follows function or function follows form that um you know if you have these
wave types that basically look like dna maybe they're meant for dna to be the receivers right
so there's also another guy named andre puharich who was very interested in extended electrodynamics
or extremely low frequencies and how they would affect kind of brain waves and and even semantic
information right and i if i could say i would dare to argue that all of what word we've been
discussing from the propulsion aspect all the way to the communications to the biological to the
energy aspect all deal with these longitudinal waves in some capacity or another there is a
harmonic component there's a sound component that has been completely um removed from uh the
teachings of of electrical engineering that in some aspects do exist in some uh institutions
regarding particle physics but um it essentially deals with an asymmetry within space time itself
that you could induce um through for example things like superconducting uh resonance circuits
or tank circuits as they're called um and certain avenues going down that road i do forgive me i do
have to be careful uh but yes there may be some resonance may be a significant aspect all of this
what is uh an aspect of this technology that we can speak about that you think will help the most
amount of people and be the least dangerous as far as describing the actual nuts and bolts
components of how it works because i'd love to get into like sure how some of these things
work close to the metal but i realize they're you know national security sensitivities and what i
you've now you haven't told me anything but my what i picked up from you know you came across
you know certain people uh entered your life or you came on their radar or whatever is that
when maybe you got these interesting downloads around science you were maybe you were maybe
tapped by people who are kind of in and around government circles right be my guess but that
that is correct yes um something uh well what's interesting is that i think uh without bringing
it up too too often i think that sal paez's patents and his work have been by far the most
revealing aspect of what propulsion uh could be applied to with regards to um essentially again
reducing the mass of an object and so on but i also think that um see this is the this and this is
where i'll be very blunt i i believe that this talk of metamaterials it's not that metamaterials
are are bad or are don't work or are a psyop not at all i think that they have a very fundamental
place in in in the field of physics and materials engineering absolutely however i think that there
has been and this is not towards any one individual in particular but there has been a narrative
pushed with respect to not discussing that you can use basic materials that we already have and
have known about for decades combined with electromagnetism to induce some of these effects
whether it's energy communication propulsion i think it's because some of these solutions
again taken with a certain perspective with a different perspective on old physics in some
cases could be so simple to engineer in some cases if one had access to you know a decent
amount of funding that it it is threatening to people that are looking to suppress this
so you think the alien narrative is sometimes tech protection is i believe there is a legitimate
aspect to it but i think in some cases yes so yeah i i hear that and then it's just extremely
confusing every time i'm like oh maybe it's just anti-gravity shit i'm like right i'll give you a
good example okay so like towns and brown is this mid-century anti-gravity guy i think he got like
really far you know made a documentary about him right and which was great oh thank you man
and uh he uh you know talks about a couple of materials so magnesium bismuth barium titanate
right um they're what's called high k dielectric so we have a high k factor you can store a lot of
electromagnetic charge right his experiment which involves a capacitor so negatively charged plate
positively charged plate you have to put this neutral insulator in between right and that has
a high when it has a high k factor you get more thrust so you pump electromagnetism into the whole
thing and you get this thrust from negative to positive right and so you know that in a way that
beats gravity so it's this exciting thing so he talks about magnesium bismuth barium titanate
and then you go i've interviewed gary nolan too stanford professor and he you know claims that
he has ufo crash parts that he received from jacques valet and it's magnesium bismuth right
right and so i'm like well maybe it's just anti-gravity or whatever right but then you
go deeper into towns and brown you realize that he started nightcap which is the first civilian ufo
tracking program in 1956 you could say that was just you know doing civilian counter intel for
you know like american anti-gravity crafts but you learn about these early stories from like you know
around the time that like dart before like the late 50s early 60s where he would go into the
field and and find stuff flashes credentials do crash retrievals basically and like he found this
green fireball thing and it was losing mass and apparently that was barium titanate and then he
himself had a ufo experience that inspired a lot of his work kind of like your thing interesting
so the whole thing gets weird where the second you're like maybe it's just anti-gravity stuff
you trip out and you're like i don't know i think it becomes yeah it starts to get very very to your
point it starts to get very very interesting because i think that it at this point in time
i think when we if there's a sighting of a uap i think that most of the time it's hard to tell
if that is human made whether a pure human the source of pure human ingenuity or whether it's a
little bit of that mixed with reverse engineering aspects or if it's something
or someone else entirely what i will say though is i think we need to look into high voltage
experiments that normally that tesla was was playing with that people these days seem to
not be interested in i think that why high voltage i think high voltage induces a polarizable effect
within the local vacuum wherever that voltage is being applied for example there was something
called the ebner effect i believe in the 1990s you can i can send you the details to this afterwards
dealing with essentially there was a small documentary put together i forgot from which
country in europe but essentially when extremely high voltage it was like half a million volts or
more were applied to crops they were growing in ways that the farmers had not seen ever
and so i think this is where it starts to get again very esoteric but the notion is that
the ether of the quantum vacuum has within it memory that are stored within these potentials
and these potentials when practically induced using high voltage could in fact enable a form
of vacuum polarization that can apply to biological systems propulsive systems communication systems
and so on and so forth in a way that we would not be able to detect or understand with our
current means of technological development it's for this is pretty freaky it feels like playing
god a little bit because yeah you're talking about how matter even comes to form or something
right first place right and like it's interesting you say that about high voltages you know half
million volts or whatever applied to plants you know towns and brown was extremely interested
in electro culture as well we lived on hawaiian would do all these experiments around you know
having plants grow in specific ways right electro culture yes um and and i look at the work of towns
and brown and tesla and they're very similar like what tesla was doing at wardenclyffe high voltages
short distances right where he's claiming to tap the ether for free energy seems to be somewhat
similar to what towns and brown i i agree and i think one of the things as we discussed earlier
before we started recording is that i think one of the concerns for in groups or elements that
don't want this to be discussed or come out is that or be disclosed in any capacity is that
once you open this can of worms it opens up a whole other set of discoveries
that people would otherwise not know that people would generally not notice unless they knew
that there's a form of um asymmetry in the vacuum using potentials that could be induced
to to create what is called higher symmetry electromagnetics using a vector and scalar
potentials and so i think that what starts happening is you start dealing with things
like again negative energy so cold electricity so cold currents for example so you get frost
bite if you if you were to touch a a wire with it with cold currents rather than you know as
normally now you get burned if you touch a wire that's got electrical currents would that allow
because i think about extremely cold you know circuits or materials right and you hear this
theory that maybe you know ufos or man-made you know crafts or whatever that exhibit these exotic
flight principles might be sort of acting like quantum macroscopic objects i agree as you know
i'm always on the hunt for things that help me stay sharp focused and full of energy while i'm
diving into life's mysteries and making this show happen and i've got to say mud water has completely
transformed my mornings back in the day i used to struggle with that post-coffee crash and let's
not even get into the caffeine jitters mud water gave me the smooth steady energy i was missing
it's packed with functional mushrooms like lion's mane chaga and reishi plus turmeric and cacao
all working together to keep me focused calm and grounded honestly it's like coffee went on a yoga
retreat and came back zen what i love most is that it's not just about replacing coffee it's a whole
new ritual it's a simple nourishing way to start the day and i actually look forward to it every
morning every ingredient is usda certified organic vegan non-gmo and there's zero sugar
it's energy that doesn't mess with your sleep or make you question your life choices at 3 a.m
ready to make the switch to cleaner energy head to mudwater.com that's mudwtr.com and grab your
starter kit today right now our listeners get an exclusive deal up to 43 off your entire order
plus free shipping and a free rechargeable frother when you use code jesse that's right up
to 43% off with code jesse at mudwtr.com after your purchase they'll ask you how you found them
please show your support and let them know we sent you keep your energy natural and refreshing all
year long with mudwater because life's too short for anything less than clean delicious energy
and so so uh to maintain quantum coherence like typically you need to be like you know extremely
cold or well i'm a big fan i'm a big proponent of the neils bohr model of the atom neils bohr
believed that superconductors were macroscopic atoms you told me that once and i blew my mind
what does that mean so the it's possible that superconductors could exhibit very um uh
quanta coherence quantum coherence that otherwise would normally be observed at the
plank scale or slightly above i think there's an entire aspect to superconductors including
things like the meissner effect and flux pinning that a lot of people just don't understand that
is right in their faces that if they truly viewed it in a different way could induce the type of
effects that we're discussing whether it's again you know the energy stuff the communication stuff
the propulsion stuff and so on and so forth and what i mean by that is when it comes to
superconductors the traditional theory that's referenced is the bard and cooper schaefer theory
called bcs theory i believe they all three of these gentlemen won a nobel prize for it
what that has left out as to whether this was conspiratorial or not i genuinely don't know
but what has been left out is has been dealing with lattice holes within superconductors so again
if you can polarize the lattice of a superconductor again we go back to polarization dr putoff's
polarizable vacuum approach and so on if we polarize the lattice of a superconductor or
of a metal of some sort it's possible we can start to get effects that would in fact again when other
engineering conditions are applied to the superconductor manipulate light manipulate
gravity and so on there was a paper from 1992 with douglas torning lee that showed that the
quantization for angular momentum in superconductors resides within the lattice holes of the
superconductor and not the cooper pairs the cooper pairs are attributed to the bcs
bard and cooper schaefer theory wow and so there's an entire little thrown out pocket of this that i
think should be looked at much more strongly and so how do you maintain coherence through the
lattice holes because you know i think about low temperature superconductors and cooper pairs and
right there are ways to explain that how do you explain that kind of deterministically uh well
essentially geometry a well you polarize the lattice but then the superconductor itself
maybe it's conical maybe it's cylindrical maybe it's a ring so to speak if you were to engineer
something that would that would match or fit or abide by the longitudinal waves if you were to
envision these slinkies all around us it's possible you may start to see effects that you otherwise
would not if you were dealing with just a square superconductor for example um it's possible that
these these effects may geometry is everything in my opinion when it comes to materials engineering
geometry is everything and so i think that you can witness certain effects in the laboratory with
you know four or five thousand dollars worth of experiment worth of material that if the
superconductor was not a ring superconductor if it was say a puck with no hole in it in the center
or it was a square superconductor um you would not see unless it were a ring superconductor
um it's possible again that these longitudinal waves are vortex-like in nature as well
so we need to materially engineer something that would abide by the geometry of what this
structure of these longitudinal waves are so that these transverse hertzian waves can then
overlap with one another and then create basically tap the um the vacuum fluctuations of the scalar
field that would other that otherwise you would not be able to do if hopefully that's an adequate
a lot of structures are like geometric inductors to convert electromagnetic waves to correct
the actual fabric of space time right correct so the idea is that like for generating high
frequency gravitational waves for example you need to oscillate the mass of a quadrupole a quadrupole
is when you have two dipoles that a dipole is a is the space between two atoms with a positive
and a negative charge the idea is that a quadrupole when you oscillate that you you can actually emit
gravitational waves from it now the if you could do it using superconductors and i say that carefully
if it would be in a very low energy format so you would not you would not like induce a you know
emit gravitons that would you know break a door down or something but if you could find a way
to pair that with the strong nuclear force then you may be able to and i i also again believe
that's what uh dr payez's some of his work was trying to allude to wow okay so you have these
lattice structures right in these conductive materials right and that allows for electromagnetism
to sort of interact with space time in exotic ways geometrically right so we initially talked
about spinning you know a capacitor which would be a mechanical version but a solid state version
would be using a superconductor in for example immersed in liquid helium for example liquid
helium is far more effective to induce these effects effects compared to liquid nitrogen
but the idea would be that the electrons move along a path that they normal that is asymmetrical
because the lattice is asymmetrical because when you polarize the lattice you induce you break the
symmetry of that lattice so you get now these non-linear effects that if we go back to when
we first started talking when when a lattice is symmetrical it is basically abiding by a flat
static space time when a lattice is now asymmetrical you're curving space time the
electrons start to move in a non-linear sense so when you break the lattice then you're having
the electrons move in this non-linear way when you break the symmetry of any particle field
no i shouldn't say particle field when you i have to watch my words here forgive me when you break
the symmetry of space time itself and in some cases that would be polarizing the lattice of
a superconductor for example you can get these non-linear effects that are the result of
electromagnetic induction but become become something else entirely topologically fascinating
so what does it become that's different topologically at that point you can start
to bend light you can start to have this pairing of electricity and gravity this goes back to the
the missing heavy side equations i know there's a lot of controversy surrounding
did heavy side butcher maxwell's equations or not it is i can what i can say is that it is well known
to my knowledge behind the scenes that there's an entire heavy side component that misses that
basically misses a circuit from an engineering aspect now what i mean by that is back in the
early 1900s heinrich lorenz he did something that was called symmetrical regaging of maxwell's
quaternions because maxwell was told you're not going to be able to get your quaternions across
to the engineers at the time which had the education of electricians today so you have
to chop it and get it simpler you have to only deal with the right angle vector and nothing
outside of that vector field basically and what's outside of that vector field the scalar potentials
now essentially what happened was lorenz threw the baby out with the bathwater again i don't know
if this was a you know conspiracy or not i don't i wasn't there at the time but the entire lorenz
regaging aspect has basically um how can i put it stagnated the the mainstream field of of particle
physics and for the audience the lorenz equation is the sum of the vector and scalar potentials
and lorenz sets this to zero right correct what he did was he played a clever trick when he chopped
up maxwell's quaternions and for the audience if i may say in a very simple manner say you say to
me dave let's order a pizza the pizza comes and i say to you there's 12 slices but i say to you
jesse there's only one slice and you go dave what do you mean there's another 11 slices and i go no
no no ignore the 11 there's just one that's basically what lorenz did wow that's i'm in
a very simple regard that's basically what lorenz did now by doing that he played a clever trick he
said and i quote he didn't deny that the energy outside the vector field existed he didn't deny
that the scalar potentials existed but what he said was and i quote they have no physical
significance that's basically it's like it's basically saying that you you're throwing the
baby out with the bathwater and i know that there was um forgot who said this but it's like saying
we have a boat right on the water and we have all this wind around the boat but the wind is
not touching our boat it's not pushing our sail so what so well it's a problem because theory is
supposed to be a descriptor of ontological reality right to the extent that it can be and you believe
science can be a descriptor of reality right it's an attempt at that it should never be
narrowly confined to present engineering capabilities because in the future engineering
capabilities will always you know be get that much more amazing so you do all these exotic
things with materials in the 1970s and 80s that you couldn't you know in the 1890s i couldn't
agree more you don't want to like constrain that within an equation exactly and i do believe with
the utmost respect to theorists although i i know for a fact behind the scenes the theory is well
understood and top theorists understand this um with that said i do believe that there are certain
calculations within theoretical physics that may seem very miniscule or may seem like an artifact
at first but when if you could take those equations and apply a form of practical
engineering to it you would get phenomena that would then um force the theorists to
readjust their model to the new phenomena that you see in the lab theory itself is not going to take
like like Feynman said it best and he was a theorist he said i don't care how beautiful your
theory is how eloquent it seems if it can't be engineered it's wrong if it can't be experimentally
verified it's wrong and so i think that as we know richard feinman and john wheeler calculated
there's enough energy inside the size of a coffee cup to evaporate all of the world's oceans if you
could practically get it up in there at first they thought it was an artifact of the mathematics
but it turns out that it's not and so basically when lorenz resymmetrized the the the maxwell's
quaternions he completely removed all the potentials dealing with the outside of the
right angle vector the vector field itself and so i think that this has to do with for example
dr putoff's vector and scalar potential communication where there are no e and b
fields but you have toroidal geometries that exist in which you can transmit information
through um topological infolding and out folding as david bohm used to call it basically the idea
that if you have a particle inside that part that particle is made up of smaller versions
of the same particle so in other words fractals that tend to fold in and out geometrically if you
could electromagnetically create such an effect in that regard and these potentials may be able
to enable that there's a lockheed martin patent called a coherent matter wave beam that deals
with using the erinoff bohm effect basically using the potentials themselves not the fields
but the potentials to cohere matter itself in a way that would basically
self-organize the particles was yeah so there's a lot there that we program matter or something
like how do you do that well that's the thing the idea is that spacetime itself is a i say this
carefully a living structure that has memory and so what happens is is if you can induce these
vector and scalar potentials in an engineering sense you start to witness geometries that would
otherwise you would not be able to notice with the standard hertzian waves in an in an engineering
regard i know that that's very controversial to theorists although i i know theorists behind the
scenes that are that openly say no this has been known for decades very in a very confidential
regard so okay let's get really specific with the put off stuff sure he's talking about quantum
communications via these uh scalar and vector potentials correct correct so how do you do that
so i think about like a classic example with a limit to a transverse hertzian wave is you're
trying to do undersea communications you have a perpendicular you know magnetic field a b field
and you know as a result of that you're going to get a lot of electron pair off in a you know very
fast decay function on any sort of signal sent out underwater right how do you get around that
with something like you know put offs it's possible like we talked about voltage focusing
purely on voltage um focusing on um acoustic resonance but specifically like what would you
do like how would you i think there are certain things that if you if you used voltage and pulsed
the superconductor for example you would be able to a transmit information in a non-linear regard
that otherwise if you that otherwise would not be possible uh using e and b fields okay if speaking
high level yeah yeah um i think that um pulsing superconductors with pure voltage is is very
interesting have you heard the term topological insulator absolutely so this is something i'm
just learning about because i have a friend who kind of works in some sensitive areas in
national security he goes pseudonymously by the name jack and we've started to interview you know
do the technical series together and speak to people who are honestly above my pay grade when
it comes to science like he helped me out on the pious interview for example oh amazing okay and
um he talks about these topological insulators these materials that barium titanate magnesium
bismuth are examples of yep is is that the type of superconductor that if you pulse you might be
able to engage in some sort of quantum comms with uh that and also there are multiple ways to skin
this cat that's the thing everything we've been talking about there are multiple ways to pursue
this however i think whether it's barium titanate whether it's yttrium barium copper oxide there's
a couple of uh low temperature superconductors with high temperature combinations using voltage
and acoustic resonance could in fact be able to transmit information that never decays um that
would i don't mean for the record i don't mean to speak for dr putoff but i i find his work
absolutely fascinating his entire set of papers on his earth tech website is every is uh acted
as a mentor type guide to me uh yeah there are things there that are revolutionary in a way that
is like it it it would break people's minds with regards to wait you're telling me that this type
of approach can be taken and all of a sudden we get these effects that we're that are considered
beyond the pale uh from a mainstream sense how should we view this from a because like from a
pure like science and civilian sector right you know you're telling me that you have these quantum
comms that like don't decay over space time you know that seems like the way an advanced alien
race would communicate that seems like it would be this massive exciting unlock for society how
do we view this from a national security perspective because i tried to get in touch with a guy named
lee hiveley who's you know working in extended electrodynamics and a friend that uh you know
helped with facilitate that you know he got in trouble yeah hively freaked out and was like you
know you shouldn't be shouldn't be reaching out to me and i think he put like the you know navy
press or something on the thread yep and i was just like hey man i just wanted to have a
conversation and 99 of you know my stuff is is offline right and i always say publicly if i'm
told that for serious national security purposes i should stop covering a specific thing i will
always do it right right and anyway so but i usually don't get the door shut in my face but
i did with highly i can give you an extended electrodynamics well i can give you an example
of what this vector and scalar potentials could do other than communication that would that would
overlap into national security for example you could use this similar method to surveil a room
without cameras interesting uh you can use the potentials that exist all around us right now
in the quantum vacuum to surveil an entire room how would you do that um that i can't get into
unfortunately but the but it is possible it's very possible if you can use use it for communication
why not in other areas and i i know for a fact it's it's possible there were i know a group that
is working in the government that has been working on this since the 90s and they've had
massive success it's it's not like an ongoing-ish prototype it's been established they're just
working on multiple new versions of it do you think humans themselves like were like these
hard drive avatars or something of something higher because i think about you know dna uses
binary code so agct you basically just have you know base pairs you have two two combos
i'll tell you something i'll tell you something i think of dna if you want that that is highly
controversial but yeah tell me i think there's a third strand to our dna i think that the two
helixes that we're used to i think there's a third one down the middle that exist that is
physical but exists at the plank scale and i think it's electrically conductive how would that not
dawn on like all these biologists and geneticists you've interviewed someone who knows okay i think
i know you're talking about you've interviewed somebody who knows yeah yeah the initials gn
no comment okay interesting well that's a that would be pretty fascinating
and what would that mean implications wise well it would mean that what we call junk dna is not
junk first off there was junk dna is prosaically understood by geneticists and biologists the idea
that there's a third strand that would be controversial correct and it's possible that
third strand is again it may overlap with luke montagnier's dna water teleportation aspect
i don't claim to be an expert in that area with that said i do believe that there is something
there i would go one step further and say that there there's there is something there and
actually you know what i'll say it there's a gentleman that was a not not dr gary nolan
but there's another gentleman that i can tell you the name of after and show you the evidence
of in which i wrote up a manuscript dealing with the third strand of dna this is a two or three
years ago and they were willing to help me put it in a peer-reviewed format to help it be reviewed
in the more international literature unfortunately that individual was restrained from being able to
help me and so biologics and and the field of medicine and dna was not my area of focus and
so i kind of let that go with that said there was a gentleman peter gary yev he was nominated for
the nobel prize in 2019 or 2020 the nomination was retracted and he later died i believe under
mysterious circumstances he was using vector and scalar potentials through polarization methods to
heal people using sound and light wow he was he has it's i believe his wife still runs the website
and it's still up um i believe it's called uh linguistic wave genetics dot com i believe um
if you google it it's in russian but you can translate it there is an english version of the
website and you have all of his papers with all of his engineering methodologies um and he was
healing people inside of pyramids a wooden wooden pyramids that were and this is not me so you want
to something trippy you know brian merescu is by any chance i've heard the name he's um you
read a book called the immortality keys really good guys buddy of mine he texted me earlier today
um because he's like man i've just been getting into the work of this guy constantine mile
and it explains a lot of my work around like you know scalar and vector potentials and its
effect on the human body right i've been interested in this for a while and it it's
it's interesting a lot of things seem to be convergent so so this guy was treating people
with pyramids uh pyramids he was having them go inside these pyramids that were
the the frame was wooden however he was using um vector and scalar potentials using uh
electronic circuits lasers semiconductors and so on to create a field in which when the person was
in that pyramid uh when they would they're again controversial but their um their ailments would be
healed whether it was depression or whether it was more of a physical ailment i don't want that
um this goes again back to the polarization of of a lattice of a material this goes back to the the
notion of voltage with potentials um the idea is that everything has memory so for example my hand
although it's aging right now the skin and everything it's possible that you can actually
actually let me give you a a very basic example so think of a stack of 10 books
now imagine we exist on book 10 we consider that as the present physical moment if you will yeah
and so it's possible that the previous let's say the previous books represent points in time that
were previous in which your hand was at a younger stage it's possible that you can use a polarizable
vacuum approach to bring say book three up to book 10 presently and replace book 10 with book three
meaning basically now your the skin is younger from a time temporal perspective and the entire
composition of the body is of that body you've body part you've treated is now literally younger
because of the negative and negantropic time reversal aspect that you've you've now implemented
using vacuum polarization using uh uh voltage and photons and light and and so on interesting
so biology does decay i guess via entropy it it it becomes more sort of yeah chaotically did you
know almost uh disassociates or something we we we disincarnate over over a period of time and
that's why we age or something there was a study sorry to interrupt you there was a study i believe
in the 70s which um basically showed that there was an observation in which a uap was hovering
near some plants and as an individual approached the uap the uap shot off as many people have
experienced however when the plants that were close to the uap were analyzed they had aged
10 years within x amount of hours it's called senescence so now yes no senescence but i mean
yeah i mean that would be the conventional term you go to chernobyl there's a study that came out
or not even a study an article that came out like this month i think about these dogs at chernobyl
that have rapidly evolved more than any other dog think about it right like it's it's easy like
uv radiation promotes you know genetic mutations or whatever right is differential selection and
that creates evolution right right and so if you were to grow a frog in a faraday chamber it would
grow you know kind of messed up and then if you're growing in a high radiation environment it would
grow you know grow too fast or whatever and so right yeah there's some sort of uh equilibrium
a la the shuman resonance of the earth this this magnetosphere of the earth that allows life to
form right and so i could see why a lot of this work would be pretty controversial because you're
kind of messing with the soup that we're all swimming in shuman resonance right it's been argued
that that is the the heartbeat of the planet so to speak yeah exactly right and that the reason
on the surface that the frequencies are so low is because you have to get closer into the center
of the earth for the frequency to get higher what if it's possible that the vector and scalar
communication potentials we were talking about again there are no electric or magnetic fields
purely toroidal geometries and when i said acoustic resonance what if that's the shuman
resonance that i'm that we're speaking of what if the shuman resonance can never disappear so to
speak from a from a field or from an area but e and b fields can but that resonance never does
because it is part of a more core makeup of this reality wow that's that it's i think you're i would
argue very strongly you're talking about the same thing there we're talking about acoustic resonance
or shuman resonance with regards to if you have a room like the room we're in now and we removed
all e and b fields yeah and there but there were still these resonant toroidal geometries um you
can overlap rf radio frequencies with acoustic uh frequencies and so these toroidal geometries
may in fact stem from uh the shuman resonance of the planet interesting so you would say that
the acoustic frequencies are sort of downstream of these rf frequencies that come from shuman
resonance or i'm saying that when you remove electric and magnetic fields and you deal purely
with potentials you you have still a resonance there interesting this goes back to what the
germans called the zitterbuegung meaning basically that from in quantum theory a particle is never
still so when we think of zero point energy the reason we call it zero point energy as i understand
is because when you get to absolute zero the particle is still oscillating classically we
think that like when you push a kid on a swing and then the kid jumps off the swing and the swing
comes to rest classically we're told we think that the swing is truly still but at the plank level
the particles that make up that swing are constantly oscillating still so all reality as
we see it is derived from some sub quantum field of arguably arguably that it's derived
yes that the potentials are more fundamental than the fields themselves and what determines how
these potentials sort of collapse i i'm i don't want to say because it starts to overlap into
stuff that's pretty uh sensitive okay uh forgive me but um it's it does the mind have anything to
do i i believe i believe so i believe that i believe that at the core of it we're dealing
with non-physical sources here with what people have called spiritual um uh sorry i thought you
were going down another avenue that's why i said i couldn't speak on it but if you're going down
the spiritual or the the consciousness avenue i'm very i'm open to talk about that i think that
at the core of it we start getting to non-physical uh uh energies that otherwise give rise to uh
physical matter and material have you built anything with your newfound knowledge that
you can talk about uh the stuff i have built i i can't speak on okay that's the forgive me
i wish i could but that's all right okay um do you feel like after having gotten into some of these
esoteric science you know concepts that it's made you a more spiritual person oh absolutely
absolutely this is the part where most people i know that you're very open to this and as i've
said before we recorded i have great respect for you because you're so open to it um amongst other
things but yes i believe the spiritual aspect is the key fundamental core of all of this as much as
people will people are so interested in physical things i believe that the spiritual or slash
metaphysical angle is the core of all this without a shadow of a doubt i me personally i think that
the soul if you will is possibly a boze einstein condensate um uh matrix or a plasma matrix of
sorts what is it boze einstein it's a lay it's a level of or a field of a tier of matter if you
will above plasma so you have solids liquids gases plasma then you have boze einstein so
and then there are more than that to what extent those have been divulged publicly i i don't know
you have levels of energy above i didn't even know you have levels of energy above plasma that's
that's where that's what doctor in my opinion not to speak for him but that's what dr paez
spoke about when he was on kirchheim mungo's theory of everything when he said that it's
possible that you can induce these types of effects like inertial mass reduction and so on
not with solids but with plasmas because it's possible that plasmas act as a doorway between
uh the quantum vacuum and the physical world so to speak it's so if you think how does that work
uh in a very basic manner example the way i gave the example of like the pizza slices
for the maxwell the lorenz gate regaging and all that if you think of the quantum vacuum all around
us as moving very very rapidly maybe faster than the speed of light or maybe at the speed of light
um think of a bunch of doorways moving quickly side to side and they're moving so fast you
can't grab one of the handles to open the those doors plasma acts as a medium that slows down
those doors so you can grab a handle and open it explain that plasma it's possible plasma slows down
uh uh quantum vacuum fluctuations and how does it slow down quantum vacuum fluctuations it's a it's
a it's an in-between state between a physical medium and a non-physical medium you see what
i'm saying so it acts as so it's like a carrier for the correct the potentials in some way the
same way that i would say uh that the work of sal paez's inventions not to speak for him but i
know that he agreed with me when i brought it up to him the devices themselves including the you
know rumored free energy devices and so on they're not generating the free energy they're acting
more as facilitators between the quantum vacuum and the material world they're not actually
generating in some cases they might be but in terms of even various forms of of energy generators
that are based in zero point uh zero point fields or zero point when we when we talk about virtual
particles right is free energy essentially uh the extraction of virtual particles into real
particles that in some cases yep uh you can argue if if one could get a coefficient of performance
over one that would be the case in some there's more than one way to skin this cat and that's
absolutely one avenue yeah and then one way is through like plasma is like this conduit it's
between the potentials world and like the world we see or something yep basically yeah have you
heard of uh ken shoulders absolutely exotic vacuum objects so how does that relate to this
i think what ken shoulders was doing was he was experimenting with curved space time uh uh
materials that induced the effects that happen when space time is not flat but curved so in other
words i believe ken shoulders had an experiment and please correct me if i'm wrong where basically
he found that electrical pulses into a ceramic would break not break ceramic but create these
punctures in the ceramic that electricity normally wouldn't do it's possible he was
interacting with a slight gravitational field in those with that with what he was doing now
another example is semiconductors and this is not well known but in the field of semiconductors
at least publicly to my knowledge when you when you're dealing with and forgive me if i butcher
this to those that are watching in the semiconductor field in the particularly on the manufacturing
but when you're dealing with the doping of the core lattice of a semiconductor yeah if you were
to take that core lattice and give it to audio experts to then analyze you would hear this non-stop
hum and that goes back to what we talked about with the zitterbuegung that the germans called
the the uh the swing stopping but there's still being every piece of matter is still oscillating
it's possible that hum is an electromagnetic interaction with the subtle gravitational field
whoa it's possible i'm not saying it is i'm saying it's possible because i don't know
it's interesting because that often is described around ufos as you hear this humming noise
that's really interesting yeah have you have you heard of burkhard heim i have i said this was this
german scientist who's working on some interesting kind of anti-gravitic you know stuff and then he
was brought over to the u.s and i think he worked with lockheed martin or martin corporation pre
lockheed merger martin marietta and martin marietta and i think they had a martin corporation at least
had a program called rias which was their anti-gravity research outfit got you and i
believe burkhard heim did contract work for them a lot of his work is in german but i believe he has
two errors on the theoretical physics side two guys named rusher and hauser okay they also believe
in two forms of gravity canonical like small scale gravity and large scale gravity and they
say one of these forms of gravity bind with electromagnetism more tightly specifically i
think some of these more exotic electromagnetic experiments involve i agree this sort of binding
i would agree i would agree i think that what they're saying there unless i'm interpreting
incorrectly is identical to what i was saying earlier in our conversation about how gravitational
effects could come from the electromagnetic conditions inducing topological states that
would lead to the coupling to the gravitational field that could then through the strong nuclear
force actually literally create you know have a you know more space time itself you know time
displacement would have you a situation where the inside of the craft is larger than the outside
you know space time metric engineering as dr putoff talks about i think there's something
there with superconductors and and semiconductors and high voltage that we already know secretly
can be done with that where do you think we are as far as ability to make progress on this because
my general sense is like if you had a governor placed on physics over the last 50 years
you know like the governor on an engine where you can only go to 25 miles per hour and the governor
in this case is like the speed of light as the speed limit right it's einstein's positivity
conditions on his field equations right it's uh you know no no scalar field you know you say
the governor is a bunch of different things right right right all those seem and that the governor
is your consciousness has nothing to do with your matter interactions you know whatever the
governor's coming off on all of those things at once is what it feels like right and so what does
that mean because i you have all these different you know dynamics at play you have the national
security state probably wanting to push this to the extent that it's not tipping the hat to the
adversary right you have all this civil side need for this just as far as our cities are in decay
like airplanes have not improved over the last 50 years at all you have this there's a duopoly
there's an energy crisis right now i believe in north america as well there's an i mean well we
have we have fracking and stuff but like right yeah i mean like there should be some update there
as far and and maybe even an update beyond you know uh nuclear fission plants right and so you
know and there there are startups working on nuclear fusion but they're often working on it
from the super sisyphean perspective of these tokamak reactors where right the energy necessary
to create these high-powered lasers is just sort of self-defeating if you're trying to
create free energy in the first place it's like right why would you do this i think there have
been to your point i think there have been discoveries that make the white world of physics
i don't want to say laughable because i have tremendous respect for the people that generally
are not in the know and that just genuinely are trying to do good research but the implications
i think to your your main the core of your question i think we're at a time right now
where and i'm not speaking for anyone other than myself but from my little corner of the world i
think that we're dealing with multiple factions or elements of both government and private industry
that are that have vast influence on what could or could not be revealed and i think right now
there's an issue of no one really knows what to do yeah and i because if you if you reveal some
then what you know of a you know a technological advancement then people are going to take it and
run with it and then that's going to open up a whole other avenue of research that admittedly
can be weaponized pretty easily if someone has a nefarious mindset yeah so i do actually understand
to a significant extent the necessity for not divulging this in some cases now in other cases
i also think however that we should not let the the the carte blanche answer of national security
impede our spiritual and technological development yeah so i'm not saying i know what the answer is
i'm saying that it should be talked about more and all the people you've had on have been fantastic
to help move this this forward i think you've played a crucial role in this but as to how the
line can be drawn i'm not going to sit here and pretend like it's easy it's it's effing tough
it's not easy yeah it's it's it's not easy because you open up one aspect of of zero point energy
engineering yeah next thing you know all of a sudden you know this guy's got uh this guy's
got cold fusion going and then that leads into maybe a coefficient of performance over one um
then that leads to all of a sudden you know with some adjustments all of a sudden you're now
basically doing what ken shoulders did you you pulse this um you know this this electromagnetic
energy into a piece of a ceramic or something and all of a sudden it breaks the ceramic when
you would expect it normally not to uh all this type of stuff and i think then you then have to
ask okay what and again this becomes an issue because it sounds like i'm trying to say that
there should be gatekeepers but i don't think there should be but at the same time you turn
some of these we have mutual friends that are privately working on some of these things where
with with you know half a year's worth of work six seven months worth of work in the lab all
of a sudden it's a weapon now and if someone gets a hold of that weapon it's game over for for a lot
of people the world's getting weird man i know it's interesting like it's like if you think about
um social control systems right hierarchies right maybe you had like religious hierarchies
of the past yes and then you have like compromise based like epstein ditty weird
shit like that yep and then you get like lower latency into like phones and laptops and digital
stuff and then you get into even weirder territory of like mind matter like you know the latency of
like these control systems and like maybe we're starting to see you know more anomalous stuff in
the sky like the veil is dropping correct it's weird i agree i think that the veil is dropping
and i think that people in general are starting to wake up more and without getting too esoteric
i think that there is a profound reason for that that is the the sum of our collective
consciousnesses speaking to something larger than what we could possibly fathom currently
yeah it's a it's a really fascinating time have you ever seen a ufo uh oh yeah i've there uh my
old house there were there were a few that would be above it above the house there are few that
were above three three in total over the course of five years yeah i mean i've seen i've seen
a i've seen a bunch of them yes if you just first instinct what do you think they were
why were they around your house i i wish i could say i don't know i i i really don't know it was
very interesting um my father said to me hey come take a look one time one of the three times and
it was your typical it was like a donut shaped craft how for you like what's your what's your
dream with this stuff what do you what do you want to do that's that's that's a good question
i didn't actually i didn't expect you to ask me that uh because it's a it's a good question i
think um i think i want to help people as much as i can um with regards to understanding this stuff
which is why i privately consult for private groups in in certain areas and then there's
other projects that i work on that i i have to be honest i wrestle in a moral sense with
with even discussing divulging or not because um i've spoken with some very uh respectable high
level people in in the in the department of defense and some of those in which you know and
the advice has always been people it's it's people will not see what you see so it's it's in many
cases uh i think you would you as jesse would but i but the because i you're you jesse if i
could say quickly you're not the type of guy where if i showed you something you'd be like oh how can
i weaponize this but others would be and that's where i'm kind of like well i'll i'll i'll make
my living with the consulting right now and and working on private projects and so on for people
because as much as i want to you know open source it if you will there's an argument to be made that
there have been people in the past that have open sourced it and then people just don't believe it
yeah i know i i i think that's fair man i mean like there's a real argument to be made that like
the next claus fuchs you know the guy that like stole the american atomic secrets worked at los
almos from 1941 to 1950 went to the soviets with all that stuff is like somebody who just kind of
runs their mouth on social media and like it brings up i don't know i mean like yeah they're
like it's like we're both you know friendly with ashton forbes the mh370 stuff i'm not at all uh
equating him to claus fuchs but i have these conversations with him uh about the mh370 videos
you know these are this these orbs teleporting the you know the malaysian airplane in 2014 was
this big news story cnn was talking about for three months this plane went missing nobody knew
where the plane some weird circumstances around the plane and then you have this video come out
that you know maybe it looks like they the these orbs just like teleported the plane right it's
really bizarre right and now he's getting into all sorts of free energy and you know exotic physics
stuff and i have these conversations with him and he's like so i think it's this can create a death
weapon that will end the world but it needs to come out and i'm like dude i don't think either
of us are smart enough to know and be high conviction that that's definitely the case
like you hear things you have intuitions around that maybe it is the case right um but if you
think that's the case and that is your intuition and you think this could be extremely dangerous
in dual use it's really irresponsible to like just put a lot of this stuff out willy-nilly
and it's the reason why with the towns and brown stuff that i put out i'm like
uh that's like you know it's this 70 year snapshot from a long time ago but i'm like
i'd love to know if somebody was like you know hey if this this is a there's one line from a
biography of towns and brown you know it's paul shatskin book the man who mastered gravity where
it's you know uh this will make a thermonuclear bomb look like a child's firecracker yes and
yes you hear that i don't know if you take that at face value but if if i heard that
that was the case i would never touch this stuff again and you've hit the nail on the head with
regards to what i was trying to convey to you just now that's exactly the problem so but d are you
high conviction that these things could be weaponized in like an extra world catastrophic way
or i am of high i would put money on it really i would put money on it that's so then what i
don't say that proudly so what do we do because on the one hand you have interstellar travel and
like that'd be great if we get that right and you have like all these cool updates you get well i
think i think i don't want to here's the thing i don't want to i wish i could i could sit here
and say jesse i have a an alternative plan i i don't with that said i think that what we're
seeing now with the discussion right now of meta materials and again i'm not trying to say that
they're not i'm not trying to say they're worthless there's a lot of value especially
you know layered semiconductors and blah blah blah but and and you know mixed with different
alloys and all that but the the point i'm trying to make is that i think
i think that's why the meta material angle was taken with regards to always saying we don't know
how the physics of it works and there's meta we do know how it works i'll blatantly say we know
exactly how it works we blame but if you if you just talk about the materials then it's like
uh you're ignoring the the physics the physics more dangerous if someone can take the theoretical
physics and apply it to experiments yeah yeah dangerous if you can bridge those two worlds
not a lot of people some people can but some people can look at the theory and go oh my god
i can make this and make that and make that other people only know how to engineer stuff and other
people only know how to do theory which is still fantastic but if you can have someone that can do
both yeah you have a problem or you have you you also it's a it's a half glass full half glass
empty type scenario that's interesting because i was on the phone um with a new friend who is
making a documentary about balbozar okay and i'm just speaking off the cuff and i'm like you know
it would be an amazing interview i was like i really want to interview man i'll do anything to
get in a room with this guy right right i'm like why don't i bring in this like a well-respected
theoretical physicist right and he can translate some of the stuff that balbozar was saying as
far as gravity a gravity b that sort of stuff right and the call kept cutting when i was saying
that and i'm like oh interesting maybe and then i think about it for a second and i'm like if the
theory i have about balbozar is right which is he was this limited hangout of a person sort of
meant to reveal certain info but meant to hold back the rest yep then you wouldn't want to
translate you know his stuff into like broader theoretical physics language you want to keep it
lowbrow and somewhat stigmatized but still be this initiation path what i to your point what i
will say is that there's information on the internet that has been out there for since the
internet almost since and to the powers that be i won't do that i'll just i'll just talk to lazar
there's information out there that has been being uploaded to the web since almost the uh the the
the birth of the internet which up until this day which as as the information is scattered out there
right now on the web is harmless but if it gets compiled in a particular order it becomes highly
sensitive that's that's a legitimate thing and so the hard part is sifting the wheat from the chaff
so to speak but if you can even to a to a even you know to a minimal extent it become that's when
one's own this is where i think the push for the spiritual angle of things is necessary like when
danny sheehan talked about we need to emphasize the spiritual component of this i couldn't agree
more with mr sheehan when he says that i think that that's one of the reasons why the alleged
stories of et visitations saying to our government leaders you have to develop spiritually before we
can exchange more technological information with you or or material with you i think that's because
that deals with the moral aspect and and spiritual responsibility of not uh blowing ourselves up and
worse and worse it may be you know we talk about the messing with time temporal displacement um i'm
familiar with that with a newspaper clipping uh from toronto canada from the 19 late 50s early
60s that talked about how there was a gentleman that invented a death ray but for the people that
came to go visit him there were some mosad uh representatives that went to go see him they
reported missing time meaning their watch show whoa right and i'll show you the article tomorrow
they reported that when they were in his living room or his basement i forgot which part of his
house he was experimenting in 25 minutes had gone by for them but they when they came outside
the other the external clocks that showed that two hours went by and the mosad showed great
interest and i believe he sold it to um to the uh this is literally in the article the the the
zionist regime of of of israel in particular he stated uh wait what yeah yeah i'll show you the
article tomorrow he sold some like sold that it was i don't want to say what it's like a timeline
manipulator no initially it was like a death ray of some sorts uh that he was working on
uh it's a it's a two-page article very old um someone like photocopied it and or scanned it
and put it on the web uh but it was essentially a death ray of sorts and some of the side effects
of when he turned it on was temporal displacement in within the vicinity of that's interesting i
mean i don't know if that's seems so wild to me but there's there's this um uh you know tesla
biographer i was speaking to recently right and he was talking about how tesla um you know would
do some of these high voltage experiments and he would say weird things like i see the future the
president of the past all at once right and towns and brown was extremely interested in time
alteration time travel yep do you think and then the final thing is you know there's a guy named
timothy taylor's a nasa mission controller right who's written about in diana pesulka's book
called american cosmic he is a successful nasa mission controller that works on like you know
spacex missions and stuff at cape canaveral right and he told i guess chris bloodsoe who's
had experienced all these sort of ufo sightings at his house for whatever reason tim taylor shows
up at his house and they become friends right and he tells uh chris i was part of this secret
time travel group uh based in nasa and the bahamas and thomas towns and brown was the president of
this group and i would think that would be total quackery if i wasn't so deep on towns and brown
right right and i didn't know he was so deep into time travel stuff and he spent a lot of time in
nasa and the bahamas and so i i do find that interesting i i agree i i think um if i could
say quickly from a scientific perspective it's been argued that what's called charge
parity inversion in the vacuum or in the quantum vacuum is equivalent to reflection and what that
means essentially is we're dealing with vacuum polarization and if we're dealing with vacuum
polarization if we polarize time but not space we can have this scenario in which time displacement
does occur wait how do you polarize because i think of time and space is indelibly bound
so how do you these longitudinal scalar waves that we've been speaking of are help tap time
rather than space how do you do that oh well you're asking how to engineer that one example
well one example would be for example uh would be sal piaz's work or how's space how put off
spacetime metric engineering but you're controlling for space or you are manipulating time to then
which which as a residual effect has effects on space interesting okay and so so time is the kind
of archimedean upstream thing that is updating space right so if you think of these longitudinal
waves right as slinkies all around us right and each slinky has a loop that loop represents a
state of entropy and neg entropy so what i mean by that is i have my water bottle here right for
example i take this water say i take this water and i put it on the table between this point in
space between here when i when i brought the water to the table and then here one loop of that
longitudinal uh wave has been completed and now we're moving on to the next loop like a movie reel
there the loops are constantly moving which is what we which is a temporal effect
and so essentially you can have a device where you can observe by polarizing if you came back
say whenever you know six months from now and you had a device that could look wherever you pointed
that device that particular part of space you could see in the past and you had a device that
could see that you could have a device that could show using the vector and scalar potentials of
space and time itself my um a visual of my hand doing this over and over why it's because that's
what i i so i i did um i did a i was on a panel one time with sal paez um and a handful of others
uh last two summers ago and basically i used this exact example and sal paez started basically
clapping as if to say yes that's what you have to yeah it's if there were to be a conflict on
some more primordial level than our earthly conflicts it would be on the level of time
correct and that leads to things like the you know the rumors of the philadelphia experiment
yeah well that was thomas towns of brown was involved in the philadelphia experiment
that's temporal displacement the rumors that the people were some people were stuck between a wall
or like yeah physical physical matter and that arguably is worse than a nuclear bomb i just am
not sure what happened in the philadelphia experiment like a part of me thinks it was this
quacky disinfo campaign maybe there i think there was actually something underlying it
even if it was fake the rumors that that that discuss that that speak of it are similar to
the way temporal displacement would work as i understand it have you heard of bob beckwith
by any chance oh robert beckwith yes yes i have yes does he say because he claims that i think
he was maybe somewhat involved in the philadelphia experiment and i think he later did some really
interesting work with like extremely high magnetic fields yep and uh and then and
teleportation until yep so i think there's something there again i think magnetism is
is gravity's cousin and i think that again you manipulate space time you're messing with gravity
but you're also messing with again time itself and so if i could say very quickly when i gave
the example of my putting the water like picking the water up and putting it on the table imagine
there's a parcel of of of memory that it will forever exist now even when i stop doing this
that is that is acting like a movie reel that is just sitting there in the vacuum
waiting to be reloaded up again if you will whoa or re-rendered if you think like a saved game
state correct there you go exactly like a saved game state so we think of the we see some you
know david bohm talked about you know this uh holographic morphogenic reality we live in there
have been some papers recently that have discussed that as well um and it's again i think there's
something there i really do it's very interesting yeah this idea of rendering holographic theory
and so on i think it speaks to what james rider was saying with regards to what what is light
i think there's something with that as well um i believe the uh the bavita gita if i'm not mistaken
right the that oppenheimer quoted i i could be wrong about this but i recall reading that the
original translation was not i am death the destroyer of worlds it was i am time the destroyer
of worlds really as i understand it is that true i we can verify that but i believe it's funny
you know i can get a little crazy with these things but like sometimes i think of like the end
of time right as like a um in the beginning of time right as like these double entendres where
it's like the end of time is like what does that even mean right like it's it's you're kind of
referring to the apocalypse right right but maybe it's the end of time itself and if you think we're
living in a lower 3d time bound universe or whatever maybe there's some apotheosis like event
there's some eschatological escalatory event yeah that will lead to the next step or fit yeah
the end of xeno's arrow of time perhaps where we're become more trans temporal in nature
very possible where we're not moving in this kind of river arrow of time that like you know well
that's why for example it's it's you know for example if we could get on that topic very
quickly it's like for if you go out to a um uh you go out with friends to a bar and then all
of a sudden you get a bad feeling that something's going to happen and then you say guys let's go
and then you know an hour or two later there's a shooting or a stabbing it's possible that you were
viewing a point in time that has already happened in in your soul if you will but hasn't played out
in the material world i believe that i think you can i think you can actually not prove that
scientifically but like we're getting there yeah the brain probably works like a room temperature
quantum system maybe i think you know as well like penrose would say this right with the
microtubules yes if that's the case you have temporal non-locality in quantum systems
exactly and we know we can reverse qubit positions in quantum computations right and so if you it's
been hypothesized by anybody working on quantum computer right very credible people will say yeah
maybe in a working quantum computer you could send information back in time even on the semantic
application layer right so you could send it you know information about like uh you know some
password you could send it back in time like you know a month prior or whatever as long for as long
as the quantum computer has been on right and so if you think about the brain as possibly this room
temperature quantum system maybe we do have access to shards of the future especially when it's
adaptive for our survival right so when you have like a really you know bad or scary premonition
really meaningful event right you might actually have access to that and there might be a physical
way of explaining that i think i think the only work that i know of and again because it's not
really my area of competency but the only work that i know of is dean raden yeah and i think
that what he's onto is very interesting to your point it can't be proven at least yet that we
know of but it's possible that it might be able to um to to be at some point in the in the near
distant future do you think that blue being that prompted you to get into all this crazy stuff
is still helping you out um yeah yes um what do you think that blue being is it's i'll be
honest with you i don't know i've i've really i don't know have you seen it since um it's more
of a feeling rather than a visual that experience was a very unique one and i haven't had it since
it's more of a feeling why do you think it chose you i think it i'll be honest with you i think
there are hundreds of thousands of people across the world that that people have encountered with
those exact similar experiences well it's interesting you have like ramanujan you know downloading
math so you look at the history of the the phenomenology of science itself and it's way
trippier i don't right so to your point i don't think i'm the only one by any stretch i think
that um if if you think about the possibility that there's an attempt to educate the younger
generation you know people younger than me there again i'm not on tiktok but the few things i've
seen on tiktok with regards to kids understanding uh just you know is science and all that baffles
me in in a positive way yeah because it's like where are they learning this from and in some
cases i've i've met with some families where the kids i've been graciously allowed to speak with
the kids and the kids have said well the the the the the ghost comes and tells me they don't know
how else to explain it and it's like wait a minute you've just described you know geodesic
time-like curves and with you know with regards to time machines or and so on and it's like how did
you you're like eight years old how did you you know what i mean yeah well it goes it goes into
like how do we know anything and what and and epistemics and and you know i actually just
interviewed this harvard neuroscientist who's studying these telepathic kids got you the whole
world's about to know about this oh wow because you have these controlled experiments where you
have the kid in one room and then you have the parent one parent specifically that they have
some sort of mind meld with right and you know random images popping up in the room with the
parent and they can 95 percent of the time accurately say that a baseball or a grapefruit
or a cloud is popping up on the screen it's absurd it's absurd and and and she got into this
because she was really interested in like people like kim peak who's the inspiration for rainman
and like savant right that would like it felt like they were accessing knowledge libraries
in the cloud they weren't just like in a toiling away learning things for years at a time or
whatever exactly so i think i think we're on the verge of a greater epistemological paradigm shift
and i'm excited to be here for it um and i think you're a part of it i appreciate it and i think
you're playing a very crucial role in all of this and i think to your point if i could say without
bringing this up again i think that that third strand of dna that we talked about
may also because it's electrically conductive may be an organic particle accelerator that our bodies
allow us to access with regards to the pineal gland that may in fact allow for information
download um from what people have called organic particle accelerator how would that work uh well
the idea would be maybe perhaps we are organic versions of what physical uap are of what physical
of what craft are um we may be the carbon-based organic version of of what if you look at the
way in which a craft allegedly operates or the way in how it it operates in an engineering sense
it's not unlike that of a human body except in a few different except with a few different uh with
a few differences well they're ancient traditions that would describe these things as sort of soul
carriers or something right right so i think that i think that's pretty spot on my opinion well then
i think about that and then i think about some of these defense use cases and i'm like that's a
little gnarly yeah yes yes i think there's a whole psychotronic aspect to this that's very
controversial but i think um for example there was a foyer leak out of the washington dc fusion
center that someone had filed a foyer with regards to looking into some uh political groups
but it turned out that they were given i think the file was called uh effects on the human body
and basically what it showed was that through the psychotronic uh electromagnetic uh i don't want
to unfortunately weapons it showed the human biofield and the different frequencies that
could be applied to it from a distance in which you could um manipulate the body i know for example
someone that worked on a on a device that uh can make someone immediately have to defecate
uncontrollably um wait you know somebody that works on a device that makes people remotely
take a shit yes are you serious yes who's this person they're they're not public but they're
but no it's it's been i mean this is and i'll tell you to the people that know of this stuff
that's old news and that's why i'm so confident in what i'm saying with regards to this oh man
that's freaky yeah and i'm not trying to scare people i believe that those same methodologies
could also be used to heal people so again we have an overlap how do we heal people well this
goes back to our conversation of the uh polarizing the vacuum the linguistic wave genetics the the
russian gentleman for example yeah yeah it goes back to that what we're dealing with is an overlap
of all these fields of and so basically the same things that can hurt people can also help people
well man i hope to god because i think these things are speeding up that uh we evolve in our
consciousness and and uh yep are made capable to handle what i think is ultimately a forcing
function for humanity which is technological progress along these lines i couldn't agree more
i couldn't agree more um yeah so that's it's pretty pretty interesting it's fascinating would
you ever do um another one of these with a theoretical physicist that i could bring in
from like a traditional academic background because i think that would be kind of yeah
sure i i'll tell if i could end end by saying this jesse i want uh what i want you and your
audience to know is i'm not expecting anyone to blindly believe me there are things that i've
seen in private laboratories that are undeniable and verified by people other than myself in those
facilities however i i'm of the view that i know what i know but i don't expect people to blindly
believe me unless unless they've seen it for themselves so for me i don't get um i don't
get discouraged if a theoretical physicist said calls me crazy or says you know i'm open to some
of your stuff but the rest is too crazy to woo for me i'll talk to anybody i love it man well
i appreciate what you're doing and um thank you you have such an amazing cool story i appreciate
i hope uh the blue being keeps helping you out thank you so much i appreciate it and i i keep
watching your show and i look forward to all the new episodes you have coming out so thank you
thanks man and go go check out generation zed which is on youtube youtube spotify apple podcast
spotify apple podcast go support thanks so much thank you so much i appreciate it thank you awesome
huge news everyone we've been sitting on a ton of unreleased footage that we will now be releasing
weekly in our new wop our first episode is a completely uncut heated discussion between
how put off and eric weinstein on remote viewing yeah you heard that right i still can't believe i
experienced that firsthand and now i'm happy to share it with you all as our first exclusive video
on wop head over to wop.com slash american alchemy premium to become a premium member today by
becoming a member you'll gain access to weekly premium videos behind the scenes footage and
monthly group calls where we discuss the ideas we love most plus you'll get early access to
merchandise drops and be the first to know about the upcoming conference we'll be holding later
in 2025 our wop community will serve as a private space where curious individuals and tech enthusiasts
can come together to challenge the status quo and explore ideas shaping our future if you're
passionate about exploring unconventional ideas and want to dive even deeper into our content i
invite you to join our wop today head over to wop.com slash american alchemy premium to
become a premium member today thank you so much and enjoy the rest of today's episode
you