It's crazy whenever I hear people like you speak about this topic because especially
you, you've been doing this for a long time, you've been around the block and you make
some wild claims.
No, I don't make claims.
I make statements based on facts and research.
I'm a scientist.
You say some things that are mind blowing and it seems like you have a lot of access
to a lot of crazy dark shit and whenever you hear people say that in today's day and age,
a lot of them are full of shit.
A lot of it is, we've sort of reached a breakout point.
There are a group of people from a few black sites, very highly classified operations with
Aerospace and JSOC, Joint Special Operations Command, who have started coming forward
that I've been working with for a couple of years and they're beginning to put their
toe in the water and put some information out and these are guys who've been on the
crash retrieval teams and they've been working with me clandestinely for about 18 months
I think, something like that, or 20 months and that team is just starting to come out
with a little bit of information but they have an enormous amount more and what they're
trying to do is get the U.S. government to finally set up the protective mechanisms so
a whole bunch of these high value targets, HVT whistle blowers, can come forward.
So we've been working to set that up through a series of briefings that I've been doing
for about three years with Senate Intelligence Committee and Senate Armed Services and taking
some of the witnesses.
Now remember I have debriefed nearly a thousand top secret guys and in our archive, you can
go to dpiarchive.com, there's about 760-some named, now only 115 you can see their testimony
but we have 115 you can go look at right now.
The others are blackened out because they don't want to be known but we're handing them
over to a special access project to look into what they know, the documents they have,
the materials they've seen and try to put together the puzzle.
So what I liken this to, I call it the disclosure mosaic.
So imagine you have a big picture you're trying to create and because of the highly compartmented
nature of top secret special compartment information projects dealing with this, you get a piece
here and a piece here and a piece here.
So what I've tried to do over the past 35 years since 1990 when I started this effort
is to put together the mechanism for people to come forward, give us information and testimony,
whistle blower testimony, documents when they can get them out of a secure facility and
then put that whole assessment.
So it's called an intelligence assessment and what I discovered back about between 1990
and 95 is that the vast majority of information on the subject is actually very carefully
curated disinformation, if I can be blunt it's bullshit and that's been done deliberately
to gaslight the public and Washington officials and the media but it's also been done to create
the specter of a threat from outer space.
So what you know, Werner von Braun who invented the rocket for Adolf Hitler told his assistant
right before he died who's on our team, Carol Rosin, he said look what we're planning to
do is to launch a fake alien threat so the world can be united around some sort of dystopian
militaristic totalitarian state and we're real close to that.
I mean a warm up for that was 9-11, a bigger warm up was COVID.
The big one is this and if it's not averted it'll panic the planet into this stupidity.
So you know and this sort of false flag operation has been run since for thousands of years
by powerful people and military people to sort of get their way and rule through fear
and so what you're doing with this is that when you look at the whole body of everything
I call the legacy ufology crowd, there's good information out there and then it's
mixed in with nine parts of nonsense and so what most people do and this is why I've
been by 94 I was ready to give up on this, let me be honest with you, most government
officials go I'm out because this is such a cacophony, it's such a mixture of fact and
fiction and rumors upon rumors upon rumors, they don't have time for it, I'm an emergency
right so I'm going this is you know crazy stuff so but I've stuck with it to try to
make my way through this vast amount of noise.
That's what I was trying to express to you kind of right before we started was that I've
had so many folks on here talking about this topic from authors to firsthand experiencers,
people that have been tried to be whistleblowers to filmmakers who have talked to all these
witnesses and whistleblowers and all these folks and it's just like this crazy cauldron
of disinformation, misinformation, different partitions of the government fighting against
each other and then you have you know just like the strategic deception that goes a lot
it's been going on since the cold war and it's just like I've literally just been out
on the UFO topic for the last probably like almost a year I've just been sick of it because
so much of it is bull and I don't know if you've ever seen that documentary I'm sure
you have Mirage Men about Richard Doty and how the Paul Benowitz thing that has been
my basically that I've been looking at this whole topic through that lens for since I
saw that about a year ago and it's it seems like as you were alluding to it seems like
that is the predominant it seems like that is about 80% of the information that's coming
out is like specifically curated there's like counterintelligence disinformation to poison
the well of information on this topic. But let's unpack that why? So if you look
in our archive we have a top-secret document that was I believe accidentally declassified
from Canada in the 1970s it's called the Wilbur Smith document and it's a top-secret document
that is from 1950 describing the US-based reverse engineering research projects on
extraterrestrial vehicles that were retrieved in the 40s and it's an authenticated document
and it says a few things number one it says quote flying saucers are real that's what they used
to be called before they made up the fake name UFO UAP those were made up I hate how everyone's
calling it NHI all of a sudden oh yeah that's we'll get into this it's the CIA psychological
warfare division that has the linguistics department yeah all right look I started
briefing the director of the CIA in 1993 I know you did you brought you brought the briefing for
Trump in today right here right here so look at this big stack of documents we got here can you
see that Steve on the camera yeah oh well I mean it is what it is so the big problem became once
they realized what they had right mm-hmm and people were seeing these things because once
we started detonating atomic bombs and then the thermonuclear weapons these civilizations
from out there came in you know like it was like a homing signal and here's why when you
detonate an atomic weapon or a thermonuclear weapon which a hydrogen bomb right a fusion
bomb as opposed to fission what you get is an electromagnetic pulse but embedded in that is
what's called a scalar signal it like Tesla talked about and that is not a wave form like a sine
wave it's a point that goes out in a straight line at multiples of the speed of light it disrupts
interstellar communications and transport so there was it was a bit like kicking a hornet's nest
right because not that they were hostile towards us but they were concerned like what is going on
in this little corner of the cosmos so that was the whole modern era of these although they've
been seen for thousands of years but once we got to the nuclear threshold we crossed the Rubicon
here all right a red line went over and so this is why they're seen all over the place near nuclear
installations and nuclear ships that are carrying that are big carriers that have nuclear weapons
on them yeah I know many officers who had these craft around them checking that out even nuclear
power plants so there's a big danger with that nuclear system and how it pertains to not only
the future of the earth which they have an interest in these these civilizations the ET
ones but they also are concerned about what happens when a civilization or a level of social
and spiritual development which ain't great has these kind of technologies and start going out
in the space so it coincided shortly within 10 15 years of detonating the first atomic bomb in
1945 by 1957 the Soviets had put Sputnik up right and so we were they knew that we were
coming to be outward looking going into space why do you think these beings are invested in
the future of the earth if they're not from here and they're from another like if we found
another earth if we found if we found another planet inhabitable with life and we were way
more advanced than we then then they were right why would we want to protect them from themselves
well I think that what I have found is people evolve I mean let's just say whether you want
to call it spiritual or or socially psychologically you develop compassion you develop empathy you
develop a longer range vision than the next quarterly report right in other words you have
a view so you get take on a long-range view and I think those civilizations some of them may
have come our way before and faced near extinction level events or they've seen other civilizations
come and go that have you know blown themselves up or become a problem right so I don't I think
there's a big let's call it cosmic institutional memory out there and there's nothing new under
the Sun's this has probably happened before but I also think they see the goodness in humanity the
capacity for creativity or exploration for intelligence even very high levels of spiritual
consciousness so I it's it's not as if they view us all as so dimly I think they see the promise
but they see right now this little window of time in the last hundred years or so where we're on the
one hand technologically advanced enough to destroy ourselves and I'll get to this in a moment
potentially threaten other worlds with technologies that we've developed from reverse
engineering extraterrestrial transport systems but we're also not socially and spiritually evolved
enough to not blow ourselves to smithereens so that is exactly the sweet spot or let's call it
the the dangerous spot of where a civilization could go sideways very badly right all right and
we're there we've been there since you know the mid 20th century do you think there's any chance
that these things are or what do you make of the theory that these are future humans well I think
there have been some encounters that are our descendants from the future so I think we have
to be careful here I think of this let's say a species evolves for half a million years and
becomes spacefaring evolution doesn't stand still and so they could evolve to something that would
look like a non-human being an extraterrestrial being but have been descended but 20 000 generations
ago right and certainly that's possible I think that that's probably what happened at rundlesham
forest spent waters from the you mean 20 000 generations in the future yes from 500 000 years
in the future and from the some of the military guys who are there where this object landed
in 19 early 80s in england there's pretty good indication that there was some contact that
happened it was psionic telepathic that they were us from half a million years in the future
and it was a pyramid shaped onyx looking black like black onyx looking object very well documented
but the eventually a ministry defense in the united kingdom I went over there and met with
them back in 93 and shortly after that they did declassify some of their information on it so my
understanding that might have been but still in the sense they were extraterrestrial but there
weren't from this you know particular time space so it gets into how you define that
uh but you know my understanding is you know if one of our whistleblowers who's passed away
sergeant stone he was on a retrieval team crash retrieval dealing with this in the 60s and
by late 60s he said there were 69 specific non-human extraterrestrial species that they
had cataloged 69 when you think about a successful business you think about a great product a cool
brand and sweet marketing but what you don't think about is the business behind the business
that's making the sales nobody does selling better than shopify it's the number one checkout on the
planet used by four million companies and they're not so secret secret shopify's shop pay boosts
conversions up to 50 meaning way less carts will go abandoned with shopify in minutes your store
can go from a blank canvas to a professional storefront that's unique to you and shopify has
powerful social media tools connect to all your channels and turn those casual scrollers into
paying customers with shoppable posts because let's face it people are already scrolling why
not make it work for your business because businesses that sell sell more on shopify
upgrade your business and get the same checkout we use with shopify sign up for your one dollar
per month trial period at shopify.com Danny Jones all lowercase go to shopify.com Danny Jones to
upgrade your selling today shopify.com slash d-a-n-n-y j-o-n-e-s and thank you shopify for
sponsoring the show yeah and i'm sure it's way more than that now so that and his information
you know we before he passed away we got his archive that's in our archive and also we got
a very extensive interview with him and so there are many people like that who come forward and
told similar accounts now one of one of the problems is if you're in a compartment operation
like that you're not going to be read into or briefed on something of very similar nature
that's in a different base or another compartment operation it's very very compartmentalized is
what they call it so what i've tried to do is to see where it syncs up so let's say you have
you know 10 people who've been on crash retrieval teams that i've debriefed i'm
just making i was probably more than that where were they what did they see what was their
methodology and how much of that is congruent and when you get congruence from people who don't know
who each other are so i'm sort of my project the disclosure projects from the clearinghouse for
hundreds of these guys then you begin to be able to find out where the sweet spot of truth is
and try to put build out this picture so that's what we've tried to do it's been painstaking
when it comes to the 69 different variations of non-human life that this gentleman cataloged
the idea of the future humans thing is interesting to me when it comes to these
beings these short little gray alien beings with two legs and two arms
because if you if you think about how rare ours we are on homo sapiens on planet earth there's
like over two million cataloged species of animals on planet earth there's out of those two million
there's 20 hominids out of the 20 hominids only one of them figured out how to develop technology
to get off the planet so we are super rare on this planet alone so now you want to extrapolate
out into the universe and find all the other goldilocks planets that are able to inhabit life
they have different oxygen levels different gravity they have most of them are water worlds
very different atmospheres what are the chances they're also going to evolve
that something like us is going to evolve bipedal upright walking two arms two legs and a head that
says brain says directly on top of the head it's very high and here's why it's a high probability
that that would happen yes and if you look at the work of rupert shell drake at oxford and
morphogenic field propagation because of quantum entanglement let me explain to the audience what
that means quantum entanglement is at that level of quantum physics where every point in space and
time is interconnected now the ultimate quantum entangled field is mind or consciousness which
we can get into this this gets into the deep end of the pond very quickly but when something
let's say something works in one area and it becomes something that is within that morphogenic
field at a quantum entangled level it spontaneously begins to pop up elsewhere and this is known as
field propagation through quantum entanglement so it would make total sense that that'd be the case
now there's certainly be huge variety amongst that say that within that template and there may be
other forms as well but i think that form was called you know the form of a universal
person a head two arms two legs is probably pretty consistent now there may be others
but and they may have evolved from like we're 98 identical to chimps so take a look i mean some
of us more than others one of my best friends calls me a big eight because i'm muscly and furry
but but they you know so we just go okay that's us right but there could be a species that evolved
from the equivalent of a cetacean or a dolphin or a bird like or what have you right so i think
there's a huge amount of variation in the cosmos but there's it's not that surprising that there
would be this morphogenic field propagation is some people call it the hundredth monkey effect
where they studied monkeys on an isolated island and once the troop learned how to do a skill
right spontaneously hundreds of miles away the monkeys on another island started doing it
yeah it was like this entangled field right i understand what you're saying you're talking
more about consciousness but i'm talking like hard biology i am too but you're you're you're
acting like those are separate they're not so this how are they so how are they not separate
like like how like i'm saying like how is it if physically on a planet if the gravity is
different if the atmosphere is different if there's no land if it's all ocean but that's
external so i'm talking about the internal see here's the thing that's very interesting
we're different in every imaginable way but we're the same in a very essential way and that they're
sentient and conscious so let's talk about field consciousness and what ermine schrodinger the
father of modern particle wave theory in quantum physics in 1908 said the total number of minds
in the universe is one that is it is a singularity so i know it sounds very spuckian but this is a
fact actually it's been proven very union yeah it's been proven by dr john at princeton university
who had the princeton you know engineering anomalies research lab and i knew him before
he passed away and they did very accurate studies with random number generators where you just think
to it and it would change it from just equal distribution of zeros and ones to shifting to
say ones the digital they're just quantum digital random number generators very well done studies
have been replicated all over the world so what is that so we always think of ourselves as sort
of these islands that are completely separate because of 3d right our bodies the environment
but what if there's a level of not only in physics physically what they call quantum entanglement and
einstein called the spooky effect but also on a level of consciousness in mind it explains a
lot of phenomenon a great deal of the phenomenon so the one good thing before i went to medical
school you're gonna laugh it's such an anachronism now i was a became a meditation teacher and studied
sanskrit and the vedas and sort of learned really in depth about the science of consciousness on
all of that you're happy when i was i was 19 20 it was great fun yeah you know it was a sort of
you know i finished college when i first went in and i said what am i gonna do now so i said well
let's do this so i and that was a consequence of a contact experience i had and then that was a
consequence of having had a near-death experience when i was 17 so it sort of opened up that
trajectory into consciousness and the study of that and then where does that intercept with all
this well it's actually some turns out to be essential so you know you have this team of
people who've just defected from i can't say which black sites i've been at those black sites and they
were using a type of psionic or psychic interface with technology to intercept and bring
craft in and then hit them with electromagnetic pulse weapons right i've been at these sites i
know where they are and i've met some of the operators and it's real i mean it sounds like
science fiction but it didn't no it sounds like stranger things in real life well i mean everything
i mean the science fiction is all ripped out of the things that are real often but this is the
real end of it and it's serious but that's why the cia had a remote viewing program 30 years on
i know a lot of those original remote viewing guys and so that whole area where does that have
to do with ufos though what it has to do with the fact now i wrote about this in a 1991 paper
called the comprehensive assessment of the ufo eti subject extraterrestrial intelligence subject
and it describes two related things phenomenon that those civilizations have technology
that assists their consciousness in these capabilities but they also have the ability
to have their consciousness augment the technology so they can think to that camera it's like
neural link without the wires you know at the speed of thought ran the speed of electromagnetic
field propagation yeah so and that's real and and so civilizations that if they're you know from
the andromeda galaxy right and two and a half million light years from here they're not using
your cell phone at speed of light it would take two and a half million years to say hey how you're
doing right and another two and a half million years for you to return the reply right so the
speed of light ain't going to cut it so when you go what i call super luminal beyond the speed of
light super you're going into trans dimensional you're crossing dimensions and within those finer
dimensions it becomes more and more preeminent that you're using conscious fields and thought
and it's really strange stuff but it's true and so if you don't understand that you're never going
to understand extraterrestrial civilizations how much faster is this conscious super super luminal
instant so if you instant it's instant now not necessarily to transport systems but if
you're communicating it's in real time because there too you're let's say you're here and your
home base is two and a half million light years away it's because it's not going in a straight
line forget about the speed of light think again about this interrelated quantum entangled cosmos
at the level of not only thought and consciousness but consciousness but even very refined
electromagnetic systems so then you go boom it's in real time and this is where they've done studies
recently where they have teleported particles and they have the spooky effect where the same
particle can be in two places at once as einstein described so i don't know if i'm boring your
audience at this point but no you're not boring them but so at that point you begin to realize
that if you're a very advanced civilization and you want to become interstellar you're not going
to be using the junk that all of us think is so i'll get out from silicon valley i mean that's
rubbish right how did you figure this out this stuff the super luminal consciousness communication
well um well the truth i prefer the truth yeah well that was a bit of a long story but anyway
in 1973 in march i got very sick and i died had near-death experience okay i was raised an atheist
and we didn't believe anything um it didn't fit in a test tube didn't it didn't exist nonsense
but i had this amazing beautiful experience actually and i had personally this experience of
my own say drop of my individuality becoming the ocean sort of this expanded
consciousness state um that was infinite it was boundless and it was very beautiful
and obviously i didn't die because here i am um but it was a very serious near-death experience
and about six months later uh no a couple months later i decided i'm going to learn meditation
because i said i want to get back to that state without getting sick and dying so i learned how
to meditate and started studying that and then i was up on a mountain in north carolina
upside the little town of boone north carolina and i was uh hiked up there before sunset
and i wanted to see uh the sunset and meditate and that was it and just before sunset i saw a
perfectly seamless uh disc that appeared uh and i'd seen of almost an identical one when i was
eight or nine in north carolina i grew up in the charlotte area and i went oh they're back
i didn't think anything more about it i just thought well there it is i mean i just accepted
this okay um because i looked into this when i was a kid after i had my sighting
but that's all that happened it was there and it didn't move off it just winked out just sort
of like dematerialized or vanished right so i go and i meditate i'm sitting there and it gets dark
and um when i open my eyes i have this the whole milky way is up above and i'm about over 5 000
feet up there crystal clear october 1973 and uh i had this beautiful thought that entered me i said
behold what a beautiful universe god has made and with that i went into that same experience i had
when i died it was it was phenomenal but i was in my body so uh i looked over and there was a glow
over the edge of the hill mountainside i think was that craft and there was a little there was a
person now i as an 18 year old kid i thought it was a deer standing on its hind legs had beautiful
eyes maybe about uh four and a half five feet tall i came over and it touched my right shoulder
and i left i just dematerialized for about four hours four hours yeah now i thought it was about
30 to 45 minutes something like that because time isn't the same in these dimensions but um so during
that encounter i started having this experience of where non-human and extra extraterrestrial
in humans where could we connect and it was at this place of non-locality it's called in physics
and consciousness so i started practicing this with these ets this episode is brought to you by
true work a clothing company hell bent on bringing you the most technical high performance work wear
on the face of the earth the true work story begins in the colorado mountains where a trade
worker knew there had to be a better solution than the wet heavy gear that was weighing him down and
true work was born i love true work because their clothing is real rugged heavy duty work wear built
for the 20th century and it's not uncomfortable it's better because it's soft comfortable stretchy
and fits better than traditional work wear and my favorite part is that when you're trying to be
agile bend down squat or contort your body in a weird way their jeans won't pinch your balls like
traditional skinny jeans that most nerds wear nowadays every true work product is engineered
for maximum efficiency comfort and protection and when you put them on you feel the difference
when i put on traditional cotton or denim pants i can literally feel the 200 year difference in
technology true work upgrades traditional classics with fabrics used by elite outdoor athletes
soft stretchy sweat wicking soft shell work pants are a huge upgrade over stiff heavy jeans
wind and waterproof shells use intelligently placed insulation for streamlined warmth and lets
you stay mobile and agile true work has over 50 000 five star reviews and countless stories from
trade pros in every state and every job across the country upgrade to true work for a major
change in the way you work true work helps you be your best when your best matters most check out
true works full lineup and get 15 off your first order at true work dot com slash danny that's 15
off at t r u e w e r k dot com slash danny it's linked below now back to the show and this
meditation yeah so we have an app called ce5 contact it's probably the most controversial
things i'm doing yeah i've heard of it yeah and it it works and if you look at the movie
close encounters of the fifth gun you're gonna go whoa wow um i just sent your producer a picture
of an et that appeared oh yeah you sent the alien can we see the alien that he said no the
aliens are from guatemala okay um these are extraterrestrial biological entities what's the
difference i'm just making a joke i know i know we're in florida nobody it's no we can't make
jokes in florida they're way dirtier than that it's impossible so this is where do you see this one
so this is in arizona a couple years ago um and we were doing the ce5 contact protocols um and uh
full screener steve yeah you have to do full screen otherwise it's useless yeah um he's learning
how to use there you go um so it looks like a beak and it's this round head and you see the
eye socket on the left there's a light source that was not ours coming from his left and uh sort of
a feathery tunic now this was about three feet from me and we had uh david marconi who wrote
enemy of the state with will smith had a great nicon camera set up on a tripod with a remote
and we had seen what looked like a red orb right between this older gentleman and a member of our
team and it was me and and i said take a picture here and he did and here's this this person that
we had heard walking around behind us without seeing it with the naked eye uh but it captured
this uh this person it's weird it's very unusual like i can't it's hard to make anything well if
oh no i mean the the right eye socket you can see it's a very big head with like a beak like
nose yeah and then a tunic and the right hand there i mean this is at night with you know no
illumination by the way we're out there in the middle of the wilderness in pitch black
so this by the way this we call this et the healer because he has appeared at other times and the man
right beside him had lost his hearing since he was in uh middle or high school and even with
hearing aids he could barely hear and this wait what is that next is that oh that's just like a
light orb or something right there steve that's just some to the left this thing yeah looks like
a i don't know that's the man that's that older gentleman oh that's a person yeah you know eyes
checked that's a person so it looks like a face floating in the middle of the no no no he's sitting
in our we're in chairs in a circle okay yeah we could give you the whole context though but
what's interesting is that he was healed of his hearing loss uh by next morning he woke up wow
totally fixed so it's you know i've been doing this since i was 18 so now i'm 69 so for 51 years
and what i find interesting about retail ufology it's always i was abducted and i was and i was
tortured and i was this i'm going yeah that's the cia you mentioned the grays i know who
manufactures those you know who manufactures the aliens yes they're not aliens well the gray the
gray beings that like willy streber talks about yeah the the fake ones as they're called so so how
do they get them to abduct people like there's all these stories that john mack has has talked
about oh yeah i knew john very well yeah and then he he talked to i think hundreds of people that
explained being abducted by the little grays and taken up into ships and had to sperm and eggs
extracted from them yeah as if how do you explain that about delusions of grandeur like they need
our sperm and eggs um have you heard the theory that they're will the future human theory like
if there was a cataclysmic event in the future like way in the future and they had to come back
in time to get our dna to repropagate humanity in the future that oh yeah that's a hypothesis
yeah i call it the cosmic noah's arc yeah right yes uh no but i mean there's a mixture of things
so here remember this okay october 1954 we mastered gravity control who mastered it
covert programs in the united states aerospace but there was a there was a couple people working
on it there was louis witten and no i'm talking about that if you take t towns and browns work
okay t towns and brown and the b phil brown effect all that started in the 20s
and if you look at a film that we released a couple years ago called the lost century it kind
of unpacks all this it's a documentary okay and and and people should look at that it explains
all this in this trajectory of how this evolved and so there were experiments with very high
voltage systems that called an electrogravitic effect where things would lift right okay and
that was in the 20s that was 28 29 it was replicated in germany and the houseky frost
experiment we have a physics journal we show that in the film okay it's in here and for the briefing
now imagine those early experiments with so-called anti-gravity okay not a good term but those use
the pop culture term it's actually electro-gravitics uh and electro-gravitic field propulsion but we're
you know it's not a physics class okay so what happened is that this that research combined
with a augmentation of that research a big leap forward by studying the extraterrestrial vehicles
that we downed right in the mid-40s and 50s right so by the time those two streams combined into a
mighty river of research but it was covert as i was referring to that wilbur smith document most
secret and he said this is the most secret operation in the united states exceeding the
secrecy of the hydrogen bomb research now this is 1950 before we detonate the first atom hydrogen
bomb so imagine something more classified and secret than the h bomb the ultimate doomsday weapon
that's this stuff so you know my uncle i had his whole career at northrop raman uh he worked on the
lunar module that land on the moon but those big aerospace companies northrop raman lockheed skunk
works and now raytheon e g and g way back then and others they got the portfolio for their special
projects to study this material figure out how it worked and then apply it yeah so by 1954
we had operational gravity control so that we were building our own ufos and i always tell people
if you see something you call a ufo or uap you have to ask yourself it's one of be one of three
things it could be an extraterrestrial vehicle or nhi craft it's the pop culture now it can be a
man-made one coming out of one of these big aerospace companies because they've been zipping
around since the late 50s right or it could be not neither of them and it could be some
uh extra-dimensional entity something from another dimension that's not extraterrestrial
so my a way though this is where it gets confusing for people and it's deliberately
been commingled in other words disinformation specialists yeah from the cia and other places
like lou elezando his yeah he called you a terrorist yeah i know it's very funny i'm a
terrorist for speaking the truth well that's yeah i mean you know as opposed to people who
are actually trying to create armageddon which would be his crowd yeah but the problem is is
that if you don't have enough of the information and this information has been in a blackout for
70 years you know if you're a if you're a david fravor flying an f-18 chasing one of these things
and you don't you're not read and you're you're a jet pilot you're not read into what's coming out
of the underground facilities at skunkworks out there in the desert yeah so you're gonna
immediately think oh shit i just saw an alien craft no you saw something that was made at
the skunkworks that was moving in a way with no visible means of propulsion i was just trying
to clarify earlier on on the on the anti-gravity side of things um jeremy riss alien scientist
as a physics historian was explaining to me that um there was two i think two main groups one was
lewis witten and his the people that he was working on it with and then brice dewitt
who was working on anti-gravity in like the earlier 50s like before 54 um and he thinks that one of
them figured it out and then i guess from my understanding is that went black all of a sudden
yeah like we got co-opted by somebody and then like in 50 i think it was 57 there was like a um
what was it there was some big like anti-gravity conference or something right where they were
trying to figure but why would they have that conference in 57 if they had figured it out in
54 you know what i mean well because of compartment i mean the left hand doesn't know the right hand
exists i mean i've done i've done briefings for the head of the defense intelligence agency three
serge general and he didn't know anything that's going on with this even though he made inquiries
he was blown off so everyone thinks that they're sort of this you know you're the president or
you're a three or four star general you have an all-access pass you do not uh and that is what
my big coming of age on this and why i started the disclosure project right in 1993 was when i
briefed the director of the cia for bill clinton i learned in two or three hours will see yeah our
james will see who's since flipped on everybody how did he find you by the way one a friend of
his that he had been on the board of the the um a think tank pentagon think tank uh knew him and knew
was following what we were doing and it was mainly because in 1992 here in pensacola florida near
there we had a ce5 contact team and we vectored in four et craft and one of them was on the front
page of the pensacola paper got picked up by the intelligence community and before you know it i
had all kinds of spooks knocking on my door um you know everyone who laughs at that i say yeah
what you're missing is the main part of the secret dude you know you're missing the big picture
totally you know you're flat earthers if you say if you think the the universe is 3d flat
you know you're a flatter society you know but um anyway so that got on the radar of this think
tank that was looking into the subject under a contract with the pentagon and then and and the
director of that think tank and the ci director were friends so once he became director ce cia
he and clinton and some other people webster hubbell at justice were trying to find out about ufos
and they were being gaslit and lied to or deceived and they knew it i mean clinton was smart enough
to know he was being zoomed and so they reached out to me to come up and and provide the information
i had now initially i will say if you look in my archive you'll see the the letter the
correspondence about this um i thought they were just trying to pick my brain and there was like
you know intel gathering exercise no i mean the director cia and the president had been completely
denied access threatened and told nothing and i you know at that time look i'm a 30
uh something your mid-30s medical doctor working full-time and as er you know like the show or
something never seen the show um but the truth is is that i thought surely they have more
information than i do this is nuts so and and they were just lying about what the purpose of
the meeting was right and they were just trying to gather information from me but it wasn't he was
shaken uh and they really did and that's when i realized that the organization that's running
that's running these covert programs is unconstitutional criminal and has been since
the late 1950s since eisenhower kind of lost control of them he was betrayed so there has
been no proper legal constitutional oversight of any of these operations and this is dangerous
since at least 1956-7 somewhere in that period yeah yeah and that's where grush came into the
picture and he was tasked to track down some of this lost black budget money right and that's
where when all these whistleblowers started to come out recently well not really i mean
we that's a late recent event yeah okay so there were more significant events that happened in the
90s that uh people don't know about or don't talk about um uh because clinton had set up
a military team you know because they used to call it team blue was the regular military
team black were these illegal projects and he set up what's called team red
to penetrate those covert illegal programs most of those and i know some of these guys most of
those guys were killed or absorbed into team black so some of the whistleblowers just now coming
forward some of the older ones had been on team red i can't say which ones but they'll disclose
that when they're ready and they got totally pulled into these illegally run operations now
remember if you're a 18 20 25 year old delta force guy or green beret you're not read into
the chain of command up above you you just go yes sir and you're going to do what you're going to
do right but once they reached a certain level of seniority they realized they were in an illegal
criminal operation which is when they reached out to me and they said one of them said thank you
for what you're doing for those of us stuck on the other side meaning stuck in this illegal
criminal operation and they want out so the good thing is there's a momentum happening now if we
can get whistleblower protections through the congress and executive order from the president
where there's a whole damn rate of break of folks like that right that we have who will
come forward and with the evidence and this will be begin to be solved it's just the beginning
so that's what we're trying to work on but it way way way predates grow i met with mr grush
when he was still undercover and gave him information and his bosses were people that
were people i had briefed in the skiff the secure compartment information facility
so he came out with what he had done but he was secondhand he had not been operational
i'm talking about the first-hand operational people what's interesting if you look at the
house oversight committee hearings it's all been all these secondhand people and i i told
congressman bruchette and lunas why don't you subpoena the people that we have here's a list
of the top 25 right and these are people like i just described who are operational at the skunk
works interestingly they never call those people to a hearing i said don't call me i'm just the
doorway i'm the opener right call these guys and here are their name and by the way here's their
dd-214 and here's where they're operational so you know you have to wonder why i mean are really
people that clueless in washington or something going on there i don't know yeah so your disclosure
project has i believe over 400 military witnesses 760 something now 760 yeah and what would you say
is the most credible out of all of those witnesses well you know it's that the hole is greater than
the sum of the parts now remember i think these guys just starting to come out who've dealt with
the targeting and downing of these craft and how they've done it and the collateral damage
the civilians in private airplanes that have been killed in the process
that is one of the biggest stories in american history that's about to come out so private planes
that have come down so let me explain how this works so let's say you're out at some black site
out in the desert out west okay i i won't say which one i was and i've i've been in this
special forces guy's chopper that's on the retrieval teams and flown over this area
um and seen the equipment and the underground base opening all that um i have pictures and
videos of it it's in here it's in your presidential briefing right here yeah and that actually this is
available for people to order now we've sanitized some of the sensitive names out and you can go
and order it in a heart this thing right this whole thing there's how do you order it well i
don't know i don't do you know that my assistant will give you guys a link but you everyone
listening can get one and how would they go about doing that they would get the link from
your assistant no well no you can put it up you know i can put a link to it and our drsteven
grue dot com there'll be a link to it right raven anyway um i don't do that stuff but and then this
is and then what is your plan with with this your briefing this has already been provided to the
incoming new president and to some of his senior folks and we're continuing and also to the key
oversight committee senate intelligence armed services and what did they what was their reaction
to it but they well they're just now studying it it's an enormous amount of information and
intelligence so um there are some entities that are on the enforcement end of u.s government
that are now drilling down heavy on the same methods and sources that are in here
the people the witnesses the whistleblowers and the facilities and corporations um probably one
of the most significant uh people to come forward if we can protect him is the former chairman of a
fortune 50 company that's been involved with this it's a household name i won't say which one
and he wants to come forward he's like 80 years old this year and he deeply regrets what they've
done and you know he's admitted that they have the schematics and the designs to provide free
energy quote unquote to the whole world and he he really regrets all this secrecy but at the same
time he as soon as he reached out to me through his assistant and friend fortune 50 one of the
top 50 companies yeah it's huge and can we play come on can i guess no i'm not gonna play that
game no i don't but i would betray that man's trust because it'd be easy for someone to figure
out who it is it wasn't a military contractor though it's a big company that has a lot of
fingers and a lot of pies right okay um but uh this man then was threatened and they threatened
to kill his whole family and his grandchildren so uh what i'm trying what i'm trying to get
and it was you know the senate intelligence committee passed in 2023 unanimously uh the
provision to give amnesty or safe harbor to these kind of people right yep but the house in the
reconciliation of the bill took it out due to a couple of guys who were i think bad actors there
yeah who were those guys again were those the ohio guys the ohio no yeah mike turner mike turner
was chair of senate intelligence and the other mike rogers who is chair of armed services and
a few other people gutted that and it will kind of and why why do you think those two guys because
i think they receive a lot of funding from the very people there that need to be exposed i mean
you know i think it's not obviously uh they're carrying water for someone
which is corruption um but that's washington right i mean who's got the money who's got the
blackmail file on you right you know yep people get bribed people get threatened people get killed
it's not a conspiracy theory it's a fact um i've had all those games run on me so um but i think
that there's you know someone like that would have you know a lot of the keys to the kingdom
but if you're at risk for rico charges right federal racketeering influence corrupt organization
charges due to the criminal activity that you oversaw as an executive and maybe worse things
but you're also under threat from the organization keeping the secret of having you or your family
killed like this gentleman i don't think he would mind if he got killed but he doesn't want his
children and grandchildren killed and what what is his what did he see what is his what is his
connection to this stuff he's a chairman of a massive corporation but he was read into
a very special projects compartmented area dealing with the technology and that's the reason he won't
he doesn't want to come forward publicly because he's he's been threatened his family's been
threatened of course yeah and so it's now i know who he is and the people who are going to need
to know you know the president the you know attorney general law enforcement and on down
the system will know or do know by now so the only question becomes what are they gonna do about it
um now you know when i was beginning to tell you about these black sites all right now imagine
okay you're out in a desert site remote no access i mean ground sensors you're not going to get in
there um easily and underneath the ground out there there is a huge complex of stiffs there's
subterranean facilities and some people are dumb steep underground military bases
and in our briefing document you can get it actually has 150 or so of these sites where ufo
related operations have been some are key ones some have been incidental or peripheral ones right
and that's available for anyone to look at anyone who wants to look at it can see it okay um and
and so i'm in this chopper hovering over one of these and there's the opening from underground
where the man-made ufos go up go over a test range and they're hit with electromagnetic weapons
to see how hardened they are before they're good to go those are man-made and they're manned with
with people and are these similar to like tic tac stuff the tic tac ufos they're all shapes
they're all different shapes eggs they're octagonal they're discs they're the ones that are
northrop grumman and raytheon generally not all tend to be triangular or trapezoidal
or they're not necessarily equilateral triangles okay you know okay isosceles
and many of the ones that are cigar shaped or tic tac shaped or discs or octagonal
are locking skunk works e g and g and some others so all the prime contractors that we know of
where we have sources are named in the briefing document and i've been building that list for 30
years right ever since i was asked to put it together um and you know the problem is and this
gets to sort of a gut check here of what are you gonna do about it because let's say you're the
president or you're if i was his own patrick beth david show a couple days ago he's a big
broadcaster and a great guy and he asked me he said well you know do you think the president is
the most powerful man in the world i said well he could be but he isn't he's he showed a clip of
mr trump saying he is but he when they realize what they're up against with this
the power you're talking about derives from extraordinary technological prowess
so to make this real for people i just tell this is a sort of apocryphal but in 1997
excuse me i was asked to do a stand-up briefing for and this document leaked a report about this
leaked out of egger mitchell's archive when he died but my military advisor will be seen
tomorrow who's retired um and i and egger mitchell the six man the walk on the moon and
an eisenhower era whistleblower right and my assistant sherry adamak were in attendance but
i was asked to do a stand-up briefing for admiral tom wilson who is j2 the head of intelligence
joint staff and you know prior to the briefing i'd sent over something similar to this but
different but one of the documents that was in there is in here and it's a national reconnaissance
office with nr o which is the big entity that runs all the spy satellites
document from area 51 nellis warning of civilians trying to spy on the range where they test
and do the research on the man-made ufos right and they didn't want that to get out but in that it's
a not been declassified but it's legit and it lists the project code numbers and names right
so and it's a 91 document this meeting is in 97 so it wasn't antique right so i give it
i have a someone hand deliver it to the admiral prior to the meeting so he starts digging into
this and he hits peter he finds a few key offices where this is going on he calls them up and he
says hey you know i want to be read into this and he says i'm admiral tom wilson i'm j2 head of
intelligence joint staff and they say sir we can't discuss this with you and you don't have a need
to know and of course his reaction was well god damn it i mean i'm the head of intelligence with
the joint chiefs of staff how can i not have a need to know right excuse my language but i mean
this is like mind-blowing right all right so then he gets threatened and he's threatened with being
demoted where they take a star off your lapel and put you out to pasture with much lower benefits
and pay and retirement yeah let's be real 2025 has been all about change and a big change for me
is how i've been dealing with the world these mind-blowing guests and general life stress
and it's all thanks to these incredible gummies produced by our sponsor via trusted by over half
a million happy customers via is the swiss army knife of wellness dedicated to harnessing the
natural benefits of hemp to create high quality wellness products with award-winning thc and thc
free gummies via has a dosage to encourage your comfort no need to block off hours of the day for
an unproductive high when you can experience the full spectrum benefits from hemp and hemp products
with a micro dose of thc to give you a little boost without compromising your responsibilities
via is also well renowned for their award-winning thc and thc free vapes thc a flower soothing
topicals and calming drops all crafted with the highest quality hemp sourced from trusted
independently owned american farms personally i like to break them up into quarters and take
them after a long podcast when i'm overstimulated and want to relax and wind down with my family
or when i'm trying to get creative late at night maybe doing writing or watching a documentary or
preparing for a podcast it's great to get my mind flowing and in a creative state via is the only
lifestyle hemp brand they are experts at using compounds found in hemp along with the active plant
extracts to produce targeted effects it's incredible and the best part via legally ships
to nearly all states in the us in discrete packaging directly to your door with a worry
free guarantee no medical card required so if you're 21 plus check out the link to via in our
description below and use the code danny to get 15 off and if you're new to via get a free gift
card of your choice after your purchase they're going to ask where you heard about them and please
support the show by telling them we sent you this year enhance your everyday with via so he
backed off of it but at the meeting at the end of the meeting and it was supposed to be 45 minutes
i think it went on for two or three hours he kept canceling appointments i asked him i said we need
your help you know i'm just an emergency doctor doing this because i'm interested but it's serious
stuff and he asked me who else has had this happen to them i said well the secretary of defense
the ci director the president he said well what am i going to do i said yeah but you're here key
in the military in the pentagon and he says no here's what i've learned and this is how he said
it he says i've learned that the best thing i have in the normal constitutional government and military
is a b2 stealth and that organization have craft that are anti-gravity that can do circles he did
like this circles around my b2 still he says it's point set match he said you know we're
checkmated because of the technology so now we're into the horns of the dilemma right here because
you know i realized going up against corrupt interests that have that level of technology
which is very dangerous and when i literally tell people the threat from that organization
which is international have these technologies far exceeds the threat of china iran russia
terrorism and by order of magnitude and no one's doing anything about it because no one has quite
figured out what the threat matrix is what the threat assessment so what we're trying to do
not to scare the hell out of these officials but to say here's the problem here's a solution
now the solution the best outcome of this that we're recommending is a glide path out
that's not kinetic in other words not violent it's not a it's not a a red on black war
or something it's giving people who want to come forward a path out and they take it
and it unravels that system and it gets transformed into another initiative that those old legacy
programs that have been going along without any accountability for 60 plus years those are put out
the pasture so and wound down but it's got to happen that way or it's going to be a mess
are you saying that these organizations that are in possession of this technology and that
control this stuff that are keeping it away from the u.s government are they like their own
autonomous government a slash military slash air force that is completely
detached from any other world government they're detached and embedded at the same time
so and almost and and more arguably more powerful oh way more absolutely way more
this is why you know it's interesting when jimmy carter you know i was asked not to tell this
story he's passed away now so
he's adjusting your camera when president carter was some years ago in spain signing guitars
it was a classical guitarist who was there told me this who's part of our team and he said that
at the words it was a fundraiser for the carter center you know okay and they were auctioning
off these guitars right president signed them and at a dinner afterwards there were a few people
there and someone asked him they said sir what was it like being the most powerful man in the
world and president carter says i wasn't that man and they go what do you mean he says well there
are certain things that i had no control over and i wasn't even allowed to know about and someone
giggled or joking well you mean things like ufos and he said yes that and more so
that was of course he was president 7680 took off 77 january left in 81 and reagan came in right so
once you understand that then you go well who is mining the store here well it's sort of like if
you remember a brilliant guy senator ennui of hawaii who did the iran contra hearings right
right right and and he said there exists a secret government shadow government with its own air
force its own navy its own funding mechanism that's free from the law and above the law itself
i'm paraphrasing but that that clip is in our archive and years later after i did the original
disclosure project conference in 2001 an attorney on our team who was then an intern
undergraduate intern was met with senator ennui and we had just done the national press club event
in 2001 right before 9 11 and and this attorney derrick arcia has written an affidavit to this
effect he talked to senator ennui he says yes and you know like basically these ufo issues that's
the crown jewel of this shadow secret government operation right and it is above the constitution
and the law but the kinds of technologies they have i mean we're not talking about a jet aircraft
or a rocket you know i tell people rockets were cool and up until 1954 so if you think space x
rocket is called get out you're you're only 70 years behind the times bro so but that's fact
but this means that you have an organization you know some initial one of the initials on that
nr o document was a magic stands for majority joint intelligence committee or magi mha i
magi that's fun yeah do you think that any of these witnesses are our strategic disinfo like
if i was the secret government that had control of this stuff i would deliberately inject some
bullshit into this and put some i would absolutely put some fake whistleblowers out there yep and
that's something we have to always we've had this happen a couple times right before we did the
meeting for admiral wilson we had a gathering off site for members of congress and the chairman of
the house oversight committee was there dan burton and all those people and we found out the night
before uh and i don't credit myself with this my military advisor who has to be nameless
and egger mitchell another person was sitting at a bar with this guy and he started telling things
that they knew were factually not true so i got word of that i was already up in my room i said
that person is removed and escorted off the properties immediately and if necessary by force
so that person was ejected from the meeting that was happening the next day with these
members of congress so yeah of course i mean that that's something we always watch for and you know
i'm not 100 but i'm certain that what i'm sharing with you about this is true and i don't rely on
one source so in other words if something the crazier the count is the more i want to hear from
multiple corroborating witnesses that don't know each other so there's no collusion so that's what
we've tried to build with this mosaic this disclosure mosaic to create the picture yes because
you could always have two or three people who work with each other that come fabulate the same
nonsense right so it's uh that's something that happened with this recent fella that was just on
jesse michaels podcast jake barber i believe his last name is no i know jake very well yeah he
mentioned you um fantastic little documentary that jesse michaels put together and um michael
herrera i believe yeah and he mentioned during that during that interview that jake and i'm
probably butchering this i don't remember it perfectly but he said that he was a part of some
secret black program going to one of your conferences to try to subvert some of your
witnesses a year and a half ago some of your witness oh that was a year and a half ago
and then when he heard this guy michael herrera's testimony he said holy shit that's exactly what i
was doing yep i think that was a i i saw this with my own eyes and then he said he had some
coming to jesus moment where he said oh no i can't do this i have to i have to go against the grain
here no he's legit no he's he's he's i know his cover i know who he worked for i've been at the
facilities jake barber and his team and uh fred and and also uh don paul great guys and uh they're
not gaslighting anyone now they're not sharing everything either because you know it's dangerous
but um now there's some unsavory people that i think have attached themselves to these guys
um you know the lou elizando crowd and the whole disinformation nexus of
retail yeah i want to get to that i don't i want you to explain that to me later i don't want to
like interject that right now but that's something i would definitely want to put a pin in yeah
yeah well it's just wait this way the world works man um in one part information
nine parts disinformation right one part truth and by the way the best disinformation false
information it's sort of like a poison pill it's coated in real information you swallow it and then
you're done right so this technique of counterintelligence i'm quite versed in
and how it operates uh and how the psyops psychological warfare operations run these
operations on people who are innocent good people but harrera by the way had approached me some
years ago and michael harrera was a marine for people who don't know you can go to our archive
and see this account uh and the illustration of what he saw okay can you explain it for people
who don't sure so he was it was in i believe 2009 and he was a young marine i think 20 years old
and there was a tsunami an earthquake in indonesia and they were on an expeditionary force a
humanitarian mission to go there and help people and out of the pacific they were in the pacific
region and he and five of his platoon buddies went off in the direction and in the jungle
and there was a clearing and there was a 300 foot diameter man-made ufo
basically octagonal he knew this it was man he knew that it was oh he could tell it was man-made
and it was manned by special operations guys but in civilian garb they were told you know basically
put down your weapons they confiscated their weapons they took their ids they threatened to
kill them for having for being seen this and one of the things he saw they're trying to kill their
own u.s marines well they're not their own this is this shadow secret government these right right
okay i mean those are the real people committing treason and traitors and yes they'll kill their
own i mean look at jonathan wygon's testimony when he was in the peruvian bolivian border
where we shot down an et craft and he and his guys came across at first and the security people
who were in there to retrieve it said you talk about this we'll fill you out of the helicopter
and they'll never find you in the jungle so this happens all the time they do kill their own people
but they're not their own people they're americans though right yeah they're americans but it's you
know these are people who are running a criminal enterprise the biggest you know think of the mafia
it's the largest criminal organization on the planet so you know when the fbi is ready and
wants to grow up and be serious they have a real target here with technology that very few
human beings can comprehend so the other thing that michael Herrera saw was this crate and it
was a it was a it was a and it looked like it had like a little oxygen and hvc mini a portable unit
on it and he thought they were running drugs and it turned out because jake was at this conference
to try to bump witnesses and see who need to be turned over for either wet works or arrest
um he heard this and of course he immediately texted me because he has my number and he we went
to the green jake did yeah and his security guy so he knew you oh yeah but he was going to your
conference to subvert some of your witnesses well that's what his job was it was to find
and stop leaks and find out if i had the panasonic tough book that had been missing out of one of
these corporations i know which one it is that had all this intel on it because i receive stuff
all the time right and he thought maybe i had it um now i didn't know that's why he was there
right and prior to that i'd had a meeting with one of his security people at a bar near langley and
near cia tyson's corner in virginia and he gave me a little thumb drive that was like a 10 page
description of his involvement what he was doing and he subsequently a month or two later came
june uh 2023 to this disclosure project conference and press conference we did
where herrera and some other whistleblowers were speaking and but he immediately said i need to see
you so i'll go back to the green room and he says that isn't drugs those are people and so what they
were doing what they the way they get their psionic and other staff let's call it at these
underground facilities is let's say there's a terrible disaster or war-torn area and people
are desperate and they're they're not kidnapped per se but it's under duress they're basically told
you can either come with us and be part of our program i'll describe it in a moment or you can
stay here and die you choose now i wouldn't call that a very but this is how it is this is brutal
stuff right oh yeah and that's what was in those crates these are people and they were people who
were candidates for being how do they discern what kind of people they need they were looking for
people with a certain demographic that they felt would have a high psionic capability and am i
correct in saying they were children they were children there were women somehow there's a
tendency for left-handedness for that ability and gay and bisexual men so that's who they were
looking for because it like ingo swan was i knew him very well ingo was and he was a gay guy
brilliant remote viewer so and who cares i mean people get hung up on that i said well it was
like if you're gay raise your hand if you're left-handed like we need you no no they don't
do it that way i know this might be silly but i mean they will scope out and then they'll say
they'll and of course it's a rough uh sort of assessment they're then created up taken to a
facility and the ones that pass muster for their psi capabilities psionic psychic capabilities
go through a program now a lot of those end up dying because they're put on drugs dopamine
electromagnetic enhancement so many end up dying or or put in comas and wait wait hold on man
so so so getting these people so this specific situation michael Herrera was in indonesia after
there was an earthquake they essentially you don't want to say kidnapped because it's not a nice way
to putting it but it's essentially kidnapped them and taken under some dress i mean come with us or
die right i mean i don't know you can call that whatever you want it sounds like some level of
human trafficking um brought these children to the to a secret base secret black site that they
control for psychic warfare and and for training to be psionic hijackers of et craft that's just
the next part of it and they trained him to be psychic psionic what is so yeah to hijack these
crap and you're saying that they put they gave them drugs what kind of drugs do they give them
and why do they give them drugs i don't have the whole protocol i just know that they were
dopamine related and also there were electromagnetic systems and there were some bad a lot of bad
outcomes but the ones who passed through it have an extraordinary capability but it's an enhanced
so basically the way they described it to me is that you have the people who are the operators say
the regular human covert folks right these people are humans that are sort of machine tools
that are then used to then tap into the guidance and control systems of these et craft because
they're using what i just described technology assisted consciousness where they're you know you
think to it you see these accounts of the et standing there touching something they just
think and it goes there so okay i know this is getting out there but no it's not it's it
makes the crazy thing is it makes sense oh it totally makes sense and of course this goes back
to my 1973 experience with the et's where i knew this is what they were using so and i believe
that's why in 1992 general stubblebine personally offered me two billion dollars to be part of his
little freak show by the way what yeah i said no gracias i mean he offered you two billion dollars
in 1992 dollars yeah why did you say no well because i'm not a corrupt person oh my god two
billion dollars i saved lives for a living i don't want to be part of a cabal of sociopaths
and psychopaths destroying the planet right what did he say no price two billion i'd be part of
his team a senior member of his team because of my abilities and also being a doctor with these
capabilities i mean they were going to and who was he exactly he had been i'm not familiar with
head of inscom and he was head of army intelligence and general albert stubblebine the third and
burt approached me and then i said no i know but hell no and then he went to my wife
we're about to have our 46th anniversary and he tried to sweet talk her into this madness
and uh she's very thought he was very nice i said no devil speak with forked tongue but what did
he do why was he such an evil person oh he was part of that whole group of folks this he was
like he's passed away but he was part of the same kind of group that people like colonel alexander
and alessandro they're all part of that whole operation they have different roles but his role
was to interface from that black illegal program world with the ufo subculture back then this is
like 33 years ago right um so so psychological information manipulation trying to trying to
handle the con the perception the public perception of this stuff in the united states
is basically what he wanted you to help him do yes but also be part of that operational team is
what i think um in terms of these capabilities because he knew that we had done he approached
me right after there was proof that our ce5 contact had worked and there are these four et
craft that appeared here in florida up outside pensacola so that is when he surfaced uh exactly
then now of course everyone makes fun of us for doing that oh it's ouija board stuff i said like
the hell it is you think you think these civilizations are using your iphone you know why would they be
using 20th century and early 21st century communications technologies they're using stuff
like elon would like to do musk would like to do with neural link except without the wires right
not the speed of light at speed of thought like that right instant so that program has been in
development for decades but it reached the level of success let's call it i mean if you can call
hijacking et craft and then blowing them out of the sky with electromagnetic pulse weapons
which are illegal by the way i just can't get over two billion dollars you're a better man than me
now well i might have been i might have been doing it i would have saluted and been a psyop
fucking head of psyops i'm not interested in that
look you know i mean i'm not rich but i'm comfortable as a doctor i don't need that
and i've never had aspirations for that yeah and yeah i say i say it all the time
whether people in the comments who think think i'm a i'm cia funded podcast if the cia wants to offer
me a million bucks i'm sign me up well that's the joke i mean you know i i bootstrapped this whole
effort for 35 years with a handful of people and no office and you know a couple you know some
volunteers and one and a half staff members and my wife and me so i said oh yeah if i were at
you know if i were that guy do you ever i wouldn't be uh i wouldn't be doing this you know do you
ever think back like just laying in bed late at night be like god damn it maybe i should have
taken that two billion dollars never never because then you're you're that you're owned
you're you're an owned asset i value my freedom i value my freedom or i value all the money on
earth did he did he offer in payments or was it like an upfront lump sum no the way he described
is that after the cold war ended and the soviet union was falling apart in the late 80s early
90s that they had seized a bunch of assets in eastern europe and they had a slush fund
and that i would have control and access of that and it was a lot of money um and look the kind
of black budget money these guys have it's enormous there's another guy who told me in 93
a couple months for a brief ci director and he was technically involved with the ufo subculture
but he was a tech guy who was embedded with this shadow government and he said look we have given
at least 10 000 people 10 million dollars a piece or more to secure their cooperation with what we're
doing and then he made another offer to me and this was about a year and a half after general
stubble bind so i said no thank you i don't want to go that route i want to stay independent and
free but um and i would imagine the disinfo people they probably target media personalities
they probably target podcasts maybe you know if they're still doing if they're still i mean
imagine what they were doing with richard doty in like what was it the 70s 80s yeah with paul
benowitz and and the level they went to to go to these ufo conferences and try to get these people
and say hey i'm going to give you some secrets if you just go out there and get us some intel on
these people and meanwhile the secrets they're giving them are like half-baked bullshit have you
ever seen the documentary unacknowledged that we did it's had about 800 900 million people i don't
think i've seen that one though i watched serious um unacknowledged is the one that prompted them to
shove elizando out into the public from his counterintelligence operation at the pentagon
it's it's had well over 800 million people see it and in that we interview
mr doty and he admits to carrying bags of cash to people oh yes i have seen this i've seen this
clip and he also admits that there were abduction programs that we were doing but then he got really
scared i said i can't talk about that right but i have multiple people who confirm that now we also
have a book in 92 that shock valet wrote who's a very you know well-known researcher on this
he's an astronomer astrophysicist i think and he admits to having a document from the cia from
1985 shock valet and go look at it this is in the briefing where he admits that this document he
has he won't release that i think he's been threatened and it talks about the agency the
cia going down to argentina and brazil abducting peasants making it look like aliens were abducting
them using these advanced technology systems for it's and i'm quoting their psychological warfare
value so imagine how easy it's like taking candy from a baby in the amateur ufo research subculture
to stage this stuff and get everyone to twitter talking about how the aliens did x y and z and
there's staging it's called stagecraft i know what the technologies are i've i have debriefed
people who are operational on the man-made ufos doing it the cattle mutilations have nothing to
do with ets it's all yes that we can prove so the project gasbury or something were they were they
detonated in the 70s they detonated a subterranean nuke and they had uh helicopters going out and
basically is this is correct where they were mutilating cattle and they were trying to
they were doing surgical operations and taking out certain parts of the cattle the tongue
the glands and trying to determine whether they had been infected with this sort of radiation
whether the food and the crops and the cattle had been infected with this stuff well that's one
operation there's another operation to get substrate material biological growth material
right for their little weird gray and other reptilian looking the man-made ets right
because some of them are not just robotic some are but the more advanced ones are sort of what
they call a bio nano machine so they have a biological and a technological component but
they're man-made um and people go this is sounds too far out i said but wait imagine what kind of
you know if you have that kind of mad scientist mentality it's like dr strangelove and you've got
the virtually limitless funding black budget and otherwise criminal organ drug running everything
yeah and you've got et technologies that you're studying for decades you're going to come be able
to come out with a whole constellation of dirty tricks right people it's so interesting to detangle
this stuff well that's my job it's to try to make sense out of this madness and from my
understanding of the cattle mutilation is the atomic energy commission like when they when they
did that um i think it was in 67 where they detonated the subterranean nuke to find natural
gas reserves in dulce new mexico um what they did was they the cattle mutilation was like a
monitoring program to assess radiation leakage in the ecosystem or whatever and at the same time
they were doing they were testing some of this exotic aircraft over the same location the people
started to think oh my god these aircraft are are doing this to the cattle it's aliens so they said
oh the people are saying that we're going to keep flying our aircraft over those cattle testing
mutilation the deals so that was like to an insane level of well that's public perception
but that's common and then all you have to do is have someone write you know an alien harvest like
you have people write abduction books and what's interesting the very people who are setting this up
will guide those victims and they are victims i'm not saying these abduction people aren't real they
have been victimized but they haven't been taken by extraterrestrials they've been taken by covert
human special operations made to look alien right so it's a look-alike right so those programs uh
uh they sell and the media which is as corrupt as anything you can imagine the legacy media
uh you know a lot of those people they're you know like i will be absolutely not only shadow
banned but banned to tell the truth on a lot of media whereas if you're going forward telling a
lie boom you're on 60 minutes boom you're on that's true because the big media is i think
probably more corrupt than any other institution in the united states or the world yeah and being
controlled by these interests yeah but how do they i understand how the media is controlled
by advertising dollars but how are how do you think they're controlled by these
rogue military aerospace companies money and control pay their back door and money to them
they're knocks they're they have a non-official cover you know by day and public persona they're
a media person they're actually working with the agency or some other entity that's part of this
compartmented shadow government and you know i know people like that i mean probably if i had
taken the money i would have been one of those guys right yeah so um you know that's how that
works and it makes one of the problems with washington is everyone's so busy doing a million
different things you know they have 99 things to do every day and and this thing as you pointed
out the beginning and you're right is a it's a such a confusing mess of conflicting information
yeah that they just go i don't want to hear it is too complicated right but that is part of the
reason they've made it complicated it's obfuscating it hides it yeah exactly by making it just
incomprehensible it's impossible to know what's real so we have to make it understandable and
i liken this to like you know the epiphany moment in the wizard of oz when darthi and
whoever the scarecrow and they pull back the curtain and there's this old crud mudgeon pulling
the levers right yeah that's what this is so you know part of what we have to do is not just say
here's the evidence for nhi craft and people extraterrestrial craft and people but here's
the other part of it here's the dominant information disinformation that's out in
ufology in the media in documentaries in films and books has actually been staged by the very
people trying to keep it secret yeah so that you're looking over here and not the truth yeah and
they're very good at doing this danny they're extremely good at one of my favorite stories
was from annie jacobson in her area 51 book where she interviewed the cia pilots who are test flying
the first jet planes over the air force base and they said they they purposely brought gorilla
masks in the cockpit for in the chance that they flew by a civilian aircraft they put the gorilla
mask on so that they're just they're poisoning that story already so if the guy goes to the bar
later because dude i saw a monkey flying a jet plane well and and the early abductions in the
late 50s early 60s they had the man-made ufos that and they had some guys very short stature
were not quite looking normal and they're kind of like hollywood you can make a guy look like
darth vader or whatever that they had that stagecraft and it was incredibly convincing
because even now now you look at one of our witness witnesses who whistleblowers who came
forward a year and a half ago steven digna he was at fort irwin california in 2000 and he was
called out by some raytheon guys to look at some objects that were out over the range and they had
to cancel their live fire exercises because of this and it was a triangular not quite
equilateral more of a pointed triangular craft and they didn't know he picked up a pair of night
vision scopes and he looked at it he saw the detail on it and then he saw that there were
several others that were holographic projections of the real one and so it looked like there was a
fleet of them yeah and this is how you stage a fake alien attack yeah they they had this this
was all part of that declassified northwoods thing where they were trying to stage a fake invasion
over cuba well no this was a separate incident but it's very similar to that it's very similar and
and so they were very upset that he figured that out right and the raytheon guys few days later
abducted him and his wife on coming back from a movie back to the base on this road out in
california remote road and if anyone who would have seen that craft and what happened would have
sworn it was a alien vehicle and his raytheon now he suffered terrible damages he's very damaged he's
very sick so you know that is what happens if you get too close to the truth and he's an incredibly
sweet man very courageous he's totally telling the truth but i would say if you took a million
people on earth and showed them that craft that that raytheon object craft in 2000 is 25 years
ago right right i don't think one person would think that it was man-made and this is a problem
for the national security council and the president because everyone assumes
that what i'm telling you they know they don't if you've seen the documentary unacknowledged
you know more about this subject than virtually anyone in the u.s congress except the bad apples
who are on the payroll of the shadow secret government right well so so this is a problem
i mean if you want to live in a in a free society in a democracy you can't have something this
important you know completely ignored by your elected officials right and also the benefit
of having so much bullshit out there is is if the truth does get out it doesn't fucking matter
because there's what's the what are the chances that they're going to pick that as being the truth
well that's that's now you're very smart because you just hit the nail in the coffin what keeps me
up at night um is and that's why i don't trust any of these whistleblowers because i don't i
don't think well i i know the ones i know and and uh now here's someone like like mr grush
he was telling 100 the truth until he started telling tall tales that were being fed to him
by lou alazando right about how the aliens had blown up villages and i don't know south america
or someplace that was alazando told him that yeah so he fell into that disinformation trap
along with the information trap but a lot of people do that and why because those guys will
say hey i can get you a 10 million dollar book or movie deal and i i can get you on 60 minutes so
you know there are advantages to going with those folks as opposed to doing it let's call it clean
because doing it clean is a hard path i mean you know i you know it's been a big struggle for me
and my family and you know you have all kinds of problems because of it but i don't regret it
i mean i wouldn't do anything different at all but it's a dangerous and it's very ungratifying
from a personal point of view nobody would do it except i feel that this is something
if this doesn't get resolved properly what verner von brown warned about right he said look the whole
plan is to stage an alien threat so we can unite the world around this sort of fascist
totalitarian militaristic sort of thing it's like the movie independence day right and we'll say
let's go kick alien butt you see the arabs and everybody in the world united to fight the aliens
so that's all right at a cia psyops scripting and guess what 99 percent of legacy ufology
that's the narrative there are the good aliens and the bad ones and the so star wars right it's
it's all that narrative and i go you at least members of congress are saying look if these
civilizations were hostile given that their technologies are hundreds of thousands of
years more advanced than ours we'd be gone we'd be a charcoal briquette floating through space
now do they have this is not to say i'm not naive this is not to say that those civilizations
don't have some self-interest because what would you think i mean just put yourself in the shoes
and through the eyes of an et you come across this planet and in a few decades it goes from
you know muskets and machine guns to thermonuclear weapons to the heads of each other to very
advanced electromagnetic weapons including the so-called scalar ones that are knocking et craft
now and then the same group going off the reservation of any controls reverse engineers
your et technologies and start using it against you got it that's the crisis that no one's talking
about because and and you know jake and people like him will say you know it's at the point now
where they just say at the advanced technologies humans have to most people on earth would be
indistinguishable from an et vehicle or nhi craft and there's a big risk there because number one
they could stage a false flag attack and everyone think it was alien which is what their plan is
that's what the drones were all about by the way i mean mr trump got that wrong
when his press secretary commented on that we we know what that was that was that was that was a
psyop it was a psyop hundred percent by coordinated by who by the same people who are trying to be
sure that when this comes out this year and next that it's done in a with the specter of fear
we don't know people look at the skies oh i'm afraid they look just like hobby drones like
they looked like they weren't they weren't moving crazy at all no i have no i know a team that was
under contract with lockheed martin that has some images of some of this stuff and some of them are
pretty amazing and some of the daytime ones that they've captured now they're not extraterrestrial
they're our advanced stuff but again and some have said well these are originated from china
but that's a misnomer because this shadow government entity is transnational
you can label whatever country you want it doesn't matter it operates you know when i was the first
time i went to meet with this the latest efforts about three years ago at the senate intelligence
committee skiff and i went in there and i said see that map of the world erase all the geopolitical
boundaries like the boundary between canada united states or mongolia and china or whatever
yeah this organization the world is their oyster they they don't care about that so now the truth
is people like jake barber and his guys are patriots who got stuck in that system as i said
and they deserve a clean path out a safe path out and that's what has to happen that's got to
happen from the congress and from the president's executive orders which i've seen some drafts of
those and and so yeah and they're and they're in here their recommendations are in here
for for what those need to be and they need to be done yesterday we kind of just got really
sidetracked down a crazy rabbit hole after we started talking about jake and michael
Herrera's situation where they were extracting these people out yeah and he's the only guy who
i've ever heard about who saw something like that and was not killed really only survived his guys
yes absolutely it's a miracle he wasn't killed i told him that i said you have no idea how rare
it is for someone like you a kid 20 years old seeing something like that for them not to just
erase you you know so yeah i remember from that story jake was like saying the guys were saying
should we smoke these guys should we smoke these guys blah blah and they ended up not doing that
so they're taking these children from foreign countries these underdeveloped places
and adults and adults but the the primary reason is because they are out of a civilized
they're not in like a metropolitan city they're not around technology all the time
they're in a completely native environment and they're eating i don't know maybe unprocessed
foods natural foods so they're more connected to nature somehow and that somehow makes them more
in tuned to this psychic consciousness the psionic stuff that he's talking about and
they put them in this program give them dopamine drugs and hook them up to all kinds of technology
and use them to summon these eggs this is what he said summon the eggs well not just the eggs
it's all different types of craft and but it's not it's more than just summon okay so let me
be a little let me unpack this a little more okay years ago you heard about this weird looking drone
that kind of looked like a ufo that the iranians were able to break into its guidance system and
land and then study to reverse engineer it i never heard about this oh it's all in the media so but
if you look into that now maybe you can find it what year i can't remember iranian iranian drone
that was caught that was no hours that they intercepted and hijacked it basically by wire
iran did yes and landed it at a base in iran and then studied the reverse engineer you gotta find
this shit dude yeah but that it it was a drone it was not a ufo right it was looked weird it was a
very unusual shape and uh now imagine being able to do that with this instead of guide by wire
right right there u.s drone recovered by iran 2011 i'm sure there have been multiple here we go
yeah see what a strange looking one sophisticated spy planes u.s intelligence is spying intensely
on iranian sites believed to be developing nuclear weapons and long-range missiles
bob oar tells us an unmanned u.s drone did vanish over the weekend the secret stealth drone
nicknamed the beast of kandahar is one of america's most sophisticated intelligence tools
for the past four years the rq-170 has flown high altitude surveillance missions over the
battlefields in afghanistan okay so here's my point in this is that this is this sort of nonsense
happens all the time yeah um what my point of it is they were able to break into the encrypted
hardened guidance system because these are all flown a lot of them out of nellis from a or bases
out in the desert underground and they're unmanned but they're on the other side of the world
so but they were able to break into that system yeah the command and control guidance and land it
they didn't crash now did they do that with this consciousness stuff no no they didn't i'm using
this as an analogy if i can get through my sentence so that's an analogy now imagine having an
interstellar vehicle an hi craft and their technologies are consciousness thought interfacing
so you train these people to basically hack into their guidance system when no one's looking and
you hijack it instead of landing it you bring it over to an area sometimes you can land the et craft
but often what they do is they hit it with an electromagnetic pulse weapon and it either is
disabled and falls to the ground or it's blown to pieces now what i was getting ready to tell you is
that in these same areas they'll put up a tfr which is basically a you know a temporary flight
restriction area over an area of space airspace if there is a civilian aircraft that strays into
that and they're wanting and they're using these electromagnetic pulse weapons they will blow the
innocent civilian cessna out of the sky and i know this for a fact sometimes the electromagnetic
pulse goes outside the tfr and hits a totally a aircraft that was trying to stay out of the tfr
so now we have over at continental united states a real threat to air traffic which are always
blaming it on the aliens no the real threat to air traffic are the man-made ufos and these
sort of operations that work because these are not always done over permanent flight restriction
areas like a top secret air force base they're done in these other places right so this is a
real problem i brought it up to officials in washington and what's astounding to me i want to
vent a little bit here you know i've been blowing the whistle on this nonsense since 93 and you
always wonder i think we have something called the fbi or law enforcement now we can prove through
our direct witnesses kidnapping murder treason killing innocent civilians like i just described
embezzlement of u.s federal dollars into black projects without oversight and oversight of the
president or congress on and on half the federal penal code has been is being violated by this
organization and it's precisely where is the congress and the white house and the fbi so now
that we have a new administration and a new congress and this is all beginning to come out
i think that the public listening either contact their senators and house member and and the white
house and say look we need to get this resolved but you need to enforce the law and protect
you know the american democracy but also the american public and that's not happening yet
and so that group goes unchecked while these terrible atrocities keep going now what i would
like to see happen is that those operations get wound down peacefully because there's a as i
mentioned earlier a glide path out to basically transform that mess into something that's forward
looking and i think all the whistleblowers i know that's what they want to see you know because
an eye for an eye leaves the whole world blind and if you go kinetic if you go into a violent
confrontation with an organization that have assets that are way beyond anything as adamor
wilson said that they can deploy it's not going to be good yeah because you're like like it's a
suicide mission what would it be like to go to war with one of these i know exactly and now i'm
advising a group that has been asked to do exactly that if it comes to it and and i don't want to
talk about detail operational details about it a military a u.s military group i won't talk about
what agency or what entity it is okay but it's a sap it's tsci top secret special compartment
information and i've been asked to provide everything i can and i will and i have been i've
been doing this for 30 some years but now we have a critical mass of people who have details i mean
talked about some of the whistleblowers that are still behind the curtain that could be brought in
and who who know of multiple places there was one gentleman who was about to come forward and
he got threatened but he was read into 18 unacknowledged special access projects dealing
with this he had baseline clearance across 18 of them in a top secret pentagon office so
we have people like that they're living they need to be protected he's afraid of not only being
killed but his pension being erased because he signed an 80-year nondisclosure agreement
that said that if he ever discussed any of this that he would lose his freedom but also his pension
and he's getting up in years he has some more injuries he's a hero and i can't you know what i
never do is just shove someone like that out i mean i am a doctor so it's like a doctor patient
confidentiality but at a certain point the people who can protect people like him have a
legal obligation i will say that given what is in here that the unredacted part what people can get
is the has redacted like this guy's name's redacted but there is a dereliction of duty here if they
don't deal with this and i think the american public they need to hear i've had so many members
of congress in the senate say we really need to hear from our constituents on this right
now people are so apathetic they just think everything happens by itself no it doesn't
you got to create a movement so i'm sort of an activist that way you got to have people say look
we want this resolved we want this fixed yesterday but we also want to bring out the technologies
that would save the biosphere and eliminate poverty so imagine i don't think the things
that are flying at 200 000 miles per hour should come out right now that are man-made because
that's a missile delivery system you don't want every terrorist in mogadishu having that to boom
do something in over downtown la but the things that would sit on your table here and run this
building from what's called the zero point or quantum vacuum energy that needs to come out
and that would then give us a civilization without pollution and without poverty within
and certainly your lifetime maybe not mine because i'm almost 70 in june but
there would be an amazing leap forward and so i think my four daughters and 12 grandkids would
actually have a planet to live on instead of it just being ruined by these 1800s technologies
we're using you know so that is the big piece of it and let's call that the big piece dividend of
this all coming out danny is that imagine a civilization without pollution and where your
energy needs are met without cost once you have a be like a heat pump or something smaller right
provide all the energy for your car or your business or your house and with no bill no
electric bill the the problem with that this is what patrick david said the other day to me he
said no one wants that to come out because there goes trillions of dollars in assets right all the
public utilities don't need them all the oil gas coal nuclear power don't need them right an electric
plug-in car like a tesla don't need it sure so well you could use the electric motor part but
those you know 900 pounds of lithium ion batteries so the idea is like don't need it right right
conventional transportation and petroleum industries that prop up our economy are going
to be all of a sudden irrelevant if we have some crazy zero point anti-gravity technology
well again the anti-gravity technology really can't come out right yet but the other can
zero point energy zero point what i call the station the basically a power plant that generates
energy but you don't want something that's flying at that kind of maneuverability in the hands of
unstable failed states and whatnot now i always point out to people the worst people in the world
have that technology now because these are rogue shadow government operators that are doing all
these terrible things and i think they have more terrible things they're planning to do
which i don't want to go into but i think we ain't seen nothing yet from that crowd
i wanted to ask you about roswell specifically because i've talked to annie jacobson about
roswell and she wrote about it in her book i'm sure you're familiar with what she said there
was an e g and g engineer that was a source for her and he told her that it was a craft
piloted by remote-controlled by the soviet union and it had deformed children in there that were
surgically altered by mengele or the nazi mengela mengela yeah and it was crashed here to basically
sow chaos and she asked him she's like why the hell wouldn't you say this this would make them
look terrible and it would be great for us if we you know were able to expose this and they would
be completely humiliated on the world stage and he said because we started doing the same exact
thing that they were doing well i'm not so sure of that because we have interviewed people who
are now deceased who handle the bodies and they most certainly were not that so now have there
been events like that yes and we've confirmed that russia and probably china have these same
technologies and have they done stagecraft and hoax things very likely but see a one source
account i know the e g and g folks one of the g's is greer i'm not related just on the record
but you know i you know again a one source
no but you know and if you look at the the the people who were there at the
retrieval site of the one that was not blown to smithereens that was no man-made object but
you know and in 1947 the only thing we had that would have been
electro-gravitic were ones that were unstable so the the what was called the disc that we brought
over from nazi germany at the end of the war that was not stable and if you look at some of the old
home movies and you see it looks like they're like falling like a leaf like this those are early
man-made ones that had didn't have the gyro let's say or the stable they had not mastered the
gravity control that was 54 late 1954 so those craft would it would be very not that stable
but they were man-made but if you look on the inside of them you know like the what's called
the arv that brad sorensen saw yeah and mark mccandless who's passed away
illustrated for us and got the sort of good concept of the schematics all the interior
components and this is late 50s early 60s were mercury era components when you looked at it
now it was electro-gravitic it had gone out in the space before we land on the moon
but it wasn't interstellar and certainly if it came to ground it would be obvious it was man-made
components like right away so i point out to people one of the big confusions here is and
it makes it easy once you understand there's the man-made and there's the non-human et but if you
don't and in here is a number of craft that are illustrated and they're side by side where you see
a man-made one versus an et one yeah but i will say can i see that one well it's i'd have to flow
we'd be flipping around but was so was roswell man-made or was it et that the one that's the
famous case and i think there may have been some cover cases that are mixed up the 1945 white sands
event and that roswell event were et there were obviously if you're out in that area this is where
you would be testing your prototype so if we already had remember the b phil brown effect from
the 1920s to 40s and then we get the nazi disc that was brought over by the billionaire paul
melon and general patten and alan dullis and it was a lot more advanced anything we had in terms
of gravity stability so and that's 45 so you can imagine in the 40s into the early 50s there had
been a number of these that would malfunction go down they wouldn't want people to know that we're
working on that technology and they would be loved for people to think it was alien or et right so i
think that again when you start getting into this sort of puzzle palace of of information disinformation
you have to first have a sort of a guidebook you know i liken this to being a doctor and having
what we call differential diagnosis so you know someone comes in with chest pain so a stupid
doctor is gonna say oh it's automatically a heart attack when it could be dozens of things it could
be a dissecting thoracic aneurysm it could be pleurisy it could be a pulmonary embolus it could
be a strain muscle so i i think what's happening with the with the ufo subculture they try to make
everything one thing and it isn't it's several things going on simultaneously and being mixed
up deliberately by very masterful counterintelligence and disinformation folks
yeah and they're very good at it i want to talk about the disinformation stuff and the
elizabeth stuff i got to get leak real quick so we'll pause real quick yeah we'll be right back
absolutely all right we're back um
sorry i can't let we gotta i gotta ask you that again you we were just talking about um with the
quiet zone in west virginia and how you do the ce5 protocols and you said you let the ets know
that the earth is armed right one of the protocols if you if you get the app it's ce5 contact app
i can get it uh in part of the training and when we're doing these sort of
sai remote viewing contact we let them know that they should only appear in any way that is safe
and appropriate for that time place and group and that the earth has a lot of systems that
can pick them up when they come out of let's call it transdimensional space time into 3d
so if you're an uh let's say you're an et craft you could be totally invisible to all sensors
because you're you can shift let's say the resonant frequency uh of that whole craft
and everyone i can shift out of this dimension into a very higher frequency so it's not 3d but
then it can pop into 3d this is why people see them materialize and dematerialize
and when they're in the non-3d form so they're not solid yeah you're not going to be able to
strike them and down them as easily right this is why we have so many weird phenomenon you know
it's funny the cia has a term wsfm it stands for weird science and freaking magic an engineer
knew it norther grumman just calls it pure fucking magic pfm and so when you start getting into
either the high end of the electronics that are man-made or the interstellar extraterrestrial
manifestations and phenomenon you're dealing with some very strange stuff right and you would
expect that but it's not what people expect uh when they usually get introduced to this idea so
we tell we make it very clear to these visitors that you know there are satellites that have what
are called neutrino light detectors on them that started in the 70s uh they can pick them up when
they drop out of let's call it transdimensional higher frequency yeah into 3d yeah boom it's a
signature so there's a neutrino light scatter that happens and there are earth-based sensors
they're space-based and aircraft and so they'll pick these objects up and then they'll then
triangulate them and hit them with one of these electromagnetic or scalar weapons so because we're
doing this it's very different from what was going on that jake barber talked about yeah we're not
luring them over so we can hit them and kill them and reverse engineer their stuff we're doing it as
sort of a uh ambassadors as it will as civilian ambassadors from humans to them so for peaceful
contact we're not doing it to get rich quick and make another widget so are there beings inside
these things yes not all of them i mean some are unmanned and some have the equivalent of a android
drone uh that's et because you know they know how dangerous earth is and don't like
my brain just thinks like wouldn't these beings that are so advanced transdimensional ets don't
they have better things to do than to interface with a couple people that are meditating in the
middle of nowhere no they don't because if they're assigned to do something about the situation here
they need a point of contact right i mean stop for a minute the reason i started this whole
project in 1990 was not the disclosure project that was an accidental outgrowth right of the
main project started with ce5 it started with ce5 contact and the reason for that was that i realized
that it was either in complete denial our society our media our most people in the government
or we were targeting them and killing them there was no one on the earth setting up let's call it
a peaceful outreach that would be let's say an ambassador level where you're just willing to be
someone who does this out of goodwill to establish the beginnings of a relationship between humans
and these other civilizations and i realized no one was doing that and so that's why i started
this whole organization in 1990 it was not to do the disclosure project i kind of got dragged
kicking and screaming into that once i realized that you know like most people they think that
the president and the congress are in control of all these covert programs and they know what's
going on when i realized that how dangerous this organization is that was had gone completely off
the leash of any oversight that's when i started doing the disclosure project but that's not what
i was mainly interested yeah but you have to warn these trans-dimensional ets that that they have
to be careful for people beaming them out of the sky right well we just do it as just a reminder
because we don't want to be responsible for the loss of life whether it be human or or et so
you know i'm a doctor so above all do no harm right i mean you know the saying that doctors
supposed to live up to so we don't want to set up a situation and so it's not to say we think
they're they're they're not monitoring this it's just to remind them and also don't be so willing
to do something in this dimension because we're wanting this right because humans are really
wanting the ones that come on these events with me they really want to make there are a lot of
people who are very pure-hearted about it they're not all just jerks right out there we have wonderful
people millions of people who have been doing ce5 now i mean william shatner got it and then
went up in that space thing and all these people and so what we're wanting to do is show these
civilizations there's another side of humanity that isn't a warmongering bunch of jerks wanting
to blow them out of the sky right but who is doing that the state department the un no so i liken this
to back in the cold war when there were physicians for social responsibility who were doctors going
over to the old soviet union to try to create a rapprochement and a dialogue right this just take
this on cosmic level to where there should be humans reaching out to these civilizations
for not some ulterior motive to get their goodies and get rich or turn them into a weapon system
or blow them out of the sky but because there's an opportunity coming up for humans to be part of
a larger cosmic family or whatever you want to call it so what kind of communication are
you having when you're summoning these beings we don't summon them you see the king of england
would summon a valet what do you call i know jake uses that term and it's appalling you should never
use that what do you use we invite them okay you summon of your you summon your uber driver
right i mean this is disrespectful it's completely disrespectful okay well look look words matter
sure right yes they do matter i agree all right so what are words words are expressions verbally
of the thought and the thought is expression of the consciousness behind it so we do not call or
summon them we invite them with a sense of the equality that exists between all intelligent life
in other words even if they're very different from us they may have much higher iqs more advanced
technologically but at the level of what erwin schrodinger talked about the singularity of mind
of consciousness and that's a universal of constant on that level they're awake we're awake
and so the light of awareness from my eyes yours and ets it's the same because they've done studies
consciousness is in fact a singularity it's not divisible sure we divide it by our egos
right yeah and in reality on a higher level of understanding it's a singularity so that is where
we come together is why our motto is one universe one people that within the universe at that level
of consciousness and mind we're all one people and so that's why i don't like the term alien
which means foreign right i like the term you know people people say what do you call i saw
they're non-human people they're extraterrestrial people now the trick here and this is where it
gets very complicated for some people is that a lot of people will do something like that
and they'll bump into something from another dimension right like an angel or a demon or
whatever but that's not an extraterrestrial so this is where you get into this you know tucker
carlson oh yeah he got he got gaslit by a lot of these intel folks who told them that the aliens
are demons well the reason he was gaslit was because they were praying on his valid you know
christian beliefs i'm not questioning that at all but this sort of cosmology that is known within
many traditional circles they wanted to conflate that with alien and it's easy to do because
that is another special operations capability and that is to use very powerful electromagnetic
systems to create phenomenon like you see at skinwalker or bradshaw ranch we know how they're
doing it i know who's doing it i know what the electronics are now there's an innate phenomenon
that was there but then those both sides were taken over by covert human black operations
so this aliens and demons narrative that it seems to be everywhere where is that coming from and
what is the purpose behind it what is the motive of it it is literally to demonize non-human
existence so we can have war see everything tracks at the fear factor yeah right everything
tracks back to how do you are you you're sorry how do you create an enemy right right all right
so if you're wanting to aggrandize the military industrial super complex on a on a you know
international level the card that has to be eventually played which is what vernon brown
warned about will be this alien threat card and so you can do it in a lot of way if you're talking
to someone who's religious relate it to demons if you're talking to someone who's conventional
geopolitical they're a national security threat or air safety threat right if you want to relate it
whatever it is so they have scripts and narratives to sort of affect and what they do is they do an
analysis of your own psychology and belief system and they target it so and which it was interesting
i was at the vatican there's a flavor of psy up for everyone yes and it's curated it's tailored
for that um you're at the vatican and i was when i was at the vatican some years ago when pope john
paul was the pope i met with him on senior balduci you may have heard of him he was a
senior theologian to the pope and very interested in this issue of the ets and ufos and
ironically he was also a demonologist at the vatican he was an exorcist in here a couple
days yeah i mean it was interesting and of course you know not my cup of tea and whatever if i
whatever fires your rockets but uh but i was at his apartments overlooking you know st peters
yeah and he's turned to me he says you know neither demons nor angels require flying saucers
and it was such a quaint succinct way of putting it and i go yeah of course so he was talking about
all this disinformation and fear mongering because that's how you control a populace you have a you
have to create fear yeah and a narrative and then you get people to buy into it two things one have
you seen the shit chris bledsoe does with the with the orbs i've heard of it i'm not that familiar
with it i know he summons orbs the sub summons a bad word he invites the he invites the orbs
yes but he's also been intercepted by jim semivan who's a ci operative exactly this is another thing
this is crazy there's so many layers to this i know right i i know that he has been the crazy
thing about this guy i had him on the podcast over a year ago and he is somehow able to invite
these orbs which i've personally witnessed with him on the beach a mile away from here me and
steve both we filmed it i have the video he it's it's real but at the same time there's cia in all
row nasa people coming and visiting him and befriending him and going to his kids baseball
game or football games yeah i know and and literally it is almost exactly like the paul
benoist story i agree and and here's the problem anything that is of an extraterrestrial phenomenon
can be simulated by these covert humans and so all of it the orbs the craft all men are
phenomenon so people are grossly underestimating covert human capabilities which is why
we we go out and when we're doing ce5 contact with a high index of suspicion and skepticism
it's it's like is that et or is that stagecraft because i i know in great detail what those
capabilities are so when and and so someone who hasn't studied that and i have the advantage of
having to brief nearly a thousand of these whistleblowers right been in corporation so
but i think this is why i'm trying to share this with the public as succinctly as i can even
though it's a complicated what my marine buddies call a clusterfuck of of stuff
but it's something that really needs to be unpacked and understood so that people aren't
tricked right so the so any event that happens i always go well you have to have in your
differential diagnosis or in your comparison you know was it something from another dimension
that's not extraterrestrial extraterrestrial or a man-made or a little more complicated subset
man-made extradimensional where you know you could set up a stimulation by a man-made
electronic system that per let's say tickles some other dimension and brings something into
this dimension humans can do that human covert physicists that i've worked with have done that
so how do you explain this guy being able to bring these light balls around him and bring them
around and like i was sat on the beach with him and his daughter for like two hours i mean steve
saw this thing that was not a plane out of the came out of the horizon right went that way back
that way and then just fizzled out into nowhere right and he posted he posts these all over his
instagram all the time like that like i understand i don't know see i haven't been with him to be
able to discern yeah you know it's like the old commercials at real or is it memorax but
from their memory steps you know is it it is it endogenous et in other words original et
or is it originating from somebody piggybacking on him right or using that i don't know and so
i don't know the gentleman i'm just saying have you i like have you ever heard anything similar
to that sure we've had very in fact i was up on our land in virginia near hot springs virginia
i believe it was october and or november and we were up at about three thousand feet and
i was there we had a buddy we made a campfire and i was doing a little meditation and there were
exactly what you described about 15 or 20 of them that emerged and came over and below the crest
in about a 40 minute period or 30 40 minute period there were more than a dozen
and i'm okay i'm going oh my god they just kept coming but so yeah we have very similar phenomenon
happen yeah but i also know that you can stagecraft that if you're a a special operations
group with with technologies and this is not to try to discourage people from doing ce5 contact
i'm just saying there has to be a higher level of education and understanding we're actually
we're doing a cruise in the caribbean april 6th to the 12th where it's for there's 200 people
be up on this big deck out in the middle of the ocean for a number of nights we're going to
webinar if people want to tune in and we're going to do this whole ce5 contact oh yeah i've never
done it i've always wanted to do it in the middle of the ocean what island oh we're going all over
it's it's some big cruise liner that we're reserving legit cruise ship yes like 3100 people
but we have 200 and we're going to have the upper deck cordoned off we'll be doing this late at
night wow it'd be way fun i've never done it it's an experiment we'll see what happens so
i still have so many questions that are still on this topic um number one why do you think
so many spooks are so interested in him and trying to push this idea encourage him
i honestly don't know i mean i i'm not an expert in that case i don't know the man or his family
well just let's hypothetically let's let's let's say it's somebody else right somebody else who has
some crazy ability right why would those specific people be so interested in a person like that
well because it's the same reason why the psionic operation teams are interested in people who have
the innate capability okay and they want to see what they're doing how they're doing it
they may want to intercept what they're doing and confuse the picture by staging some hoaxed
events with real ones it's not like either or you have to think about how these guys would think
and what that motivation ultimately is i have no idea i just know there's some very bad actors
swirling around the gentleman i'm going to write the name down on this ipad i'm going to show it
to you because i don't want to say this guy's name on the podcast because it'll get this podcast
shadow band and i want to see if you know who he is steve blur it out or don't show it
i can't see it
no you don't know that name no okay no anyway i get shadow banned all the time yeah i know
although you know it's funny i was on a on a conference called a bunch of tech people say oh
that's a myth nobody gets shadow man i said oh it definitely happened it's ridiculous yeah
definitely happens and it happens to the ufo topic which is very odd yeah oh no it's not at all i
mean if you if you think about go back to that 1950 documents the biggest secret in the history
of the united states exceeding the secrecy of the development the hydrogen bomb so you know the idea
that the high end of the intelligence community trying to keep this secret wouldn't sanitize
information or and the other naivete about most people now is that those interests
are not only penetrating the tech companies in many cases they control those tech companies
that's right think of the corporate nexus it's crazy think about black rock think about well
all right google i don't go too far into google was literally funded and incubated by the cia the
nsa and darpa that's i know that and so is microsoft crazy yeah completely batshit nuts
when you think of when you go and you realize that sergue had cia nsa people visiting him like
monthly sure and the technology came straight from darpa like it's like it sounds like such a
crazy conspiracy no i read this no it makes total sense though yeah no it does it makes total sense
because if you can have keystroke by keystroke surveillance of everyone right um that's what
they wanted that's what they wanted with microsoft that's what they wanted with the big tech companies
and ironically the technology for doing that from all accounts much of it was reverse engineered
from et materials but they didn't let out the energy systems that would eliminate poverty and
human suffering and save the biosphere they let the things out that would enable them to have the
uber surveillance state we have today mostly through the private sector and you know if people
said the government were doing these things but instead you click on an i agree on all your tech
platforms and you're giving the corporate titans who are interfacing with the intelligence community
carte blanche everything it's like a cutout it is a cutout yeah yeah it's you know it's to anyone
who really analyzes this it's obvious um and and that's another question about you know our
freedoms and privacy and much of the constitutional protections right and i keep coming back to that
because whether it's here or anywhere else in the world if we don't have the rule of law then we're
in the jungle and on this issue that then has sort of infiltrated many other sectors of our society
we don't have freedom and the rule of law i always tell people they brag about us having a free
market economy i go really when the most important breakthroughs the last 100 years in science and
technology that would completely turn this planet into a paradise of with free energy
and all kinds of technologies have been ruthlessly suppressed up to and including
killing people right no we don't have a free market we have a managed economy
right um but so what what the public needs to understand is we need to evolve out of that
100 years of nonsense and to this whole transformative new golden age i mean the
new president's calling that well you're not going to do just a golden age based purely on
drilling more oil out of the ground you've got to create a golden age by letting our society advance
both uh technologically but also uh in our understanding of consciousness and spirituality
and that we're not alone in the universe and do it in a way that doesn't cause everyone to go
running for the door and jumping off bridges because we're being invaded by aliens i would
love to see trump do one of your ce5 uh oh that'd be great yeah maybe well i want to see you
meditate and kind of communicate with these yeah with these beings i think look you know i i'm
completely non-partisan because i have to be i've worked through many administrations and members
of congress luckily on this issue in the congress it's very non-partisan currently the people who
are interested which is interesting yeah and it should be that way because it's not just the
united states i'm dealing with countries all over the world and leaders all over the world on this
frankly i won't say which ones but it needs to be a global understanding that transcends
the usual idiotic fracture lines of murderous monkeys fighting over every little division we
can find right i think we have to go beyond that in our in our thinking and on something like this
it can't just be a partisan or even just an american issue it really needs to be a global
issue and that that's never happened there have been attempts you know the original disclosure
project of that was supposed to happen at the u.n general assembly in 2001 and the u.n secretary
general was threatened kofi Annan he was absolutely three says if you do this there'll be no more
funding for the united nations so we had to do at the national press club and his right hand guy
called me up says dr greer we cannot do it here at the u.n so whoa that was 24 years ago in may
so um we got off track again we were talking about ce5 and i wanted to i was asking you
when you're inviting these extraterrestrials into the space in in your meditation and you're
interfacing with them what is the what is the communication go it runs the gamut um almost
almost any weird thing you can imagine has happened um we've had fully materialized craft appear
and disappear we've had like that one et that appeared between two people uh and then vanish
we've had unusual electromagnetic signals come through our electronic sensor systems
so like we'll have uh magnetometers and other equipment out there and they will override the
circuitry and start communicating through them very strange and some of its very repeatable
sequences that we've recorded almost like um ericebo without the billion dollar telescopes
you know it's just a repeatable how like like a sequence a pattern that that repeats repeats
that you know would not naturally occur or would not happen from a man-made source um and and of
course many people have it will be deep in meditation and get a an override vision of a
craft or a person and say oh there's i'm sensing something in the northwest sky at 60 degrees
five minutes later craft appears there and moves and comes over so there's a lot of
precognitive capabilities that develop when you develop the consciousness any like direct
telepathic communication yes all the time yeah and what is the context of it it runs to gamut but
it's it's oh for many people who i know this is my experience is that they're making it quite clear
they're here for very good reason uh but there a lot of it is also laden with some warning
of where we are and that our civilization is at a point where it needs to either
you know change directions or it's going to face some really terrible outcomes and it's not a
threat it's it's just like this is where you are and it's sort of like the hopi prophecy where
you know one line terminates and the other one goes on forever if you know the hopi prophecy
right it's sort of like that that that is a theme that comes up a lot and i think we are at that
point where we're going to have to transition if we continue to think in the same paradigm of
division and war and conflict you know it sounds like we're using machine guns and tanks you know
we have not only thermonuclear but these other technologies that are covert it's not sustainable
to live like this uh and nor is it sustainable for the earth's biosphere to have eight billion
people living like we did in the 1800s burning stuff right so these there's a very frequently
a sort of earth-based environmental message that comes through about the dangers not only
geopolitically of endless war with these technologies but also what we're doing to the
oceans and the atmosphere and genetic mutations and cancer rates yeah then all of this is a
consequence of having suppressed for 100 years breakthroughs in technology that would have moved
us onto another path right so that's what we call the documentary the lost century
because there's a lost century of social and technological evolution but also with that
uh sort of spiritual evolution because what happens when a world no longer is in want and
fighting over scarce resources i think the work week will drop to 10 or 15 hours a week
people have extraordinary amount of time for creative pursuits and the pursuit of higher
states of consciousness and meditative and what have you hopefully not everyone's spending all
their time on youtube looking at kitty cats playing the piano but that might happen too but
i think there's two main drivers there's fear of death and i think there's um
sex i think those are the two main drivers of of our civilization the way we're going
right now there's this there's that there's a famous a great quote uh from this show west
world where he's saying um the human intellect is like peacock feathers the human psyche is
like peacock feathers it's an elaborate mating call everything from the mona lisa to the eiffel
tower to the brooklyn bridge the statue of david all it is is is an elaborate mating call some of
the best creations and pieces of artwork in human history and that's sort of what drives our
innovation and our our our part of our drive to make more money to get better things to drive
a nicer car to have a bigger house um and it seems like if we didn't have that if we were
genderless and we didn't have if we didn't fuck each other to reproduce then maybe that wouldn't
be maybe we would be on a different trajectory well i don't think it's either or either i mean
i think you can have a body and a planet that's physical and also pursue higher states of consciousness
and and spirituality i don't think the setazism is the way i don't i don't think you deny the one
but you add to that a higher conscious understanding and spirituality and there's an
i think that is the balance there's sort of like these inherent tensions and contradictions that
that exists in the modern era and has for many many times but one of the features you mentioned
earlier of the p3 or psionic operators it when you mentioned that some of these areas that we
would call primitive but they're living more in touch with nature have this innate ability it
harkens back to the aboriginals in australia that had what was called dream time and they would
literally have lucid dreams at night communicate with each other and have meetups with no telephones
or smoke signals or anything and so in many civilizations that we would dismiss as primitive
that was just net part of the natural order western civilization coming into
science and and through the scientific revolution and also rejecting the superstitions and excesses
of the middle ages and whatnot sort of threw the baby out with the bath water so i see a time where
we'll go forward as a high tech civilization but at the same time an increasingly conscious and
enlightened civilization both and i think that's the sort of balance where you become a very
advanced civilization because primacy is with your conscious evolution you know the world is as you
are as it says in the vedas the world we see as a reflection of what our level of consciousness
and thoughts are and so i think that can evolve there's no reason why we have to be stuck in the
current state of things now change is difficult most people don't like change or adventures i
love adventures and change but it's something that if we stay you know there's like the old chinese
saying unless we change directions we're likely to end up where we're going and i say look where are
we going you're going to hell in a hand basket right now not just geopolitically but in terms
of tensions and wars but also with the earth and the environment and and poverty do you know there
the economists last couple years ago had an article three billion people on earth don't even have
energy to cook their food so they're cutting out the brush and making deserts appear and cutting
down the rainforest three billion of the eight billion so there's no way to have a peaceful world
or a just world with the zero-sum game of the current energy system this becomes very clear
but as patrick david told me the other day if you bring these out there are so many powerful
interests you're talking about hundreds of trillions of dollars in aggregate impact so
and that was the mistake of a hundred years ago if these technologies had been brought out when
there were only two and a half billion people on the earth and very few of those people had
electricity and cars it would have been a natural evolution now we're either headed towards a very
bad situation globally geopolitically and environmentally geophysically or we have to
bring these out which will be admittedly very disruptive you know talk about a disruptive
technology so how do we do that what's going to have to be very smart and very managed
and so these are the complexities that to be honest with you world leaders and the president
and the national security council need to be discussing urgently and what i'm concerned
about is that it seems that in the next year or two this is all going to get disclosed and
when i meet with senior government officials which i do quite often they don't know anything
about the subject or what they do know has been some blended false information
that has led them gas lit them in the wrong path and this frightens me i mean because
knowledge is power and if you don't have it you're going to be manipulated into all the wrong
decisions and i think we need to have our leaders here and abroad brought up the speed on this in a
serious way which is i mean what i should be doing and i'm trying to do what i really ought
to do is retire but i'm tired and i'm getting old but go relax on those 600 acres oh we do
i take time for that i work out a lot and you know i was almost killed in an accident
about 15 months ago and oh shit oh yeah what happened i don't talk about it it was a mess
someone saw through the seat on my bicycle mountain bike and it snapped what and my left
leg came up my left foot came off the bones were in the air this shoulder was ripped off
my abdomen split open i had four surges oh yeah i even believe the things i've had happen to me
holy shit it was bad it was the worst i've had um and you know in the 90s had three people my team
killed a two by electronically induced cancers and the former ci director bill colby who was
going to help us bring these energy technologies out they just wet worked him in the river south
of dc made it look like an accident so you know this is serious stuff
they literally tried to stay tried to kill you on your bike oh i think it was more of a speed bump
slow me down it was three weeks after i got back from the black site and the chopper
where i filmed the underground opening yeah uh where some of the lockheed objects come up from
an underground facility and are tested and i handed that over to the senate intelligence you gotta
be so paranoid man no i'm not not at all no no if you've all these people that you've worked with
have been whacked no no no your paranoid implies that you'd be afraid of all this
but i think the saving grace even though i was raised an agnostic atheist of having had that
near-death experience when i was 17 not afraid of death i'm not afraid of that because now i don't
like being tortured i don't want to be injured i don't want to have a life of misery which is
what they've made my life a miserable thing um but you know no i mean being uh without this
uh you know physical body and being in the worlds of the conscious light that i've experienced no
that's a beautiful thing i don't have a death wish but i'm also not afraid i mean it's sort of
like the old shambhala warriors of old you know they were spirit warriors why haven't they i mean
i would imagine like all this stuff that you're doing and you've been doing this for so freaking
long yeah i can't believe they haven't tried to take you out yet well i mean other than the
bicycle incident oh i've had other i had metastatic malignant melanoma at the same month that a member
of congress in my right hand assistant got cancers i almost died that was in 96 seven something like
that but um yeah i think colby was killed 95 96 bill colby the ci director but how was he killed
well he allegedly was out canoeing on yeah i've read the story but his his son thought he
committed suicide but he was working with a colonel and with a member of my team to hand over
one of these zero point quantum generators with about uh 50 million dollars in seed money so we
could get it out open source it and get it out to the public and um the week he was going to meet
with a member of my board they found him floating down the potomac but it's an unsolved
murder but we know what happened his best friend came to my friend's funeral sherry's funeral and
said we both have had terrible losses but can't look back um going back to the angels and demons
stuff have you heard of the virginia brazil uh incident yes i have that thing smelled like
sulfur and in the bible it talks about demons smelling like sulfur well here's the other
problem i don't i'm not an expert on that case the question is was it et was it human induced
was it or was it from another dimension um and have you ever seen anything like that you you
know all about the alien species right you you know all about the catalogue the guy said there's
69 different oh yeah there's and our our team has had experiences with a huge variety and you've
never seen anything like that one with the red eyes the virginia one no no and one of the questions
i always have is given what i know about what human electromagnetic field experimentation is done
there's a physicist i'm working with uh he's down near the redstone arsenal huntsville yeah space
flight center marshal space flight center he has his own skiff i've been in um and his lower level
his house is also a skiff a secure compartment information facility and uh i mean these guys
have created like toroidal electromagnetic systems where they will tap into the ninth ring of hell or
whatever and some creature will be 3d running around the lab what and it sounds absolutely
batshit crazy and it is but it's true so what i whatever you can imagine you know ben rich
the week he died was talking to a friend of mine jim goodall who's a well-known aerospace historian
and said and he and jim was pushing on this issue about while lockheed skunk works had he says he
said well anything you can imagine that you've seen on star trek we've already done at the lockheed
skunk works and it's not at area 51 it's out in the desert underground and that is true and i've
been over that facility i mean not longer right before i was critically injured but um so there
are people who have surfaced describing some of those what does that mean uh it means that
the capabilities of these covert human group could stage anything and this is why people say
we are the biggest skeptic i ever heard you don't believe that i said well you know i'm not saying
there aren't genuine uh extraterrestrial non-human intelligence but there's all this other stuff
and all this other stuff gets really complicated and it makes sense once you unpack 70 or 80 years
of super advanced uh engineering and science and technology from studying this area of physics
um and one of the big mistakes everyone makes is they don't give enough credit to the genius
of the people who worked on those programs like this gentleman i just referred to he's in he's
redacted in in the what we're making available to the public but he's not redacted for some other
folks highest iq one of the highest iqs of anyone i've ever met on earth and what i have found is
that people have very high capabilities they're tapped either right out of college or in high
school even and brought in because they have such amazing aptitude and there is a process for
screening for that and it's a real process and uh and they're looking for people with
extraordinary talents and iqs and abilities so i always tell people the smartest people i've
ever met are not at harvard mit caltech or whatever they're in covert uh operations and
corporate and some government and those guys are are amazingly brilliant and they're highly
incentivized to study this and figure out different applications and i think people
grossly underestimate that and because they underestimate it they're constantly being
deceived and tricked by human phenomenon human events and and weird stuff and thinking it's
something that isn't uh and that's what happened with the skinwalker ranch there was an innate
phenomenon there i don't think it was extraterrestrial i think it was extra-dimensional
and a bunch of guys operating with robert bigelow and and the intelligence community
set up some electronics that ran the rancher off so they forcibly bought it virtually and then they
set up all these weird electromagnetic phenomenon there and i know how they did it and i have
someone who was embedded in that team has described it same thing with the bradshaw ranch near sedona
you know recently there was someone who works with elizandro on a podcast talking about yeah
that's an alien but i've had my people scouted out there guys all dressed in black down below a hill
and it's a complete black site i don't know if it's cia or corporate but you know so this happens
all the time if you have an area that has an innate someone say a portal but an innate phenomenon
going on those will get taken over and turned into a black site that's human and then the public gets
gaslit and deceived about all the phenomenon there so uh so they'll it's a trick it's more trickery
you're saying that they will deliberately use their tricks to make it seem like there's some
crazy fuckery going on there and it's some sort of interdimensional portals with witches and all
this stuff and then that will force the ranchers to get rid of to flee and they can buy it terrifying
and they can keep doing that stuff they ran off the people in the bradshaw ranch same thing with
skimwalker now there's a new owner i don't know him but i knew the people who got it after the
rancher was terrified and run off and they can do things through normal electric wires you know
power lines that they can put a signal down and all of a sudden some creepy thing happens and
apparition appear and disappear so you know this is the high end of uh what we call the stagecraft
or tradecraft stagecraft yeah staging things and one of the problems with ufology and with
this whole subject is that you really can't begin to uh even make a judgment call on what
you're looking at right unless you unpack what the human capabilities are and then you can begin to
put it into the categories and and get some discernment and but it's a very difficult
thing to do and you know in 1991 i was at a conference and a cia guy old guy he looked
like the cigarette man in the what's that show x-files because they've got some of those episodes
they took from my early work and we were walking along and he said let's walk along the beach
and he said look the truth is so much stranger than any fiction we can sell the fiction and
people will believe it but if you tell people the truth they won't believe it and it's less
believable than the fiction and it is so that's been a real conundrum fiction has to make sense
truth doesn't yeah exactly and the truth on this is such a tangled web and it's been done
deliberately because it has the ability to then confuse the picture but also create the specter
of fear where the long-term goals can be fulfilled my concern is that disclosure i wrote a paper in
1999 called this on our website when disclosure serves secrecy meaning the secret government
operations and if this issue gets disclosed the way it currently is on track to be it'll be a war
of the world's panic in the aisle it'll be a thousand times worse than covet the way it's
on track to be disclosed yes where you have the people who have or keep going up to congress and
the white house and other places and conflating man-made frightening things like abductions and
villages being blown up with extraterrestrial threat or nhi threat and they're deliberately
co-mingling no one is making this discernment between a bunch of psyops and covert technologies
masquerading as et there's no one is doing that in fact the dominant paradigm
is to call all of it one thing and in that calling it one thing it makes people conclude
there is a threat and we need to fight it so let's go to defcon one let's go to independence day the
movie let's go to war of the world so i think this manipulation is 99 percent of what people hear
and i don't really honestly right now if you were to put me under a sodium pen a truth serum
i don't so do you oh good go for it steve lock the doors all right i really don't see
that right now as things stand as of this moment that there is a critical mass of people
who are able to come forward and not be captured let's call it by that narrative
you know trapped by that narrative now it's even gets more spooky when you start dealing with senior
people in government who have not been read into this who who are brand new to this and we'll go
in with information and then right after us will be a disinformation team that goes in yeah like
like clockwork so and i'm a private civilian and those people going with credentials from
the pentagon right or some intelligence agency so you know it's a it's daunting but
i'm not no i don't think we should give up on getting the truth out and exposing the lies and
the cover-up but also the trickery but i don't see right now there's a lot of
bandwidth let's just say so um you were alluding to earlier when you were mentioning elizondo he
is behind this whole threat narrative it's mixed i mean he's actually evolving a little bit off
of that because he needs to and and that's been exposed but i think one of the the reason you
initially emerged was to be sure that two or three major false narratives came out one was
we don't have anything that's man-made that could be this when 80% of what people are saying are
man-made covert okay okay that was one message the other was that it's a threat to the national
security which it is but not from out there in space it's the threat is within i mean right but
he was the rogue secret government organization is the threat it's treasonous it's traitorous
it's murderous it's unconstitutional it's criminal so that narrative uh it is to say
what i just described when disclosure serves secrecy yes this is real it's all coming out the
ufos are real which everybody's known forever um but they're a threat and we don't have anything
that can fly like that now luckily in the last two or three years does elizando say that that
we don't have anything like this yes he did initially not anymore not anymore and neither
neither is grush and neither is fravor and others but that was something that i was forcefully
in the public saying that is a falsehood and i would go to senators and congressmen say
no that is wrong and that is a lie and a damnable lie because if you believe that
then a priori you have to think that all the horrible things that have happened have also
been at the hands of the ets when they've been at the hands of a cia special operations team
right or so special operators right so i think that that was the thing that concerned me the most
now i'm hoping you know i mean i look i don't have any grievance against any individual honestly
i mean mostly i don't know them i'm more concerned about the human future and human
consciousness being polluted with a false narrative that leads us into this dystopian future of
endless war and expanded war into space and all this stuff because that's how you get the
armageddon that's how you get to a catastrophic conclusion so that's my big concern and i think
this is why i don't care who you are um i'm going to speak the truth about it there's an
old saying i speak the truth whether it gives you counsel or offense um so that's the er doc in me
you know if you've got a brain tumor i'm not going to tell you have a migraine right so that's just
me but you know and it makes me very controversial and very unlikable which i don't care i'm not
running for mayor of crazy town ufology either so i couldn't care about that sure i care about
what the truth is but also how the truth is articulated that doesn't result in some just
furtherance of the agenda of the secret group because what would be i mean this is their dream
is to let this come out and pivot the whole world onto a path of needing big brother to run endless
war in offensive and defensive operations against nhi right that that's been the plan and and i you
know right now i will say that the weight of the thrust of how this is being brought forward if
you'll get media reports social media that is the thrust of what's happening we're trying to bend the
curve towards something truthful but also a positive outcome for humanity and for the
united states because the united states is to crown jewel in these covert secret programs and
many of our big corporations are tied into these in a compartmented special projects divisions and
a lot of them so i think we we have to figure out how to do this but you know this needs to come out
where it's and i basically in here there's a you're gonna laugh it's a draft speech for the
president or other world leaders to give that i've written why would i laugh about that no
because people go really it's kind of i said but it has to be this coming out you cannot speak about
this with well let's just blow them out of the sky you know right that kind of thing so you know
this is dangerous the kind of talk that attends the disclosure discussions
leads to a catastrophic outcome for the earth and humanity and there's one other risk it's a
little bit more ominous and that is there are three different people i'm working with they don't know
each other that have been in comm centers communication centers where somehow they have
intercepted communications from nhi direction terrestrials yeah that they're getting quite
fed up with the fact that we're taking their technologies and using it against them and that
that has reached the point where we are a threat not just to ourselves but out there so people
are grossly underestimating how those covert programs are threatening earth because not that
these civilizations are hostile but they certainly are not going to let a rogue group of psychopaths
threaten other worlds so if we don't get this under control it'll have to be brought under control
but the worst case scenario is why don't the aliens just fix this i said that would be the
worst case scenario because if that happens it'll be portrayed as an alien invasion wouldn't those
wouldn't the aliens just too smart for that yeah the aliens are smart they're way smarter than us
they have to be iq's 400 north of 400 so why wouldn't they just quietly go after those people
and just shut them down there would be no way to do that without it also being portrayed by their
lackeys in government in the media as an alien invasion so i'm saying quietly do it so no one
no way to quietly do this my friend i mean do you if you start looking at the map in here
and the list of corporations sites facilities the trillions of dollars involved with this
that ain't gonna happen where it wouldn't be noticed now humans can get our here's what i
think is the one of the messages is that we need to fix our own mess here and there's no reason we
can't i think it's sort of a weird cosmic codependency to think that someone from out
there and he's going to land here and fix our problems i mean how well did that work in
afghanistan right oh we're going to go in and nation build and they're right back to warlords
and nonsense it's got to come from the people right now i don't necessarily say the leaders the
people they know that the people will lead the leaders will have to follow but we become very
passive people and i think we have to not be so passive i think the people need to
speak up stand up articulate and hopefully exhort our leaders to do the right thing
you know i grew up in the i was born 1955 so i remember i grew up in the south report
and you know my my my grandmother's Cherokee my father was half native and they were called half
breeds and uh i have a twin sister looks very native and but you know the at that time there
was jim crow in the south there was still segregated water fountains all that and uh and i
remember how weird that was i mean i was four five six and i'd go to a water fountain where
there was no line and a little old lady would grab me and say don't drink out of that one
that's for i think they said colored people or something like that yeah and i went because i
was in it my parents were not all racist i went well is the water different is it it was like
this magical system this racist system and i saw that evolve and i had an african american
girlfriend in high school i almost got run over by a bunch of racists who did not like that and
you know but that all changed not because the president and congress changed it it happened
because of baird rustin and martin luther king and there was a movement that made that happen
right so i think people forget that big changes in society rarely come from the top down it comes
from the people up sure and this is uh not that lesson is lost in most people today because
most people just sit around looking at their phones and don't do anything but uh i remember
that era and i remember how different i mean things aren't perfect now with race relations
but boy it's a big difference from the 50s and 60s when i was a kid and imagine having an african
american girlfriend in north carolina in 72 or three you know so i think that you know progress
can happen but it's a lot of hard work and a lot of sacrifice and people have to stand up and be
heard and uh that's part of what the whole disclosure movement has been about that that i
when i started people don't realize that we started the whole disclosure movement in the 90s
it's now the even the word disclosure is used by the new york times but that was
we started that in in the mid the late 90s yeah right now obviously i think you've said it before
but you believe that people organizations whether i don't know if it's if you're talking about the
government or if you're talking about these rogue groups have possession or captive alien bodies
you know they have living ones as well they have living ones and who and who is this that is this
is this the government or is this this rogue rogue organization that's the rogue government
it's the secret government and those are in places that need to be let's call liberated and
do you know where they are not precisely i have a very good idea so one of the things we have mapped
are the underground entry points and then we're in the connectivity say you have the edwards
complex and then you have east of there what's called the ant hill and those are entry points
into underground subterranean facilities or bases but they connect underground to nellis
and out to the northern net so it's an underground that's what they call it an ant hill if you go to
an ant there's tunnels you go in and there are all these connections right so we we have a very good
idea of where those are and some of the whistleblowers we're working with know even more and that needs to
be provided to people in the u.s government so that they can get control of those and
there are some very brave men i'm working with who have been special forces guys
who are prepared to go in and get those facilities under control and also to liberate those people
that's crazy too if these things are so smart and so advanced how are they going to let
one of their own be captive by by us well you know that's a lot of people say that but
just because you're advanced doesn't mean terrible things don't happen i mean you know it technically
you could throw a bunch of spears by cavemen into the rotors of a sikorsky helicopter and
jam it up and have it crash so you know bad things happen you know of course being a trauma guy i
mean i you just see the weirdest things happen so just because they're very advanced people
conflate that with being infallible right well i think god's infallible but certainly no
individual person or civilization is infallible so this concept it just because they're extremely
high tech and bright mean they're infallible no uh now is it that often that it happens
no it doesn't the one site i was over um i was told there are one or two et craft per year downed
and i went over two black sites and so you know two to four a year over a big area of that part
of the desert um so it's not like they're dropping out the sky like flies is what i'm saying uh it's
still terrible uh but then remember we have sites like that all over the world out back up australia
south america all around and it's still tragic and it shouldn't be happening and when there are
ones that are living they just don't flat out kill them they would prefer to interrogate them
and keep them and so they're my understanding is that there are a number of et's that are in
captivity and are still living one guy euphemistically called them refugees i think not
they're prisoners but uh you know so i think that is another you know humanitarian effort that should
happen at some point where they're uh they're freed and how many different versions or species
of these things do you think we have and have you ever seen any of them in person i'm not seen living
ones in captivity on those bases no i've seen et's and but um they're not to my knowledge i've
never heard anyone describe the variety of them i know that in the crash retrievals now we have
122 documented crash retrieval events that are in part of them are in here but in our archive dpi
archive.com all of them are in there um and they range from ones that are a foot foot and a half
tall to some that are eight ten feet tall and all kinds of different we just say you know genetic
expressions but they seem to all have a head two arms and two legs but interesting but beyond that
there's just an infinite variety uh what about the mantis ones well that one that was the healer
when you see him and they is sort of a triangular head and they're known as really extraordinary
healers i mean they have some amazing healing capabilities that one right there this guy that's
a mantis yeah what some people would call a sort of triangular head uh you can see in a sort of uh
you can outline it if i had my cursor i could do it but um remember this is in complete darkness
in the wilderness up on a mountain in arizona this was actually in uh oracle ironic o-r-a-c like
oh really or oracle arizona interesting yeah a couple years ago and um so that's uh you know
and we love doing that that's my real passion is going out in the experimentation and uh using
consciousness and remote viewing to make contact and see what happens and a lot of it varies on the
group because if there's someone not on the page or someone there who's filled with superstition
and fear they won't show up uh because they don't want to be around dumb people who haven't figured
now what sorry but um you know if you haven't figured that out they're going why are you out
there with us you know go home yeah and go look at uh stranger things or something
what how far have you gotten in your investigation into those beings that you talked about and studied
in your serious documentary the small beings and i think you talked about gary nolan worked with
you on that yeah gary nolan received a lot of money right after we gave him that genetic sample
and he altered the results of it so we don't know what that creature is he he received a lot of money
yeah i think it was 3.4 million from the pentagon and uh and then so he is now contracting with the
intelligence community to show uap injuries which is just a psyop it's a yes of course i mean the
uap injuries are all man-made but of course you get someone like him man-made it's the man-made
reverse engineered of course and of course but you you put this uh the stink on the ets when
it's something we've done right so uh unfortunately you know i think that went sideways very badly so
to this day we don't know what that thing was now he published a report saying it was a deformed
fetus even though the top uh geneticist or a doctor who deals with bone malformations said
no way because it was global it had growth plates uh consistent equivalent of a six-year-old human
but it was only about six inches tall and so we don't know what it was it could have been something
that is a completely unknown species on earth it could have been something that's a result of
both earth and non-human interactions that are ancient in that part of the Atacama desert and
Shelly yeah there are accounts of these ufos being seen and these small creatures the adult
ones are like a foot and a half tall but to this day we actually don't know what it is i mean i
never said it was et i said we don't know what it is but it's most certainly not human so what was
published by gary nolan and those guys and i've had the top geneticists in the world tear apart
their data so it's totally hoaxed it's totally academic fraud really yes but this happened you
know this and this is why you asked about being paranoid i'm careful but i'm not paranoid because
i've had so many people who could go on the path of finding the truth and they either get blackmailed
and or both bribed given a lot of money and the next thing you know there everything goes
sideways and so you know i've seen that dozens hundreds of times in 35 years the way you know
you know it makes you a little bit cynical i guess they are skeptical so but no no he i mean he
completely started out as an honest person i know that and and when we first met in 2012 i think
but at this point man that's got to be cleaned up it's a mess what about those mummies that were
the or in peru the the mummies that were shown to mexican congress by by jamie a heime muson
those those were actually from peru and from a cave and we know i know the researchers the
scientists who looked into that i've never been down there but um it was handled like you would
handle there's a lot of buffoonery that goes on with the ufo subculture it was handled in a poor
way but i actually think the the actual mummies are legitimate a very old thousands of years old
uh non-human species now how they got there where they're originally from but these are not
hoaxes i've seen the cross sections i've seen the cat scans but unfortunately i was going to go down
there with the team this past spring last year and try to do a scientific expedition but there was
too much interference from other people and i i pulled out of that but there needs to be a whole
series you have to do ancient dna right which you mean is different from dna you pull on a live
person and it's a whole different technique you need to have really good forensic dissections
partial dissections and you need to have every one of them cat scanned and then the metal objects
on them have to go through a very sophisticated and expensive analysis to see if the atomic
uh let's just say whether it was of earth origin metal or from out there and you can do that but
this is a very um complex and expensive and time-consuming endeavor that would run into
the hundreds of thousands to a couple million bucks to do right properly now there's never
that kind of the only funding like that in the ufo subculture is to fund things that are
disinformation operations um fact so that has not happened yet i maybe it will at some point
but my assessment of i actually visited a man in utah who had acquired several of these but they
were still in peru and he gave me a lot of information that i when i saw it and he was
scientist and i went yeah these are real now their origins i don't know you know and uh no
one's to my knowledge done a proper dna someone attempted to i think it was a russian archaeologist
but it was not done properly i don't have faith in it because it's very different when you take
dna from either someone recently deceased or living sure how you run that is very different
than what's called ancient dna an ancient could be even 30 years old because it anyway it breaks
down in a way that to get a correct genetic code read on it is a completely esoteric and you in
specialized area of genetic sequencing it isn't like regular genetic sequencing so you know i
would know how to direct that scientific project i haven't had time and then when we were going
to go down there was all kinds of nonsense and theatrics and trickery and i said i'm out of here
until this gets cleaned up yeah so what's on the horizon for you as far as like your whistleblowers
and what like what do you think is going to happen and in what time frame as far as getting these
people like jake in front of congress and getting this stuff actually not going into a skiff and then
disappearing and actually seeing something happen something tangible take place and and guide this
whole thing in the right direction well you make a good point the worst one of my concerns is
this comes out and gets spun as a threat like i was talking about or it simply goes back into
the black pit of calcutta you know in other words it just gets put back into a black project it
begins to surface it gets slammed back down again both could happen hopefully it neither do but so
what i'm continuing to do i'm going from from here back up to well i'm actually given a lecture
here in st petersburg oh really and then i'm going to be going back to dc for some meetings
with congress folks and then i'll be back down here to meet with anyway a general oh really who
is yes and who had been at one point the national security advisor for a president so you know we're
trying to still work the system and get the the more important trajectory i think is going to be
empowered people through an executive order to take all these whistleblowers we have
protect them and then get their information and then get those old legacy corrupt programs
under control and that's the real plan you know and whether we can make it happen we're going to
give it the all-out effort this year and and i think it can i actually i think there are people
in the new administration very open to this i don't think they have much information i mean i've met
with some of the incoming prospective cabinet members already and but what what's i don't think
there's yet a consensus on the path to take and unfortunately a lot of them have been targeted
with false information so it's complicated just like members of congress have had that happen
the best i can do is give the information the evidence and the advice and
and then see how they carry the ball in the meanwhile i actually think that they need to
be hearing from the public you know the public can get this and say oh these recommendations these
executive orders and what kind do it you know just write a letter you know to your members and a lot
of people don't do that they may as very old-fashioned but i mentioned this earlier
i've heard from so many people in washington who are elected representatives and they go
we really want to hear from our constituents on this but most people they just this is
entertainment for people right it's just yeah that's the other thing about it that we haven't
talked about we've been talking about the the psyop within a psyop angle of this whole thing
the whole time and the counterintelligence disinformation and strategic deception but like
you have to layer on top of that this whole this whole subject is a business for people too
yep people that build their careers off talking about this stuff and doing all kinds of crazy
shit i lost my career over it but yeah i've given up 15 or 20 million dollars i mean careers i mean
careers based on the topic itself oh of course and the scarier and more false it is the more
money there is yeah because they're going to open every door to a book publisher or a big movie deal
if the information is bs right but it's scary so that's the other thing i discovered is that
you know we'll put something like this out of print on demand
but harper collins will give someone a million dollar contract to put out a book this full of
nonsense and sure disinformation designed to scare the hell out of people gee i wonder how
that happens yeah so i you know this is something i just accept is the way things are right now it
might change who knows well and we've started our own podcast by the way oh yeah i was gonna say
i was gonna say tell people uh where they can learn more about what you're doing and
yeah you know your your uh your website and all that stuff yeah so uh you'll be able to get this
now on you know our site the briefing document material we have a podcast uh that we've started
we've only done i think four or five episodes they're not fancy like this they're very homemade
but that's that's our bandwidth the homemade ones are the best yeah it's quite primitive
but it it's to get the information out and as all this begins to break i want to be able to
on a weekly basis comment on it um and then uh if you want to sort of be part of the ce5
there's the app ce5 contact you can get on any of your app stores and if you want to join us for
that cruise out in the caribbean virtually uh now a caveat there there will be places for starlink
and our connectivity out in the middle of the caribbean won't be live we'll have to record it
and put it up but it'll still be a fun experience you'll really learn a lot because you'll be part
of the daytime uh conference and then also the nighttime uh four of the nights we'll be out on
the upper deck out on those stars in the middle of the ocean and we'll see what happens you know
it'll be fun okay uh steve we have patreon questions our beautiful patreon our beautiful
patreon community uh had some questions for you uh well we can rip through those real quick and
then we can wrap it up so this is the end of the podcast for everyone good night folks
thank you very much sleep tight thank you