If you were asked to appear before Congress under oath, would you willingly do that?
The only way I'll testify actually, the reality is in a classified setting.
DOD can come after me.
What happened to Dave Grush?
Physically harassed at his home and in his vehicles after he filed his whistleblower complaint.
It was before he ever testified.
All I have was the stuff that I accumulated and gathered going up through the OSAP and ATIP.
And that's how I met Dave Grush.
Jay Stratton introduced me to Dave.
He was the NRO liaison officer to the UAPTF.
So anyway, I met both of them and I gave Dave all my data, all my briefing information,
and he took that, ran with it, and he found everything.
George Bush, when he was the CIA director, he was given some pretty spectacular information
about a major UAP event that took place in the early 60s.
And Bush's eyes lit up and this is what he told me.
He said, what are you talking about?
The Pentagon liaison officer told him all about it.
He said, are you kidding me?
There's a there there?
Yeah. And he said, absolutely.
And he said, well, I want to see the evidence.
And the evidence was in the form of documentation, but the film was the primary thing.
We are thrilled to announce this special episode of American Alchemy featuring a groundbreaking
interview with the legendary Eric Davis.
Eric is a renowned scientist, Hal Putoff's protege, and probably more of an expert in
UFO propulsion and exotic physics principles than just about anybody on earth.
He's written a fantastic book called The Frontiers of Propulsion Science, which is as
comprehensive of an overview as you could possibly get when it comes to exotic propulsion
and anomalies in topological physics.
He's also written all sorts of great research papers on subjects ranging from UAP tracking
to quantum teleportation.
This conversation wouldn't have been possible without my technical correspondent, pseudonymously
named Jack or Missileman on Twitter.
Jack has over 15 years of experience in defense in aerospace and holds a very strong background
in mathematics, materials, R&D and physics.
For now, he's chosen to remain pseudonymous due to his work in sensitive areas of national security.
Jack and I are going to be starting a technical series together on UFO physics.
It's going to be an extremely deep dive on how UFOs fly, the exotic principles they employ,
and materials they use.
But this interview also involves some incredible journalists in the world of UFOs.
This interview would not have been possible without them.
First off, thank you to Thenvir, the incredible host of Catastrophic Disclosure.
I also want to thank his partner on the channel, Katarina, who is a biomedical PhD.
She's brilliant and she's the editor and videographer on the channel.
We're also super grateful to James Falk, host of Neon Galactic, a PBS-affiliated podcast
and YouTube channel, which goes into UAP's consciousness.
It's incredibly deep and worth checking out.
Rob Jones was also involved here.
He's a nuclear engineer and Navy sailor.
Go follow him on Twitter for some incredible insights.
Finally, I want to give a special shout out and thank you to UAP Gerb.
He is honestly the deepest researcher I've met in the last year when it comes to UAPs.
He runs an incredible channel called UAP Gerb.
He's deeper than just about anybody I know on nuts and bolts UFO research.
We're going to drop an interview very soon and hopefully all of you get to see how ridiculously
impressive his knowledge is.
So if you're going to watch this interview, please subscribe to all of these channels.
They're going to come out with variations of this interview with commentary and other
remixes and maybe even some footage that we don't include here on their own respective
channels.
They're doing incredibly important work.
Consider subscriptions on those channels, the passcode for watching this interview.
We need more people covering this topic.
The point is there's strength in numbers.
We're all on the same team and we need as many high credibility, high quality people
covering this as possible.
Without further ado, please enjoy this special episode of American Alchemy with our amazing
technical correspondent, Jack and the prince of exotic propulsion himself, Eric W. Davis.
So the little aerospace guys, the autotap guys, the ATIP guys, y'all have been at the
forefront of really starting the public discourse on all of this stuff.
And Dr. Jim Lukaski, he mentioned if he were asked to testify before Congress, he would
actually lie before Congress instead of, you know, speaking against his NDAs and to honor
his NDAs and the things he's, you know, wants to protect.
And so I know that's a bit controversial because at this point, New Elizondo has testified.
We interviewed him last week.
And they did so under oath.
So Jim didn't say what happens if he takes an oath, because if he takes an oath lying
to Congress in a testimony as perjury, then he can go to jail for that.
And you saw what happened to the NDA.
Hopefully the NDA will prevent him from giving testimony, but however, if they issue him
a subpoena to appear before Congress, then he's going to have to work with the DOD staff
to figure out how to how he's going to do it.
Now here's how Dave Gresh did it.
Dave Gresh was able to give was approved by the Department of Defense.
I don't remember what the acronym means anymore as TOPSR.
So TOPSR approved his public testimony and approved what he could say publicly.
The rest of what he couldn't say publicly, he said in a classified hearing.
So we had a classified hearing on his whistleblower complaint.
Jim would have to do the same thing, and Jim should know that.
And I worked with him on the OSAP, so I know him.
So he, I don't know why he was said have to lie before Congress.
He knows if you're going to take an oath before the committee lying as perjury and you're
in trouble.
The NDA issue can be worked out with the TOPSR.
However, there are times when they don't administer an oath, but you don't want to lie because
that'll be a public reputation damage on you.
Right.
If even though you didn't take an oath, but you lied before Congress, you told you lied.
I know for you, it's kind of a weird state right now because your alleged memo has been
entered into Congressional record.
And so my question is simply this, if you were asked to appear before Congress under
oath, would you willingly do that?
Would you testify?
I would have to get advice from a lawyer first.
Very smart answer.
I'd have to get an advice from a lawyer who has a background in that particular issue
because DOD can come after me and the IC could come after me.
They could permit me from getting a job again by making sure that I don't get my security
clearances passed.
And what happened to Dave Grush after he filed his whistleblower complaint?
It was before he ever testified.
What happened to Dave Grush is he got harassed and intimidated, both him and his wife.
He got harassed by someone in the National Reconnaissance Office, and then he got physically
harassed at his home and in his vehicles by people unknown.
And then somebody leaked a PTSD episode he had because remember, he's a war veteran and
he was in the combat field and he suffered PTSD and was going through a crisis with his
wife.
Somebody decides they're going to illegally go into his private medical files, violate
the HIPAA law, and release that to the news media so that they can attack his character.
And there are a lot more lawyers at this point on your side, on the UAP Disclosure Fund,
and a number of other organizations have spun up to offer pro bono legal support to whistleblowers
and people being harassed.
Do you feel any better than, do you feel like it's safer now than it was when Dave came
out?
Possibly.
I just have to have a lawyer tell me, look at the situation, look at the circumstances
under which Admiral Wilson gave me information and then find out if that's something I should
do at the level of Congressional hearing.
Congressional hearing.
That's ironic.
Hang on.
I briefed the Senate Select Committee of Intelligence staff and the Senate Armed Services Committee
staff in classified settings.
What happened is I briefed the first group in 2019, then later now we're in 2022, and
another group comes out to Huntsville.
Instead of me going to DC, they're coming out to see me in Huntsville, and I'm briefing
them.
So it's a new group of people.
And after one phone call with Representative Mike Gallagher, Republican representative
of his district in Wyoming, so I had a short phone call with him, maybe about 20, 25 minutes.
And then I had an interview just last month with the two senior staff on the subcommittee
that just recently held the House hearings that Lou Elizondo appeared at.
So they asked me a lot of questions.
They were short on time, so we had a half hour conversation and there really should
have been a follow-up interview because there were more open questions left to be answered
that they didn't have time.
They never followed up and I never got an invite to testify.
I have made it known that the only way I'll testify actually, the reality is in a classified
setting.
I would imagine there's not much slam dunk testimony that can be given in the unclassified
thing.
Right.
Well, I'll tell you this, Dave did give the classified testimony.
He gave them everything.
He gave them the names and locations and programs and people.
All I have was the stuff that I accumulated and gathered going up through the OSAP and
ATIP.
And what happened during the UAPETF was what Jay Stratton was doing then.
So I had left that area and then I had a little bit of stuff going on when I worked for the
Aerospace Corporation and that's how I met Dave Brush.
Jay Stratton introduced me to Dave and his government customer, who I won't name.
He was a GS-15 at the time and Dave worked for him and he got promoted later to SCS-1.
This anonymous individual.
This is the one that Dave worked with at the NRO.
And so I briefed them.
So they basically invited me through the Aerospace Corporation apparatus because Aerospace is
the FFRC that supports NRO.
And so they have a contract and they flew me out to where they were located in Colorado
Springs and I gave them both briefings.
Not just them.
This included the aerospace personnel that were supporting the office.
The NRO was a tenant organization in the aerospace campus there.
So we have one building now, it's two, and in that one building they have skiffs building
entire floors and then office suites that are built inside of skiffs that close the
office suites.
So this program that Dave and his government customer worked at was one of those office
suites in a skip.
So that GS-15 has a number of aerospace employees supporting his program.
And Dave was doing some aspect of that on the security side as one of Jay Stratton's
contributors to the UAPTF because he was the NRO liaison officer to the UAPTF.
So anyway, I met both of them and I gave Dave all my data, all my briefing information
and he took that, ran with it and he found everything.
And then later on, I think maybe a year or two later, yeah, actually almost two years
later, somewhere in that period, they finally got to meet with Hal Puthoff and he briefed
them with his set of information, a lot of what he has overlaps mine, but I have a lot
of unique information both in and outside of the era of the 15 years that I worked with
Hal.
And Hal knew some of that, a lot of it came from AFRL and then a lot of it came through
the OSAP with my interactions with the CIA and other agencies and companies and so forth.
So Dave, yeah, Dave basically ran with our data, mine and Hal's, and found everything.
Found 40 witnesses, I'm not going to say who they are, but I could say that I know two
of them.
Can you say how many of them are in this building?
I'll say I know that at least one, that only one of them is in the building and the guy
who didn't come to the conference because he had a travel conflict for a prearranged,
I think family trip or something, if he were here, he'd be the second one and all the rest
of them are not here in the building.
And there's more to it than that, but I can't discuss it because then that would identify
who the two witnesses are.
So yesterday you made some pretty remarkable statements on kind of finding evidence of
legacy programs while working at OSAP.
And you mentioned that under Eisenhower, P-E-A-D-S's Presidential Emergency Action
Documents were kind of used to create WAVE special access programs free from congressional
oversight.
I wanted to see during your time investigating legacy programs, did you encounter other kind
of unique classification standards like no foreign, no foreign national excluded program
material for these programs kind of dealing with NHI artifacts?
Yeah, those are not new or unusual.
There's known SCI compartments, SCI being Sensitive Compartmentalized Information, but
there's hidden SCI compartments and that's what a lot of the American public is not aware
of.
That's not talked about a lot.
And then there's the special access programs and you've got four types, you've got regular
SAPs, just special access program, then you have a WAVE special access program, you'll
have an unacknowledged one and then you'll have a WAVE unacknowledged one.
And actually, I'm not sure that the two in the middle are separate really, I think more
likely it's WAVED and unacknowledged at the same time.
So that might be just a third category or even just a second category.
So Dave and I had a lot of discussions.
I went through, when I was at aerospace, I went through special access program security
training so I could qualify to be, it's not that I wanted to qualify to be a security
officer, I just wanted to qualify to indicate to the company and the government customers
that I've gone through that level of training comparable to what security officers for special
access programs have.
And so that would help my eligibility to get access more than anything.
And that didn't happen.
I didn't get it.
But I did get, I did do the training.
So Dave and I talked about that as a consequence.
And I said, Dave, it seems like these hidden SCIs are no different than SAPs.
And so that's when he said, yeah, really, they've been having that argument among the
personnel security experts throughout the IC and the DOD.
They've been having an argument for some significant period of time over really whether
there is a real distinction between a hidden SCI and an SAP.
Most of the people like Dave and I actually came to the conclusion that SAPs are just
the same thing as a hidden SCI.
I think something a lot of people don't ask that has kind of captured my attention.
During your time investigating legacy programs, did you see much collaboration or
compartmentalization between programs that may exist in Navy, Air Force, Army?
It's too stove-piped or compartmentalized.
You can't open it up to another one unless there is a need to do that.
That need to get access is defined on a government form called the DD-254.
And the DD-254 documents who has access and why and what gets accessed.
And if you're going to have to get access to another compartmentalized program, then
that has to be justified in the DD-254.
And usually that's not justified because programs don't really overlap.
However, I think it was Bill Sweetman back in the 1980s who did a deep dive in this after
Reagan became president.
And he did correctly say that the compartmentalization of SCIs, but mostly SAPs, was really horrible
because you end up duplicating programs, doing the same thing.
So we're now spending taxpayers' dollars at twice the magnitude doing the same thing
between two programs, and they can't communicate that to you.
They can't elaborate.
They can't come to an understanding and say, hey, oh yeah, you exist, oh, and you exist,
and what you're working on is what we're working on, but we're spending all the government's
money this way.
Why don't we join forces and maybe cut the budget?
But that isn't what happens.
You can't do that.
You actually sent me the article to the Liberation Times piece that Chris Sharpe wrote.
He was kind of describing, for I think the first time, some of the intimate details of
the ecosystem of the program, eponymously.
And that was where I heard for the first time that DOE and then, what was it called?
Office of C.I.A. Weapons Counter-Proliferation Center.
That's the modern name of WINPAC, the Weapons Intelligence Nuclear Proliferation and Arm
Control.
I actually got hired by the C.I.A. to be the branch chief scientist of WINPAC back in late
2003.
Wow.
And so they talked about how DOE, that group, and a bunch of combatant commands all do their
own thing to some extent.
And there's really not an executive head adjudicating conflicts or do work like you're
saying.
You could have Navy programs and Air Force programs doing the same thing.
Keep in mind that that, we call it the counter-proliferation program, and WINPAC are
actually multi-agency.
They're not just the C.I.A.
They're C.I.A., NSA, NRO, because when I got hired, the hiring manager that was going to
be my boss, he briefed me on what my job duties were going to be, what organizations were
involved, and that I was going to interface with all these organizations.
And he wrote down two long lists on a couple of, well, two lists on a couple of columns.
They weren't that long, but they were all the agencies that were fused together to run
the WINPAC operation.
So WINPAC will seek resources and personnel from that agency.
That agency, this agency, and that agency do accomplish different things.
I think one WINPAC member recently mentioned kind of as a gatekeeper of legacy programs was
Glenn Gaffney.
If you guys remember that from various reporting, I think Chris Sharp touched on it as well.
Did you ever interact with Glenn Gaffney?
I didn't have direct interaction with him.
But the aerospace defense firm that we were working, we were trying to work with during
the OSAP, had direct interaction with him, as well as he was a senior VP, and the executive
VP of the corporation, they had to have a conversation with Glenn Gaffney.
And he was very antagonistic about that company releasing to us, under the DIA-
To NIDS.
To NIDS, right?
To us?
No, to Bigler Aerospace Advanced Space Studies and ERTEC, to release to us their collection
of crash retrieval materials that they've had since before got shut down in 89.
So he stepped right in the middle of it.
First, he was surprised that that company still retained materials that when they were
supposed to give it up and return it back in 89.
No kidding.
And then he said his answer to that whole question about giving permission for them
to share it with us under that classified setting, because that was SAP level, we were
TSSEI, we were trying to get SAP, and Harry Reid was trying to get Deputy Secretary of
Defense William Lin to give us an SAP, and William Lin denied his request.
And the reason why he denied it is because Harry Reid was using political muscle, and
you can't do that.
It has to go through the security channels and the program management to create a justification
and a need to give a program that's already TSSEI a SAP level.
Right.
Okay, add on SAP.
Yeah.
So he's looking at, I can understand what William Lin is looking at.
The majority leader of the Senate is telling him, I want you to, you know, a very nice
letter, the letter has been posted on the internet.
So very nice letter saying, well, we have reason that we need to do this, etc., etc.
And Lin didn't buy it because that wasn't an official channel for how you create a SAP,
a program that's already TSSEI and elevated up to a SAP.
There's a whole process, procedure, bureaucracy and red tape that you have to go through.
And Harry was using political muscle to bypass all that.
And the executive branch is taught or trained not to do that.
Capitol Hill is not their taskmaster.
The taskmaster is the president of the United States, the commander in chief, the head of
the executive branch.
Now, who was the president at that?
It was Bush.
So George W. Bush, if Harry Reid had written the letter to Bush or actually met him face
to face, which would have been far more effective.
I don't know how possible it would have been, but it would have been had a much higher chance
that Bush would call down to William Lin or he would have maybe his national security
advisor, Stephen Hadley, call the secretary of defense's office, actually.
And maybe the undersecretary of defense for intelligence and security and say,
okay, there's this program I wanted to get a SAP.
Sure.
And if the president says I want a SAP, they're going to have to SAP it.
And Luis Elizondo's book, he specifically mentions how they went to
see if they could get inside this program and have some of this material.
And they were pretty much, you know, blocked out by the program manager.
And of course, the red tape.
Glenn Gaffney was the director of the funds.
Yeah, he was the director.
I think his title was deputy director of the CIA over the directorate of science and technology.
That's where the UFO or the UAP portfolio was held.
So he's the portfolio owner at the time he was there.
So I guess maybe his title is deputy director of science and technology.
It depends on how they organize it.
Yeah.
These days.
But anyway, that's what he ran that directorate.
So he just stepped in the middle and just said, absolutely not.
We're not going to do that.
I wonder, HW, former director of CIA, do you think it stands to reason that HW might have
known more than many other modern presidents by virtue of this?
I had conversations with him back in 2003.
And what he learned, he was not briefed as a president on this subject.
He was briefed as an incoming CIA director.
Not surprised.
And that's all he had on it.
When he became president, he didn't hear about it anymore.
When he was the CIA director, he was given some pretty spectacular information.
And he insisted that he wanted to see that.
This is DOD information.
What's funny is that his agency was the portfolio for UAPs.
So even he wasn't told who in the CIA was running it for him to get briefed by, for
him to call on his phone and say, I need you to brief me.
He wasn't told.
Instead, it was the Pentagon liaison officer who had no intention on briefing him about
UFOs or UAPs.
And instead, he assumed that Bush had already been briefed by his CIA personnel or his
leadership who oversee that portfolio.
And he accidentally assumed that.
He started rattling off about a major UAP event that took place in the early 60s.
And Bush's eyes lit up.
And this is what he's told me.
He said, what are you talking about?
So the Pentagon liaison officer told him all about it.
And he said, are you kidding me?
There's a there there.
And he said, absolutely.
And he said, well, I want to see the evidence.
And the evidence was in the form of a film and some documentation, reports or something.
But the film was the primary thing.
And he was declined.
The liaison officer said, no, you don't have a need to know because this is DOD intelligence.
And we're not going to give it to you.
Only if there's an event that happens that requires you to take that information up to
the president and the national security.
Actually, go to the national security advisor.
He's the clearinghouse for all things UAP.
So you go to the national, the president's national security advisor, and you say,
my agency just had a major event that we collected intelligence on.
And it's going to require a presidential decision.
And the national security advisor is going to have to say, okay, here's a number in your
agency who you're going to call to get a full briefing on the whole UFO thing.
And meanwhile, I will schedule a meeting in the Oval Office with the president for each.
That's how that works.
And I think the PED documents could possibly emerge from that.
If it's a historical thing, no, that historical event might already be covered by a PED.
And that's probably why that guy, that briefing officer, the liaison officer from the Pentagon
actually slipped up by wrongly assuming that Bush was already briefed.
The fact is, yes, you can brief the PED within the executive branch,
but he assumed that Bush had been and he hadn't been.
So my guess is that since that was not a new event, it was an old historical event,
that there would be no need to brief Bush on the PED that was involved.
So he would never know.
He would just hear about the evidence that recorded that event happening.
And it happened at a military base.
And so there you go.
And speaking of those PEDs, yesterday you also made some super interesting comments
on kind of private contracts.
Specifically, I think you said source contract.
It's all source.
Instead of putting out a project for a contract bid.
An RFP.
Yeah, you have to have to issue either a broad area announcement, which is how
Bigelero Space applied to submit a bid for the OSAP contract.
So it's either a request for proposals or a broad area announcement.
And if you do that, then you're going to severely compromise the security of an SAP.
So they don't do that.
You don't invite different companies to see the specs of the program,
the outline and the specs and the deliverables expected
over the period of performance expected in the RFP or the BAA.
Instead, the government agency has the contract guy and the program manager guy
and maybe one other authority over all that.
They're going to call up their favorite contractor who they know or believe
could successfully execute the project.
And they'll say, okay, we want to give you a contract.
Here's how much money and here's how many years we're going to pay up.
And the company's stupid.
They'll say no.
If the company's smart, they'll say yes.
And generally, the Beltway bandits and the legacy aerospace industry are not stupid.
They need money, so they will always say yes.
Would those be authorized contracts then or have a transfer of authority?
Those sole source contracts?
Would they be traceable?
No, usually they set up a front company to pass the money through.
So this roster of kind of the big defense contractors for these big projects,
would that roster be pretty thin?
Only a couple entries there?
And I don't know.
I do know from the aerospace company that I interacted with quite frequently during the OSAP.
Yeah.
They didn't go to the government customer.
It wasn't always the CIA.
It was Air Force at times.
So I think the money is transmitted through a pass-through company.
But they know very well who their government customer is.
The government customer knows very well who they are and that they have a contract.
So I think the fact that the money goes through a hard-to-audit channel
doesn't prevent the two from talking.
Because the program does get contract monitoring
and contract oversight from the government customer.
So they will exert that authority over them.
I wanted to ask you about Dave Grush's IRAD fraud allegations.
You recall what he talks about in Congress.
He alleged that at least one contract, and I believe
Elizondo repeated it in his House hearing.
The allegation was made that at some point in time, for some duration,
a contractor artificially inflated the proposal budget for a black budget program
so that they could siphon that money off into IRAD to do an IRAD project.
Because frequently you can tax deduct the funding from the profit dollars and move them.
And instead of just hoping they overperform, they like doctor the situation so that they
definitely overperform.
Then the extra money was sort of moved into this.
Okay. I don't have any insights on that.
Okay.
There are two types of contracts.
It's either cost plus fee or fixed cost, fixed firm price.
Yeah. So those are the only contract vehicles I'm aware of.
I'm not aware that there's anything special just because of UAPs.
So it's either cost plus or firm cost, fixed price.
Sure.
One of those is how NASA tends to issue contracts,
like Artemis is way over budget, over schedule,
and the Orion heat shield did the same thing to the Orion.
Boeing has become a disaster with the CST-100 or the Starliner.
Yes. So that is under cost plus.
Right. Right.
And that's where the government gets screwed on.
So I have no idea what contract vehicles are used for UAPs.
It's like now you're down in the weeds and it really doesn't matter.
Sure. Sure.
Speaking of these sort of corporate entities here,
people are sort of aware that, okay, maybe they have their groups
to do the work in engineering, to do the material analysis,
what have you in their programs.
But is there any merit to there being private strike teams
who are having their own contested crash recovery,
coverings with the public strike teams?
No, I'm not familiar with any.
I haven't heard any such thing.
Even out in the open, even in the classified venue, I haven't heard.
There's a story of apparently a private military contractor,
contracted by Lockheed Martin, sent out to recover a crash.
The JSOC team sent out to the same crash site
and there apparently being exchange of fire and case.
And clearly this would generate a lot of paper, right?
Well, I'm not familiar with that incident.
So all this talk about private contractors,
the big Lockheed Martin, what about federally funded research
and development centers such as MITRE, RAND, Triad, Oak Ridge,
and UARCs, University Affiliated Research Centers?
Where do they fall into this?
Only one, and I won't name it, started out as a contractor in the 1960s.
Not too long after it was born, it was actually a spinoff of TRW.
So TRW was the principal investigator for the first,
roughly, what, almost 30, yeah, practically, what, 29 years.
But I know that another company would dispute that.
They thought they were a principal contractor.
In fact, the principal contractor served a leadership role
that the other companies kind of, they don't know what's going on,
but they know who's involved at the, you know, the scuttle,
the scuttle, you know, scuttle-bet level.
And so they know at the scuttle-bet level through communications
with the government customer, who else would be involved?
But they don't have direct communications with those other
companies because of compartmentalization.
So I do know that there'd be a dispute because there was, I mean,
the senior VP of the company I interacted with during the OSAP with that.
Well, we had the program running and they didn't consider somebody else
as the principal investigator.
I think that they would know that.
The government customer knows that.
So I think that's where the misunderstanding was occurring,
is down at the company level.
So yeah, the only FFRDC I know of is the one that spinoff of TRW.
My recollection from the senior vice president of the other company
is that they kind of left that whole line of work at some point
just because I think they did all they could do.
And so they got out of it somewhere maybe 10 or a little more years
after they got started on it.
So probably in the early 70s is when they left it.
And then we had the other legacy firms that were involved.
So there were four overall.
That would make sense because a lot of the FFRDCs that were started kind of
were born out of the early 60s, late 50s,
and kind of fulfilled their purpose within 10 years
and then moved on to other projects.
Like RAND, for example, started off as Project RAND.
And just speaking of what you know and what you don't know,
one of the things you kind of definitively said during your talk up there
was that there are no ARVs or alien reproduction vehicles.
And so I think that's really kind of a bombshell
because there are so many theories out there like,
oh, this incident or that incident.
Well, I know.
But, you know, I can kind of take their word for it
because we've barely scratched the surface of how they even.
Yeah.
So I have some questions about this.
So like, do you think anything's happened recently maybe,
like in the last like 10 years that's real new, like advancement, like progress?
I'm not aware of it because I'm out of it now.
Sure.
I've been out of it since the Ashes, the age it ended.
So I'm not right into it.
At the level I was for the ASAP and ATIP purposes,
I don't know.
All I do know is I was given a firm.
Hey, in 1989, the CIA shut it all down because nobody,
us and we know the other companies that we had been found out from our customer
didn't make any progress after several decades of investigating.
There was no progress made.
So I said, so what's the story about
Northrop Grumman having an ARV or somebody out in Area 51 having an ARV?
And he said, oh, that's all myth.
He said the people that had been putting out there
don't know what the hell they're talking about.
And they don't know why unless they're just another Bob Lazar type.
They're just going to, they're long on the tooth and they're going to tell a story.
Yeah.
Is there any chance that was disinformation or that was passage material?
No, actually it wasn't disinformation.
It was even Bob Lazar's information is disinformation.
It's because they believe their own bullshit.
I mean that they were telling you that there's no ARVs.
We've made no...
Oh, no, that's not disinformation.
You know, that's coming straight on a classified level with me having the need to know.
And they don't have a need to give me this information.
We're on a program and we're going to give them contract money to work with us.
And they're not going to sit there and bullshit with us.
Wait, we're going to give them money.
I don't think so.
It's way too 5D chess.
When you're saying ARV, do you mean like a one-to-one recreation of a UAP and NHI vehicle?
Or do you think there's aircraft systems that have kind of leveraged technologies?
Definitely no aircraft systems that have leveraged anything.
And there's been no one-to-one reproduction.
A lot of that fell into the psyche of the UFO community because of Bob Lazar
and then Brad Sorensen and Mark McCandless.
So I don't know where they're coming from.
And then other people kind of came out of the woodwork saying the same thing,
but no proof.
I mean, there's been photographs, but those photographs, I haven't analyzed them.
I don't remember if Bruce Maccabee looked at them.
I know Bruce Maccabee had only said they definitely looked like hoaxes to him,
but I don't think he ever issued a report on them because he's got lots of reports on UAPs
that he has done photo and film and video analysis of.
Have you ever spoken to the Brad Sorensen and McCandless?
No, I have.
I've put off asking.
What do you think about adversarial governments having
functional vehicles that they've...
Okay, if they do, then basically, why are we still a country?
Why haven't we been conquered?
And especially if it's an adversarial government with the resources,
because there are adversarial governments that don't have the resources.
That'd be North Korea, Iran, and probably a few others,
but the big ones would be China and Russia.
Well, suppose it's still...
Yeah, right now, they're still playing with conventional propulsion like hypersonic missiles,
supersonic missiles, subsonic missiles, multiple munitions, multiple warheads, et cetera, et cetera.
Nobody's got an ARV type crap zipping over Ukraine,
and Ukraine certainly hasn't been reporting any such things of that nature,
and they would have.
They would have screamed bloody murder and taken it straight to the President of the United States,
the CIA, the Department of State would have said,
here's our photographs, and here's our recordings of it.
And look, there's a Russian symbol on it.
And so, no, that hasn't happened.
I mean, if it was for real, we would see a dramatic change in the balance of power.
The United States, our intelligence agency would probably have known about it before
Ukraine would have gotten hit in such a hypothetical story or scenario,
and that just hasn't happened.
So, they haven't been successful.
I can't believe they're any more successful than we do.
You do agree with Grush's contention that they have programs, they have wreckage,
they have technology that they're...
China is like a closed door.
I know through how put up that they have at least one,
and I think he might have gotten that officially through some work he did with the DIA,
where he did go to China for them, but not for that reason,
and he's probably learned something over there.
I think there's other sources that have said similar.
Probably Dave Grush has more information on that than even I thought to ask him about.
But Russia is one that had some crash retrievals,
and that's been released when the Soviet Union fell,
KGB opened up the files, George Knapp went there,
other people went there, found the Thread 3 documents.
And I had independent, and I can't get into this because it's still super classified,
but through the OSAP program, I had a connection in with a three-letter agency that collected
not from the KGB open records, they collected it from their own asset,
and the asset was was filtering out actual legitimate documents, photos,
reports, technical and operational and executive summary type.
There's enough evidence that I saw in classified setting that convinced me that they have it.
At least for quite some time.
Crash retrieval, yeah.
I can't say that it would go back to the 40s, 50s, or 60s, or 70s.
I know I was at the end of the 80s was the one I was exposed to.
So they have had something, and they've got hardware,
but I don't see that they've been any successful.
It's not holding up.
Are there any other breadcrumbs that you gave to Dave Grush that might be useful to us from
kind of like an open source intelligence perspective that we could start to follow
and kind of pick up and-
Oh, boy, this is really super, it's classified still.
The breadcrumbs I gave him are proprietary to NIDS and BAS,
Bigelow Aerospace Advanced Space Studies, and classified to the DIA and another three-letter
agency. That made me two.
I need to wait for a couple of people at the corporate level to die of old age.
And when they do that, I won't have trouble with lawyers,
and then I'll come out with a book.
Now, the classified stuff in that, I don't know what I'm going to do with that.
That's classified for life.
Yeah.
So they can declassify it up to 25 years, but I've had so much derivative classification training
that I found out that the rules for declassification are,
do include the ability to maintain classification up to even 75 years.
So BAS has to maintain that classification for 75 years.
Wow.
So if you sincerely can justify that you can't declassify after 25 years,
75 seems to be the maximum.
How did your perspective change on what viable approaches were to break through
propulsion physics from when you started it to when you end, when you finish the project?
What did you initially think was interesting that you threw away,
and then what sort of came to the floor from it?
Well, what got thrown away is those concepts that don't meet the criteria for novel disruptive
innovation or testable or theoretically well-defined concepts.
People come to you or came to us and others with all kinds of inventions and ideas,
like the Searle effect, the Dean drive, those kinds of things,
space-time torsion.
And torsion, for your viewers, is basically just a defect or crack or fissure in the space-time
continuum.
And Einstein looked at that and it looked like the issue of, well, if you're going to have a
path of a particle undergoing motion through space-time and it's going to encounter this,
what's the gravitational or space-time curvature manifestations of coming into that crack,
going around it?
What does it do to you if you go around it or can you go across it?
What are the physics consequences of doing that from within general relativity?
So Einstein looked at all that and he was trying to find out if torsion might give you
a prescription to describe elementary particle spin.
And he found out that was not the case.
So he also found out that torsion does not produce testable predictions that we have observed.
And it actually produces or predicts inconsistent results.
And so he ended up tossing away torsion saying, you know, it's a great theoretical
concept to look at, but it doesn't hold water because it makes the general relativistic
field equations inconsistent.
So it loses its self-consistency.
It'll make wrong predictions of phenomena already observed.
And it's just not refined enough.
There's just something missing from it.
And it cannot definitely be used to describe particle spin, whether it be macroscopic
particles or quantum particles.
It just didn't reach that threshold.
So Ringamacher actually did an experiment, and I'm not going to get into it because I
don't remember enough of it anymore.
And he did an experiment that was specifically designed to test whether torsion existed in
space-time.
And it was a well thought out apparatus, very well designed.
They did it at General Electric.
So they had a staff of physicists and engineers to help do the prediction on what such an
instrument would be like and how it would function and how you would design it and build
it.
So they did it just like Kip Thorne and the big giant team that formed LIGO did when
they got started looking at gravitational wave detectors in the 1970s.
And he got an old result.
Basically, he couldn't find any sign of any space-time torsion.
And so at least at that level, it was a thorough enough type of experiment.
It's just like what Gary Nolan said.
It was data.
And then the data formed the evidence, and then you interpret it in the context of the
hypothesis, and then you form your conclusion.
And the conclusion was, we don't see space-time torsion, so it must not exist, at least at
that level.
That doesn't close the door on torsion because there could be other experiments.
Somebody can think of some other formulas.
That's right.
But unfortunately, we haven't seen that happen yet.
And the interesting thing is that, like I said, as we go back to general relativity,
and Einstein messing with that when he was developing the general theory of relativity
and its 16 field equations, it starts out as 256 field equations.
But due to symmetry properties, you can knock them down to 16.
And I think a couple more will bring it down to 10.
So 10 field equations, and it just basically gets you inconsistent results.
And that's a problem.
So it's telling you already that you're not going to get right answers by incorporating
torsion, and that's a problem because that means you're trying to develop a physics that
produces a testable prediction that, when you observe them, you're not going to just
observe new predictions.
You want to observe old predictions just to make sure the theory is still correct,
because it's not a predict the old stuff that have been observed, old phenomenon.
And it didn't do that.
It just gave you wrong answers all the way around.
Yeah.
Now, when you talk about like the nth order differential equations associated with GR,
and you get 256 equations that only simplify due to symmetries, what is your perspective
on the approach to like mathematical beauty in physics?
I mean, do you insist or do you have a notion that the theory of everything or the gut will
turn out to be elegant?
Or do you sort of think it might be clumsy and clunky and, you know, 19,000 equations?
I mean, do you have any perspective on that?
With regard to what?
A unified field theory?
Yes, with respect to each other?
I don't think it's...
Yeah, no, I'm in the camp of physicists that we already know and a lot of other physicists
know that Einstein proved that gravity is not a fundamental force of nature.
It emerges from the fabric of space-time when it's distorted or curved or bent.
And Sakharov, he believed that the metric elasticity of space described by the space-time
metric, which is just a very simple equation actually, and he said that should come from
the quantum vacuum fluctuations because he sees the quantum vacuum fluctuations as being
the seed of all existence.
And he was right.
Basically, that started from Richard Feynman when he got the Nobel Prize for the quantum
electrodynamics theory.
And then later on, when that got unified with the weak nuclear force, it became the
electroweak theory.
Separately, we have quantum chromodynamic theory, which describes the theory overseeing
the strong nuclear force, which basically emerges from quark or quantum thermodynamics
or the interaction between quarks and gluons, gluons being the photons of the strong nuclear
force.
They have instead of...
They don't have a mass, they move at the speed of light, they have a spin one just
like a photon does.
But unlike a photon, they have three color charges, or it can have a combination of those
color...
Actually, they have two color charges.
So they have a combination of color charges, which are a symmetry property of the theory.
They're not an actual...
They're not an electric charge, really.
They actually have no electric charge.
Generally can't be separated.
Is that right?
You can't get color charged particles in terms of pulling them apart, popping them apart.
You can, but inside the hadrons, you can.
But when you have high energy collisions, like what happened at the relativistic heavy
ion collider at Brookhaven National Lab, for a brief instant, or just an instant long enough
that you can measure it, you can pull the quarks out of the hadrons, they'll be mixed
in with the gluons, and you will actually produce quark gluon plasmas.
And the plasmas will exist as an entity.
I don't want to say a soliton, but as an entity on its own, and it's outside of the elementary
particle from which it was created.
The collider is colliding heavy atoms, usually uranium, lead, iron, even protons.
Yeah, at 99.9996% the speed of light.
And so there's enough energy, centered mass energy, in there in the relativistic
reference frame that you can literally blow those hadrons apart.
A hadron is basically two classes, mesons and baryons.
And of the baryons, there's protons and neutrons.
So basically, you're looking at the heavy nuclei of these ions, so you strip the electrons
off, and you're going to have these super heavy uranium or iron or lead, or gold and
silver and other ones, and even as light as a single proton for hydrogen atom nucleus.
And they smash these things together, and you're liberating literally the quarks right
out of those protons, and then the heavier atoms out of all the protons and neutrons,
they get bashed into each other at really high energy.
And so that's an example of when that happens.
So QCD theory is not complementary or compatible with electroweak theory.
They cannot be unified.
That was a dream, that was a projection, an extrapolation, and has not come to fruition.
Likewise, gravity is not a force of nature.
It emerges from space-time phenomenon, the space-time manifold or the continuum,
however you want to describe it.
And it's a coupling constant measures the strength of the interaction force between
particles.
So for the quantum electrodynamics, that's the electromagnetic fine structure constant.
Then for electroweak theory, well, now that's blended in with the weak nuclear force.
The weak force is responsible for the decay of quarks in high-energy quarks,
the low-energy quarks.
Radioactive decay is another one, where atoms transmute and decay away, and elementary
particles are emitted, or even alpha particles, which are helium nucleus, are emitted.
So that's what the weak force is.
It turns out they're both two sides of the same coin.
Of the same unified force.
Well, its coupling constant is actually the electromagnetic fine structure constant divided
by 100 times the proton mass squared.
So it's scaled to the proton mass.
So then when you're talking about gravity, gravity's coupling constant.
The first two I mentioned have known dimensions.
The coupling constant in general relativity is the universal gravitational constant times
8 pi divided by the speed of light to the fourth power.
You know what the units of that are?
One over force.
One over newtons.
That's right.
And that's a coupling constant to convert the
dimensional units of the stress energy tension, which is the source of spacetime curvature.
That's in units of joules per cubic meter, or energy density, or pressure,
because an equivalent is newtons per square meter.
Okay, so those have to be converted using that one over newton factor
from the coupling constant into units of one over meter squared.
That's how you measure spacetime curvature on the left side of the field equation.
That has the Ritchie curvature tensor and the Ritchie scalar multiplied by the metric tensor
and one half.
And they take this difference between the two.
For that reason, we know we really can't unify those two forces.
It's really electroweak and quantum chromodynamics.
We can't unify it to spacetime curvature model.
And everybody's still attacking quantum superstring.
It's kind of died away because it can't make useful predictions or testable predictions.
However, it's been very successful in mathematics and geometry and topology.
They have predicted a lot of new things in those areas,
but they're still hacking away at trying to get it to work as a quantum gravity theory.
Same thing with quantum loop gravity.
And gosh, Roger Penrose had the most sexy version of quantum gravity
that I fell in love with when I was in graduate school.
And it came out, it was twister theory.
So he replaced the whole concept with a whole new,
instead of a four-dimensional spacetime point of x, y, z, and a t,
or a different coordinate system, but you always have a time in there.
And instead, he was looking at energy, momentum as a four vector
to describe an event in spacetime.
So we wanted to build an edifice of an algebra that handled that,
then a geometry that that algebra builds up.
And from that, he was hoping to get a unified picture of the forces of nature and gravity.
And it was beautiful.
Again, like super string theory, great, beautiful mathematical results came out.
It's geometrical.
Oh my gosh, this thing is an exercise of the most advanced version of complex math.
You've seen complex math when you were in aerospace engineering,
so it just didn't go anywhere in predicting.
It just didn't give you anything useful.
So basically, we can't see a unified field theory coming out of that.
Well, Dr. Davis, thank you so much for sitting down with us.
It's been incredibly revelatory.
And we're so glad you came this year to give a talk at Seoul.
We hope we see you back.
Oh, yeah. Thank you very much.
Yeah, absolutely.
See you, Jack.
Yeah, you're both in the tree.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
We'll wait another 14 years this year.