Okay, but the real men in black, are we talking about humans or non-human intelligence?
What is the real men in black compared to just government agents being, you know, interrogating
people?
I think there's enough evidence in the literature to indicate that the phenomenon may be associated
with some cases of what we call men in black.
But what are they?
Secrets, cover-ups, and strange phenomena.
UFOs and ideas that challenge reality itself.
All these mysteries, all this time, are we ever going to get to the bottom of these?
My name is George Knapp.
I dig into news stories that others can't or won't.
I'm Jeremy Korbel, and for some reason, people tell me things they probably shouldn't.
And this is Weaponize.
Alright you guys, welcome to Weaponize.
We had some technological problems, I'm going to blame that on George Knapp, but we have
a great episode with Dr. James Lakatsky, Dr. Colm Kelleher, talking about the UFO programs
and their new book, which is Inside the U.S. Government Cover UFO Program, Initial Revelations.
So jumping on in with all you all, here we go.
James Lakatsky, it's so great to have you and Colm here to talk about OSAP.
For the benefit of our audience that does not understand the difference between OSAP
and ATIP, your new book, Inside the U.S. Government Covert UFO Program, Initial Revelations, really
draws a distinction.
And it's not bashing ATIP, it's not going after Lou Elizondo or showing differences,
but there were distinct differences between those two programs.
Can you outline for our audience, those who are not aware of what each of those acronyms
mean, what the difference was?
Well, the Advanced Aerospace Weapons System Applications Program was basically created
between myself and Senator Reid at the Defense Intelligence Agency.
It was a $22 million program.
It had the capability of going five years.
We completed our objectives in two years.
You might say it was test of various components of a UFO, UAP, paranormal research program.
Right from the beginning, it included all aspects of both UFOs and the paranormal in
relationship to UFOs.
It was a contract that was put out on the Internet, it had a quick turnaround because
of the funding mechanism.
The first year was $10 million, the second year was $12 million.
And we gutted out, we had numerous interested parties who wished to bid on the contract,
but following the regulations, it first had to go to small businesses.
Well, the only small business, we found small businesses that were capable of bidding on
it, but they chose not to.
Bob Bigelow's Bass created specifically, and that was so important to DIA, specifically
to address our needs in this program.
And when I say needs, we used a new method of putting out this request for proposal.
We did not tell the contractor, the bidder, what to do.
We said, this is what we wanted achieved, how would you do it?
And that's how this program was created and had specifically all the right components.
Let me back up a little bit just for our listeners, people that are listening, and also just for
the visual audience here.
Dr. Lekatsky, first of all, in December 2017, the world learned that there was a UFO study
program and that it was funded for $22 million.
They heard that that program was called AATIP, but what you've told us is that no, you ran
the program, the DIA for studying UFOs, and it was called AWSEP, Advanced Aerospace Weapon
System Applications Program.
So you're talking now about a government study, a UFO program, studying all the physics
and the nature of UFOs up to date.
And so you're kind of coming forward with these books, with Dr. Kelleher and George
Knapp, and you're laying it out for people, this is what we did, this is how we did it,
we don't want it to get messed up, we want to tell you what happened.
It's a big deal that you're speaking to us right now as someone from the DIA who studied
UFOs.
So I guess the question for me, very simple, the audience might want to know, is that when
that came out, December 2017, and you didn't see your program named there, what does that
feel like?
Are you doing this because you want to clarify the record to the public?
Exactly.
And we stated that clearly in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
We want to clarify the record.
Now we're giving the details of the record.
Now, the thing is, ATIP, the name itself, I did not create that name, but it was created
for a specific reason, and I don't think that's ever been printed.
It was done, yes, in Senator Reed's letter asking for a special access program.
That's been out in the press for, what, five years now.
But where did the need for a different name come from?
It came from, which took me by surprise when I saw the funding, someone, in other words,
the notification of funding that, yes, DIA was getting this money.
It was on a piece of paper that had highly classified programs listed on the rest of
the paper, and someone in Congress put secret on the program name and its very abbreviated
contents that were on that document.
I did not want to get us crossways with any security considerations.
I wanted a different name.
Now, I believe that who we called Axelrod or perhaps Luella's on or perhaps some of
their cohorts, and maybe all of them came up with the name ATIP, that name would have
been a great problem for DIA because ASAP routed the money to the Defense Warning Office
of DIA, period.
It had to be that name.
So the contract may have been called that, too, because that's what we put at the open
solicitation that can still be found on the Internet.
And I've repeated in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon a concise amount of material as to what we
requested. But that's where the name ATIP came from.
ATIP was something that was necessary to be
proceeded with on military cases.
Lue handled that.
I was not privy because it was mainly spun up as I was getting ready to retire.
I will say this, though, that when I left, all of our references were electronically,
specifically scanned in electronically at DIA.
Now, I can't say what happened in the years since I retired in 2016.
It could have been that they're purged, but they weren't physical records.
So I don't see why there is a problem in people asking for them, except for the fact.
And this is why these books are required.
Most of them were proprietary.
Remember, they were monthly reports from the contractor and specialized studies.
They had people's names, contractor names, the facilities that were being bought and
constructed. They had security information.
They had all of this.
And I have already told I wasn't asked to have these documents cleaned for release.
But the proprietary information is so much I said preemptively I wouldn't take on that
job. It's just too much.
We're doing it in this manner.
The public knows what went on in that program within the constraints of security.
I hope that answers your question, because ATIP was a specialized small program.
It had access, I'm sure, to funds that I also had access to, but not use on this program of
where we can go out and, let's say, review facilities at DIA.
I used them to review missile contractors, in other words, so I could learn the nuts and bolts.
But money, I'm sure, was available for ATIP, but nowhere near $22 million in two years.
That's really helpful. So, George, we're talking about that, like how ATIP kept its legs,
because it was heroic in an attempt to kind of continue it.
The fact there was money available wasn't out of the $22 million.
And we're making that clear. It was misreported in The New York Times.
However, it is nice to know somehow how they got any funding to do the work they were doing.
Yes. And I was aware of some of the programs, the cases that they were looking into.
And I can say without going into detail, because it's a classified endeavor, I was
fascinated by one of their cases, because it was a repeat from the 60s.
And if you go through our databases, you're going to see cases where people claim,
wait a minute, I saw the same UFO when I was 20 years younger.
And those cases kind of fascinate me.
How can that be? At least, are we talking about time machines?
Well, what are we talking about?
But you will find that another fascinating point of our huge databases,
it would be the equivalent of us going out for a drive in our car.
And every car and truck we meet on the road is of a different design.
I mean, to me, that's that's an interesting insight, because when people make up charts
and we have a nice one of all the configurations of UFOs
and those are main configurations like triangle, there are very many variants of triangles.
It's like, how can this be?
I mean, it's like, certainly we're doing things exactly the opposite in the auto industry.
Every SUV looks like every other SUV.
You have to look at the name badge in order to tell what brand is that.
I like it or I dislike it.
But right now, I like them all, mainly because they all look like in the UFOs, totally the opposite.
There's one particular UFO design that gets discussed in the book that you reveal.
And if you if you blink, you'll miss it.
But it's it's maybe the most controversial and important piece of information that this book conveys.
You say something at the beginning of Chapter nine about a craft of unknown
origin that our government access, finally access the inside.
Can you share with us what's in the book?
And is there anything else you can add to that?
Well, what's in the book is an exact statement of of the event that occurred in the.
And let's say in a congressional facility.
There was more to it, considerably more to that discussion about what this situation was.
We can't go into that because it's it's and what I mean, column and I, yes, we know about it.
People are interested in it, I'm quite sure.
But security has to trump everything else.
A lot of things can be said.
This was this book, as was Skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
I keep flashing book, basically was reviewed by the Department of Defense for
released and approved the wording that's in it, the wording.
If we varied that wording, we'd get back.
This was a seven month review.
This was quick.
D.O.D. on Skinwalkers at the Pentagon took 14 months to review that book.
And there was I agreed with all of the changes on both of these books.
I agreed with except for one, I made the fatal mistake of complementing the help from a
non D.O.D. organization.
And it was, whoa, we can't do that.
We've got to align that out.
And so that's that was the only thing that was a straight line out.
D.O.D. helped us reward things by their security regulations.
And so you're getting as much as we can say, Jeremy.
OK, hold on, hold on, hold on.
So for our audience, this list is George has dropped an atom bomb because it was
dropped in the book. So audience is just listening.
I want to read you something.
Beginning of Chapter nine, at the conclusion of a 2011 meeting in the Capitol building
with a U.S. Senator and an agency undersecretary, Lekatsky, the only one of the
book's authors present, posed a question.
But this is where it gets good.
He stated, meaning you, Dr.
Lekatsky, that the United States was in possession of a craft of unknown origin and
had successfully gained access to its interior.
This craft had a streamlined configuration suitable for aerodynamic flight, but no
intakes, exhaust, wings or control surfaces.
In fact, it appeared not to have an engine, fuel tanks or fuel.
Now, there's a next part which I'll read in a minute.
But what this is, is you're officially allowed to tell us that the United States
government has in its possession a craft of unknown origin and you were able to
access the inside.
Is that correct?
The wording that you read is correct.
Ah, you're going beyond the wording.
No, I'm not. I'm not. I'm asking you, did that happen?
And is it true? And it's true.
OK, you're telling us, you told us because you were allowed to tell us that our
government has a UFO in its possession and has been able to access the inside of it.
Right? Yes.
Well, I was allowed to tell you, let me show the back of the book.
This is what I know.
I know. Hold up.
George, will you translate, George?
All right. Let's try another tack.
How do we know it's a craft and not a doorstop?
We accessed it. It has no engine.
It has no wings, no, no, no fuel.
It doesn't. We don't know that it travels.
Do we know it's a craft or it's just a rock?
George, you're you're going into the further discussion that occurred that day.
All right. We can't we can't go there.
But let me tell you, we're going to try to cover that in the future.
But it's it's delicate.
It's it's. It makes it.
It makes the technology described in here look primitive.
Why is it delicate?
Why is this topic?
The United States government has a UFO in its possession,
and we've been reverse engineering it.
You've done it. Why is it delicate?
The details you I'm old school.
I'll use the term.
I won't use the term adversary competitor as the way we describe.
We are surrounded, maybe not surrounded, but hopefully not so.
By our enemies and our enemies, you can be sure they're listening to this show right now.
You can be sure that they were monitoring awesome.
You can be sure that perhaps they had employees.
Hopefully, not in the contract or part that was we're giving out information for I am.
I am. I know that, so the thing is, is we can't say anything more than what we've been approved to say.
And there's insight to this, but I want to I want to I want to shift it just slightly.
But it shows my point, Skinwalkers at the Pentagon and Initial Revelations,
if I might use the shorter title on this new book.
But has some interesting doors that have not been even mentioned.
One, why was this program started?
Two, why was this program ended?
And we've raised this partially and Skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
Did it end?
Also, we had an interesting program that ended in the middle of the year.
Also, we had a chapter in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon where we met with a high level Brazilian official at a meeting,
started introducing some of our cohorts.
And no one ever asked us, why did you have that meeting?
What was so important about that meeting?
You know, there's a lot of material in there that as Kit Green, Dr.
Kit Green, one of our consultants on the OSAT program said, read between the lines.
That applies both to Skinwalkers at the Pentagon and Initial Revelations.
Read between the lines.
Now, you may come to the wrong conclusions.
And I can tell you on the topics I just read, read, you don't have enough information to come to the correct answers.
OK, so why? Sorry, go ahead, go ahead, Jeremy, go ahead.
So why? You're asking one big question people should ask is why was the UFO program started?
Maybe you can't tell the full story, but give us a hint.
Why was the UFO program started?
You said that's important.
I can't do that without documenting more and getting approval.
I mean, can I just do that?
I know, Jeremy, you and I have met previously several times and you want the bottom line.
But the bottom line may not.
Let me just give you the bottom line may not be what you anticipate.
In other words, there may be no bottom line.
There may be multiple bottom lines.
And we've got a lot of work.
You know, if Arrow is going to move forward from this point, they've got a lot more work to do.
Why? One of the questions that you posed to us just now was why was the program started?
OK, you can't answer that.
But another question you're saying people should ask is why did you do all the defense intelligence reference documents?
So can you answer that?
Why did you do all those defense intelligence reference documents?
And the answer is no, I can't answer that, because that would that would be an answer that would just floor people.
Really?
Yes, the real answer.
And by the way, I don't know whether there's ever been real criticism, but there kind of has by the nature of some of these topics.
We solicited the input for the topics for the 38 papers from from Air Force Intelligence, CIA, Naval Intelligence and Ground Intelligence.
That those are the topics they chose to do, but they were completely legitimate at the time.
And by the way, they're pretty close to state of the art right now.
OK, so that's one thing I would like to say about the timeliness of our program or the timelessness.
If this program ASAP, you know, the physics would have been different back in the in the 50s and 60s, or if this was being done in the 2000 70s and 80s.
What is being covered in this book and what Arrow has been mandated to do by Congress is timeless.
In other words, you will be doing the same thing, regardless of the time frame.
It's just that I'm sure it configurations, if there are any further configurations, there could possibly be of craft will be available in the future.
But, you know, triangles have been seen back into the into the 60s, and I'm sure will be seen into the future.
Flying saucers, even craft that look like something from the Jetsons have been seen.
You know, the the flying saucer with a big bubble on it with with occupants.
That's all the same. In other words, if if if you look at ASAP and study what's in ASAP and try to answer some of the
questions, you're you're you're not wasting your time.
In other words, there there there there's a timelessness to it.
All right. So we hit we hit some technical problems, which is not strange for us.
But we got we got George Knapp here on the phone and we're just getting, you know, back down to the point.
So, George, I was asking you, help me this guy, Lakatsky, he's being a little dodgy as a reporter.
I can't nail him down. We're talking about why these why our government would or why he can't talk more about this.
So I don't know. Help me out, George.
Well, Jim is the rocket Gibraltar.
He's not going to answer that question for you. If he's decided not to answer it, he's not going to.
I was thinking maybe there's another way in. We could go around the corner here.
Let's start with Colum. Colum, this book is so much different from Skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
And that was not an idle decision.
Jim had used the phrase earlier in this conversation, nuts and bolts, which you will recall you and I were kicking around ideas for a possible title for the for the book.
And nuts and bolts came up. But we didn't think that having the word nuts in a UFO book was a good idea.
Well, you know, the point is, you know, that first Skinwalkers at the Pentagon had a lot of weird stuff.
And people think, well, maybe we made a mistake by including all those stories of strange paranormal type events that were highly criticized.
But in fact, that was part of the focus of OSAP.
Why why this different approach this time? What distinction is being made here?
Well, the critical part of OSAP that we tried to convey in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon was that there were two fundamental parallel tracks that OSAP ran on.
The first one was the the examination of UFO performance.
And, you know, the UFO performance part was getting all of the data from eyewitnesses plus deploying sensors into the field in order to gather data on the performance of UFOs.
That was track number one. And track number two was what effects do UFOs have on humans?
That was a parallel track that from the get go, OSAP decided unambiguously to run both tracks in parallel.
Skinwalkers at the Pentagon focused a lot of its reporting on the second part, which is the effects of UFOs on humans.
So that, you know, to summarize that book, we looked at a variety of effects on humans that included medical effects.
We documented several medical effects, pathological effects, physiological effects.
You know, the people people having weird metallic taste in their mouth, sometimes hair loss and a whole bunch of other things.
We documented psychological effects and then we also documented paranormal effects.
So all of these under the rubric of, you know, effects on humans were reported in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
A lot of the pushback that we got from that book was that these guys were using taxpayers money to camp out on Skinwalker Ranch and,
you know, basically document Dogman, dino beavers and a whole bunch of other weird stuff.
Whereas, in fact, that was only a very minor part of the entire OSAP program.
So the purpose of the second book is to balance that whole thing out.
And so we unambiguously focused the reporting on the initial, you know, initial revelations.
The second book on the nuts and bolts aspects of the UFO phenomenon, which was half of what OSAP was doing.
So the purpose of the second book is really to look at the UFO performance angle strictly from the from only the performance angle.
You know, things things like, you know, lift, propulsion, power generation, spatial temporal translation, configuration,
a whole bunch of other aspects of UFO performance that is translatable into theoretical physics, eventually into engineering.
In the only other interview you've given about the OSAP, you had said that the DIRTS essentially established a baseline for analysis.
It's a baseline of here's what humans are known to be able to do.
Here's what we think humans will be able to do in 50 years.
And when we look at UFO cases that you do in great detail in this book, it is clear that this is technology that we certainly didn't have 50 years ago.
That we don't have now.
And it's not even clear we will have 50 years hence.
This is a nuts and bolts UFO book, and it was a nuts and bolts UFO program.
Correct. Yes, absolutely correct.
Now, the thing is, is there have been again on the Internet, because anything can be said on the Internet, it seems factual or not.
Well, one thing that is not factual is DIA knew what it was getting into in regard to both aspects that Callum just described to you.
And let me end my statement right here.
We had no choice but to pursue both aspects.
Why?
I said I ended it.
Again, hey, let me tell you, Jeremy, you cannot compete with some of the offers that have been made to me.
I'm joking now, but this is factual.
Airplane tickets, speaker presentations, car rentals, hotel rooms pay for you just can't compete with all that.
I can throw in a steak dinner.
Oh, they've already done that, but you know what they always want.
Listen, listen, I am way more handsome and way more charming than any of those other people asking you to spill.
You know, the thing the thing is at the bottom line is what they all want.
And then when I hear the phone being clunked on me is when I say I cannot go beyond what is stated in the book.
Now, of course, now there are two books.
I can't go beyond that because it needs to.
Oh, that's OK. You gave us a great one.
You told us U.S. government is interested in UFOs, is studying UFOs, has been studying UFOs, is reverse engineering UFOs, has one and got inside of one.
Thank you. Thank you.
OK, so let me ask you about some current events here.
I really want to get your opinion on this.
So as we know, we're out in Congress and you saw like everybody else.
In fact, I mean, I'll spill the beans a little bit myself.
We were hoping you were going to testify in front of Congress.
You didn't. But David Grush did.
So I want to ask you your opinion.
Here's a guy who says that he was looking at reverse engineering programs, black budget programs, and has provided a whistleblower statement through the Presidential
Protection Act, came forward and told us all these things that he believes them to be true from his investigations into 40 witnesses.
And that has been corroborated by being labeled urgent and credible by our inspector general of intelligence, what David Grush said.
So what are your thoughts on David Grush and what he said at that hearing?
I don't know, Mr. Grush, never met him.
I was asked almost verbatim the same question by a congressional office to me, a telephone conversation.
And I said, I don't have a comment.
What he's saying is credible.
Now, let me do say one thing that I never witnessed.
And I don't know if Collin ever witnessed this, but I never saw any what I would consider illegal activities.
I saw security procedures that are paramount, but not illegal activities.
So I don't concur with that.
But it's reasonable what he's saying.
And that's what I told.
Okay, it's reasonable.
It's reasonable that we have UFOs, reverse engineering, that there are biologicals associated with those biologicals because I can't say anything about that.
Why can't you say you don't know or?
I can't say anything about that, Jeremy.
Okay, no, that's great.
So just another question about that.
Well, let me tell you, these books are loaded with questions because someone criticized me, gave me a three rating on skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
Why do they read this one?
They said it's textbook like.
Well, in a sense, they are.
They're a learning instrument.
And one thing, and I don't know if I discussed this with you, Collin, but I was going to put like a textbook questions in the back of each chapter.
What do you know?
What do you think?
And what do you just further for now?
I wasn't going to give an answer sheet to them.
But basically, I think that people really need to delve deeper into the books they have.
And, you know, I personally love hard copies, but at some point it's going to be hard to flip back and forth.
You obviously are well doing it well, Jeremy.
I always had trouble on an electronic copy of flipping back and forth.
I like hard copies.
Well, yeah, for sure.
Well, listen, however you get the information out, it's great.
So let me ask you this, though.
The big the big question with David Grash was they're like, well, he didn't see a UFO.
Now you're in a meeting in the Capitol Hill and you're telling them we have a UFO.
We've gotten inside of it.
Did you see it yourself and answer that?
OK, but if the answer was no, you could answer that, right?
No, that comes goes back to something that occurred.
A similar question, very similar to your question.
It wasn't asked by you, but it was asked to call him.
And he said, we found no smoking gun.
That is the standard answer we're to give is so I could say no, and it's still not be the truth.
So the thing is, is security is paramount.
We follow the rules and there's a good reason, a good reason to follow them.
Yeah, you can't tell me that good reason.
We've talked about that.
You can't give me a reason.
You can't give me that good reason.
But you're alluding to a really good reason why you can't tell me more about biologics, UFOs, exploitation.
You can only say what you said.
I get that. I wish you could give me a good reason because it makes me very suspicious.
It makes people like me very suspicious.
Like, what is it? Is the reason so dark?
Is it so disturbing?
I see. If you want my opinion on that, I see no darkness at all here.
Basically, OK, there was some considerable write ups on the skin walker at the Pentagon that our program was stopped due to religious concerns from the far right.
Well, if there were, I knew nothing about that.
I saw no evidence of that being true.
But people can say whatever they want on the Internet, apparently.
And that was not that was not I did not witness any of that.
And I think that that's come up in some of these congressional hearings.
George Sansevier in skin walkers at the Pentagon.
And and column has backed us up in public statements.
Both of you indicated that you were on the trail of reverse engineering, crash saucer, meta materials, weird stuff.
You went knocking at different places and the door was slammed in your face.
That sounds like you were looking for exactly what we're talking about right here.
Is that wrong? Of course not.
That was part of the program.
But I'm saying the door being slammed in our face wasn't because of of suspected demonic activities within this at all.
In fact, I would say there's evidence that this is something of a nature that.
Well, I better not say much more.
It's if if full human capabilities were known to us right now, it is not something that we need to fear.
And I do not I just don't believe it.
Maybe I'm influenced by my Catholic faith.
I don't know, but I'm optimistic.
I think everything heads toward good.
What do you mean by if full human capabilities were understood, it would be nothing to fear any, any.
We'll get into that later at some later point.
But our capabilities, as Colmwell knows, he's probably an expert in all of these areas, more so than me, is our capabilities are, are, are, are.
Have never been fully revealed, and we're we're still learning.
We've got a long way to evolve still.
George, what were you saying?
Well, there are two questions I've asked, and neither one of them were answered.
But the first one was, were the DURDS established as a baseline?
Because that's what has been said before they were a baseline by which we can measure that's that's correct.
Yes, they're a baseline.
Well, they're a baseline, but also the purpose of them was to project 40 to 50 years out in the future in terms of the best known projections by the sort of the best people at hand.
So they were a baseline, but they were also projecting into the future.
So they were a baseline, but they were also projecting into the future so that would be an attempt to look at UFO performance and then marry those to the projections, the baseline projections.
All right. Well, the second part of the question was, do we not in fact report in Skinwalkers at the Pentagon that you guys went knocking on doors asking about these materials, that the materials and I'm assuming we're talking about
crash saucer type stuff that was part of what the bass plant was modified to receive.
That was part of the contract that you were you were asked to prepare to receive certain materials that you never got and you went looking for them.
And that's when the door was slammed in your face column.
Am I characterizing that incorrectly?
Well, slightly, because the people who were moving forward on that were not they were working with the OSAP program, but they weren't part of the OSAP program.
Am I incorrect that you guys were looking for stuff?
Remember, George, there's always multiple doors.
There are always multiple ways of doing things.
So just because a door was slammed in our face, is that a common expression that we're using?
Is that all we can say?
Remember, I and Colin became this are experts at taking higher classification material and describing it at lower classifications.
There is no contradiction between the two.
It's just that the lower classification isn't complete.
And I can tell you there is a lot of material here in both books.
It's not complete.
And it can't be at this point.
OK, well, we've dodged the question again.
Is you pursuing this material?
Were you trying to find this?
You know, part of your question is there's material and there's material.
Are you talking about material to be investigated?
In other words, pieces falling off flying saucers, or are you talking about full blown craft?
You know, there's a big difference.
And I'm not so sure that I would ever characterize it that we were constructing facilities in order to look at full blown craft.
I mean, again, we're talking about a commitment of money.
Bob Bigelow went over well over and well and beyond commitment to the contract.
I mean, we stopped tracking a DIA, his losses at one point five million dollars.
Now, is he going to be constructing large facilities?
There's a lot of statements that have been made on the Internet that partially ring true, but ultimately aren't really true.
I mean, that's a large commitment of money on his part.
And as a contractor, he's responsible for having his supplying the facilities, not the government.
Right. But didn't he revert or didn't he retrofit Bigelow Aerospace?
I mean, Dr. Kelleher, maybe you could talk about this, but didn't he retrofit Bigelow Aerospace in hopes to gain either some materials or a full craft?
You've already told us that we have a full craft that we got inside it, that we've been reverse engineering within our government.
Didn't he want to be part of that and get some of that material?
Part of the contract was that, you know, DIA wanted a facility security clearance bestowed on some of the buildings associated with Bigelow Aerospace Advanced Space Studies.
And so in order to be accredited to achieve that facility security clearance, a lot of retrofitting was necessary.
So, you know, the National Security Agency got involved and all of these audits happened on a very regular basis.
So you had to dock the I's and cross the T's.
That was a part of the requirements of the contract that we had to perform.
That's a very different thing from, you know, building a hangar outside Wright-Patterson Air Force Base in order to receive a craft.
I mean, we were mandated by the contract in order to adhere to facility security clearance requirements.
OK, so let me let me just go one last time.
So basically, David Grush, what he told us, you both feel that that information is credible, right?
Is that what you implied?
It's credible, but I'm simply saying he worked with someone that I know and trust as the UAP Task Force leader.
And I think you should take his statements now, whether whether whether or not if we could just take a moment here.
I've observed to call him something that is I'm looking at it particularly in regard to UFOs and the paranormal.
There are people who have have written, have talked about things they are absolutely wrong about, but they totally believe it.
I mean, you can't call them liars.
They totally believe it.
Now, how many of those people that David Grush came across are fit in that category?
I could name a list of them right now, but I won't.
I mean, obviously, I, I, I, I respect their opinions, but I know what they're saying is false.
So it's a phenomenon now.
I certainly hope that does not spread across all topics on the Internet because we're in big trouble if that's the case,
because that means people are delusional, the correct word.
I'm not a psychiatrist or a psychologist.
I don't know what it is.
Yeah, but hold on, because we don't have Grush here to talk about, but he talks about program names.
He talked about program names.
He talked about holding locations of UFOs, which you've already admitted that we've got them and we've been exploiting them.
So he's talking about things that are very tangible and physical.
People that worked on UFOs, those programs, part of the 40 witnesses that came forward to him are people that actually work on these legacy UFO programs, which he says exist.
We've talked about it.
All the four of us have talked about it.
We know UFO legacy programs have existed, whether or not you can talk about it or not.
We know that they existed.
So just to give, you know, kind of looking at what he said, he's saying that there are individuals with direct first hand experience, not opinions they could be wrong or right about.
It's whether or not these programs existed and we have these crafts we've been working on.
OK, and I have seen in multiple cases what I would call can only call forged documents.
OK, so there's another thing we should talk about.
So what do you mean by that?
Forged. There are documents talking about programs that are not legitimate documents.
Within intelligence servers, within your industry, there are forged documents inside of our government's, you know.
Or what are you talking about, just on the Internet?
I'm talking about both.
Really? How could that happen?
Forged documents with inside our intelligence agencies?
They even covered this on an X-Files episode.
Every special access program has a counterintelligence officer.
That's their job.
You know, it's their job.
So, you know, you might say, well, wait a minute, Jim and then call them our counterintelligence officer.
No, we're not.
You know, there's no reason to be.
But if you're in a program, you have you have that person either assigned to you or you bring them in.
And there's a source of forged documents right there.
Have your listeners and readers go back through the UFO history and you'll see fingers pointing to others that
again, I won't name them that, hey, this is all fabricated and.
Yeah, like Rick Doty, that's who you're talking about, maybe.
Can't say.
Oh, hold on. Here's George. Here's George.
He's going to say something. Go ahead, George.
Which counterintelligence officer wrote this in Skin Markers at the Pentagon on page 152?
OK, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
He'll read it. 152.
Yeah. Sasha Mover and Jim Bell began knocking on doors beyond DHS to connect with, quote,
the keepers of the secrets in at least two other agencies in these meetings, which took place June, July 2011.
Sasha, Jim and colleagues were treated rudely and harshly.
Bell and Mover were repeatedly told no and hell no.
This left them convinced that advanced technology was sequestered under government supervision at aerospace contractor facilities.
As a result, the DHS facilities to Harvard Department of Homeland Security officials became very hesitant and even fearful of moving forward.
Perhaps these two only belatedly realized the unique game changing and earth shattering nature of the biggest secret ever kept by the United States.
Is that counterintelligence stuff or did you two guys write that?
Well, we wrote that and it was approved by the Pentagon and by DHS.
But the thing is, is that that's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about playing out and outforged documents that are shown as proof of something.
And it's it's it's been applied to us to that their documents.
I want to emphasize something I said on my first and only interview.
It was a closed program.
It operated very similar to a SAP.
The director, the director of analysis and my office chief and, of course, division chief knew about this program.
No one else did.
Now, I was also protected by the stovepipe nature of that.
I did not have to address political type questions.
I I was insulated, but they were, too.
They there was no one else.
People in the surrounding cubicles didn't know nothing was purposely being hid.
It was a closed stovepipe system.
And it needed to be it needed to be operated that way.
What I'm talking about here is documents that have that have risen up in the meantime that are out and out forgeries.
Again, I'm not saying why this was done.
I'm saying officially if this was a counterintelligence effort, it probably wasn't a very good one.
But the thing is, is there there's phony material out there.
And I we have no reason to do that.
And that's why, you know, we were questioned in the review of skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
Why did we list all the references?
Why? Because we have real references.
Whether or not people can see that because of all the material that's the proprietary information in those references is is another situation.
But the thing is, is we we we have our references and they're not fabrications.
They exist and they exist both in and outside of D.I.A.
So what I was trying to get to is that mass during that period, you confronted the keepers of the secrets.
You were on the trail of what the keepers of the secrets have.
The biggest secret in the history of the U.S.
government is how we described it in that book.
What do we talk about bits and pieces of metal here?
Are we your your crew, your team was on the trail of that stuff, right?
I mean, and are we wrong about that?
Is that counterintelligence or did you come to believe that we really do have this stuff?
Well, I can tell you, George, that, as you know, those events in 2011 occurred after the OSAP program was shut down.
So OSAP was officially sort of stopped in terms of funding being received in September of 2010.
By December of 2010, we had a 90 day no cost extension.
And at that stage, the program was over.
There was a lot of interaction between different departments and different agencies subsequent to that regarding additional funding.
What you are referencing in the skinwalkers at the Pentagon occurred after the OSAP program officially was terminated.
And it involved a lot of negotiation and back and forth between different organizations.
One of those organizations that we worked with was DHS, as it says in that book.
And those those elements within DHS did their own version of due diligence.
And that's what's being referenced in that book.
I think what George is getting at is that you guys have already explained that you have gone off,
you know, after the people that are guarding these secrets that you did find that they're storing this stuff somewhere else.
I mean, is that, George, is that your point is that they've already said I think that they believe that those goods exist somewhere hidden in the bowels of defense contractors by the elements of the US government.
They think they're real.
The period that column is describing is when Jim and column and some of their colleagues were trying to find a new home for a version of OSAP.
Is that correct?
That is correct.
So on one hand, you're telling me there's disinfo even within intelligence servers and systems where you can cover up your programs.
But you're also telling me UFOs, our government knows that's why you did all those dirts and that we have them.
We've been inside of one of them.
You've admitted it now.
I don't know that anybody from the DIA, from your level of the intelligence agency running a UFO program has ever admitted publicly before that we have a UFO and have been inside of it, have been able to get inside of it.
That's a big deal, you guys.
Well, that still doesn't address George's question.
You know, you're not addressing any.
We're not.
I know you're dodgy.
Maybe we take a different tack and try to talk about the book in a general term and try to circle back.
We've mentioned about Arrow a couple of times.
Jim, you and Colm have both said in a limited number of interviews that you believe that the data warehouse that was established by OSAP, the biggest UFO data warehouse in existence that we know of, that it was subsequently being put into use by U.S.
government agencies.
Is Arrow one of those agencies?
And if it is, have they reached out to you and Colm or can you say?
Because Arrow using the database that you guys created from OSAP, the largest UFO database in history, Jacques Valle worked a lot with you guys on that.
Is Arrow using that?
Have they reached out to you about that?
On that particular issue, no, they have not.
But I know that the originator of, you know, the lead of the UAP task force from when Arrow evolved did have it.
So as for using it, it's it's more of a tool to get broad trends.
I mean, obviously, my broad trend observation is every car on the road is different if you look at the UFO database.
In other words, models don't that if there's if multiple craft are seen at the same time, yes, they can be duplicates.
But in general, everything is different.
That's something you use the database for.
Also, what do you make of that?
What do you make of that in general?
I'm sorry.
But what do you make of that?
I mean, there's some indications of what I could say, but I won't say yet.
I don't I think that that's odd.
And why is everything dissimilar?
You know, you have to that's you have there are a lot of things that you have to question here.
Why did why that mean in on regard to Skinwalker Ranch?
You've seen nothing yet, nothing.
I mean, you'd be flabbergasted at some of the occurrences there.
And yes, there is documentation for these.
Why? For what purpose?
And and I think it's very dangerous to commit to an answer that someone knows the solution or what's occurring.
I think it's why I can also going back to George's question, I can answer that also from my perspective.
You know, as you know, George, the the transition that occurred between the UAPTF and the various iterations of the UAPTF,
that the transition to AOI MSG and then ultimately to AARO occurred under completely different leadership
and completely different circumstances than the original UAPTF.
So I was I was interacting with members of the UAPTF on a sort of a consultant, informal consultant basis.
And I know for a fact that they had access to the the electronic version of the database.
However, the transition that that occurred in the leadership of the UAPTF was very abrupt, as we know.
And the, you know, the transition that ultimately led to the formation of the AOI MSG was very abrupt.
And the leadership transferred into the USDA.
So once the leadership transferred into the USDA, AOI MSG ultimately became AARO.
And under those two leaderships of the USDA, I have no personal knowledge that the full OSAP database was used by AOI MSG or by AARO.
But I do know it was used by UAPTF.
I think we're dodging another bullet here.
I was trying to figure out if AARO had reached out to you guys.
Jim indicated that AARO has not reached out about the database, but they didn't say he doesn't say whether AARO has reached out at all.
I would think there are a few people in the world that have more expertise on this issue than Colm and Jim.
And I was just curious if I were running AARO, I would want to talk to you guys.
Have they reached out and tried to just establish a line of communications or are you able to say?
The reach out was on an unclassified network.
I would give you the answer.
Yes, for me.
Was it Dr.
Kirkpatrick, you guys, or was it somebody from his office?
Now, Jeremy's getting back to it was it was a person from his office.
In a position to reach out, I can say that, that as based on his background and his position, it was a proper contact.
Yes.
So you guys, the OSAP program is the largest acknowledged UFO program to the public, to the American public.
But we know there were other and are other UFO programs.
We'll get into the are other because on camera, you guys talked with me about that this study continues.
We'll get into that. But as far as legacy UFO programs, like what is your understanding of that?
Like David Grush talked about it. It's now public that there were these things.
Have you ever had experience with that, Jim?
Have you been part of a of a UFO program, a legacy UFO program?
I couldn't say yes or no on that.
What I can say is that I am describing that which I was involved with, and that was OSAP.
And I have always said you must do what OSAP did.
You've got you have no choice but to do all aspects of what OSAP did.
Now, you might call it, well, was that fortunate that we did the right things?
Well, actually, looking back, yes, it was.
I'm kind of surprised we did what you need to do.
But any program that is truly looking into UAP paranormal has to do what we did and what we did.
And now put in another thing or may still be going on.
OK, so so as far as future looks at the UFO topic, the OSAP, it ended in the form that we know it.
But you have said to me directly and George on camera, we just haven't put that footage out yet.
Both of you that the program continues just under a different guise, a different name.
So that's what you're saying.
You're saying the two arrow.
Look, I know.
No, don't play with me with the arrow thing.
There's got to be something on that.
What was it? What is it?
Chapter, chapter two, the comparison between the two.
The only difference between OSAP and what has been mandated by Congress for Arrow is the high cost sensors.
We couldn't afford that.
Now, we describe in the book.
In chapter and chapter, what is it?
Eighteen, the integrated sensor package.
Yes, we had our own design for a sensor package and there are other.
Other individuals, entities that were interested in placing their own sensor packages with us.
Like NASA, like another agency, like who?
No, I can't say.
You'd say, I mean, would have been the same equipment while they may have had resources that we didn't.
Ours was kind of something we could place at multiple locations.
OK, so let me just ask you, both of you can answer this.
This is just your opinion.
So we know that Project Blue Book ended in 1969 and they said nothing to see here.
Move on. We do not believe that the UFOs pose a national security threat.
We now know that that was a lie just because of OSAP.
Even if you don't admit another legacy program, we know that we were studying UFOs and funding it.
Let me ask you this.
That excuse that was given back in 1969 with the closing of Project Blue Book that they don't believe there's any national security threat.
I can't imagine a world where the DIA would be funded for the Defense Warning Office for something like OSAP if they didn't believe that there was a national security threat.
So my question is to you.
Do you believe UFOs represent a national security threat?
Well, lack of knowledge always can.
I mean, directly a direct threat.
Well, is it something that you can do something about or not do something about or there's so many qualifiers to this question and to the answer.
It's almost like we're getting into an endless.
Well, I can I can step in here because that question has been posed to me multiple times.
And, you know, threat has two components.
One is capability and the second is intent.
And we had the OSAP program generated gobs of data on UFO capability.
We generated almost nothing on UFO intent.
And unless you have both, and I was lectured pretty strongly by one of the one of the consultants to OSAP, you cannot make the case that without without data on intent,
you cannot make the case that these objects are a threat to national security.
What you can say is that they are a threat to human health.
And we made that statement in at the end of the OSAP program.
We we generated a fairly large summary of all of the data that pointed in that direction,
including medical injury cases, including a lot of pathological cases and physiological cases.
And, yes, we did say that UFOs are a threat to human health.
Are they a threat to national security?
We do not know.
We did not accumulate any data regarding UFO intent.
I'm going to pull George here, George.
So read in their book over the last few days, they talk a lot in the book.
You guys talk a lot about Calaris in Brazil and how for decades that human beings were being physically harmed to the point of death.
So from UFOs and that their military studied it, is this like a case?
And that also OSAP, you're going to reveal in a future book, did actually do an in-depth investigation about Calaris.
So my question is, OK, maybe not national security, but in this case, the UFOs were fucking people up.
They were hurting them to the point, sometimes to death.
So are you telling me with your book and all this information that UFOs do pose a physical threat a lot of times to people like in Brazil?
Yes, absolutely.
And that's one of the reasons that we were trying to complete the database in regard to Brazil.
And it's simply that that if that was occurring here in the US, let me tell you, every day you'd see a front page article that did not occur.
But, you know, there's there's I don't want to go into something I'm unfamiliar with that is an OSAP in nature.
But there's there's current problems now in in in South America, you know, and you probably know more about that, Jeremy, about what appear to be, again, threats.
Yeah, you hear that. But, you know, it's not as studied as what you guys were able to.
Calaris and the surrounding areas, correct. But that.
So anybody. Yeah, anybody that reads your guys book, just so our audience knows, basically, there's a bunch of dedication of pages into these bizarre events in Brazil.
They were studied by the Brazilian military where these UFOs for decades were harming, murdering, burning, messing up human beings.
This is not just like, oh, these great space brothers.
This is something that was really devastating to these communities and left them in terror.
So I suggest people check that out.
I would agree with you, Jeremy, and I think even beyond the Brazilian cases,
I think we accumulated enough cases within the United States to say that, you know, if you're in the wrong place at the wrong time,
in terms of proximity to UFOs, in terms of proximity to blue orbs that you can come off the worst,
you'll have a lot of symptoms that mimic radiation sickness, for example, you know, metallic taste in the mouth, sunburn.
Your hair starts falling out. We documented these cases.
And if you add that to the events in Calaris, you can make the statement that UFOs are really bad for your health.
I would also ask, you know, I think the strength of this new book is the is the examples that you guys use,
that we use to to document and demonstrate certain principles.
Why engineering principles, physics principles of how strange this technology is, how advanced it is.
One of the cases that comes up is a military case.
And I'd remind our listeners that, you know, the Tic Tac case was an OSAP, a bass investigation.
It started with OSAP. Later on, iterations of other UFO programs looked into it.
But OSAP started that investigation off and you had another investigation into a military encounter at Lake and Heath.
Colin, can you share with our listeners what some of the details about that Lake and Heath case and what stood out that made it interesting to you?
Well, I think it was mostly because it was a again, it was a military situation with the RAF, Lake and Heath,
got a bunch of unknown signals regarding something that needed to be checked out.
There were two fighter jets that came very, very close and personal with an object that had no aerodynamic surfaces,
that looked like basically, you know, the raw ingredients of a meteor.
It was tracked both on the ground and by the fighters.
And they made several passes with this and they had communication, constant communication with ground control.
And, you know, the upshot of this thing was that an object was flying.
It did not seem to react to their presence. They came up close and personal.
They had visual confirmation. They had radar confirmation, you know, in other words, instrumented and sensor confirmation of this object.
And it was nowhere near as spectacular as the Tic-Tac,
but it was certainly an unknown flying object in the vicinity of RAF, Lake and Heath.
And very similar to.
You know, one of the things that we sort of focused on in the book was correlating some of the aspects of UFO performance,
like lift and propulsion, power generation, spatial temporal translation.
And we generated a bunch of different cases from the historical literature.
And you'll notice a lot of those cases are old cases.
So one of the things that, you know, a lot of modern cases are thrown up against is, you know, these could be drones.
These could be, you know, these could be sort of, you name it, either commercial drones or Chinese spy drones or whatever.
But, you know, back in the 1950s or 1960s, a lot of these cases are pretty pristine.
And, you know, I'm thinking, for example, of the RB-47 case that we cite in this book,
which is an absolute classic case that Brad Sparks investigated.
And a lot of write ups, AIAA actually did a write up on it.
And this was a classic case of RB-47 aircraft down in Texas, Louisiana area that was flying electronic countermeasures equipment
and had this visual sighting, instrumented sighting, radar sightings of this UFO that essentially outgunned them, outmaneuvered them.
And this was all the way back in July of 1957.
So you cannot say this was a Chinese high speed drone.
And the level of documentation on that case really is illustrative of, you know,
the properties that we cite in the OSSOP study regarding Lyft.
Jim, same sort of question.
I know we're sort of hair splitting here on the terms of national security threat.
But when you have these unknown objects dancing around over our base at Lakenheath or interacting with in the area of the Nimitz and the Princeton,
flying around with impunity, it's not attacking U.S. cities, it's not using laser beams to wipe out New York or Washington, D.C.
So maybe it's not considered a strategic threat, but it certainly has to be considered of interest to our national security interests
when it shows such an ongoing fascination with military facilities, personnel and equipment.
Oh, yes. But the thing is, we're investigating them probably properly now.
It's true that the Lakenheath incident did not involve near collision.
The ones since 2014-15 perhaps involved more of that, but again, probably not deliberate.
So, yes, you should be investigating that. It's more or less interference in flight.
You certainly wouldn't want an airliner to have one of these be sucked into an engine intake.
They're rather large, relatively speaking.
So, yes, it should be investigated.
And that's why I believe Arrow exists right now, is that's a starting point.
As for investigating many of these civilian cases, it needs to be done.
There's a need to be done by the government.
I believe the contractors are fully capable, but there needs to be certainly a database that needs to be up kept and also constructed properly.
I think Colum hasn't mentioned this yet, but we do mention in this book, more than mentioned,
it's a couple of chapters, the Vali Davis system of categorizing.
You know, you can have a database and it's just a bunch of data.
Unless it's categorized properly and be able to be searched on, then you can see trends.
And that's what we did with the Capella database, the Capella Bass database.
So, yes, it's huge, but it is searchable.
I want to read something from your book.
So when you talk about future work in your book, you make eight suggestions, a couple of which are establish a data facility liaison for operations,
collect and analyze uncorrelated target data, which would be from like NORAD.
This is something that a friend of mine in Georgia is a journalist named Chris Sharp has really dug into, which is he's getting information from them.
Well, we don't keep any UFO data.
We do keep uncorrelated target data, though.
Where do they put that?
So you would like to see all that come in, be able to analyze what they call uncorrelated data,
which is things that do propel through the sky with intention, but we can't correlate it to our own craft.
So you'd like to see that data come in in future studies.
But one thing you said, when you guys gave the eight different suggestions for future work,
you talk about collection of oral and written histories.
Now, let me just read you what you wrote two sentences.
It says collect under appropriate security caveats, oral and written histories from individuals with firsthand exposure to apparent exotic technologies and or circumstances surrounding the same.
This would include seeking out and contacting military and civilian personnel, scientists and engineers and companies that may already have had access to firsthand data concerning novel technologies.
So in writing that, you got to know that there are corporations, companies, military individuals who have direct firsthand experience in this exploitation program or programs.
But you're reading something exactly that was in the both proposal and which I don't think will ever be released.
The proposal from Bass and also the program planning documents for the startup of ASAP.
That's direct wording from that.
That was a hope that we could do that.
So I wouldn't I wouldn't say in other words, I wouldn't put too much.
Well, that's a that's a statement based upon knowledge, but a statement based upon desire.
In other words, that those those are exact words from the doctor.
I should say, you know, since S.A.T.P.
Skinwalkers, the Pentagon was a compilation document, it was written on our new book.
We tried to keep with editing, of course, we needed to edit or edit the grammar and the spelling.
We tried to keep as close to the original language that was in our documentation that DIA received.
And the reason for that is I want your listeners and the readers of this document to understand they're in the same management shoes or position that we were.
This is the document that really came in.
So I wouldn't put too much into the statement you you read because it was used as a plan.
And as I said, these plans never came to fruition mainly because one, the core items were completed in the two years.
And two, it would have required more money and more personnel.
To do them. OK, fine, fine, fine.
But Jim, like, do you think the American public deserves to know about the ultimate reality,
the fact that there are appear to be nonhuman intelligence flying spacecraft or something that looks like them?
That's why we're doing we're doing these books.
We're trying. So you believe the American public has a right to know within the security limits.
Within security limits, security comes first.
But the thing is, is national security comes first.
But that's why we're assembling these books and we're trying to accurately assemble them based on real references that may or may not be available to the public.
But you're getting direct extracts from these these references.
No, it's great. I just wanted to see where you stand on that UAP transparency or not.
I mean, we've got to crack the egg. Am I a disclosure advocate?
The answer is no. What's the difference in your mind?
The difference is security. You know, there's certain things.
Oh, and now if this involves security plus.
Because having come from the contractor world in the first half of my career,
I can say if there's heavy investment of contractor capital,
their overhead money into technologies and they've been given these technologies,
they're going to hang on to them. It's just like, hey, wait a minute.
We've invested a lot of our personal resources into research and that can apply to every topic.
It's going to be difficult to pry loose technology when something's been given over and a private company has invested their money,
their stockholders money into research.
So that's an entirely different aspect. But ours is security.
We're trying to release it for you. But doesn't it doesn't it drive you crazy?
I mean, I get it. There's security. I get it that private companies were given something, have invested a lot of money.
But isn't this topic kind of bigger than these issues, those two issues, the fact that we might not be alone?
Well, yes, but I think that we can convey that through the proper method.
And that's what we're trying to do.
OK, so you are trying to convey that in the proper way.
I'm not going out there and interviewing with everybody to say what I really feel.
No, it was hard to get you to do this. I mean, I can testify you're not doing it in an improper way.
People hang up on me when I say you can offer me all of this, but I'm not going to say anything more than what's been approved.
So let me get back to George here. So, George, what do you think?
Are we cracking the egg here with Jim and Colin?
Oh, not even coming. Not coming close. Here's another tack we could take.
Jim, Dr. Kasky, I believe that you have made it clear that you were in contact with Congress.
I know that you were asked about testifying and you declined.
Do you feel that telling Congress all of what you know would constitute a possible threat that, you know,
a mutual friend of ours of mine and yours and columns has said it many times, you can't tell your friends without telling your enemies.
Well, do you think that telling Congress the lowdown on things that you really know but can't say here would represent a likely threat
that that would be that information would be linked to our adversaries and enemies?
That's my personal belief. I mean, there's two things I said, and that's in response to your mention of Congress contacting me.
One, and I repeated this to multiple folks, I don't want to get involved in what would appear to be a three ring circus right now.
It's just it's too much for me. That's why I'm devoting and I don't want I don't get involved in answering things in Twitter,
which I easily could or read it, which I easily could.
I want it to be documented in these DOD approved books. That's my method of saying what I have to say.
Do I have a lot more that I could say and that will be seen perhaps if it's approved?
Yes. I mean, I can tell you with skin walkers at the Pentagon,
they had a number of comments that I felt were really legitimate security observations that it needed to be changed.
But did the story still come through? Absolutely, yes.
You mean, what's the old saying? There's there's more than one way to skin a cat, whatever that means.
But there's there's just there are multiple ways of doing it.
And we're trying to calm and I and George are trying to now George is good at pushing.
And so are you, you know, push the limits, push the limits.
Well, we can write whatever we want, but if it doesn't get by by Dobson, DOD review, then, you know, we're kind of wasting our time.
I think we know what are our red lines not to cross and going to Congress would be a red line to me personally because I I talk too much.
I say too much, but I purposely cut it off right here.
I just. Well, what if you what if you were subpoenaed, though?
I mean, you know, they're trying to do that in Congress.
They're trying to subpoena people and say, hey, Dr.
Dr. Lucas, you know, you've heard rumors about Dr. Lucas.
OK, but hold on. If you're subpoenaed and asked and asked to tell the truth, you're under oath.
First of all, right. Would you tell the truth phrase?
Let's cross that bridge when we come to it.
OK, George, I'm laughing so hard right now, George.
I wish you were on video. So, George, I was thinking, do you have I want to bring column into something that was written in the book.
It sounds like something column has tried to answer for me before.
It's about the nature of the phenomenon itself.
So let me read that, George, from the book. Cool.
OK, guys. So when we're talking about what we know about UFOs, George and I have talked about this a bunch.
What do we know? OK, we know that UFOs represent a huge amount of energy in a small amount of space.
That's that's been proven. However, what do we really know?
And you guys have something in your book that is just it's just a couple of sentences or one sentence.
It was so profound to me. And I want to hear you guys elaborate on it.
It says everything works as if UAP were the product of a technology that integrates physical and psychic phenomenon
and primarily affects cultural variables in our society through the manipulation of psychological and physiological parameters in the witness, in the witnesses.
Can you guys expand? That's a huge statement. Can you expand on that?
Well, I know that a lot of that that statement comes at least from my personal experience with spending hundreds of days on Skinwalker Ranch.
And as we've gone over before, you know, Skinwalker Ranch had both nuts and bolts, objects, shiny metallic objects.
It also had a plethora of very unusual phenomena. There was a lot of evidence that was gathered
and some that I saw personally involving the manipulation of perception.
And so there is a lot of really good work and really good documentation regarding the manipulation of perception by people like Jacques Vallee.
You know, even Whitley Strieber has written in his latest book, there is a lot to do with manipulation of perception.
So a technology that is both influential in terms of, you know, leaving an imprint on the ground that you can extrapolate that this thing weighed two and a half tons to altering people's psychic makeup.
There's really no contradiction there. I mean, you've got to be able to harness and work with ambiguity if you're working with the UFO topic at all,
because putting them into one box, you know, the nuts and bolts box or only the psychic box just doesn't work.
You've got to balance the idea that a technology can manipulate human perception and even from a long term perspective,
manipulate human cultural phenomena as well as, you know, operate as a machine.
So you've got to you've got to hold those two balls in the air. And if you're not capable of doing that, you should not be looking at UFOs.
Yeah. It's you know, a lot of people have filed FOIA requests, you know, based on skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
We listed all those reports that were produced by OSAP and BAS. And, you know, there's some great stuff, as we know.
But, you know, people write to the DIA and the responses they get is we don't have it.
There is no such report. For example, there's an analysis that is referenced in skinwalkers at the Pentagon about an analysis of Tic Tac, for example, that case and a few others.
DIA's answer is we don't have it. It doesn't exist. Do you suspect that those documents will ever be made public?
That particular one, as you probably already know, was a complete document analyzing a Tic Tac object and a spherical object.
And it was done based on BAS capabilities at the time.
It actually is. Well, the way it was written was it had that plus background material on the Tic Tac.
And I would say that there was information in there that was personal information, not proprietary information.
We were using commercial software. Will that document ever be released? I don't know.
We can do pieces of it in a future book, but the analysis tool that was being used was state of the art at the time.
And you need the color aspect of it. Well, as probably your listeners and readers know, color is kind of expensive in any book,
especially books that are reaching the size that we're doing. So will it reach?
They have the document, whether they've destroyed it. How do you destroy an electronic document?
That's unclear. Whether they would be willing to go through removing the personal information?
I don't know. I can't speak to that. The wording is probably wrong that the document doesn't exist.
Yes, it does. I mean, you had it in your hand. But the thing is, as for the public ever seeing the full document,
again, there's the color problem.
Hold on, hold on. So George, he just said, oh, does the document exist?
Meaning 140 plus page analysis of the tic-tac-toe that the world has never seen generated by the atmospheric object generated by the DIA.
You know, famously, George would have loved to have given that, you know, as a submission to Congress famously.
But the thing is, is Jim Murkowski just said, George, you had that in your hands.
So if the DIA is telling us some document doesn't exist, but you had it in your hands, George,
what does that mean for the fate of the document? Couldn't that just go out to the public then?
If they don't admit it exists.
There's the problem of having that personal information in there. Someone has to scrub it.
It is DIA's job to scrub it.
George would be willing to scrub it.
Oh, no, that's not...
George, okay, that was a rhetorical question, Jim.
So, George, just tell us what your thoughts are here.
Well, I could not. It's not my document to release and I wouldn't release it without permission from the people that allowed me to see it.
So I just couldn't do that because if I were to do that, I would never get access to documents again of that nature.
So I can't do it, but I'd be happy to do it if somebody gave me the green light.
Yeah, if people weren't going to have problems.
Well, so, Colin, back to this basic thing, you've tried to talk with me before about the physical and the psychic nature of UFOs.
And you're saying, look, you got to be prepared for both if you're going to investigate this.
But that statement that you guys wrote in your book, it really is something I think people really need to pay attention to.
You're saying that everything works if UAP were the product of a technology that integrates physical and psychic phenomena.
But then you say, and primarily affects cultural variables in our society through manipulation of psychological and physiological parameters.
What do you mean manipulate cultural variables?
I'm sorry, I'm obsessed with this quote.
Well, do you want to take that, Jim, because I've already answered it?
Well, we see cultural variables.
Don't we see that occurring right now?
What do you mean? No, you're asking me that.
Basically, there's a well, I got it.
I got something to really reference and it'll be another little bombshell of mine.
But you're going to answer my question.
What is the purpose of the men in black?
We that is a question we have encountered the men in black, the legitimate ones, legitimate ones.
You have I didn't say me, but the answer the answer is yes.
What do you mean the legitimate people who are gaming gaming knowledge of the men in black?
But what is the purpose of the men in black?
Is it to draw attention away from the UFO phenomenon or using reverse psychology, draw attention to it and the paranormal, of course?
What is the purpose?
It could be their polar opposites.
The answers that's always been the men in black.
Dissuade, do they knowing human psychology, do they or do they do exactly the opposite?
They draw attention to the phenomenon.
And that's what I mean in my answer to you.
I wanted to use an example of manipulating cultural variables that they're drawing attention.
Hey, this really exists.
Now, you can also go off on the side a little bit is say, are we in the realm?
Because I've been I've talked to multiple people about this.
Are we in the realm of what we would consider demonic influence?
Have we crossed into that?
That's a cultural variable to operating at the same level.
We've got to consider all this.
That's why I think this is such a wonderful topic, because you've got all these things you still have to consider.
And now I'm going to be long gone and Colin probably will be long gone and you'll be long gone.
And they'll still be exploring all this and not have all the answers.
But that's that's the manipulation from my point of view of, hey, get interested in this stuff.
It's real. And don't just jokingly, you know, like the term dino beavers, you know,
that Juliet and Colin saw a dino beaver.
No one said that's just created to make a joke about about our efforts.
But this is a real phenomenon, except it is such and you'll see that that was part of what DIA did.
Collect data, collect data, collect that the Intel communities are great at doing that.
But that's an answer to your question.
And there's so many aspects of cultural manipulation.
And I think it's positive manipulation.
Using an I again, an old expression, the train has left the station.
No, it hasn't. These books are proof that people can still get on the train.
But those who laugh and joke don't bother getting on the train because, you know,
you just you're not learning anything from the experience.
So, George, Dr.
Katsi just gave us a good answer, but I did notice when he was telling us that he said
something about the real men in black and that he's actually met him or something.
Can you can you just we can't let that go after you said to let it go?
You have to let it go.
But now the false men in black.
Now, there was an incident, and I'm not going to go into the incident, but column is aware of this.
There was an incident of a false men in black.
And let's assume they were working for some government agency.
What they've never known and never has been revealed is a person they were interview obtained a gun.
He was so afraid of them, he was ready to shoot out.
If they made the wrong move, it would have been a disaster.
It would have come back on us in some way, I'm sure, because I was asked in an interview once.
What was your greatest fear during ASAP?
And it was like it's tomorrow and the next day because there was always something that was happening
that would come back and we had to fix.
But we've never revealed that that this person was so afraid of the false men in black
that he had a gun tucked into his waistband under his sweatshirt.
Were you guys the false men in black just going into another government agency?
No, no, no, we were. We followed all the rules.
We don't know. You don't know who you can trace back so far.
But you can't if it was a counter intel operation by some organization, then it would have could have.
I mean, that was a bad decision on their part.
Bad. They shouldn't have pushed this fellow to that point where he was ready to resort to violence in defense.
And he was in his own home being potentially threatened.
Well, you know, I think there's a long history also of especially back in the 60s and 70s.
I think everybody is aware of this, of the Air Force Office of Special Investigations having people out there
trying to dissuade witnesses from talking to the media, threatening them.
I think in the 50s and 60s, threats were much more overt than they would be now.
But I think there's this this multiple arenas of men in black,
all of which are sort of mutually supportive in driving paranoia in witnesses and in the field in general.
And a lot of these are multiple agendas for different reasons.
And some of them are mimicking the real men in black.
Some of them are the real men in black.
It's a I think it's one of these I would class it as another example of what I call bi-directional mimicry.
OK, but the real men in black are we talking about humans or non-human intelligence?
What is the real men in black compared to just government agents being interrogating people?
I think there's enough evidence in the literature to indicate that the phenomenon
may be associated with some cases of what we call men in black.
But what are they?
Well, they're parts of the phenomenon.
OK, so not just government agents walking around.
Well, there's government agents that are also at the same time in parallel working on,
you know, on intimidating witnesses.
I know, but I'm not talking about the government.
I'm talking about what you're calling the real men in black.
I'm saying that they're part of the phenomenon.
OK, I think there's enough I think there's enough data in the literature,
especially if you go back all the way to the 1950s, to corroborate that statement.
Even in the 1800s, there was a phenomenon like that.
If you read John Keel's Trojan Horse, Operation Trojan Horse,
there's in the 1800s, there's a version of the men in black.
Well, George, I am highly frustrated, as always,
when I talk with Dr. Kelleher and Dr. Wachatsky.
So what do you think, George?
Where does this go from here?
Well, there's a lot of great stuff in this book.
I mean, you know, part of the a lot of criticism that came at us from
skinwalkers at the Pentagon is too much woo.
It's just too weird.
And I always thought, you know, I was proud of what we did with that.
And because it followed the evidence where it led and the people who were involved
with OSAP, with BAST and some of their allies,
looked at this without self-censorship.
They didn't decide, hey, this is an interesting UFO case,
but it's got this weird poltergeist angle, so we're going to toss that out.
They had the courage to include it because it was necessary to look at the big picture.
And that was where we started with the skinwalkers at the Pentagon.
This book narrows down the focus.
People have complained and griped and bitched and moaned that they want data.
Here's some data.
Here's the principles that are laid out in those dirts that started off the OSAP
program, that the baseline projections of what we know now and what we hope will
happen 50 years down the road.
And then it has examples, real life examples, solid UFO cases from government
files that were investigated and that remain really perplexing.
And each of those cases, Jim and Colm have really deftly used to demonstrate a
particular engineering principle, a physics principle, indicating that these
things are real, that they are beyond our capabilities.
They were certainly way beyond our capabilities when they happened and that
there's a genuine mystery here.
And it is, again, I think in very great detail demonstrates why this is a
legitimate topic for investigation, that there's real things to consider.
That there's physics and engineering, nuts and bolts, and case after case that
demonstrates that this is a legitimate inquiry.
That's my take on it.
Very good.
Totally agree, George.
I guess we're on the right track, George.
We're getting a double thumbs up here.
Look, guys, I really appreciate it.
I think if I take I have to kind of think about the people watching or listening to
this, if I could take one thing away other than reading your book, which I
suggest people do, but if I could take one thing away that really struck me, it
is the first time in history, I think, that we have somebody of your, Dr.
Lukatsky, of your kind of depth within the intelligence agency, the defense
intelligence agency, and within the UFO program that you ran for the defense
intelligence agency that stated, and I quote, the United States was in
possession of a craft of unknown origin and had successfully gained access to
its interior, so you personally know about a UFO that we got access inside of.
I have to assume, Dr.
Lukatsky, that you've seen this bad boy.
You don't got to answer me, but I'm going to make that assumption
unless you tell me otherwise.
You also say that this craft had a streamlined configuration suitable for
aerodynamic flight, but no intakes, exhaust wings or control surfaces.
So if I had to take something away from all of this, you just made the
admission that our government is reverse engineering.
If we got inside of it, we're reverse engineering UFOs.
You see, I'm not speaking at all.
I mean, I'm not going beyond what it was, what you read from the book.
Okay.
Well, thank you very much.
I do appreciate that you did put that in the book.
Look, we have Dr.
Eric Davis in the New York Times said craft, you know, not made here on earth.
There are individuals like you have come out and pushed the envelope a little bit.
And I thank you for that.
Even if you can't speak further from the book, that is a huge admission.
I mean, that'll be the title of the YouTube video.
I mean, that's a huge admission.
What do you think, George?
I'd also say this is that I know that people in UFO world will be
listening to this, pulling their hair out because Jim is very careful.
And what he says, the fact is that that is why that is a big reason why he's
been trusted with this information to start with, that he doesn't go blabbing
and talk and reveal things that he's not supposed to talk about.
And that's why I suspect he will continue to be trusted by our government.
And hopefully there's going to be a future investigation or maybe one
underway right now that he would be allowed to know about.
I know it does get frustrating that we have the hair split and dance around
certain of these cases and incidents and information, but.
You know, that's part of, of who he is and why he got that job.
You know, so it's, it's great always to talk with Jim on or off the record.
And with column, of course, they've helped me understand this big white world so much.
And even though they've shared things with me that I can't say publicly, it
has helped me so much in understanding who else is completely full of crap out there.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
Well, thank you guys so much.
I mean, you know, I think that with the limited things you can say, people
should read your book and start to understand a little bit more about what
OSAP did and how it did it, what the thought process was.
I do appreciate that.
And for, for, you know, just coming on the show and for help guiding, as George said,
you know, what, what he knows is sometimes BS just from kind of getting to understand
where you guys are coming from.
So thank you for all this.
Never have so few, have so much to tell, but could say so little.
Following this new weaponized presentation of Jeremy Corbell, George Knapp,
Dark Horse Entertainment, and Cadence 13 Studios available now for free on the
Odyssey app or wherever you get your shows.