what's up jesse michaels what's up danny jones like i just said to you bro you're gonna have
to pull me back into the believer make me a believer again because the more i learn
about ufos the more i am just out on this topic lately that's understandable and i'm
not here to bring you back i'm not an evangelist i do think damn it i'm sorry i do think if the
question is is the topic worthy of further investigation and is there something very
interesting at the bottom of all of this you know you get to the final room is there something
interesting going on my answer would be i think i think yes um but yeah not i don't want to
evangelize i think in many ways interest in ufos is maladaptive and a distraction for a lot of
people and doesn't make sense yes yes there's a lot of you got to cut through bro like not just
the if you want to talk about like psyop stuff like sure there's a lot of stuff you got to cut
through with that but then there's a whole nother layer of of people monetizing this there's a
business right yep like there's we're doing a podcast in a spaceship about ufos because my
audience loves ufos and i'm gonna make money talking about ufos half the books on that on
that shelf are about ufos so it's it's a huge business too yeah which muddies the water even
more yeah it totally muddies the water and it's it's a weird dynamic and i i think when you have
a topic that's kind of pointing at the sacred you know it's it might be the tip of the iceberg
it's not the rest of the iceberg like it's just an unidentified flying object is not necessarily
what you're going for i think a lot of people that are into it are like ultimately meaning
seekers and they want like a kind of a they want to understand the reality of religion they want
to understand metaphysics and so i think ufos are just a foray they're just one kind of route in but
i think combining that with money is a very weird thing i mean then it's like sort of the modern
modern catholic indulgences or something it doesn't doesn't really work right yeah totally
so we were just talking before we started rolling about that movie the adjustment bureau
and there's some crazy people like some deep dark secretive people in this whole ufo world that
aren't public that i guess we can talk about the guy right like he's a he's fully the reason i'm
scared to talk about this guy yeah is because my puck i say with chris bledsoe yeah completely got
nuked off youtube yeah do you should we tell this story because you told me some really interesting
stuff on a phone call i did yeah what did i tell you well you said that you said i don't care okay
cool um you said that uh the views were like you know it was like doing 50k a day oh yes and then
it cuts off yeah you speak to some rep at google and they're like we don't know what the hell
happened here doesn't make any sense given the click-through rate average view duration which
should basically define the video's performance he goes the one other time i've seen this is
with jesse's david grush video exactly performance fell off a cliff yep so and he said that he said
that my video with bledsoe and your video with grush neither of them broke any youtube rules or
had any internal red flags that he was able to see yep and he goes whenever this happens
which has happened one other time recently with david grush yep it's basically the floor above me
that i have no access to yep some something above my head that i don't know what the hell is going
on so what the hell is going on why are they why are they doing this erasing podcasts with
people who talk about getting abducted by aliens off of the internet i feel like they have way
bigger fish to fry you would think i i don't know um there's something very interesting about chris
bledsoe's story it's like why is you know jim semivan is very high up at the cia why is he
showing up at chris bledsoe's you know place in fayetteville north carolina when when he's you
know starts to kind of attract ufos he talks to the lady or whatever you know the whole story
he's definitely attracted the attention of some very interesting people you know we were just
talking about you know tim taylor yes that's the guy i would always mention pseudonymously he was
written about in this great book by dana pesolka religious studies professor called american
cosmic and then he was kind of doxed by chris bledsoe on your show actually right which i
thought that that might have been the reason that that video got completely blasted off the face of
youtube because of him talking about him right because if i'm that guy yeah and i have all these
connections that he allegedly has yeah i could probably make a call or send an email to somebody
youtube being like nuke this thing totally yeah well that's what and bledsoe even says in the
story that tim taylor gives him a whole brief about ufos and then he says you can't send this
to anybody and then he like sends the email or something to his wife or like i don't somebody
very close and immediately gets a call from tim being like knowing that he forwarded it yeah like
he fucked up yeah and so you know who knows if that's like a test and like you know they're
sort of being psyoped or you know i don't i think even bledsoe thinks that you know maybe he was
being messed with initially when he sort of entered his life and even when he was i think
he was giving him a tour of like kennedy space center oh yeah he said he said when you walk
through the security yeah when you walk past the security tower he goes just play a song in your
head yeah so they can't access your thoughts so they can't access your thoughts right yeah and
i asked him like what yeah i'm like who's in there yeah and he he was very he didn't know he's like
mind readers i don't know i don't know if they're aliens or humans but they they read your minds
and then he also said some that i'm like i don't even know if i want to say on camera but he like
say it danny he told me some stuff okay essentially i'll make it i'll dumb it down
so it's not too technical but he basically told me that this fella showed him
a real life men in black neuralyzer no way that wipes your memory no way this is what he told me
how can you know it's a neuralyzer we actually cut the segment out of the podcast because i
was like there's no way i'm putting this on the podcast it was like a five it was like a
10-minute chunk of that bledsoe podcast where he explains yeah everything about it how it works
where they got it from no way yeah bro why didn't they neuralyze him after they described
the whole thing that would seem like you would think they would want to do that right yeah but
like that is like essentially is like one of the explanations for the missing time stuff and he had
another story about like missing time where they were like walking through a forest yep i'm not
familiar with that one but like they were walking him and tim were walking through a forest with
somebody like looking for something and then all of a sudden that like they started over
whoa like they almost like started back to where they were an hour ago with like
like in an instant like almost it was like a loop like they looped through time or something
it's fascinating i don't know well i just you know we were talking earlier about i did a piece on
this guy thomas townsend brown who i think is just a fascinating character one of the best
documentaries i've ever seen thank you man is incredible appreciate that um yeah well he's
he's amazing he's uh i think like a forgotten hero in american history i think he made all
sorts of breakthroughs and in the world of gravity but in general relativity gravity and time are
related so the kind of subplot of his whole biography it's a great biography called the man
who mastered gravity by a guy named paul shatskin recommend you all read it um the subplot is that
he's obsessed with time travel he talks about time travel constantly with his wife josephine
his daughter linda and here's where it gets really weird uh apparently tim taylor told chris
bledsoe that he was part of a secret time travel group in nassau in the bahamas and the president
of that group was thomas townsend brown now i would think that was total i would dismiss that
out of hand i would be like that's you know that's sort of you know madness but i know from my own
research independent research on thomas townsend brown he spent a ton of time in nassau in the
bahamas and he was just extremely interested in time travel and it was he was spending a lot of
time with this guy william stevenson who was james bond's super spy or sorry he was the
inspiration for james bond he was winston churchill's super spy but he was you know
ian flumming's inspiration for james bond he's just like fascinating kind of he's you know
coordinating a lot with wild bill donovan early oss or late oss you know early cia involved in
the formation of the cia was working out of the rockefeller center in new york and kind of calling
a lot of interesting shots as you know almost part of like a shadow government if you will so
he's close with thomas townsend brown there in the bahamas a lot and then you have you know ryan
bloodsoe saying that tim taylor told his father that he's part of the secret time travel group
with thomas townsend brown just very very interesting and then and then you you know we
were talking about this before the show you said uh you know that tim taylor told chris bloodsoe
that the adjustment bureau was like you know yeah his life or whatever and that's all about like
changing one little variable like it's like if i were to freeze this room and like i don't know
move your mic like a little bit right and you get this butterfly butterfly effect style multiplicative
effect down the line or whatever of like you know changing timelines it's madness it sounds kind of
crazy madness science fiction it is sci-fi and i'm not proposing that that's you know a real thing
but it it is fascinating that there are some connections there and then the final thing the
final connection i made is townsend brown's daughter uh is a an amazing woman uh she was
in the documentary right she's in the documentary on the phone call and her name's linda brown but
it was linda leach uh for a while and she has an amazon review on tim taylor's biography tim
taylor's biography is called launch fever and i think he wrote 2003 2004 right and in 20
12 or 13 or 14 like early well before diana pusulka even pseudonymously published about tim taylor
under the pseudonym tyler in american cosmic in 2018 linda leach is writing a review on launch
fever saying this is you know wonderful homage to you know the the space program or whatever so
clearly there's a connection between townsend brown and tim taylor which is that's it's pretty
interesting yeah yeah so you have this mid-century inventor who i i think i mean at the very least
like we have an fbi file on thomas townsend brown saying he was the the lead radar scientist
in the entire navy like this guy's a real guy you can say he didn't crack anti-gravity that's
fine i'm like totally open to that like you have to think probabilistically around that i have a
lot of evidence that he did you can but you say he didn't do that or whatever he's like a very
real guy and he's talking about time travel constantly and then there's this really interesting
connection with a modern nasa mission controller i don't know i don't understand it yeah going to
the like the adjustment bureau comment that he made do you think that there's a thing that happens
to people and i wouldn't know because i don't have the personal experience but do you think
it's possible there's something that happens to somebody or certain individuals when they have
tons of super super top secret information that they have and nobody else has where they sort of
feel like their life is for lack of a better term they're living the da vinci code
and they sort of like fall into that and they sort of like look through their entire life at that
through that lens right like like i am living i am living this movie or like i am the superhero
character because i hold these secrets that like literally would change the power balance of the
world if i let them out yeah i wonder what that does to your brain you know what i mean i want i
do wonder that as well and then i wonder how much of it is like human clearance systems versus like
have you ever experienced synchronicities in your life oh all the time popping up showing up like
really in really cool interesting fun way so maybe there are people that are more tapped into that
in a and sort of a weird way you know that's what this guy tries to do right he's trying to tap into
this this other thing he's trying to get these downloads that she's in her new book she talks
about like yeah all these diana pusulka in her new i forget the name of her new book she taught
in that one she talks about encounters yeah that's great awesome book um about diana shout out to
diana um all these protocols that he goes through every day by not drinking coffee
yep and like going outside getting sunlight and all this stuff in the morning and like
trying to download some sort of cosmic shit so we can make more patents yeah it sounds so
and wild and like you know i don't i don't know what to say about it um i think that's more how
thinking works than the average person realize it you know i'm a big fan of the transmission
theory of consciousness i don't when you're daydreaming you're not actively producing those
thoughts right it's like you're like you're like a receptacle for the thoughts and uh so i think
it's just like it's an important kind of epistemological question is are we locally
producing the content in our minds or are we somehow downloading them from elsewhere yeah sure
i think that is probably going to be proven by some sort of you know scientific model of the
future right now electromagnetism as we know it decays over and attenuates over spacetime so we
don't have a good model for like how that transmission might occur you know like neutrino
information transfer but uh increasingly in vogue is this extended electrodynamics model which
uh you know nasa and uh not the doe the national science foundation nasa just launched this podcast
and like how put off and all these interesting like kind of figures in ufo world but also
with some pretty impressive bona fides just in science as well uh you got a former skunkworks guy
you know um some navy scientists all righty fellas it's time to talk about personal grooming
which is not just about looking good it's about feeling good whether it's gearing up for a meeting
getting ready to go on a date or just preparing for the day the right tools make all the difference
take care of your skin and skip the cuts and irritation meet the beard and balls bundle from
manscaped your all-in-one grooming solution to keep you polished from head to toe or more
precisely from beard to balls and let's be real no one wants to look like they just lost a battle
with a weed whacker that's where the beard hedger comes in with 20 adjustable settings you have
total control over your beard whether it's the rugged stubble look or the lumberjack masterpiece
one tool all the lengths you don't need a ton of tools to get it right and what about below the
belt that's where the lawnmower 5.0 ultra shines literally it's got an led spotlight so you're not
fumbling around in the dark plus you can swap between a foil and trimmer say goodbye to nicks
tugs and that awkward why did i do this to myself feeling with their skin safe technology both
devices are completely waterproof meaning you can handle your business in the shower and with over
an hour of battery life you won't be going to work half done with a 30-day money back guarantee
why not so do yourself and everyone who has to look at you a favor don't cut corners on your
grooming routine upgrade to the beard and balls bundle with manscaped visit manscaped.com and
use my code danny jones to get 20 off plus free shipping whether you're suiting up for work
heading out for a night on the town or just relaxing at home manscaped has everything you
need to stay sharp from face to balls again visit manscaped.com and use the code danny jones to get
20% off plus free shipping and thank you manscaped for sponsoring the show and they're all
speaking about extended electrodynamics and this is basically a model that involves a scalar field
so unlike classical electrodynamics you don't get the attenuation over space time so you can have
you can have it basically in classical electrodynamics you just have one electromagnetic
wave a transverse hertzian wave so you have a magnetic field an electric field and wave
propagation and all three are perpendicular to one another and so because of that you get this
attenuation you get electrons pairing off you know and you know you get this decay function on
the signal but in the scalar field you can get like scalar longitudinal waves you get all these
interesting wave types and you don't get the same decay and so maybe we are downloading thoughts
via one of these sort of scalar field waves that would just be one thought experiment i don't know
right but i do think something like that will get proven out just given the phenomenology of thought
or invention where like a wheel pops up in africa at the same time as south america yes this this
you look at the phenomenology of science it looks way more like revelation than it does like
mechanics or something it looks like something's popping into the person's head every single time
whether it's dirac staring at the fire at cambridge coming up with the dirac equation or einstein at
his desk as a patent clerk like it literally it's the exception to the rule is like i just finished
the equation on the whiteboard no you're like in the shower you're like uh there's so many examples
so yeah i think you know heisenberg at helgoland you know making all these downloads about you know
how how you know electrons make quantum leaps and you know electron cloud like it's just it's sort
of constant so i so tim taylor saying that it's like yeah i think that's real but and then and
then i don't know it's hard to sift through some of the other quackiness i'm not i don't want to
endorse any of the stuff that he says it's definitively real but it's interesting he seems
like the most i mean it's because he's so elusive i think is making it makes him so interesting
yes you know especially the way she talks about some of the stuff that he was involved with like
like you've met the dude right yeah i had it i had like a 20 minute call with him really yeah how did
that come about uh i can't say because i will say anything on any podcast i'll always be public but
i want to protect sources yeah sources exactly i just don't want to like burn relationships sure
can you tell what you talked about him with what you talked about with him um yeah well
the impetus on my end so i always i invest um and i'm the venture capitalist steven did you
leave your phone out we gotta put our phones out there we got palantir in the building bro we can't
let all our info get sucked out of here dude he's a palantir honey trap jesse michaels i i am i am
not i am not you're furthering the internet bullshit daddy come on man just kidding just kidding but
no you you uh what you talked about on julian dory's podcast a great podcast you guys went
into like your whole background into investing and how you you're invest basically you invest
peter teal's money exactly yeah love julian great guy and um yeah so i worked at the the family
office for for a long amount of time and even even now um i still have a contract with them and
i do investing and uh but i mainly focus on the show it's like right 90 95 show at this point
um but uh yeah so one of the companies that i was invested in was uh you know a rocket company
and they were struggling rocket rocket trees incredibly hard it's it's uh it's got a very
high failure rate yeah yeah yeah it's it's it's absurd i mean the amount of you're talking about
like thousands of sub components and like you know one thing fails and you get this chain reaction
the whole thing screws up so uh we had had a you know a couple of failures and i always try to keep
my um you know uh investment stuff and uh you know the the the quacky stuff that i'm into
i always try to keep those separate um for for for many reasons but i'm kind of scraping the
bottom of the barrel as far as you know it's like oh we're struggling to get off the ground
and i know a startup rocket company yeah it's a startup rocket company yeah yeah and so i know
about um you know uh tim taylor being this nasa mission controller he uses consciousness
protocols to get rockets off the ground and i also know about the history of rocketry where it's like
jack parson's the you know founder of jpl and like basically the american rocket program
or tchaikovsky the equivalent in uh russia or warner von braun like all of these guys believed
in versions of this so i'm scraping the bottom of the barrel that's so crazy yeah i basically
like in my you know in putting my investment hat on i'm like i'm a materialist reductionist
like i don't want to bring the woo-woo stuff in but again it's you know i i'm like if i have
access to this guy i gotta you know find a way to meet him pretend or pretend i'm not interested in
ufos yeah yeah yeah exactly exactly yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah well yeah i actually that
was literally the impetus actually was like helping on the rocket stuff so it actually
wasn't as much like sure the ufo thing right and so yeah we spoke and he said some interesting
stuff he was like he's you know most of it was actually kind of very like like kind of platitudes
around the american cosmic style stuff like you know use these protocols and tap in and like don't
use your phone i was like i already read that in the you know book that basulka you know published
but thank you and then um he was also like look if you want the rocket to work you know maybe you
have to get aligned with what they want and i was like who is it they yeah like the non-human
intelligence he said this to you knowing that you weren't you didn't bring you didn't bring the
first he brought it up first no i i brought it i oh i didn't bring i bring it didn't bring up
non-human intelligence first he was the one yeah yeah yeah yeah i know i i just asked questions
about rocket bless you bless you i just i just i just bless you i just i was just asking questions
about the rocket and getting it to work yeah yeah and so did you ask did you follow up on
that when he was like they did you ask who they were i don't remember exactly i mean i'm sure i
did um and i'm sure i was sure that when he said they he was talking about non-human intelligence
either due to a follow-up question that i asked or something he made that kind of clear so yeah
i don't know what to make of this stuff man i mean he even said like apparently like
he knows elon right he has to know elon he works for elon and at spacex and like watches the rockets
and supposedly is part of nr o where they have to like watch everything that happens around the
rocket with the satellites and drones or whatever i i think so i don't i don't know you know i've
heard that and um pusulkas tweeted that and but yeah i think he does work occasionally with with
elon i know he works on some i think you know some serious launches he also works at aerospace
corporation which is a very interesting company um so they're sort of like remind me what that
one is they're like a i think they're kind of like a think tank they have like 5 000 employees
split between virginia and you know fairfax area and i think that yeah they show up in interesting
places around the question for sure aerospace corporation yep yeah yeah i don't know like my
world got turned upside down when when when which i talk about it at nauseam on this show but like
when bledsoe came in here and talked about this stuff and then after recently after that i became
aware of the mirage man documentary yeah which flipped my world upside down again yeah yeah yeah
and i've been looking at this whole topic through that lens yeah ever since then sure and it really
makes a ton of sense yep well there yeah i mean that's an example of like should we like talk
about so so this guy paul benowitz is outside kirtland air force base he sees this like
vertical takeoff and landing occur of probably some exotic you know craft or whatever which
to me doesn't mean look away it's like what is that what's the initial thing you saw
and then rick dotty who's an air force office special investigations officer enters into his
life and kind of drives him crazy and he ends up committing suicide he's driven in a psychiatric
hospitalization he's told that he's communicating with aliens via these
signals across the street beaming into his house right telling him they're aliens that are like
running out of gas on their planet and they're on their way here yep yep yeah so pretty pretty
nuts so now like so so after watching the documentary and learning the story this guy
paul benowitz and seeing how this this world really works behind the scenes like i have to
just assume that most of this stuff that is going on is just super secret military technology and
there's a huge apparatus and bureaucracy of people behind the scenes that are just involved in
making information murkier right and like what they were doing with paul if i understand it
correctly was they were because he was in the ufo field he was part of mufon and all this stuff
so they were trying to use him as a conduit of disinfo to poison the well yep and tried and
because they knew there was also russian spies in the ufo community out west so they thought
okay we can just throw a couple curveballs through paul benowitz it'll throw off the russians and
they won't know what we really have going on yeah so now i look at people like in the media today
like and i don't i'm you're gonna have to explain this up to me better but like people like crush
people like all these whistleblowers yeah people like uh bledsoe like okay is he paul benowitz is
he a paul benowitz is he a paul but the thing with bledsoe is like there's like cia people nsa
people inaru people saw like the guy uh that he talked about that mapped the moon for the
apollo missions was like visiting him and like befriending him right and telling him all this
secret stuff yep and then like god dude it's just it's too much yeah it's extremely confusing i mean
here's what i would say that seems like a massive waste of resource like to what end
right why why why are you why are you um getting all these kind of super high up guys at nasa cia
to visit this guy driving to north carolina from from the middle of florida so but that points
to there being some real like proto architecture underneath like there's a different you can try
to you can attempt to manipulate or like shade a thing differently and by the way i'm not saying
i have no evidence that this at all happened right and for example bledsoe's case um and he
seems like a really earnest good guy to me and i'm hopefully can go he is very very sweet sweet guy
yeah yeah um but as his daughter she was she was in here with him when he came in awesome yeah
their whole family seems really cool um but i think you can have an experience and you can shade that
experience differently versus like you didn't experience anything to begin with because it's
like why are you spending all this like manpower and resources you know like yeah it's like this
huge waste of resources otherwise and so if it's all passage material or all some honey trap or
like i just that feels like a little crazy to me and then you have all this you have like so you
have to think probabilistically with all this stuff sure so like there's the stuff where the
adjustment like the crazy stuff like to me i hold that extremely loosely i catalog it as very low
probability and i'll look for corroboration in the future for it but like if you're like do you
believe that's definitely a thing i know i don't have no idea right right but then you have things
like you have this book called ufos and nukes by a guy named robert hastings and he documented
we've talked about this he documents 167 queue cleared icbm security personnel radar operators
guys that most psychologically sound people in the military right they're on the prp program
the personal reliability program where they have to report if they're taking ibuprofen or tylenol
they inherently have to be the the the paradigm of a sound mind because you're guarding the crown
jewels like you would never let you know crazy person right next to a nuke right right um and
and in certain cases they have their finger on the button uh and so uh all these guys see tic tacs
saucers orbs often they're messing with comms links shutting down the nukes rendering them
inoperable in the case of you know malmstrom 67 robert solace um uh in you know 64 vandenberg
you have a nuke wrapping around an atlas 5 dummy missile and taking it out of the sky
and then you have air force office of special investigations people like rick doty in fact
rick doty is literally one of these people who shows up with this guy mario woods at elsworth
air force base in 1977 and swearing them to secrecy and saying you never talk about this
again and and demoting them in cases where they do come out when they speak to robert hastings
robert hastings getting threatening phone calls and so to me if you were to you know like you
have to think about everything is like a database and it's like okay there's one thing if you have
like the you know national ufo reporting center or move on it's another thing if you have this
you know database that which i would call ufos and nukes of these inherently very credible people
coming forward saying they've seen things yes and then did you know sleeping less than six
hours per night nearly doubles your risk of death poor sleep is also linked to obesity heart disease
high blood pressure diabetes depression and weakened immune system i've struggled with sleep
for a while and i'm not alone the cdc reports over 35 percent of adults in the u.s sleep less
than the recommended seven hours many sleep supplements contain melatonin and other ingredients
that create dependencies cause morning grogginess and lose their effectiveness over time and that
is why i take evening being by verso after three years of perfecting the formula they created a
melatonin free drink mix with clinically studied patented ingredients it's formulated to an active
mind helps you fall asleep faster stay asleep longer and improves deep and REM sleep without
creating dependencies or causing morning grogginess i look forward to my evening being nightcap every
night now and it's become a staple in my nightly routine because it not only helps me stay asleep
longer fall asleep faster but i wake up with far more energy i hop out of bed quicker and in a
better mood and it tastes great which is why it's become my new nightcap click the link in the
description or head on over to ver.so slash danny and use my coupon code danny at checkout to save
15% off your first order again hit the link in the description or head on over to ver.so slash
danny and use the code danny at checkout to save 15% off your first order and thank you verso for
sponsoring the show you could say oh okay well it's just some u.s deep state cabal thing like
okay maybe but the even then your null hypothesis gets pretty fantastical and weird if that's what
you're saying but then you look at fukushima leno which is a town right next to fukushima
next to the pre-fracture where they have their civilian energy nuclear energy grid and they've
had it there since the 70s they're famous for their nuclear spill in 2011 right and in the 90s they
built a museum dedicated to ufos and vice did a documentary about how obsessed the townspeople
are with ufos and it's probably due to the nuclear energy presence and you have a famous
case in bariloche argentina where they have their civilian civilian nuclear grid where you know a
commercial pilot sees a ufo and you have stories around ternobyl and so this nuclear connection
is extremely important then you hear about ufos basically being bound up within nuclear secrecy
and betel memorial institute being you know very big part of ufo research you look at the special
definition of nuclear material under the atomic energy commission which was in 1954 and it's
basically any material with emitting any sort of radiation so alpha beta gamma radio anything
is born secret and it's restricted data meaning that you don't even have to fall under the direct
clearances of government if you are a private aerospace corporation and you pick this stuff up
it is restricted for you too so it's like born classified so you have all this evidence that
there's this kind of like doe atomic research ufo thing that's been going on for for very long time
and i think that's where you have to start this coherent picture and then yeah there's psyops
there's weird shit but i think what people don't understand is that um if there are psyops around
a thing it means the thing is more likely to be real how many oh sure how many big foot psyops do
you know none yeah because nobody would fucking believe it right psyops are 95 true and five
percent false and the five percent that's false matters a ton because it throws you entirely off
the trail it's it's 95 true yes five percent false yes oh really that's what people don't
understand about psyops they think they thought it was the opposite that's sure they think that
it's 95 false but you you dismiss it out of hand if it was 95 false you'd be like oh it's big foot
fuck them i don't i'm not gonna believe that ufos are standard deviations more charismatic than any
other if it's the psyop well big foot's big foot's more more believable than a fucking alien coming
here from another universe right it's a hominid there's a big hominid right right right which is
why and i i actually i'm i'm more in the like joc valet dina pusulka line of thinking where i
don't think you know little green men from zeta reticuli is the answer to like what we're seeing
in in you know the airspace shout out to mike masters shout to mike masters yeah i love mike
man and he does some really important work my favorite he's amazing yeah and he's he's great
because he's he's thinking about this stuff inductively most people don't realize they're
bringing priors into thinking about ufos that deal with movies they've seen and that zeitgeist and
culture and so they're not looking at the phenomena ground up first principles and he is and that's
why mike masters is amazing yep and people should definitely follow him yeah but that's what people
don't so the psi just i think i think is a really important point um if if there are psyops around a
thing it's more likely to be real and then if ufos are real there are going to be psyops around it
obviously if you have this like core important truth they're going to be psyops around it yeah
if you're talking about the nature of reality obviously and but it's ephemeral and hard to
detect and it's like this thing that happens only to certain people of course you're going
to co-op that manipulate it for narratives and you're going to have all these competing
factions trying to like overlay their narratives on top of the thing yeah so these things are
psyop or real is positive sum it's not zero sum the fact that it's real means there's going to be
a psyop the fact that there's a psyop probably means there's an element of reality too why would
why else would they invest manpower into it why would they invest so much manpower at the highest
levels right and so that's i think people don't get that and they're they snap it to grid they're
like this is a psyop or this is real and it's like no there are psyops and it's real it's the same
it's both and that makes it really interesting yes and worthy of investigation everybody should
think for themselves and you should distrust anybody who's saying it's definitely this
that's why the the um the bob lazar story is so interesting to me and it stays interesting
because like the more we learn about the more we learn about the psychological warfare and the
counterintelligence stuff like in this current ufo state we're in the more light it shines on
the bob lazar story in what was it 1980 or something 1990 what was it 87 87 yep so like
apparently he was the guy who first came to area 51 blew the whistle in area 51
but then i think this this was all part of your um documentary was this a part of your towns and
brown documentary it was yeah yeah so like i think one of the questions you ask in the towns and
brown document which was which was brilliant was why would the cia let a guy come in who has this
crazy history yep right he i think and another thing that happened was i think he like recently
gotten a divorce with with his previous wife who then like killed herself i didn't know that she
she she like went in her car in her garage and let her car run until like she suffocated
this was like a week after they got a divorce oh no i think bob also owned a strip club in vegas
yeah i know that yeah yeah he did and then what were they were i think a brothel not not just
oh it was a brothel yeah yeah yeah and a brothel so the cia is gonna go out and find it and to
think they're not gonna do a background check and find that kind of stuff if it's the cia at their
most top secret facility on in america well you've seen oppenheimer right yeah so you remember
that leslie matt damon's character leslie groves yes who's running basically the the entire matt
and hatton project from like a national security standpoint and he says i didn't hire uh uh
oppenheimer in spite of his socialist sympathies i hired him because of them and so you hire you
hire people when it comes to some of these more secret programs sometimes if they do have
compromise on them because they're more easily controllable so that wouldn't necessarily cut
against so the whole bob lazar story for them that's an argument for them hiring him okay
but and discrediting him if he ever decides to spill the beans yeah and there's there's even a
so what i was saying in that documentary is john leer is a cia cargo pilot cargo jet pilot or
whatever right uh and the the the son of bill lear who created the first uh you know a business uh
basically private jet in the in the u.s who's known as the autopilot wizard and actually worked
with thomas towns and brown who comes from this like aerospace like you know dynasty right and he
yeah affiliated with the cia and says he disaffiliated in 83 but definitely was still
flying cargo jets for them like into the mid 80s at least so my question is like you know we we
kind of know that if there is a ufo program it's being run partially by the cia and the cia has a
part in it and so if you're the cia why do you continue unless you're extremely dysfunctional
and not coordinated why do you continue to pay this guy you know he's flying cargo jets for you
if he's leaking your most vital important secrets because john leer put all of the files around bob
lazar on george napp's desk he broke the story yeah so why would you pay a guy who's leaking your
you know your crown jewel secrets so that that's one question and then john leer also had a ufo
blog before and was friends with bob lazar and there's some story that bob lazar says all this
ufo stuff's crazy and wacky and bullshit before he gets hired by area 51 and s4 but the question
stands why would you hire bob lazar to your top secret ufo reverse engineering program if
your good friend or his good friend john leer was a babbling ufo nut who has a ufo blog
like you'd obviously find that in a background check right yeah so like
there's a lot to me that points to the cia wanting the bob lazar story out again that doesn't mean
the details of the bob lazar story are not incredibly interesting and maybe it's 95
true and 5 false and maybe this billy meyers sports model that he worked on was real i don't
know maybe gravity a and gravity b are high level frameworks that if you are working on a secret ufo
program you need some initiate you know stem student to start to develop an entry an interest
in but you need to protect this from getting into adversary hands so you put it out through these
kind of this quacky person who is discreditable in bob lazar and so it's kind of this limited
hangout of a person where you can always retract it you can always point to you know you say faked
is mit you know educational credentials yeah and you could say you'd say all this stuff about
bob you say the the the brothel thing but maybe there are elements of it that you know are are
very real so i think it's this incredibly intriguing story and what i want to be clear
about is i think like the corbell and george napp reporting on it are awesome like i think it's
we should be looking into this stuff but to me if you're not thinking about it through a
a meta lens of like the cia probably wanted elements of this out i think you're losing the plot
you know i think you're going to fall for your you can't take the thing at face value you need
to understand that it's being pushed for some reason and i think there's even a john lear
interview where i believe he says a guy named i think it was like an admiral mcclellan he says
that this guy who was part of like legacy ufo efforts told him that he needed to leak the
lazar story because he knew that it was discreditable but that there were it was mostly true but also
discreditable and so there's there's literally a lear interview because lear was clearly kind
of unhinged and a little you know crazy himself where he's just saying what i'm telling you now
which is that the lazar story again there could be elements of truth but it was put out because
it was discreditable and i think that's the way a lot of this stuff works so what was the benefit
of putting it out was it to recruit new talent was it tons it's it's yeah so it's like if you
want to throw the adversary off the trail or like keep things fundamentally protected but have
initiates you know develop intrigue and want to be recruited or whatever like it's like the perfect
way to do it yeah so it's like tech protection it's adversary signaling it's recruitment it's
increasing the surface area it's if you expect a leak in the future you can manage that leak
because you're like conditioning people and like softening the blow for something you expect to
leak in the future anyways there's so many reasons to get in front of and do something
like that and ben rich who was you know president of of lockheed skunkworks you know their most
secretive you know advanced aerospace aircraft division at the time responsible for you know
the sr-71 and you know you too he was complaining at the time how he was basically saying like
you know i have to spend tons and tons of money on tech protection because the f-117a which was
their first stealth fighter had just crashed in bakersfield in 1986 lear actually established
credibility with klas with george napp's you know news station by giving them information on that
f-117a oh wow yeah so there's some interesting ties there the the final thing is john lear
and jim goodall his buddy had been camping outside of area 51 for the better part of a decade
taking pictures of all these advanced recon stealth craft and so the security knew him
they know they all knew who he was so it's like if he's leaking stuff it's probably for a reason
and so i think you know people like ben rich were smart really smart he used to get ben rich used
to call ufos unfunded opportunities and i think you know he was kind of using john lear to those
ends if that makes sense again i don't know if you have to throw the baby out with the bath water and
say that we're not you know reverse engineering ufos and in sort of you know secret compartments
of the government but that's the way you i think you need that meta lens to look at it through if
that makes sense and on my list on my on top of my to-do list is read the book that jock
fillet wrote about this stuff where he talks about bob lozare drinking something weird or something
like that yeah messengers of deception jock fillet jock fillet is always i've had a bunch of
conversation i love that guy you know french godfather of ufos right and he's always thought
bob lozare was like just completely full of shit which which i do i think there are more elements
of truth to it and there's actually a great movie coming out about bob lozare by my buddy luigi and
it's called project gravatar and i do think it's actually going to corroborate that lozare probably
was at area 51 i just yeah and then he's working on it with lozare he's working on it with lozare
yeah it's gonna be epic it's gonna be really awesome but yeah so in messengers of deception
uh jock fillet says you know uh and what about the the the liquid that that bob lozare said he was
you know meant to drink or whatever and the memory lapses that it caused and immediately my mind goes
to mk ultra and i'm like yeah you know and and and i i lozare admits that and i think he's admitted
it to luigi and he'll tell you know he'll talk about this that the fact that they like made him
drink a weird liquid and he'll forget certain things and so something kind of you know weird
going on there i don't know i don't know what it is a psyop wrapped in a mystery wrapped in another
psyop wrapped in some sort of strategic deception i love what annie jacobson says in her book about
when they're first flying the first jet planes out of out of uh air 51 he the cia pilots had to bring
gorilla masks in the cockpit oh remember that no because in case because the cia pilots when
they were flying those first jet planes in case they came in visual distance of a civilian airplane
yeah they had to put on the gorilla masks no way how crazy is that that's crazy that's my
favorite one oh that's so fast is that an area 51 that's an area 51 yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah you
spent a lot of time with jock fillet right you guys you guys are did you live you lived close to
him or no you used to live closer to la right yeah i lived in la for most of my life and um
no i just whenever we're in the same city i try to hit him up and visit him and um he's amazing
he's just a very very deep thinker yeah and they're clearly a lot of layers to his understanding of
the ufo a lot of layers the most interesting thing to me and i'm interested to hear your
thoughts on this was in diana's book she talks about him being obsessed with angels and demons
yes and this medieval spiritual stuff right oh yeah and she says that he gave her a book about
the devil uh-huh with 666 pages and he said to her if you want to understand this stuff
read the book about the devil what the hell i don't know what to make of that i don't think
diana did either when i asked her i'm like did you read the book she goes no can't find it
you lost it um no he didn't give it to her he just like showed her the book okay okay got it got it
yeah um i don't know man i mean i will say what you know you know the concept of lindy
so it's this idea that the current age of something should define its expected survival in
the future so really old things are very durable and are probably more true or right or like you
know yeah just valid um so like the bible very lindy play-doh very lindy you know modern
architecture or you know i don't know the museum of ice cream not lindy you know like right and so
okay um i would say that really applies to the ufo question whatever we are seeing now is probably
what we've historically seen forever and that's what jock valet's book passport to megonia touches
on it's like you know celtic medieval you know fairies and leprechauns and you know angels and
demons and you know passports and megonias it's based on the denizens of megonia and medieval
france it's probably what we're seeing today and they almost pattern match one to one in terms of
you know the actual story it's like somebody comes down there's missing time involved there's
sometimes implants and physical marks there's healings but people also freak out and sometimes
they get sick afterwards it's uh it's it's just very common and so i think
when you get into the religious stuff a modern scientist would say oh that's crazy or whatever
but if you treat that as a real phenomenology in the past if you treat you know like diana
posolka has in her book saint francis of assisi you know experience on mount laverne in 13th
century italy if you treat that as a historical artifact which i think you should then i think a
lot of these things were just ufos now where it gets weird is like then you say oh ufos are
just angels and demons like so many people say that and then you just you give them one more
question you say tucker carlson says that more oh he says it more than anybody and and you know
i'm a fan of tucker's but like then you ask any you ask tucker ask anybody then you say what's
an angel what's a demon they'll have no idea they'll be like i don't know what are you talking about
you know and so yeah there you go yeah yeah that's that's what i'll say by the way love that
fucking podcast you did with with alex jones oh thank you amazing one of your original ones
one of the og yeah yeah he he's hilarious man i love alex jones he's so funny dude that was
that was pure entertainment it was pure was so fun with painting rocks painting rocks with alex
jones well we did this thing in in austin and like at like info wars hq and he had covid and he gave
me covid what yeah so i share some genetics with oh my god and and it was just i don't know it was
fun we shot guns and stuff but the vibe was like a little off and then my friend reva she was like
in la at the time and he was coming into la and she was like we gotta just make it gonzo weird
and funny and we got to paint rocks she bought all these board games and stuff and it was just
lighten the mood it was awesome it was so funny there it is what is the title of it isn't it like
painting rocks with alex jones yeah getting drunk and painting rocks and he just said that's such an
og vice title yeah exactly it felt like very vice it felt like just i feel like your stuff is very
vice too like you have a lot of episodes like that but yeah he's just like oh man he's such he's so
fun to spend time he spent he looks so he looks like he said he would be such fun to hang out with
he's so fun he spent that whole day at my house and i gave him all these books and it was just
such a good fun vibe what were you guys drinking i think tequila tequila yeah yeah and he went he
was going oh he's he go yeah i know what he's saying right now he goes he this is so weird he
goes uh i didn't have a sexual desire for my for my mother but when i look at her
what oh my god when i look at her you know she's so beautiful and then i'll be like alex you are
crazy but dude he is he is such a smart dude he's actually extremely smart he's such a smart dude
yeah but like i like he the thing about alex jones that people a lot of people don't realize
is that he throws so many so much shit at the wall yeah there's the whole there's the there's the
meme right like alex jones always like he gets stuff right over time yeah he's like the difference
between conspiracy theory and the truth is six months you know alex jones was right again yeah
but like if you saw the volume of shit that he says yeah you would realize how much he actually
doesn't get right he does he does get a ton of shit right so much survivorship bias he's constantly
just throwing shit out there right of course he's going to predict something right yeah you know the
911 stuff is crazy how he predict like literally called out that al-qaeda was going to fly planes
in the tower on air it goes on osama specifically it's wild that is fucking it's why i think he's
like i think he's tapped in it goes back to our conversation on consciousness i feel like he's
like a a bit of a prophet he's like one of these people it's like a generically magnified receptor
and like i think he's like an antenna he's like an antenna and a lot of bad shit gloms onto him
he's like kanye too where it's like so much bad stuff gloms onto kanye and then so much good too
and like i think that's where people like don't understand somebody like him he's he can be so
wildly wrong when he's wrong yeah but when he's right it's like nobody else was right like it's
like a download that he got that was so prophetic it's so like out of his time it's really amazing
yeah and it's almost like you have to you have to be able to get rid of that filter
yeah for that stuff to happen because if you have that filter and you're like constantly like
sitting and mulling on things before you talk about them or before you claim them whatever it
is it's like automatically that is that is like you're not going to have that superpower but if
you don't have the filter built in at all yeah and you're just constantly just coming in and
it's going out it's flowing through you yeah then it's like you're more tapped in somehow and i
see yeah it's totally it's definitely you can see that with yeah it's like it's like automatic
writing where like you like you get the first like page you write is like contrives it's coming
from your like prefrontal cortex like this intellectual thing and then boom you get into
the flow and you're on autopilot and something's coming through you and the muse is you're tapping
in the muses yes and yeah i agree you can't have the filter and i think and that's why i get so
that's that's the double-edged sword that you have to be okay with you have to be okay with it and
you have to be discerning it's condescending to an audience to say i'm going to a priori conceal
you from this entire thing instead of i'm going to let you think for yourself and there's a lot
that this guy says is completely quacky and wrong and there's a lot that's super right and like but
we're not going to like you're not going to be like bubble boy and bubble girl who they you know
like like like like siphon you off from like this like you know really important you know possible
you know slivers of information that are really important yeah golden nuggets yeah totally
where where we're going before we start talking about how did we get to alice oh demons yeah i
said hillary hillary clinton yeah yeah yeah yeah oh you know you're talking about jock valet saying
jock valet i mean if you get into like there's like a gnostic three line in thinking about ufos so
like you're familiar with gnosticism yeah yes gnosticism yeah yeah i'm familiar with it so like
you know the idea that these are like arcani you know uh protectors or tricksters protectors
of the material world but that you know that there's like a you know there's like a demiurge
that you know runs the material world and that's like a lower god and then there's like a higher
god and this is not something i would fully subscribe to i think they're too anti i think
the material world's very special and we can learn all these amazing things from it i also
think there's higher stuff going on yeah so i'd say i'm more like i don't know like a neoplatonist
or something but there's definitely some gnostic thought and through lines in this world and like
i think that is one lens you can overlay the whole ufo question with but as to you know i don't know
yeah super into fallen angels and he's interested in demons and i don't i can't quite you know
explain that well the demon thing is interesting when you look at the virginia brazil case yeah
the thing that smelled like sulfur and they call it the three women they go it's like what's like
a demon you know it's yeah smelled like a demon had horns and eyes like a demon uh-huh and killed a
guy uh-huh uh-huh yeah no totally some of these things pattern or even the rumors of roswell
there's a cia liaison named chase brandon who wrote a book called cryptos conundrum
and the the alien being that comes out of roswell and i think there's some true stuff that
do you think we really have a being that came out of roswell i again i would say low probability
high probability that roswell happened something there was a crash there and then lower probability
that there was a being i don't know what i'd you know maybe lower probability that there's
50 ish percent but i at decently high there's a so many towns people at roswell like something
happened here beings came out edgar mitchell who i know this is going to kind of muddy the waters
because he was you know an apollo 14 astronaut who then got really interested in consciousness
and aliens you know this trip on the way back to the moon he almost this conversion experience
he was from roswell and it's like an open secret there that something happened um and then the
beings i would rank as lower probability than like the memory medal that jesse marcel this air force
flight surgeon i think definitely collected and i think it did make it to right right airfield the
tritium tritium what is the word for that metal the trit trit tritium or night tritium tritium
no not tritium it was like uh it was like there was a crazy uh medal that there was a name a word
a name for it where it would bend and go back to its original shape oh you're talking about the
um titanium nickel alloy that so there's a contract between uh right airfield and
memorial institute right from 1949 that my buddy the gerb video uap gerb everybody check out his
channel shout out to gerb amazing researcher he's you should have him on he's awesome um
yeah so there's this titanium and i think it's a uh nick i don't know it's a crazy word it's an
yeah i don't know but it's it's titanium nickel alloy yes yeah tritium nickel alloy and that's
there's evidence that we that we have that we have that well we definitely have that that was
declassified as a material that we have in 1961 then you have to ask the question why does betel
memorial institute that runs all of our nuclear stuff have a contract with right airfield where
the roswell materials were yeah nitinol no no that's what it was that's the word yep so so that
they have a contract to study this stuff between right airfield and betel memorial institute in
1949 again there's the nuclear connection and then i think in 61 or 62 it comes out that
nitinol is a thing but why are you keeping it secret for 12 years and then nitinol is really
interesting because it exactly patterned so jesse marcel this air force flight surgeon he comes out
later in 1979 i think saying you know actually i was like forced to pose with this you know fake
material and you know and the project mogul comes out later the air force says that you know it was
just a weather balloon or whatever but actually it was this kind of you know memory metal that
was like extremely very uh durable and like you could you could apply a lot of stress to it and
it would kind of like uh it had like shape memory it would go it would go back into its original
form and look unperturbed and nitinol is that you can that's we know that that's the case yeah
that is crazy and james fox's witnesses literally said this is the exact same stuff they found in
brazil when that thing crashed there you go yeah so they said he explained it like he was like foil
that you could bend around and it would go back to its original yeah and robert sarbacher who was
very close with thomas townsend brown is probably working on a lot of this stuff talks about material
thinly layered materials that you know do similar things from that time yeah so i there's i think
they're there and then the bodies i'd you know rank a little lower probability but i've i've
heard from some pretty credible sources that you know i think there's something there too
so what do you make about what and moment of contact is and i think more by the way is
going to come out about the vargenia case moment of contact is in some ways better
what else is going to come out you guys special info jesse well my fellow men if you've lost your
hair it doesn't mean you can't find it again try hims hair loss solutions and join hundreds of
thousands of men who have found their hair again without even leaving the couch here's the deal
hims offers doctor approved clinically backed treatments like finasteride and minoxidil the
good stuff that's proven to actually regrow your hair in three to six months whether you're into
chewables pills sprays or serums they've got the solution that fits your vibe no awkward
doctor visits and no waiting rooms just answer a few quick questions online and a medical provider
will see if the treatment is right for you if it is they'll ship it straight to your door for free
no insurance no problem one low price covers everything from treatments to ongoing care and
with hundreds of thousands of happy customers hims is pretty much the go-to for getting back
thicker fuller hair and your confidence start your free online visit today at hims.com
slash danny that's h i m s dot com slash d a n y for your personalized hair loss treatment options
hims.com slash danny results vary based on studies of topical and oral minoxidil and
finasteride prescription products require an online consultation with a health care provider
who will determine if a prescription is appropriate restrictions apply see website
for full details and important safety information make your hair great again with hims i i i love
james fox and i'm buddies with him and i just know he's kind of actively pursuing that okay so
yeah so i think i'm really excited to see what happens there but like i would rank that as
higher probability as far as the beings than roswell because we have witnesses who are alive
and we have them on video saying they were right there there's the three women who like how about
the scene where they go to the guy's house and he's like he pulls his gun out and he's about
to shoot him totally that scene and and then you know that there's this doctor that reportedly
died when the thing was in his hands and this kind of ammonia like smell which keeps coming up
so yeah he said that the the doctor who did the x-ray said the whole hospital spent like ammonia
for a week there yeah no no sulfur i'm sorry sulfur sulfur which is the smell of the devil so
yes weird yeah then you have to ask yourself the question like yeah how much of that stuff
is actually just historical and real like we if something has a religious veneer to it we throw
it out as not historical but we have to remember like pre-enlightenment everybody was religious
everybody yes so it's history it's not religious just because something has a religious overlay to
it doesn't mean it's inherently not true you can say a lot of the things in the bible feel beyond
the pale for you to believe or whatever like the seas parting in the old time whatever yeah but
to say that like somebody definitely didn't have this experience that seemed paranormal we put this
religious overlay over there i think is extremely close my sure yeah we have all these examples now
of people experiencing paranormal stuff and it's just not a religious overlay because that's not
the kind of mythology of today sciences right right yeah again like you say don't have it can't
throw the baby out with the bath water yeah but there's um when it comes to the crashes though
yeah what do you make of the crashes like if these things are so advanced if they're
extraterrestrials or if they're future humans that are 500 000 years in the future
why are they crashing yeah this gets into weird uh stuff but i think there's high-powered radar
that was developed in the 40s um i think uh watson watt was like the first guy that developed radar
that was in um in britain and then we started to experiment with more and more high-powered radar
and that we had that at white sands and i think we had that probably at right airfield and i think
we've had that at air force bases across the u.s and then i think they're attracted to nuclear
stuff and so i think they they can be disrupted by some of these high-powered radars and this is
where i it's the conversation kind of gets weird because i and they're not aware of our high-powered
radar i think that's possible man i mean there's also yeah i think it's possible like they could
not be care like okay if they're like directed any energy weapons is that like similar yeah and
it's weird i don't like talking about it because i think it's kind of
fucked up to be honest like i don't think that um should be you know yeah it's it's kind of weird
but yeah how so what do you mean well just just messing with these things at all i think they're
not kind of interfering with us and so we shouldn't interfere with them totally you know um but but
yeah i think as far as that being possible i don't think we know what they are i think we assuming
oh they traveled the cosmos to get here and they're so advanced or whatever and then they
they get messed up due to our you know like like how do we have the hubris to think that we could
like pop them out of the sky with this stuff it's like we don't know what they are and like why
they're here and there are ways in which you could be extremely advanced and then ways in which you
could be super simple like agi is way more advanced not agi any ai model is way more advanced on like
vector calculus than like a human way more advanced when it comes to like snap intuition and like
judgment of like kind of multimodal stuff like across different domains humans are way more
advanced than ai right so this idea that like they are stepwise better than us in like every
single way and can't crash i think is ridiculous and then it also is predicated on the space alien
thing that like again we don't know like they could just exist in this kind of interior fabric of
reality they could be kind of mostly ignoring us outside of certain things that light up in
our population around consciousness or nuclear you know things of that nature and so yeah the
development of certain you know weapons technology might interfere with them and i don't think that's
crazy to to say well it might not be as crazy if they were sending things that weren't biological
right if they were sending sort of drones through reconnaissance drones like kind of like we send
to other planets everybody i know is deep on this topic says that the biological stuff they're drones
and like the grays and all this they're like 3d printed things they're anatomically compiled
like like what is darpa looking into right now like like programming biology yes so like that's
probably what they are too and if you think talk look at like all the interactions with the alien
beings they're always like do not fear do not fear we won't hurt you this will take a second
and then they like you know this is like an incision and they like put an implant in you and
and then they go away and so like they are doing a low level task they're probably not the beings
themselves they're probably von neumann replicator envoys to like achieve a specific function so it's
not going to be that catastrophic if they lose something no not at all they lose something through
a lightning strike or a dew or whatever no it's like your little robot avatar but some people
think that they're crashing them on purpose right yeah we're like yeah it's like a donation or a
gift joc valet speculates that i don't i this is where i'm you know i have no idea yeah but um but
i do believe there are crashes there's just so many i mean lennard stringfield at 119 cases
there's a guy named ryan wood who has 104 cases most of which are uncorrelated with the lennard
stringfield cases so so when you're talking about those like anatomically uh 3d printed
biological beings that everyone thinks about is like the little gray aliens yeah when i had
greer in here last week he's as soon as i said that to ask him about those things he goes oh
that's just cia i'm like willy i'm like what about willy streber he's like oh that's all cia
that's all cia mind control stuff he like completely he completely brushed it off as like intelligence
black shit happening yeah he he his easy straw man for anything that he thinks is like fake in the
ufo world is it's like intel national security deep state whatever and like i i just think that's
like super close-minded thinking and like i don't know i don't know it could be in the case of
whitley whitley did whitley has a really interesting story where um he was he did a
great podcast with him that everybody should check out but there were experiments done on him as a
child at randolph air force base near san antonio i believe did he tell you about when he went to
mexico yes yeah that was very strange as well yeah so i don't i don't know what to make of
yeah i don't know if you like have like a theory there but i mean and that's i think less of an
uncommon story than people realize as well these like gait programs these gifted and talent
talented student programs recruiting kids stranger things type shit stranger things yeah exactly
yeah whitley first of all when he came on that podcast i didn't know he had an implant and he
fucking dropped it on me right when we started recording by the way touch the implant or see
no i didn't touch it but he gave me he showed me a video you should have dude because that thing is
weird really he sent me a video of it there's a video of it i have and then he showed me like
the x-rays of it i saw you touch it though yeah that's crazy he says that he says that it moves
around yeah that's what he said he said they tried to take it out and it just moved like yeah which
also is a common thing that you hear of these things move on their own metabolism which is
that's that's very common with the implant thing so again it points to this kind of biological drone
thing have you read so have you read all whitley's books or just read i've just read communion so
there's a bunch of other stuff oh and i read his book on jesus actually oh did you really okay i
read that one too yeah um but there's a lot of there's a lot of interesting stuff that he
didn't include in communion that he does include in his other books this fella i had on the show
jason giorgiani is like i've seen that episode he is a historian of whitley streber he's read
every single book front to back multiple times and like i spent like two hours on the phone with
him before i had uh william here and there's a lot of other interesting things like wild wild
things that he left out of communion like for example there's one scene in one of his books i
can't remember the name of the book but where he talks about when the alien girl is like riding
him okay he says there's a cia guy in the room watching him a cia guy that he knows watching him
have sex with an alien watching him have sex with an alien no way and like like how do you explain
that what first of all why did you leave that out of the book yeah what was going i think i talked i
don't know i don't remember if i asked him about that in the podcast but like there's there's so
many just bizarre and then also like the history of him going to mexico yeah and like he didn't
want to talk about that to me on the show i don't know if he talked about it with you but like
apparently there were some kids who went down to mexico and he was a part of it
where he was at some house that was like guarded by the military and it was all military stuff
where they were like subjecting children to watching like like murder videos of people
getting like tortured and murdered to do something to their mind yeah to like to induce some sort of
trauma to these children right so if you combine that yeah with his stories yeah what i don't what
do you i don't know what to make of that well i i do think the inducing of trauma and dissociation
is more common than we realize when it comes to these programs that recruit kids and try to find
kids with high psi abilities and this is going to sound nuts to the average person who doesn't
believe that there's any sort of mind matter interaction or whatever but parapsychology has
been studied at elite universities since you know mid-century stanford research institute
princeton you know engineering and anomalous research pair lab duke the ryan center from 1931
1960 was the first one in the u.s and i think aerospace is known about this for a long time
and unfortunately i think we have a dark past checkered past when it comes to mk ultra which
came out in the church committee in 1975 and i think mk ultra and and a lot of the psychic stuff
dealt with trying to find kids and and and and and induce trauma and so i don't know
you know i find i find witley to be pretty pretty honest in his readout of things you know like it
not like a he's like a good guy and then like you know i don't know what to make of any of this stuff
i just listen to what people say and repeat it like me too sure yeah yeah well i think i think
um and then you can obviously remember things falsely as your you know kid so i don't know on
that but i i would be lying if i weren't to say that that didn't kind of pattern match to other
stories that you hear so whitley story yeah i just interviewed a psionic asset on my show oh jake
barber not jake barber oh but jake barber does say he says he kind of hints at this he goes
i was traumatized he had a really rough childhood his stepfather didn't
treat him super well and he kind of talks about how he was gifted as well where he was like you
know he had matched colors up as a kid with major chords and minor chords and so certain colors
would make you happy like a major chord certain colors would make you sad like a minor chord
and to me like my like almost uh coded read on that is like maybe you know he was part of something
as a kid or maybe they like they they they looked at him or yeah maybe maybe early on they thought
that he had something kind of special going on and that again it's a a lot of stuff around
gait programs in the u.s i think are going to come out in the next year programs gait g-a-t-e gifted
and talented education oh yeah i think a lot a lot of stuff there is going to get stranger things
style stuff i think stranger things as a show will look a lot more real than people now think it is
in a couple years from now yeah and there are people i know deeper than me on this who are the
tip of the spear as far as investigative research on this stuff so i'm not trying to blow up their
spot and uh yeah but it's kind of it's kind of weird it's kind of weird it's really weird that's
putting it like it's really it's really like uh it's it's messed up i was i'm just like
my pause with the shit with people like jake barber and um all the whistleblowers for that
matter is that if i am a part of this secret government right or the secret rogue private
organization that has possession and understands this super anti-gravity ufo technology contacting
non-human intelligence whatever it is it seems like something that's so much more powerful than
anything that the u.s government would even have or any government for that matter and if i wanted
to protect my secrets i would absolutely send out fake whistleblowers you know sure i think we
don't know exactly what to do with what we have i think we have bits and pieces okay if they take
this analogy if you had uh you gave a uh thumb drive to a caveman would they have any idea what
to do with it they don't know information theory they don't have a computer to plug it into just
look at this thing they probably like try to make a fire with it right right so like i think that's
you know maybe you can get some interesting derivative technology maybe the you know the
nickel alloy titanium maybe we've done some interesting stuff with that you know uh maybe
there are elements of the philip j corso day after roswell you know narrative that are true that some
of this stuff has made its way into civil side you know infrastructure yeah elements of it i think
there's clearly falsities in that book like i don't i don't think semiconductors required you know
alien tech to to you know their their patents of transistors that go back way back to the 30s
but by and large i think we're extremely confused and in the stone age on what we've retrieved
and so if you find this stuff and it's like cold war era we who do i mean it's the u.s government
the u.s the people who know what's going on yeah yeah yeah and and so like yeah i mean just like
america okay you know i don't know if you meant me or if you meant the guy that's working on the
craft well let me tell you i got a stash yeah yeah no i think i think like the the programs around
this stuff i don't i don't i don't think they know exactly what they're working with or what
they're doing and to me that explains a lot of like you like you you need in the era of cold war
secrecy um you know we're like we're like way ahead of like china and russia on like retrieving
this stuff to begin with then like you can keep it super over compartmentalized right and like
that's fine it doesn't matter then all of a sudden if like the cold war ends and then now
we're probably back in another cold war and it's this multipolar kind of scary thing and china
starts to catch up and like eat our lunch on some of this stuff then all of a sudden you need like
some civil side eyes like a lot of our best and brightest are not working at like lockheed or
northrop or like any of these places so you need to like let certain things out and so that i'm not
cynical about you know a lot of these whistleblowers i think they're they're genuinely
wanting to come out why they might have some sort of top cover or like why they're not dead to me
might be explained by you got to kind of let the cat out of the bag somewhat if that makes sense
because you need certain eyes on this thing because i don't think we've made a ton of progress
and on many dimensions you know i've heard rumors that we have alien reproduction vehicles or you
know advanced research vehicles that pattern match the UFOs we've made them flyable and then
i just i just don't know i don't know if that's like you know how much progress we've actually
made so and then even if we have made progress it's really that fundamental question of like
if we're at parity with china or russia then this stuff has to come out somewhat if that makes sense
and then we live in this like information age too it's just like impossible to keep a lid on
this shit and i do think there's there's these snowball effects where somebody displays a
tremendous amount of courage like david grush where he pieces together all this stuff and he
you know goes forward to the inspector the ic inspector general gives him a thousand pages and
you know offers to say i'll go to skiff with anybody and i'll you know show you where the
bodies are buried and i can give you the exact addresses of the you know facilities and stuff
it does this in front of congress and i think if you're on the program you're somebody like jake
and you're seeing that you're like this guy's really courageous and it like it inspires you
you know it's like the banister effect roger banister broke the four minute mile
and then 10 people broke the four minute mile like two years after him i think you see somebody go a
little you know you've had like moral qualms about what you've been doing already and you
see somebody like you know take it this far and you're like okay well i know a little bit more
and i could probably help with this effort i'm gonna go a little farther and so yeah yeah i
can see the problem though what you alluded to in that conversation with jake that if all of this
super high tech secretive war stuff that we're working on is so compartmentalized and
not available to even people in the highest levels of the military and you know the highest
generals and the president like if we get into a war i'm sure that russia and china under their
dictatorships they're going to be able to get shit done instantly and they probably don't have
this problem of compartmentalization and keeping secrets from their actual government yes right so
like that's not that's a problem that's a huge problem from a national security standpoint i mean
read the three-body problem and like that's how it goes down it's like you see like a scientist
that you know you're the ccp or the you know the pla yeah and you see a scientist like working on
some really interesting neutrino info transfer you have something like really far out crazy stuff
that like you don't have yeah you just knock on their door you say we're relocating you yeah
you're working at this base that's it that's the way it goes that's not the way the us the us is
like you have these competing factions you have all this you know it's just it's it's way more
of this kind of uncoordinated octopus and so that's a good way put again so i think the reason you
know i think a lot of these nda's that people have signed in the aerospace context to work on this
stuff in the past are extremely threatening and they're you know really scary retributions that
could occur hypothetically for a lot of these people and then i do think whatever legacy programs
like don't want anything to come back come out are on their back heels and they're like
some limited disclosure has to occur and i think they're sort of they're they're kind of like we
don't quite know what to do here and i think my hope is there are people on the inside who are a
little more like we need basic ontological truths to come out it's like nuclear stuff right like you
have nuclear physics you have programs all over the country it's it's physics it's open source
ontological truths the ideas that there could be bodies and crafts like people need to know this
shit that's crazy yeah and then you know anything that um you know any trade secret that could
immediately be weaponized or as low barrier to entry you know blow up the world kind of stuff
that obviously should be classified yeah and we just need to think about it reasonably through
those lens but i do i do think there are people on the inside who are just dogmatically pro-secrecy
because it's like this like cargo cult bureaucracy thing it's just like they don't
they don't understand how to be any other way or something yeah i mean the the most frightening
thing is that if this rogue government that's like has its own air force military uh navy whatever
that has all this power and has this technology that could essentially like
beat any world government's technology as far as like war or whatever it is like and if they
go row and they start and if they decide to start a war against the rest of the world
like that's that's the worst that seems like the scariest thing regarding these companies
that have this stuff because what what's going to stop them from just keep from keeping more
secrets from you and just and just taking this technology and exponentially gaining more
information and and revealing more insight into it and understanding more about the universe
and keeping that shit from the us right turns into like a breakaway civilization a breakaway
military military breakaway it's not a country well i did it's like a company that's more
powerful than any country you know i did find it very interesting that like matthew livelsberger
the green beret he blows up a cyber truck in front of the trump tower so it's like this
weird message or something symbolic yeah felt kind of symbolic like some sort of meme warfare
thing and then the email he sends to sam shoemate who goes on sean ryan is all about chinese
gravitic propulsion drones which i think is china is not flying with impunity with you know
electrogravity propulsion like that's game over right like that's like we're in the cuban missile
crisis it's been going on for three months or whatever like that's not that but maybe it's
sort of a little bit of a shot across the bow bow depending on what was what force was behind
that because clearly he was dealing with a lot of trauma ptsd and you know i think was like a good
guy in his private life but like what leads somebody who's like that to do that and to send
that email and i did speak to a green beret about this and he was like maybe this is a way to let
out some of the gravity stuff that you know we have made breakthroughs with so think about it
like this like maybe you're sending a little shot across the bow again to elon to trump you know
civil side government and you're saying we've got some some hardcore shit that you don't have
and again this is deep conspiracy i would hold this very kind of loosely low probability but
it goes to the point that you know you've made and then yeah i don't know i don't know i don't
know where they are technologically and if they even have the power to sort of to sort of flex and
do that but i i i do think that aerospace has some pretty advanced technology that you know that
those drones over new jersey they didn't seem like anything special like they seem moving like
regular drones like they weren't moving at light speed or like they weren't moving like tic tacs
making sharp turns they were just like floating around like normal quadcopters they were floating
around for longer periods of time than you would ever expect like you know hours and hours at a
time they'd stay stationary so they were exhibiting some kind of exotic effects with the kind of winds
and stuff but like yeah generally and then i would make a huge distinction between a lot of people
were seeing orbs and like other weird stuff and then there were like the fixed wing drones that
looked like they were meeting faa regs which were obviously human and so i would make a clear
distinction between those two things i would also make a distinction between the stuff showing up
at nuclear bases which if you know robert hastings work yes that looks more i don't
want to say paranormal because that sounds quacky but that looks more like of the ufo the classic
ufo variety right to classify it probably is that the new jersey stuff didn't seem like anything
near the ufo variety no i i agree with that a lot of it and then you but you had salient nuclear
plant right there and you had stuff showing up there and a picatinny arsenal right you know
stuff was showing up right right right i think i think it was definitely our government or
one of our government contractors that was in charge of that i don't know what they were doing
but did you hear the audio of um you know right patterson's like comms links were down like their
power was out for like a few hours like that to me is classic robert hastings ufos and nukes
and that was happening around that time what happened with right patterson i thought they
just had to i thought they just had to like shut down the runway or something for
no that i think the power was out for for a couple of hours right patterson the power was out i
believe either the power cost all comms were down for a little bit yeah and there's an audio
this up can we find this we should look it up yeah let's find let's find out yeah i think it's on
twitter is where what would we search how do right right patterson uh communications outage
right patterson drone and there's an audio air force base experienced a closure of its airspace
for about four hours late friday night into early saturday morning due to sightings of small unmanned
aerial systems drones in the vicinity of the base the base's airspace was closed as a precautionary
measure to ensure the safety of the installation and its residents no property was damaged or
residents harmed during the incident so they closed the airspace okay and i guess there was
maybe there wasn't a comms outage it was like it was due it was precautionary because there
were stuff flying around it right right huh yeah i did hear i did hear uh i did hear like a um some
sort of radio comm thing too where they were talking about like shutting down the airspace or
i have a crazy one for you so in 2010 after robert hastings wrote his book which was 2008
yeah effie warren experienced an outage for what's that he warned effie warren is a nuclear base in
wyoming okay and it experienced an outage for they said 59 minutes but robert hastings did
back channeling and it was 24 hours and president obama was briefed on this now do effie warren
outage uh atlantic effie warren uh yeah outage atlantic and you'll see that this was reported on by
like mainstream media and i don't know if they go to broadband no the like the atlantic like the
you know the the periodical or whatever oh power and the atlantic magazine atlantic magazine oh
okay okay okay magazine atlantic magazine yeah is it a power outage uh just looks like a failure
shut that down yeah yeah exactly so i okay this is really crazy so president obama was briefed on
this and uh hastings backchanneled with this guy this retired missile technician named john mills
yeah and he uh backchanneled with some missile security officers on site and were like there was
a tic tac flying around all over the base and that caused the outage is this like one of the
minutemen missile silos like where they have those underground icbms i know malmstrom is i don't know
if effie warren is maybe but this is what's crazy is you can even see in the article at the top of
the article engineering so power is crossed out and then it goes into engineering failure
i think it's covering their ass i think they're they don't want it to seem like it was attributed
to a ufo or to a tic tac or whatever which again robert hastings back and by the way i should say i
think you know i was wrong about the right path thing so i don't want to like conflate like this
is another thing that i think is very uh uh legit um but i mean yeah that's huge when they shut down
a nuclear dude obama was briefed yeah right that's big that's a big deal no shit yeah and
and then you're backchanneling with these guys who say that it's attributed to a tic tac flying
around in the airspace right and then they're crossing out power and they're making it seem
like it's an engineering thing what does it say three other lccs were successfully restarted
the suspect lcc remains offline what is it lcc uh let's see here the lcc uh launch control center
oh okay so the lc the launch control centers they lost comms like they couldn't launch the
thing if they wanted to interrogate each missile in sequence so if they begin to send signals out
when they're not supposed to receivers on the missiles themselves on the missiles themselves
will notice this and send out error codes um it left 50 missiles in the dark the missiles then
restarted one of the lccs and began to normally wow dude dude that's freaky it's really freaky
and then you're doing you know hastings who i think is a very honest actor is doing backchanneling
with these guys and they're like there's a tic tac flying around and that's what caused the outage
and then i think one of them faces kind of career reprisals as a result of this back channel with
hastings and stuff so and then you have that it's crossed power is crossed out and engineering is
it's like the live editing is shown on the atlantic article until i cover it up we're on um uh we're
on the brave browser the brave browser browser shows you all i wonder if it shows it in chrome
it does show it in chrome too it does because i put it in my documentary on hastings but okay
so anyway so so the right pat thing that is interesting that it i guess it sounds like
they were just incurred they were incursions on right and then they ended up shutting the
airspace down as a result that wasn't a coms link failure so that's my bad but i think they were
getting ready for the uh the eagles to win the super bowl so they had to like start figuring out
philadelphia they knew people were going to be looting and terrorizing the whole town
is going to turn into afghanistan for a week that's funny exactly but that just goes to the point
that like if these things are showing up around sensitive military sites yeah it points to the
nuclear connection it points this more generalizable three-body problem narrative where they're not
just showing up at nuclear sites they're showing up at advanced science research sites uh and the
most sensitive military sites and that was the case with the new jersey drone the whole new jersey
drone the the name new jersey drone is a psyop because they weren't just in new jersey they were
at lakenheath they were in florida they're in florida they're everywhere and they weren't just
drones the the drones were drones when this shit you could see that were taken down occasionally
blinking red and green because they're meeting faa regs obviously drones you know like clearly
those were drones in fact even the white house statement on the drones uh the press secretary
trump said well trump says it's very weird very strange it's not adversary and they're going to
the they're going they're coming from the garage and we know where the garage is so that that's
interesting right yeah the way he talks is just so confusing sometimes it's it's very confusing but
then his his white the press secretary tries to minimize it and say there's nothing to see here
she says oh it would they were faa approved they were research drones yeah see that begs a question
if you were given orders by the president who told you we will clear this up immediately because
he was asked this as soon as he was elected he goes what happened there we have to figure that
out and he like orders somebody to figure it out yeah so those were your orders you're saying we
have faa research drones what were they researching if it's a prosaic easy thing to
explain away yes you say it how come no one has that if it's not if it is not then you don't say
it so i think it points to some more exotic answers again i don't know i don't know you have
to think probabilistically about all this stuff and i'd be open right to it not being ufos but
like yeah i think there's a lot of evidence also south port new brunswick duke energy plant there
was ufos showing up there too so like so so drones or ufos ufos meaning what what do they look like
they look more like these plasma orb style things yeah like the bledsoe orbs more like the bledsoe
orbs like those look very different than these like fixed wing like yeah they're just different
okay that's why the whole thing is it's like not new jersey and it's not just drugs yeah it's a
whole host of stuff and and it's again it but you get into these weird kind of questions of like
were they trying to distract were they trying to run a simulation there's so many so many questions
but also in the case in which it wasn't ours say it say in the case in which there were real ufos
like not you know not ours not prosaically explained ufos yeah you would probably put
some stuff out to research it you put some of our stuff out so it's like really murky and it's
it's way more charismatic and easy and goes viral much quicker to be like there's a loose nuke on
the eastern seaboard right that will go viral way faster than like it's actually a whole host of
things it's kind of complicated it's not that interesting yeah yeah exactly so i think that's
kind of what happened and that's why like the you know if there were psyops around explaining things
away i think that's why it was so charismatic but then you talk to like the nuclear you know support
teams that the emergency teams nest or whatever all of those guys were like no there's nothing
there like you know nobody was like being evacuated right so clearly wasn't that so i it's weird
dude with like all of this stuff that's been happening lately with the news cycle and all
the crazy things that have gone on in the last six months like from trump almost getting killed on
on live tv yeah to like a week later that story's completely dead and then we have like the olympics
debacle and then we have like the the debates the election and all this the new jersey drones like
there's like so much stuff happening on top of the fact that people are more awake now than ever
of all the fuckery that's going on with like not only just the media trying to subvert stuff with
advertisers but with the government trying to subvert stuff like people more aware of the word
psyop now than ever i'm sure i'm sure we did a google trend on that word psyop it's probably
skyrocketed last year for sure so like i wonder if the government came out tomorrow and said yes
we made a deal with these alien civilization and they're here we have their ufos i wonder legitimately
what percentage of people would believe that or just run the other way this is such an important
thing you're bringing up because already already with the jake barber piece the ufo world has
cleaved off and is on another island of reality from mainstream media has no idea who jake barber
is unfortunate it sucks because it's such an important story but like because it's a hard
pill to swallow we're talking about psionics mind matter connection yeah you know uh egg shaped
things showing up in our ears like it's a lot to stomach all at once yes and it breaks the brain
of these normie legacy people who like aren't down these rabbit holes that you and i are down
because we've spoken to a lot of people and so it's this really important ontological question
where it's like people we need disclosure we need disclosure i'm like if you walked into a
hanger and were shown a ufo you walked into the ufo it wouldn't change your life at all you'd have
no idea what you were looking at and it would beget all sorts of other questions that you'd have
that wouldn't be answered upon walking into the ufo or whatever so it's disclosure isn't some file
that's going to come out where it's like this this this these are you know facts or whatever
i do look i do think if trump or tulsi or like one of these people with like you know serious
you know credentials in the government like cabinet level credentials or even from the past
cabinet level credentials says there's a there there i do think that's like a step function
up as far as disclosure like that's that's progress but it's going to be this it's you're
dealing with people's core belief systems and it's going to be this sort of broken jagged
process it's not going to be this like overnight like we have disclosure like people in our world
are you know i don't know where you lie but in a lot of my world or whatever they're like we've
had disclosure like so much has come out outside of 8k you know imagery with like the president
standing next to a ufo it's like we've kind of given a lot if they wanted to make it available
if they wanted to do disclosure think about it they're doing it the right way right no one's
losing their mind yeah yeah sure religion is not burning to the ground people aren't quitting their
jobs and like sure shooting it's not turning into mad max out there like they they are doing it the
right way although like kind of what i was alluding to is like with the distrust of media and
government now and people being aware of the deception the strategic deception that they are
capable of yep if the government was to say yes there's aliens we have them we have a we have a
saucer right there would be a huge chunk of people who think automatically if they're saying that
the opposite must be true yeah of course of course and i understand that skepticism and
i have a reflexive allergic reaction to the government telling me anything
as well and i would just say just because you think somebody has an ulterior motive
because a lot of people in the ufo world have a fucking ulterior motive doesn't mean everything
they're saying is wrong right maybe they're doing some weird controlled opposition thing maybe
they're doing something where they want to make money and inherit some equities outside of the
government maybe they're like they're i can give you 50 million reasons as to why somebody would
say some shit about ufos and you know claim to come from an authoritative background that aren't
pure that doesn't mean the facts they're saying are wrong and i think a you know a lot of these
guys like i think that the the the prima facie stories of a lot of these guys are just fully
right they're just correct and people just can't stomach them they can't they're like this just
breaks their brain it breaks their priors and uh yeah it's tough and it's that's why you think
mainstream media hasn't reported on jake story yeah i think it breaks i think they don't know
how to process it i think they have no idea how to get the the computer it like breaks their
computer i mean dude those guys are mind controlled i mean like in those guys want money though they
want that's true they do want money but they also you know have certain commercial interests and
like are you know uh connected to like various i mean you're seeing what's happening with mike
you know mike bens is reporting on all this like usaid like you know back channel shit with like
every legacy media i'm so shocked that youtube's letting that shit go it's wild it's wild that
they're letting it go but i think we've crossed the rubicon of sorts but like i hope so we don't
know who's making calls at these studios but look at like covet like for a year i mean even in like
i think 2022 the new york times published a steel manning of the like zoonotic origin of
covet yeah it's like give it up guys it's so stupid like you literally have to it takes the
probabilistic thinking of a child to realize their wet markets all over china why was it the one wet
market right six miles next to the wuhan institute of virology which is studying spike proteins added
on to like a basically modification of sars and how they can create a pandemic like give me a
break like there's an outbreak of chocolatey goodness in hershey pennsylvania john steward
said it best hilarious and that just gets so simple right but they don't they're it they're
overeducated they've lost their instinct they don't actually think about any media story critically
at all they're i hate to say i come from this world i went to columbia and like i you know i
know a lot of these people i love them they think i'm crazy now whatever yeah but they
don't actually do thinking around like like they hear a story and they they're they ideas are fashion
statements and they don't want to look bad at the water cooler you know at con day nest or whatever
they are you know they don't want to like they and they're snarky and if you watch you know i
used to end i interned for you know the daily show back in the day and like i i thought they were
that's crazy i john stuart was a total uh bulwark against neoconservatism back in the day that was
very healthy and like amazing and now he's just out they're out of touch man like like you have
you know these correspondents go out these like mager rallies and they just like make fun of them
and like they're snarky and look i was probably guilty of i was anti-trump in 2016 and like i
think you know i thought he was kind of crazy and like i was the same way you know and i was like
these these these states don't understand these red states don't understand what's good for them
and then you my now belief is like the more like you go through like the liberal arts like
ivy league education the more you lose touch with your real instincts about reality and your your
worldview and like mental models on things are actually like really wrong you're like way off
and it's couched in this veneer of sophistry and of sophistication and so it sounds really smart
but it's actually really stupid and it's wrong i try i try my hardest to be open-minded about
things and look at things from multiple angles but like every single big topic like ufos or
ancients graham hancock's a big one yeah yeah he's like he's like they hate him he's like no well no
they fucking love him well it's either one or the other he's so polarizing it's so polarizing and
the lack of open-mindedness and and and ability to form independent thoughts outside of the
comment bubble yeah is astonishing yeah no it's it's crazy and it's it's it's an age-old trope
in history of this amateur gentleman journeyer who has correct instincts is outside of the priestly
citadel of experts and then gets proven right heinrich schleiman was this german businessman
that was laughed at forever because he thought the ancient city of troy you know in the
peloponnesian war written about by homer and thucydides was actually you know that wasn't
mythology like that was actually a real place and then he goes out and he finds it in anatolia and
in the 1870s and we have now tons of corroboration that's now consensus right louise walter alvarez
thought that you know an asteroid impact took out the dinosaurs 66 million years ago and in their
case they actually were extremely credentialed louise walter alvarez the father was uh you know
in the manhattan project very involved with oppenheimer and so yeah but he was this like
you know he was out of his domain right it was he was an archaeologist but he was right right
and now now you have graham hankock and randall carlson they're saying the same thing about
younger drag impact yeah younger dryus impact they're also pointing to mythology just like
uh heinrich von schleiman did in the case of plato and dates around plato but they also have
tons of archaeological evidence like great archaeological evidence that uh there was an
air burst from the torrid meteor stream around that time and they're just not being taken
seriously and my money's on them my money's not on the citadel so it's yeah it's just it's it's
reflexive bad thinking and at any there's a great book by this guy sam arbisman it's called the
half life of facts and at any point in history we were wrong about 50 percent of the like
conventional wisdom at the time like or roughly right okay like so we're probably wrong about 50
percent of what we know now yeah so if you are going around being this like michael schermer
style or richard dockins kyle skeptic neil degrasse tyson like we know everything
you're you you are being ahistorical you're engaging in bad thinking unless you can point to
some percentage of current knowledge that you think is wrong you are a you're like a member
an extension of the borg you're like you're the thought police for the conventional wisdom and
you're probably wrong so yeah i just i like to systematically go through the anomalies
because i think that there are tells on what the next scientific paradigms are like if you look at
you know black body radiation uh was discovered by this german guy in the 1860s we couldn't that was
you know the fact that that would create this ultraviolet catastrophe it was this guy gustav
kerchop we couldn't understand that until max plank in the quantum revolution in the 1900s
the mercury the the orbit of mercury wasn't understood in the newtonian context and we
needed general relativity to explain it so when you see an anomaly like a ufo or like you know
scabble you know washington scablands like you know impacts or whatever that you know you might
represent you know the younger driest thing you have to systematically look at the anomalies you
can't ignore them right because they lead to new science this is the scientific revolutions 101
thomas kuhn wrote about this in the structure of scientific revolutions the anomalies bring
in the new paradigm yeah so what i think you're doing and what i love to do is like talk to people
on the fringes and just because you're talking to them doesn't mean you agree with everything
they say you're not platforming them we have the benefit of talking to people on the fringes and
the people in the center of the academic institutions totally totally which they each one to you know
some of them the people in the academic institutions are most are in a bubble they're
not talking to people in the fringe every day yeah and same thing most the time with people on the
fringes yeah and like the way i explained like the whole flint dibble graham hancock thing is like
i completely understand how flint dibble who his dad named him flint because he's an archaeologist
and his dad's probably an archaeologist yeah who spent his whole life studying archaeology reading
the boring books doing the boring shit traveling all over yeah digging through the mud and pulling
stuff out his whole life and nobody knows who the fuck you are yeah then graham hancock comes along
writes some crazy fucking book and becomes a super celebrity and makes tons of money
going on joe rogan all the time i'm gonna be i'm gonna be super jealous and resentful of that guy
too hundred percent and i'm not gonna go as far as flint dibble did to make that very clear yeah
some of the shit he did was really terrible in my opinion he was like lying about he was the some
certain slides were up on that rogan episode that were just like wrong and not only that but like
and this is a super unpopular opinion and i will get completely destroyed in the comments for saying
this but i think flint killed him on that debate oh great hancock without having the ability of
being able to monday morning quarterback and see okay he was wrong about a lot of stuff because
he did do some dishonest things by like he was very confident in saying things that were quite
literally wrong after people were able to go back and review the stuff and graham was actually
able to go back over the podcast and find out like okay like you're completely wrong about the
number of ships right or any of this other stuff that you were talking about but like right but
like i learned a fuckload from flint during that podcast he was able to fill in the gaps of stuff
that graham didn't really understand during that podcast i feel like and i feel like even rogan
during that podcast was siding with flint sure on things like he was like graham don't you think
that looks like that looks kind of natural to me yeah i was like no no no no no anyways that's
neither here nor there i i think that like i thought he did a great job but what i don't
like is how he went on twitter afterwards and like oh do you see how much i kicked graham's
ass during that podcast some tweeting every tweet that graham did looking like a complete
douchebag totally yeah but like so i guess my point is like i understand i understand how
flint feels the why he feels the way he feels yeah right and why people in academia feel the way
um the way flint feels and i see how there's sort of like a rift between these two groups
and just like combine that with the way modern media works like podcasting is the number one
form of information in the world now right and like people are more interested in the fringe
stuff because it's exciting yep and it's more sensational and um i think you know long way of
putting it but you know academia academics get resentful of that and it's created this sort of
like this dichotomy if you will totally totally and and i but i think there's value in it to your
point with flint double where it's like you need to stress test the really bold grand new ideas
and theories and uh yeah i think science is a process it's like you know you have skepticism
and dogmatism and it's a sillon karybdis and you want to you want you know you want both and i
think having debates like that are really good but i'm always partial or sympathetic to quote
unquote platforming the people with the bold grand ideas where like some of the stuff
might be wrong semantically yeah but they're directionally correct on like in like a big way
that's exciting versus these guys that are just defending the modern paradigm because i don't
think that gets us anywhere like yeah like i agree like darwin is like a locally useful theory like
i don't like i wouldn't i don't think like darwin's like fake right it's a theory and i think
gravity's also a theory gravity's also a theory totally and but i think it's also useful in a
scientific you know i don't i wouldn't like throw it out at all like these things are like extremely
useful gravity is a great example because there are like many anomalies with it both on a macroscopic
you know level with with dark matter and on a microscopic level you know with you know
it's irreconcilable with the other you know forces on a quantum level
and you know electrons don't exhibit gravity you know in the same in the same way you know other
super wild objects do yeah it's interesting yeah yeah um so yeah i i don't know i think i i'm
always partial to let's like systematically talk to the people with the bold theories and then
stress test and come at them and try to you know uh uh uh negate any parts of their thinking that
are kind of flimsy right but like you know really take seriously their their ideas especially when
they're driven i think the difference between dibble and graham hankock is like one is driven
more by intuition and this like life purpose mission thing and in our modern day that's seen
as inherently bs or something whereas the other person's like like came up through the system
yeah and like that's just seen as more valid and i would say if you're like you feel like hermetically
called to a thing you're going to be extremely motivated you're going to find out all sorts of
stuff and he had i mean we would not be talking about gobekli teppi if it weren't for graham
hankock and so we the conventional wisdom on like how old civilization is would be the you know
classic mesopotamia was the cradle of civilization so like who's who's had more of an impact just
based on that 100 it's graham hankock even flint said when he was in here he goes graham inspired
a lot of people that i know that are now academic archaeologists and devoted their career to this
stuff there you go so you know totally so yeah again and i don't even know like i don't even
know what the actual objective was of that debate other than to like disprove graham's
ancient civilization idea debates like this are tough yeah because like often it's like
like i did like this informal debate with like michael shirmer i saw that and like who was the
guy that he debated who michael shirmer you're michael shirmer and who no i i it was just me and
oh no but i saw one on your channel with oh no no mick that was mick west and merrick von rennan
camp and okay and that that was that was a tough one too where it's just you have the skeptics who
i think do provide this service and i even came out thinking okay like mick actually you know has
some interesting debunks in these certain areas i'm gonna like hold certain some of these videos in
lower probability like actually one of my takeaways is like video evidence isn't the kind of archimedes
lever for disclosure in general like it's not the thing you want to hinge your belief on at all
because like they're all kind of murky and like not great although i think maybe on the margins
merrick won the debate but yeah i think the the classic thing with like skeptic versus pro when
it comes to these really kind of hard to answer questions is like the pro people have all these
reasons as to like why you know it's anomalous and then the anti people they just they sit on these
kind of like oh it's a law of large numbers where it's ockham's razor or it's that you know it's
like these like rules of thumb that like are just it's like kind of lame and like provocative
and like you're not actually looking at the data like finally i think mick west has read
ufos and nukes by robert hastings because it's such an important data set when it comes to ufos
but he can't say anything there's nothing he can say because he gets like how are you going to go
at these guys you can't go at their credentials you know say call them liars like they're on the
prp program it's kind of hard so like you end up with these this like two trains passing in the
night in the debates where it's like one side has a data set and the other side just won't agree
that the data set is legitimate they're just like it's survivorship bias it's file drawer issues
it's you're a liar you're a grifter or whatever but like look at the data look at them what do
you mean like i've met a lot of these guys who've seen this stuff at nuclear sites and it's like
some of them have maintained cue clearances for years after they've seen this stuff like
and then at that point it's like i don't know what to tell you if you're not going to like believe
you know if you're not going to like read the book which is a 580 page book
extremely dry and it's almost boring really because it's so rigorous and good and meticulously done
like robert hastings has like an eidetic memory and so like you're either going to read the book
and like engage with it or you're not and if you're not then like i don't know what the
debate is about right what do you make of elon not being impressed or not being interested in
this stuff i find it really interesting um you know starlink is just like an optical
group of you know satellites and it's it's the biggest you know optical you know group but and
then obviously the rf communication have you seen like the videos of all the satellites that we have
surrounding the earth it's insane yeah it's crazy especially starlink is just blowing it out of the
water i mean it's it's everywhere and they have they have um i think it's star shield is like
the dual use kind of you know optical or whatever but so you hear that these things the ufos are
like picked up by like other sensor modalities i don't know on elon i like look in the world in
which ufos exist i would have to think he's got to know some stuff you know like i just so i don't
know if he's playing especially these rocket guys like tim are fucking dedicating their like their
lives to this stuff totally and they have any overlap okay the interesting thing i thought on
elon is he kind of toothed he walked back a couple of things recently in the last couple of months
somebody said mentioned david gresh to him and said like you know maybe we're hiding all the
secret tech and he said well if we are hiding secret tech i would hope that that would you know
come out and so that was a change in tune that wasn't this like you know joke oh i'm an alien
or like i would know like it's you know we don't have high resolution imagery like he kind of walked
that back in that in that you know interview question yeah and then the second thing he said
i think tucker asked him about ufos and he said i think it's deep black american programs really
at that point you're kind of backing yourself into a corner where it's really interesting like
what are you saying man are you saying that we have deep black american programs that
look like they're breaking physics so like they break conservation momentum they fly mock you know
10 and then they stop on a dime yeah and then they you know make right angle turns yeah and then they
go from you know right above the water to like above 80 000 feet like david fravor is saying
and you know uh looks like they're you know not using chemical combustion because if you are then
you're saying we have physics that's in deep black compartments that you know well surpass what we're
doing with chemical combustion when it comes to starlink where you have these you know i don't
know 33 36 raptor engines and it's all just mass ejection and it's all just you know newton's laws
yeah and so it's you're kind of backing yourself into a corner where it's like we either have
secret physics or you're because you're saying this stuff is real in that interview you're saying
the stuff is real or maybe there's you could hang on like um that we have some you know really
good like radar spoofing you know and like that would be your you know or flier spoofing or
whatever you'd have you know yeah some some version of that maybe you could do holograms and optical
spoof i don't i don't know what he would say but it's weird it's such a mind fuck because i think
if i can think of anyone who'd be more interested who should be interested in stuff i would think of
him i know i'm with you it's a it's a strange it feels like you know just like there's like
dark matter in physics it's like what's the dark matter there like we can't detect something
going on there and i don't i don't know what it is that's so true man that's so true um i gotta
get leaked go take a quick break yeah let's do it yeah cool all right we're back from our pp break
yes um yeah the elon stuff is crazy so i wanted i did want to ask you um yeah how did you find
this guy jake barber and
i don't even know where to start with this guy can you explain how you met him and then how
like what happened with him and where he came from like his story yeah so he was originally
like a red team guy who was well he was on the program what does that mean
around that means he was like meant to infiltrate like like adversary groups
okay and stuff and so like he and he was like you know it's basically like security for the
program so he was part of the crash retrieval program he was pipelined through air force combat
control which is a special uh the air force version of special forces he didn't become air force
special forces at that point he became kind of sheep dipped if you know that term and like
intel circles or whatever like erased like he became like you know director of operations
for a helicopter company and you know he that was basically his title okay but he was working
with these you know prime contractors you might be able to guess who they are he doesn't reveal
who they are exactly but he is he so he says he was working with the secret aerospace contractors
aerospace contractors and i would imagine he's talking about companies that are are like or
similar to battelle or any of these other ones like lockheed or something like that yeah i don't
know you could guess he didn't he didn't he said he said if you tried to guess too you'd probably
get them right on your first try so i might have got those two right maybe maybe um and so he's
doing retrieval operations for them and then on behalf of his employer he goes to red team
stephen greer the stephen greer was the we were just talking about this he was like the go-to guy
for like any whistleblower in the government like he was the guy the disclosure project was
for the last 20 years he was trying to subvert stephen greer's whistleblowers and in 2023
stephen greer held his like disclosure you know congress thing or whatever and he had done a
version of this two decades prior in 2001 i think and it was with a lot of really impressive amazing
whistleblowers and it unfortunately it's kind of couched under the veneer of stephen greer who
has you know certain issues yeah personnel everybody i mean every single respectable
person in the ufo world um they all detest stephen greer he can i don't know why yeah i mean i can
i mean i can i can i can imagine why yeah i don't know if there's like any kind of like like solid
reason why they don't like him i don't know the guy personally and i've been trying to interview
him for like a year through various go betweens and it's i've gotten a lot of like weird respect
like ego and responses i don't know i don't know what the deal is yeah so for anybody watching like
i'll put you in touch with them oh thanks man appreciate it oh that'd be awesome yeah um i'll
trade you for a grush that's not a fair trade bro i need somebody else that's so funny um so like
we're trading them these ufo people like pokemon cards yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah exactly gotta
write you it's yeah greer's like in the pokemon what would he be is he like uh
don't say it i don't know i'm not i know like there's collectibles you gotta catch them all
but like what which one would greer be would he be the charizard or what maybe it might be charizard
i don't know okay what's the big one that would puff out all that stinky gas what's the most what's
the most valuable pokemon charizard right no it's mew it's mew no mew too no mew is even more
valuable than mew too mew too and then mew is like the baby mew too i think oh okay i don't know
yeah you gotta if you're gonna if you're collecting these guys you gotta have you gotta
have greer on your belt yeah i know like you explained that to me right he's one of the most
legendary like like og ufo people totally you said he was like in the 90s he was the only guy he was
like the only guy but i mean that's not that's actually an important thing to correct he was
the only very public facing guy and that's why he became who he is now but i think he took a lot of
his stuff from a guy named uh bill hamilton william hamilton who would write about these deep
underground military bases covert operations and there was a lot of actually hard-headed research
going on at the time and he kind of shored it up and made it this more public then it was interesting
it's an interesting origin story because i don't quite understand how he went from he was a
physician and he just says he was an er doctor he was an er doctor and then he got super into ufos
he said during one of his ce5 things um there was a an air force spook or something there and saw
the stuff he was doing and told the cia guy the head of the cia who then wanted to go to dinner
with him yeah it's super interesting i mean and again i believe the jake barber account and like
it kind of comports with that where it involves like trying to call stuff in which is so at that
time you have this guy albert stubblebine who also has connections with remote viewing at the time
and john alexander who's this long-time kind of ufo historian but he also debunks certain things
and he clearly has deep government ties also close to with blood so and inserts himself in like all
sorts of interesting like john hutchinson was this guy who would claim to like have mind matter
effects with like these like metallic instruments around him in california and john alexander shows
up there john alexander is this very interesting figure in ufo world where he just pops in like
you know at very opportune times so stubblebine career claims he offered him two billion dollars
to participate in the legacy ufo or oh i thought the side i thought it was like joint come join our
ufo program or something it was okay he explained it to me like it was part of the offered him two
billion dollars to basically be a part of their building the public narrative or something okay
interesting interesting well that yeah it sounds like yes sounds like i mean i like i actually i
think there's an email showing that maybe but but i i don't think the offer was real i think i mean
stubblebine's this weird character he's army counter intel and he's also on record touting all
sorts of other bizarre conspiracies and he's one of these people you just don't mind it
stubblebine is yeah yeah and so it's one of these people you just don't know what to make of him
but they do insert themselves in greer's life and then greer becomes the de facto guy where
if you're on the inside and you're working at lock eed or north rip or you know you're a cia
contractor or whatever you see some shit and you want the public to know you go to greer and so
the disclosure disclosure project archives are to this day probably like among the best ufo
databases treasure troves of pretty interesting contemporary information and so i you can't throw
baby out with the bathwater as much as he's a very interesting kind of strange character yeah
there's some ego there he's easy to dismiss for sure yeah and there's definitely some messianic
but like it feels like he's you know so he's the guy who's bringing the dance like come on dude it's
everybody you know yeah it is most people yeah and this you know it's just like there's also like a
thing when somebody has you know has all the answers to everything yep yep you know there's
a weird thing that happens there too yep yeah but um what we're talking oh we're talking about
jake barber so so greer um greer was hosting this thing uh where he had all these whistleblowers he
was providing an outlet for these whistleblowers to come out and um you were saying that jake
barber went there to try to red team red team meaning what infiltrate greer and trying to like
like like bust one of these guys for blowing the whistle but bust the whole organization maybe
infiltrate the organization and then become you know like the guy from legacy who's feeding info
back into legacy ufo programs from like you know this important kind of vulnerability threat
vector or whatever yeah and so he's at this congress or whatever and you know his story is
that michael Herrera do you know who that is yeah he's a marine who was in the philippines and
he gets diverted with his unit of i think like eight or nine people to indonesia and indonesia
is a disaster zone it's due to this earthquake there's a tsunami warning and so everybody's
evacuating the area and he's marines he and his marines are apprehended first he sees an eight
gone like an octagon shaped craft hovering above the treetops that he says is vanta black and it's
like he calls it blacker than black and it's above the treetops and he starts to close in on that
craft with his marines because they're like what the hell is going on here and then they get
apprehended by this elite paramilitary unit which in like i think it was 2009 like they had like
bioscanners and like all sorts of gear you would never expect that they like they were clearly and
they were very well trained probably tier one special forces and we're kind of running circles
around these marines saying stuff like it's easy to get lost in the woods or it's easy to get lost
in the jungle you know like well you know uh did these guys say they were part of any any specific
branch of the military or were they did they have any like badging on them they had it was
completely nondescript but very advanced according to Herrera and so private prop yeah maybe yeah and
they were loading these crates onto this flatbed this truck it was like an forward f-250 or something
and uh he was like i don't know what the crates were whatever and so barber he's at this disclosure
event where Herrera is giving this account and Herrera also gets interviewed by Shawn Ryan as
well and barber is like i could see the authenticity in Herrera and i you know what am i doing here sort
of thing and there are other reasons i guess barber felt like he was betrayed by his you know
contractor uh in the past and at that moment he goes like fuck this i'm gonna like red team the
red team or i'm gonna like red team you know the the i'm gonna i'm gonna talk to these guys
earnestly yeah i'm gonna side up with you know the Herrera's of the world and try to see if we can get
you know some of these truths out um and so he back he talks to Herrera and he says that the crates
actually had people in them in indonesia and that these crates were bringing back these psionic
assets that are used for the ufo program to attract ufos and so it's this crazy story
psionic assets meaning like 11 from stranger things they're trying to find girls like they're
like young children i don't know i don't had superpowers i don't know what age again there
are stories that like really match stranger things as far as the ages of the people being
recruited into the programs and that gets into some weird weird shit um and so i don't know what
age these people were because they were in these like metallic containers and they were being
evacuated from the area i mean even the fact that they're being kept in the metallic containers is
weird right like rear also said there was uh they were trying to get homosexual people that's
apparently this thing apparently uh uh gay men and uh left people were left-handed yeah and again
this is something i just i have no idea if that's right how true that is but that's i'm just trying
i'm trying to like think through the logistics of that you're in an earthquake zone where there
was a crazy natural disaster people are like they're i don't know if they speak english right or
they have the other guys speaking indonesian right but like were they like raise your hand if you're
a homosexual or like are you left-handed or right-handed like how are you doing this are you just
bulk gathering these people and then figuring it out later i don't know and it's it's there's
another question is like were they engaging in operations and did they have to evacuate because
of the tsunami or where they take and this is the way Herrera presented on Sean Ryan which is
more nefarious honestly where it's like are you taking advantage of the fact that there's a
disaster zone and people could go missing yeah and taking them back with you which is like weird
of course they would be why wouldn't they be well it's a question of like were those people
already like willfully signed up for the program they were attracting stuff in the jungle of
indonesia that's why the the the black craft was there i guess the black craft
i think was human so so i take that back but like maybe that was part of the operation but like
so yeah they were like engaging in operate field operations there or was where you just the
operation itself was to round up these people who were lost that's the impression that i got was
that i mean just from watching your podcast the impression i got was that they saw there was a
disaster there and thought this would be an opportunity to right extract some people we
want to talk to Herrera and i want to get to the bottom of it he says that on the Sean Ryan
podcast yeah but barber says on my podcast or they were engaging in operations and they had
to get the hell out of dodge because this tsunami was coming so barber also seemed very off put
about Sean Ryan and Herrera saying that that they were just going there to exploit the the disaster
and get those people out he seemed kind of like right he's like i didn't like the Sean Ryan even
used the word human trafficking right right he was like defended by it almost right right yeah so
yeah i don't know i don't know the the kind of ground truth on that but so so he's saying that
their people that these people are being taken from this place in indonesia and my assessment
my guess is that like these people are are more in tune to nature they're not around technology
and civilization so jake said that they he said that on your podcast maybe they have a different
diet they're not eating processed garbage so that would automatically give them let them be tapped
into this muse or this consciousness or whatever well that's what they say in the u.s too like
you know you have dolce you know new mexico you have tacoma washington you have skinwalker ranch
all of these are ancient native american lands and apparently that's where a lot of this kind
of weird stuff shows up skinwalker ranch we know was professionally you know as part of ufo research
efforts investigated as part of osap from 2007 to 2012 and so i i think both like the people
are like it's it's it's just like you know if you go to like you know most indigenous tribes you
talk about people from the stars you're not going to freak them out like they're going to be kind
of familiar with those concepts like yeah we come down during our ceremonies you know it's both i
think that for the people it's like they have less of like an allergic reaction because they haven't
been indoctrinated with this materialist reductionist western paradigm where we even need
the idea of disclosure like for them it's like second nature or whatever yes exactly and um
and then also the land itself which then you're getting into like trippier territory as to is
there a residue on the places themselves that where like more kind of strange stuff goes on
like i i would say yes like i think a lot of the stuff that goes on at skinwalker ranch is
genuinely not you know we need to explain it via science but it's weird it's definitely weird like
i don't think that that show you know the secrets of skinwalker ranch yeah it might be like you know
you know the the the noise effects probably do it at disservice and you've got that kind of
history channel thing but like yeah it's produced it's produced but like i i don't think they're
lying about a lot of that stuff and if you again if you just investigate the you know first principles
like what's happening there it's pretty weird it's pretty weird it is so the cattle mutilation
thing though that they talk about on mirage men yeah is fascinating yeah what's your take there
oh i mean it just seems like a perfect distraction or just a psyop right i mean but it was all well
they it seemed like an unintended psyop that worked perfect for them right because i guess there was
some sort of they were trying to prospect for oil i think it was there was a company that was trying
to find oil by detonating an underground nuclear bomb uh-huh and they were trying to test the local
agriculture and wildlife to see how far the contamination went in the soil yep so they
were trying to find like they were extracting the glands of these cows to see if they had been
affected by this radiation or whatever see if there was contamination and that happened to be
the same place that they were flying this crazy exotic stuff yeah and so the people were like oh
my god we're seeing ufos and these cows are looking like this like it must be it must be them doing
this so it's like now okay that's the perfect place to keep doing these test flights yeah yeah
yeah sure sure yeah yeah that was super interesting to learn about that and to see how like you know
just just like two operations collide and end up being the perfect fucking mind fuck for the public
to like 100 make sure people don't know what's going on 100 100 no and that movie's super
important to realize how sophisticated a lot of the psyops can be and and and it's like you can
you know write scripts and backgrounds and like make everything kind of weave together and fit but
like the the a could you know be a data point b could be a data point that could be look completely
uncorrelated but like you're the source of both or whatever you know and like that's definitely
a thing you have to look out for in this world for sure so going back to barbara he was saying
that there was a secret place where they were trying to use these people that they captured
and give them drugs and get them to yep summon these ufos yeah stress inoculation and dissociation
and yeah it's like weird yeah and i think people who've had trauma in their past i guess are
predisposed of all of this is seems a little great i was saying it was dopaminergic drugs
that they were giving them yeah that might make sense yeah yeah i mean i again this is not based
on firsthand knowledge so i don't i don't know you know this is all like super super speculative
but i also like so i'm in the camp where i believe the summoning stuff is very real and very dangerous
and the i i feel pretty like you know like i think jake barbara's story is like pretty
beyond reproach actually on the like surface level details of it and then what do you mean by that
what do you mean it's beyond like you think it's super legit i think it's super legit yeah i do
where i get worried about what might be an after effect is this idea of like summoning
things into your purview i think that stuff's really real and i think it's dangerous i don't
think it's for the you know i think you have to have very pure intentions and i think if you show
up in certain places and you try to you know do these things i think that's it's very it's very
it could end very badly for for people so and i think it's the reason you have all this stuff
at skinwalker ranch where like often it's guys with big egos or whatever it's like they have
the story of this like hell's angels chieftain who like you know goes there and he's like put
into a catatonic state like on the mesa or whatever and then he has to go he's in the
hospital for three weeks after that and uh so i think it's i think it's kind of dangerous to
do some of this stuff if you're not doing it safely and and and honestly with it just pure intentions
what's the danger i don't you know have you uh you've had dana pesolka on right yeah okay so like
you remember the story with saint francis of assisi no so okay so he's this you know um he's
actually kind of grows up like kind of this popular guy and um you know he's kind of you know life of
the party kind of guy and then uh you know he becomes a brother and he's you know in a in a
monastery and he starts to become more religious and he's on mount laverne he's hiking with his
confidant brother leo who like records all the stuff that happens to him and uh he basically has
an encounter with an angel and the angel burns him and basically you know oh i remember this now
it gives him you know what he calls this he sees he says it's like a vision of christ but if you
actually go back to the original translation which pesolka did it's a flaming torch and which was it
uh it must have been uh uh latin oh latin yeah i think so medieval right yeah yeah probably latin
okay um so saint francis of assisi was when like uh in medieval time 13th century i think yeah okay
yeah um so like the subplot of the whole thing was saint francis of assisi is like he has basically
electromagnetic radiation damage and he calls it the stigmata he says it's a vision of christ but
like it's probably what you would say is just electromagnetic radiation now and he dies from
this stuff and if you look at the files given to gary nolan on people who've had you know paranormal
you know it basically encounters with ufos and with you know alien beings it's often electromagnetic
damage and you know ultraviolet burns and you you know i think some of these truths have been
disseminated through fiction if you watch close encounters of the third kind the guy's a sunburn
after he sees a ufo and i think steven spielberg definitely has some spooky sources and he has
across the years and so i think calling these things into your i think there are two things
that attract this stuff nuclear and and certain states of consciousness and uh the latter is
going to you know give a lot of people you know an allergic reaction if you're coming from kind
of like a you know more western materialist reductionist you know academia you know that's
that's that's where you're coming from but i do believe that's that's part of it and um
calling these things into your purview can be very dangerous a la all the files that nolan looked at
and a la what happened to you know st francis of assisi and i think as with all this stuff there's
a left-hand path and there's a right way to do it and the left-hand path is basically a cult stuff
it's like trying to summon stuff and yeah you're gonna get burned it's it's like it's a typical
every myth whether it's lord of the rings faust prometheus it always ends badly we've seen this
movie before if you want the secret knowledge and you don't have the right you know pure intention
in your heart you're just going to get burned because what you see will be an excavation of
what's inside of you i mean that
so you're saying that first of all when it comes to gary nolan he was looking at people who
who these people that he studied people that got injured and or died yep right after having radiation
poisoning or something like this from these these things those people how were they getting in
contact with these things were they summoning them so that's a total black box i don't know
i have no idea but i just think coming into contact with them it's like you know the legend
i'm not saying the ark of the covenant is real but this is a good analogy it's like you know the
holiest of holies if you don't go in with a pure heart it's going to be bad for you i think dealing
if you're dealing with this other world it's it's it's going to you know kind of see you from the
inside now and it's going to be very bad for you if you it's it's a it's a classic myth and i think
it's and i think it's it's not just myth i think it's very real i think we live inside of a cave
basically and and that cave is our kind of perceptive epistemology and if you want to see
something that's outside of the cave you can ask for it and it can come and you're going to get
you know hit like a load of bricks if you ask with the wrong intention
what you're describing sounds a lot like a psychedelic trip it's the exact it's very similar
because if you go into a psychedelic trip and you have a lot of ego going in yeah you're going to
get smashed yeah it's going and it's going to excavate it but it's not necessarily bad for you
it'll excavate what's inside of you often but it needs to be done in a way that like you can handle
and honestly i don't believe in psych that's why i don't believe in like i believe in like veterans
who are like on their last legs who need to take like ibogaine or like of course like you know or
like you know mushrooms or whatever but like this like oh let's just like you know willy-nilly do
this recreationally that i don't think that's going to be good at all the the veil we have it's
definitely not for everybody it's not it's not we have the veil for a reason you don't want to
unveil everything all at once right and so i i do believe that we have a very limited scope we only
see between 400 and 700 nanometers on the electromagnetic wave spectrum you know our
decibel range that we hear is limited like yeah the idea that like there's nothing outside of
what we see is ridiculous and then you have people like donald hoffman cognitive psychologists
showing that what we see are basically like icons of reality like they're categorizations of reality
like you're not seeing electromagnetic wavelengths you're not seeing the waves themselves you are
seeing this table right because you need to instantly categorize things yes so the idea
that we are seeing ground reality is crazy and then the idea that physics is the end of history
is also crazy like our consciousness definitely plays a part in what we're seeing you say you
experience synchronicities all the time you're basically admitting that your personal
epistemology is out of step with the western materialist dogma you're admitting that and
saying that and maybe you're saying i don't know it could be like the pattern matching of my mind
or whatever but if you like get down to it with most people they're like yeah a bunch of shit
happened to me that's like beyond chance and probability and there's probably something
with your consciousness that affects the material world or whatever so i think it's not beyond the
pale to say like if you want to experience something paranormal you probably will if you
like you know do certain things and doing that in a reckless way is very bad and doing that honestly
it's the whole issue i think with the ufo thing like the whole context of this conversation is
around weaponization of this stuff yeah and in certain cases i always like my rallying cry is
like it's actually bad for national security because like i want the powers that be to let
more out so that's like i'll say that right like it's bad for national security if the left hand
isn't talking to the right hand and like russia and china have their own ufo programs and they're
like beating us but my motivation is not weaponizing these things like i just i kind of
want to like poke the bear a little so they like let more out yeah because they are holding on to
a lot of stuff but the whole the fact that all this whole conversation is couched in like how
can we build weapons out of the like this like meta material that like is like mana from heaven
is so perverse and fucked yeah and so like my whole goal like to the extent that i ever do
anything in a capitalist context with the ufos stuff it's i want civil side infrastructure updates
in the our cities to make our lives better and i want more meaning in the world in people's
individual lives and if i can do that and have top cover from national security people who are like
yeah if you find something dual use we'll take it to the back room and work on it fine i'm cool
with protecting the free world and making sure we're ahead of china and russia but the whole idea
that like people's impetus into this topic like that the fact that they're into it is just like
let's weaponize this like immediately is so fucked like you don't know what you're dealing with it
probably is angels i mean that's that's the whole reason that we have everything that we have is i
mean the most absurd and mind-blowing science and technology that we have was literally created in
the context of war like john von neumann like you were saying the brain power of that motherfucker
yeah like was literally used and monopolized for war like they the i think i think it was him was
i think he was the one that calculated the exact elevation that the fat man little boy nukes needed
to be to cause the most civilian casualties like he he estimated the exact elevation they needed
to detonate those apps to kill the most people it's death that's death yeah it's so yeah i didn't
even know that's a that's a crazy yeah that's brilliant i mean in in anny jacobson's pentagon
brain book all about the history of darpa wow dude one of the most insane books yeah it's
that's an amazing book that's one of my favorite books she's amazing what like an epic chronicler
just love her man yeah and her voice god
she's a great voice she has like the best podcast she has the best voice the best voice
she's so seductive so funny yeah she's awesome but yeah no i don't know how i don't like
going to what you're saying i don't know yeah how you break the out of that right like how do you
break out of that that's that's the way the world works yeah that's the way the world works the the
the the main motivation for technological innovation is for super bow superpowers
to maintain their power and to gain more power well i think i mean again this requires a predisposition
to some pretty trippy kind of ontological world views but like i think the veil is dropping i
think like we're seeing more of this stuff now and it might be because we're not being super
responsible with our world we live in this multipolar nuclear world and you're right to
the extent we have access to you know anything off the books and you know of celestial origin
or whatever we're weaponizing it immediately and you know things are just not good on a global
scale right now no so i think what we might be seeing is kind of intervention a la the three
body problem or ufos and nukes with robert hastings where if you talk to any of these guys
any of the icbm security personnel any of these people you know firsthand witnesses
their first instinct is always they're trying to tell us to like stop our way you know to like
you know hang back and like not destroy ourselves so and then you can get into the mike masters
things where it's like you know is it some future version of humanity that is coming back in time
trying to protect sustain the existence of the human timeline because like we're going to blow
ourselves up yeah and who would care more than the future version of ourselves it's like and back to
the future where it's like you know marty goes back in time because he wants his parents you
know to be together yeah yeah and what mike says about that the pedomorphism yep thing that happens
how our ancestors that when the adults look more like the children of our of our descendants yep
is crazy that and that's like like all the depictions of aliens look like children
yeah that's right so in 500 000 years fully grown adults are going to look more like the toddlers of
today if you were to ask any conventional biologist like somebody who doesn't believe in
aliens what will humanity look like in a few thousand years you'd say okay humans are getting
domesticated so we're losing the melanin in our skin so it's getting kind of more pale our brains
are becoming selected for because of more white collar work so cranial size gets much bigger nose
and ears they don't matter so much because you know we're not hunter gathering right we yes there
is pedomorphosis there's neoteny we retain the larval features like of like young people in our
you know basically like your kids are going to look like what your ancestors look like in the
future right and and we're becoming domesticated a dog is to a wolf what we will look like you know
in the future is to us right and so i think yeah and then if you look at like all the databases
around ufo abductions over 50 percent in almost all cases are hominid creatures you know so and
and then and then you think the the likelihood of evolutionary convergence on zeta reticuli
proxima centauri of on them looking like hominid beings what are the changes their atmosphere their
gravity their solar system everything like like were they water worlds i know most of the godilocks
planets that we've discovered have been water worlds if i'm not mistaken so like if they evolved
in a world that was mostly water yeah it wouldn't look anything like us are they going to have a
brain that's directly on top of the head you have eight million species on earth and you have like
20 upright hominid exactly and then you have like one one that figured out the technology
right so you're saying like a gray looks exactly like us it doesn't make any sense that blew my
mind the most out of that book is how rare we are yes as as a species homo sapiens on planet earth
which is a a planet that's teeming with fucking life yes and how few planets that we've discovered
that are habitable of life and like what how much like he was basically saying it's like we are zero
point zero zero zero one percent of the species on this earth so if you extrapolate that out into
the universe and how many planets are able to inhabit life what's the chance they're going to
look like us like like that accurate yeah yeah it seems almost like impossible yeah no it's the
exactly it's the likelihood and if you're seeing a thing in your neighborhood it's more likely to
be related it's think about like north sentinel island is off the coast of india and they never
get visited occasionally by missionaries and they'll kill the missionaries right and they
probably think when people visit them like you know you're just some white dude and you like show
up there they'd be like you're an alien because they don't know the rest of the world exists
if you see a thing in your neighborhood and it looks like you it's probably an extension of you
it's probably related to you that's just kind of ockham's razor yeah so and then we have 20
billion you know earth-like planets in the you know milky way galaxy so people love to say that
but then you have over a trillion non-earth-like planets so again the likelihood that you are
seeing a thing in your neighborhood that looks like you doesn't only look like you looks like
what you probably are going to look like in a certain amount of time from a conventional
evolutionary biology perspective yeah it's probably i love the mike masters thesis as a result of that
where i think mike where i would disagree with him or where i think he might fall slightly short
and he would probably admit this because he's again he's done amazing foundational work is like
i don't know if it's us from the future i think we might be stuck in a time-bound reality where
we're subject to zeno's arrow of time where we are kind of indelibly permanently moving forward
in zeno's arrow of time and they have some ability to do trans temporal stuff where they can time
travel and so you get into all all these weird questions of like if time travel is future is
possible at any point in the future which he's saying it is right with his book because they're
saying they're coming back in time they wouldn't be able to go back past when that time machine
was created is that right that's right then it's always been inherently available if time travel
is available at any point in the future it's always been available inherently right so that
means time travel would have been figured out somewhere else in the universe yes that's right
and so then you get into these questions of like you have the angels and demons ontology and you
have the human future time travel to ontology i think a really valid you know use of like a
think tank would be like how do those two things comport are these ascended humans that have
trans temporal capabilities time travel capabilities that are like the next step on
the evolutionary chain and but they like saying future is kind of a misnomer because in their
paradigm time doesn't even exist the way it exists in ours right so i don't know you get into all
sorts of like crazy rabbit holes but what i love about that book is it's just it's very scientific
goes through cases and it goes through data to the extent we have data unfortunately the data is kind
of scant but it goes through the data and it just makes a very compelling ground up argument
for why time travel is involved and why they're related to humans and not just you know the time
dilation paradox thing is really interesting too like how he said that i love the part where
he's talking about like if we sent some um interstellar crew out into the universe to
find another planet or whatever he's like 20 years of their rocket time would be like a
hundred thousand years of our time here on earth totally so by like so half like 20 years into
their trip we we would have figured out technology on earth to be able to blow past them and like he's
he's like he's like 20 years into their trip we're gonna have people from earth passing them and they
just left that morning with a belly full of breakfast and they're like what the fuck we
wasted our entire lives on this like uh-huh that's an interesting paradox too oh it's a fascinating
one any of the whole planet of the apes that yeah it's like the time itself is very weird
in general relativity you have time dilation which we just described the twin paradox all that stuff
and then in quantum stuff i don't think we quite understand time we take it as like this formal
axiom in schrodinger's equation but it's actually kind of really weird and like time and gravity are
coupled in general relativity the closer you get to a gravitational source time slows and in quantum
stuff you can't fit we can't figure out gravity that's this big field of quantum gravity which
has turned into string theory which is like we've never been able to solve for for gravity we've
never been able to you know um fully you know uh figure that out i love that documentary you did
too with eric weinstein and uh yeah that was fun man like like string theory is some limited
hangout or something that's basically distract yeah eric makes that proposition he goes i don't
know he goes if you were trying to limit the physics string theory would be a pretty good way
to do it which that's gets beyond me okay it's like is string theory this like padded walls
2d version of the real physics that they have in the back room and it's just this like initiation
recruitment thing but it's like less dangerous i don't know if you can do that deliberately that
seems like maybe like beyond human coordination abilities that it gets beyond my physics knowledge
and eric might be able to speak to that more in a more sophisticated way as to like why that might
even be possible but crazy thing that he said that really that really resonated with me in that video
was he was like look at the civil war in 1860 at less than a human lifetime later we figured out
the fucking atom bomb yeah yeah i had to drop an atom bomb out of a plane in less than a hundred
years less than a hundred years less than a hundred years i mean so like just the understanding of
physics how that changes changes our world and our technology and our civilization we were using
muskets and yeah dude and from muskets to nukes to nukes and if you take the three body problems
seriously where you have the fermi paradox where it's like can you explain the three body problem
for people who might not comprehend it yeah it's like these these tricellarian
aliens that like we've been in contact with it takes place actually originally in the cultural
revolution in china and you have all these like scientists getting kind of like stamped out or
whatever and then you have modern scientists that are making contact with aliens and often it's in
these extremely advanced science projects like particle accelerators at places like cern
and they're getting all sorts of like interesting comms from the aliens and the tricellarian aliens
are like in touch with the government and they're like you cannot tell the populace that we are in
touch with you because it's going to like kind of you know it's going to tip off mass hysteria so
we have to like slowly infiltrate ourselves which is by the way very similar to arthur c clark's
amazing book childhood's end and i think this idea that like an alien civilization is slowly
incepting itself is very popular and actually probably a good answer to the you know fermi
paradox if you were incredibly sophisticated you wouldn't show up as this foreign invader hominid
you would just incept yourself you'd create hybrids you do genetic experiment you do all sorts of
stuff so what what were we just talking about why did i bring up the three-body problem do you
remember i forgot um oh we're talking about yeah yeah muskets to nukes yeah to nukes so like if
you take the three-body problem like in the three-body problem there's this dark forest analogy
and it's like the the universe could be teeming with life and it could be adaptive from the
perspective of an alien race to not show themselves to you because they're worried that you're going
to kill them or like going to harm them and why would they care until you start creating nukes
or like certain things that like maybe you reach a certain level of consciousness maybe you create
a nuke maybe it's high energy physics and maybe it's certain people reaching certain levels of
consciousness and then all of a sudden they make themselves known where it's like you're living
you you're living in this time-bound simulation and you're poking at the edges of the simulation
you can do it with consciousness you do with high energy physics and you know here we are like trying
to like you know guard guard the simulation um and like make sure you're not going to like
mess anything up in a big way um and so i think that's actually a very good answer to the Fermi
paradox it's like why don't they show themselves well there's actually like probably evolutionarily
adaptive for them to not show themselves it like makes more sense that they wouldn't in many ways
yes yes yeah that does make a lot of sense so you think what what are your thoughts on on the
whole string theory thing do you think that it's like i know i know eric's like gone off the rails
with it he says michikaku he's had a controller he's talked to michikaku yeah yeah yeah yeah i'm on
eric's side like i think clearly it doesn't work and like it doesn't take eric or any physicist
like you or me can say it doesn't work it like name me like a piece of technology that's come from
string theory right can't name anything unfortunately name me something that's come from quantum field
theory like semiconductors like a third of our economy quantum field theory so yeah so it's
like one thing is like this you're lost in like science is the map and not the territory in my
belief so yes like my my metaphysical worldview is more like play-doh like it's like there's
something beyond us that's true it exists in the world of like forms and ideas but like when it
comes to science i'm more kind of Aristotelian in that what is useful is true and the quantum stuff
is eminently useful if you want the most accurate sensor it's a quantum sensor if you want the best
computer you know eventually it'll be a quantum computer you know quantum stuff just seems to
work incredibly well especially at like lower scale subatomic scales and it's really useful
from an engineering standpoint and string theory is just basically trying to force fit what
describes our kind of cosmological worldviews of general with general relativity and quantum
field theory force fit them with math and so you have a map here that's not the map is not
the territory so you have stuff that you can do cool things with with quantum field theory you
have some stuff you can do cool things with with general relativity neither are descriptors of the
underlying reality so the maps are going to be a little jagged and off string theory is like you
have these jagged off maps that aren't perfect and you are forcing them together with math like it
doesn't take a genius like you or i could look at that and be like that's the wrong approach
yeah it's just the wrong approach so that's the way i look at it from like a more high level
perspective as to like you know whether it's some limited hangout there are all these really
interesting things i've uncovered with so the people that funded quantum gravity were you know
it was like uh uh initially kind of established at this chapel hill conference at university of
north carolina in 1957 yeah and it was this guy agnew bonson and he was obsessed with gravity
wasn't there also a guy named dewitt and then bryce dewitt yeah institute of field physics was
bonson's outfit and bryce dewitt was his chief theoretical physicist and he's basically convening
the top physicists in the world at the time i don't think anybody would argue with this like
john wheeler peter bergman you know freeman dyson like these legends and they're all trying to figure
out why gravity breaks down you know at subatomic scale so like why gravity doesn't work with
quantum stuff and that establishes the field of quantum gravity from which you could say string
theory is like a later offshoot right this is the crazy part bonson in the back room is funding
towns and brown and in my opinion i've uncovered all sorts of stuff as to why towns and brown
experimentally is figuring out real physics and is using these capacitors and with high voltage
experimentation in a way that ostensibly seems to create some sort of connection between a
electromagnetism and gravity which again if you were to talk to any conventional physicist they'd
be like if you can experimentally do that that is crazy leads to all sorts of amazing possibilities
yeah propulsion comms whatever and so i think bonson was like funding some like you know back
of the house research with this guy towns and brown who was according to a couple of books this
guy paula paula violette um he was maybe even at the chapel hill conference and the thing about
brown is he was never an amazing theoretician he was more of an experimentalist he was more
of a tesla type and he actually wasn't like traditionally super credentialed but he had
theories around what he was doing and i i think he was kind of breaking physics and and there
are all these kind of credible witnesses who saw what he was doing and were freaked out edward
teller was one of those witnesses who freaked out kurtis lame witnessed his experiments and so
you know i think he was doing some really interesting off the book stuff and then
meanwhile academic physics is being sent into a cul-de-sac being sent into a dead end is that
incidental and emergent i don't know i'm not i don't know how conspiratorial to be about that
but it's fascinating yeah um jeremy riss was explained to me alien scientist yeah he's awesome
he does great work on the he's like a fucking historian on this anti-gravity history he really
is yeah it's good the the amount of knowledge he has is on is unimaginable oh yeah but like i
think he was explained to me that um dewitt and witten were both working on this stuff previous
to that north carolina summit event or whatever yes so yes so okay and then here's the interesting
string theory connection lewis witten was the representative of that conference from rias which
is martin corporation's anti-gravity research group and so martin corporation is pre-lockheed
merger so it's the original lockheed martin has like an anti-gravity research group lewis witten
is researching gravity and he even says this there's a there's a video online where he says
i was uh i was meant to research gravity and right right field told me to research gravity
the whole conference is sponsored by right airfield that's crazy which is the epicenter
of all ufo lore bryce dewitt almost worked at rias as well and then he ended up at the
institute of field physics there are all these interesting aerospace connections john there
was so much it was so bound up in aerospace that john wheeler would complain at like the how like
tied in air tied to aerospace and anti-gravity like he he kept being like the you know all this
talk of anti-gravity it's just too much like we have to figure this out in like a serious academic
way yeah but that just shows you the prevailing ethos of you know the place itself and so it's
really fascinating right field had its own this guy named josh goldberg who is a phd from syracuse
and they were systematically studying anti-gravity anti-gravity in the 50s was
you know louis witten even says this in the wind meaning it was everywhere but it also the other
meaning of in the wind it's it's a spy term that could mean in the dark and so it's really
interesting like that there could be some double meaning there so the the tie between quantum
gravity and string theory is louis witten's son is a guy named ed witten yeah ed witten is the
number one string theorist you know in the world bar none and this is the guy that that eric was
talking about on the joe rogan podcast saying this guy is like untouchable he's like i'm so
scared michael jordan yeah yeah yeah exactly i'm so intimidated by this guy's intel intelligence
yeah exactly like alien level yeah exactly so so that's ed witten so that's the son of the guy
studying anti-gravity with martin corporation and establishing quantum gravity which is this
cul-de-sac so like your son is like the king of the cul-de-sac and like maybe there's some
interesting updates going on in the back of the house with guys like towns and brown who also
has a work history at martin corporation right he joined martin corporation in 1943 or two or
three right when skunk work starts the same year skunk work starts so there's some interesting
weird connections there a lot of smoke i don't have fire so this louis witten fella has anyone
talked to him have you ever talked to him has eric ever talked to him he is i think 99 years old or
something like say it's like in so he's super old and i have a friend who has corresponded
over email with him and as soon as he said you know hey i want to get into the anti-gravity stuff
the the line went dark and he stopped responding emails i make of it that we've made updates in the
world of gravity that are off the books and not and he you don't even need me to say this like
like the national science foundation is now coming out with these podcasts talking about
extended electrodynamics and literally scientific frameworks that if i were to say this a year ago
to you you'd be like that's quacky it doesn't make any sense and like this was relegated to like
zero point energy conferences in the southwest like that you know some crystal healer would
tell you about extended electrodynamics and you'd be like okay yeah go get but it's being
vindicated as real and uh electro-gravitics being vindicated a lot of people who are high up have
kind of like hey you're kind of on to things some things with this stuff and um i i just
interviewed carl nel who's the army representative for the uap task force worked alongside grush
extremely smart was the deputy cto of northrop grumman part of what the argument i made in my
towns and brown documentary is that some of this gravity you know interesting gravity stuff made
it into the b2 stealth bomber some of brown's work this is like the ion wind stuff like the
yes somehow because it looks like the the stealth bombers they look like
they defy gravity because they don't look built like they're like unless they have some super
powerful jet engines the the uh which they do but most legendary air airspace journalist in uh the
uk was a guy named bill gunston and he's writing a survey level overview of all aero tech you know
aero engine technology um since world war ii and he gets to the b2 stealth bomber and he says
um you know i do not wish to reside in the tower of london so i will refrain from talking about
clever wings with leading edges charged to millions of volts positive with trailing edges
charged to millions of volts negative he's talking about the b2 stealth bomber and um
your aerospace uh uh or aviation week aviation week bill scott another you know amazing uh
aviation journalist he says you know when when the b2 gets revealed you know early 90s he's like
the b2 surfs its own wave and uses a bifield brown effect some people even think b2 is stands for
bifield brown wow and so the majority owner of northrup where the b2 came from northrop grumman
so this is pre-merger with grumman the majority owner or the majority investor rather there's a
guy named floyd odlam he's a lawyer he's a financier for an aerospace he's funding brown's
research in santa monica right and the the research fails quote unquote in 67 then in 68
three months later because the end of 67 early 68 they publish a paper northrup saying we are
looking into electro aerodynamics and um and it's this paper that was archived in the american
institute of astronautics and aeronautics aeronautics and astronautics and that paper
just goes missing and so they retract that paper and say oh there's nothing to see here whatever
and then a couple decades later the b2 stealth bomber gets revealed so it's like you tell me
like i think there's a there there so so so basically in the 50s before that conference
in north carolina yeah like the idea is that or what eric was speculating is a possibility that
this stuff just went dark and got captured by these aerospace companies and like they came up
with a plan to basically like deceive the public send the public down the string theory rabbit
hole and take all this stuff that dewitt and witton and brown were doing and make this part
of this secret black project stuff i think it's hard to say whether we just had updates in
topological physics and experimental physics and we figured out some anomalies and like locally
useful frameworks where it's like we know how this works in the context of a single you know this
stealth aircraft but like how generalizable that gets like how much you can do with that i don't
know it's a total black box to me and i don't know how coordinated the sequestering of that
there's a ton of smoke there's there's not a lot of fire it's just hard to say and then you can
either say it was like sequestered by you know just humans you know where it's like you need
you need top side science you need black side science or whatever which we definitely have i
mean that's ridiculous to say we don't even like and you know uh mark and reese and ben horowitz
i think we're at the white house and like some national security council person was like yeah
we're gonna like regulate ai just like we regulated physics in the past physics you're talking about
physics so like this has definitely been done the idea that hasn't been done is absurd yeah um and
so is that coordinated on a human level do you believe the three body problem stuff where the
aliens are controlling the way science emerges to begin with right and like are they like playing
deceptive tricks on our top scientists and then like inspiring other scientists like
that are you getting to these like crazy questions i don't know how it went down
have we made updates in science in the black yeah like you watch my towns and brown documentary
i think it's hard to come out of it being like this stuff is fake like if you actually like
ingest the details it's like absolutely like i even may have to think probabilistically but
80% yeah yeah um and then so go back to jake barber so so going back to this uh jake barber
thing where they're getting these psionic assets from other countries and getting them and putting
them in this program using drugs and using protocols to get them to sort of summon these
things he's saying that they're using these people to summon these crafts did he say he had
any idea where they were coming from no that that was um the jake interview was simultaneously
felt historic and epic and he was so articulate and like such a good you know purveyor of like
so intelligent clearly grush yeah yeah totally and then where it was incredibly frustrating
even in a way that like grush grush is like can get into the theory and speculation
and is like a good fact finder and it felt like with jake he was just he really wanted
to like keep to like the core details of like what he experienced and it it made it it was a
little frustrating for me because i i think i'm strongest on the theory stuff and like that's
i always want to get into that shit right and like i understand his position to like not want to you
know totally go off the rails and speculate into crazy stuff and then there was uh some sort of
tough book hard drive that was uh held underwater in a glacier lake yep and top of a mountain
yep yep yep and then and he had to like retrieve that and then they were trying to like sever the
hidden like they were trying to like basically uh get rid of him and like like because when
you're when you're like sheep dipped like that and you're like you know director of operations
for a helicopter uh company there's so much plausible deniability your employer can just
be like that dude what do you tell that guy's crazy you know just like people in the public are
now saying you know jake's crazy or whatever even if though you know all these guys with dd
214s and like clear history are like coming to back him up and i think he's totally legit but
like who's coming who's backing him up uh you know this guy don paul uh don paul bales uh
there's other guys that ross colthart has interviewed um so he's one uh fred baker is another
um john blitch i think knows him less well doesn't have like a you know as much of a history with him
but he's a he's a darpa guy uh who's come out and he vetted him i think on behalf of grush and some
other people to see if he was the real deal and like he was like yeah this guy's story totally
comports with like the that world that i've you know come to know and research a little bit so
it just seems so crazy to me that they're like we on earth with our motives our military motives
and our financial motives are able to do something as crazy as summon something from another fucking
dimension and crash it yeah so we can study it it feels crazy to me too the the thing the question
that that begets which i think is really important that we should all question is like you hear that
we only have i don't know 10 to 15 ufos in our possession they're in specific hangars or whatever
or maybe you get one you know some people say one to two crashes a year so that would be you know
since roswell maybe since a little before that say 120 or whatever you know whatever
but if you can like summon these things on command then you'd expect us to have a thousand plus
right if you have a thousand plus you're going to get leakage yes right so like it can't be this
like you put a coin in the slot machine that you know the drink comes out sort of vibe like it
can't just be this like extremely repeatable predictable thing right it has to be more
hard to you know successfully do than that and so yeah there are all these questions that the
interview begets that i think people should ask because i yeah i don't know the answer to them
yeah and they're like why like why isn't he or people he knows or even greers people being put
in front of congress and and testifying all their stuff yeah why are they and jake jake has said i
would 100 testify before congress and so that again that show of confidence i think is important
you know to to which look i my guess is congress has been lied to before i like i've been in like
rooms with congress i'm like god these guys are so they're not smart but like um but uh you know i
think just the fact that he's he's willing to do that i think and going under oath under you know
threat of perjury i think is you know a good a good display yeah um so again i think that the
the details are you you know everybody has to think probabilistically but i think they're
they're they're pretty solid and then it's like and then there are so many other questions it
begets where it's like what yeah yeah like what you were saying about like like being afraid to
interact with this or try to interact try to summon it or try to somehow like do some one of
these ce5 things that that greer talks about you know and one of the things that um i think i
talked about with greer was this hitchhiker effect yeah that happens where like not only can
people get damaged or hurt or killed by the radiation or whatever it is that these things
have but like there's some sort of portal that's permanently opened with you if you're able to
interact with this stuff or even see it to where now like you have all you have unlimited access
to all this crazy um paranormal stuff yeah like some of the stuff that you see a skinwalker that's
extremely common like everybody's yeah the skinwalker is a great example and in those
cases i think it was very negative because again i think if you're trying to like weaponize this
stuff it explains yeah these kind of hauntings where these you know aerospace practitioners
come home and their their kids and their family get haunted by this stuff it is like they have
like residue lou alzondo always calls it a sticky portfolio and i think he calls it that for very
specific reason which is like stuff gloms on to you yeah like what you know it's like you stare
at the abyss long enough the abyss stares back and i i think that's just a truism especially in
this topic and then what do you make of all like the infighting of all these people like like
alzondo versus greer versus like yeah like you have alzondo calling greer a terrorist i think
right right and like you know and simultaneously these guys are all writing books going on all
these podcasts it's just like what it's it's it's it's weird uh and at times i see you know all the
infighting and i'm like i'm like tired like i i just want like more of like a normal life and like
why am i like covering this like it's just so ridiculous um so we used to get fatigued by it
it is it is i think like the meta psyop would be like you get distracted by this internal drama
or whatever and like a rule that i really try to adhere to is i don't go after anybody ad hominem
there's like a map that i have of ufo and like i should say this for the sake of your audience
and my audience there are people i've interviewed that i suspect have ulterior motives i don't call
out those ulterior motives because i'm in enough danger seeking truth and i don't want to be like
i don't want people like specifically coming after me because i'm like fucking with them
not only that but there are people with ulterior motives where like we said earlier
there are elements of truth to what they say and like a lot of what they people can tell the
truth in limited ways and have ulterior motives that's what people don't understand so you can
sift out valuable stuff so i think the the the best way is you know just be open friendly cool
with everybody you know i'm cool with you know the two guys you just mentioned i guess we're
i haven't met yet but like i would be cool with him you know i'm just i just try to have like an
open honest fun conversation and then glean out what i think is true and honestly ask rhetorical
if there's any untruths you ask rhetorical questions that like show on the face of it
that like there's something kind of going on here but like you don't have to call it out directly
because it's just you're just going to end up in some fucking food fight on twitter and it's going
to waste your time and you're not going to get close to the truth that way right you're going
to get distracted by like getting into it the times i feel conflicted about having that
predisposition is like i do think there's been like harassment of people and i see it on like
twitter and other places and like that fucks with me because i'm like i want to like come out and
defend you know anybody who's been harassed just for looking into this stuff yeah and then and by
the way i've faced it too and there's stuff i could tell you that would like i could tell you off
it's fucking crazy as far as stuff that's happened come my way really yeah yeah so yeah
so like that that riles me up for sure wanting to defend other people but otherwise man it's
just like it's a it's not it's a fool's errand trying to like get you know come after somebody
yeah i agree you know so i just i try to stay like pretty you know switzerland-esque it seems
like you're the closest dude out there to this stuff like you're it seems like you have like
flown closer to the sun than anybody that's not good man icarus does not oh no like the people
you know and the circles you run in like i mean i mean i'm not even just talking about
working for peter teal but like being befriending grush and you know talking to all these secret
aerospace people and getting all this stuff like you your brain you probably got more this puzzle
put together than most people i thank you i mean a hundred percent you have more of the puzzle
than most people that are like in the media doing podcasts but like even when it comes to behind the
scenes shit i thank you for saying that i don't know if that's a good spot to be in you that's
what i'm saying i'm like if i'm if i'm one of these people or if i'm one of these folks that
are in charge of this stuff i'm gonna be maybe trying to get to you and subvert you a hundred
percent i think i'm being fully tracked at all times i think every every conversation every text
every interaction um and uh i think they're insights that i've probably come to that have
been gleaned and like taken for you know profit or whatever and uh you know that's kind of weird
but like you gotta just uh kind of ignore it put your blinders on keep going used to get to me more
and now i just try to you know i think if you have pure intentions and you're just trying to
seek truth then i think things end well for you karmically you know but yeah it's it for sure it's
a weird spot to to be in i think it is partially because like if somebody tells me something and
then they say not to say it like i i respect relationships like really like i don't if somebody
you know is providing a you know as a source for something like i really i don't fuck people over
right like and and even like i think in the microeconomics of like podcasting journalist
world it's like some of these people would like push their grandma in front of a moving taxi for
a tip you know for a story and it's like i just don't do that shit like i just i uh you know and
then if it that cuts against the truth i'm just not going to air it i'm not going to put it out
you know but i'll kind of walk away not touch the fine china and be like i kind of know what
you're up to but like i don't want to what would you do if the cia came to you jesse michaels we
needed to have a talk we're going to tell you everything we're going to give you access to
everything but you need to shut the fuck up or you need to just run with the stories that we gave you
the green light here's the thing i think national security jesse i think that's a counterfactual i
don't think the cia has everything i don't think right the government has everything and i realize
this might be a you know slightly evading your question but it's like genuinely i think it's so
important to to emphasize for people like if this is not a file that you can just get the government
has tons of data that like reality is not what it seems they probably have meta material there's
probably some biologics there's probably you know there's a lot of stuff that where they like know
reality is way weirder than what the average civilian does in fact i think that you would
say this too the closer you get to government circles the more they're conspiratorial than the
average citizen like they're more conspiratorial so they know that does that mean they have like
an ontological worldview a map of what the aliens are what their intentions are how many races there
are where they're from whether they're interdimensional extraterrestrials absolutely not i think maybe you
get in a certain core circles and areas they have better frameworks than you know people on the
civil side do what if it was battelle that came to you jesse michaels we need to have a talk brother
we're gonna fund your podcast five million dollars a year subsidized by no way i would i would never
get like funded if the funding involves like steering the content like now yeah um if it's
like educational and like you know in in order to like tell the truth about something and there was
some like public private partnership i would entertain it especially if i could be open
to that to the public and i wasn't like lying about that yeah for sure like i don't think like
everybody in government's like a bad person or like right it's not a monolith right for sure um
but yeah no i wouldn't like i wouldn't do some like intentional limited hangout thing yeah yeah
it'd be it'd be an interesting bridge to cross if the opportunity ever presented itself i always
think about that is that your pitch nanny yeah you're like you're like just hit me up
that's so funny uh yeah would it matter because i mean most people online already think that
we're cias i know dude it's exactly half the people are like he's a spook and he's funded
by peter teal and blah blah blah yeah right yeah you're already you're already you got an uphill
battle that's an uphill battle for sure for sure and like i don't know i always just like okay don't
trust anything i'm saying like fine and then like the people who do like you're gonna learn a lot
of crazy shit because i'm revealing like really crazy shit stuff that i came to on my own and
honestly i've lost i've put a lot of money like like the opportunity cost involved in like study
like going after ufos like i i managed like nine figures of capital like i was investing a lot of
money in a way that would have been like really good for my future if i wanted like a chill good
life like i had that like set up like i easily could have kept going on the path that was going
on do some conventional venture fund yeah you know have fucking cocktails at happy hour in la
go fucking bevely hills hotel and go to like i could have done that and i and i decided to go
like a way more masochistic route so it's fine like you can call me whatever but like trust me
it's not fucking that yeah how do you have time to do the investing stuff anymore i honestly don't do
that much of it anymore it's like yeah it's like most of what we've done like i'm managing up on
you know like existing investments and just making sure they're going well and i'm like in touch with
the you know the fund managers that i've sourced as well as uh the companies themselves and then
occasionally if something jumps the bar and feels like a no-brainer i'll do a little bit of i'll do
diligence on like you know an early stage thing where it's more qualitative and not quantitative
analysis and i'll do a deal but it's like i was deploying much more money three years ago than
i am now so it's just slow down right what is to you what is the absolute spookiest darkest
sinister theory about what these things are that you've heard that you may not believe but that
you've heard that you think may have may have some little bit of merit like the one that you
don't want to be true i can't say it really yeah it's too dark yeah it's really fun you can't say
because you'd be betraying somebody or because you just know put it out there i don't put it out
there really yeah there there are well there are probably good factions that are angelic you know
to use a simple term and then bad factions that are demonic and then what are the demonic things
doing it looks like maybe they're mining our attention you know like robert monroe who studied
consciousness and you know um you know virginia has this institute you know that he started
like he had this concept of louche and so maybe there's stuff like that going on where like
when you're in a zombie state where does your consciousness go maybe that's sort of like a
mining process but then you look at like you know scapegoating cycles like pagan scapegoating cycles
and like i don't know you get in a weird territory and like it's hard to i don't know what the darkest
you know theory is but um i think the the good ones are like don't don't interfere
as much with you and you're more like you're ascending to their level and it's like a two-way
bilateral connection where like one of my favorite quotes is uh the world is full of magical things
patiently waiting for our wits to grow sharper and it's like there's once if if you can like
increase your own you know kind of spiritual sense and your knowledge and you can increase
the purity of your intention i think you get closer to to truth around a lot of these things
and i think this idea this bifurcation this idea that it's just academic rote knowledge that you
have to learn and then this kind of you know spiritual sense like that's totally different
like your own you know moral development as a person yeah i think they're go hand in hand
and i think the more you do that the more you have synchronicities the more you get in touch
you feel this sort of angelic guidance in your life the more you feel protected and the and and
and uh and so i think whatever's good is like this kind of non-interferent initiation process
and then the bad stuff you know i don't know in the world in which these beings exist they're
probably behind a whole lot of human affairs and they're probably stoking wars and causing
violence and division and then you have to ask why and i don't know why right well i mean why
wouldn't they be like us right why wouldn't there be good versions and bad versions totally
totally yeah you have good and bad humans yeah yeah i i agree with that have you ever seen a ufo
in real life oh yeah yeah yeah really yeah i've seen more than one see that's the thing that i
i'm kind of like on the fence about sure because like like me and you talk about this stuff all the
time but i don't know if i want to have any of these experiences yeah i don't know if i want to
actually encounter this kind of shit in real life i don't know how it would affect me i think that's
totally valid and i definitely don't want to have an abduction experience like i actually get
everybody i interview who's had an abduction experience my buddy from yes theory amar can
deal who does a lot of the shows with me i make him come with me because he's like this like
positive energy like protective energy bubble and i'm like i get spooked i get freaked even with
witley i was a little freaked out dude i've never been more terrified yeah and he'll say stuff like
oh people he said it with you i remember he said like people who are with me sometimes have like
experiences and i remember you're like i was like i don't want that he's like it might happen he's
like absolutely it'll happen to you i'm like please no yeah okay i'll tell him not to yeah yeah yeah
no i i think um any jacobson when she wrote a great book the phenomenon um yes also i think
she was like she was talking to jock valet and she was like please like don't don't i just don't
want to get abducted like i'll study this stuff but yeah once you start studying this stuff you
the second you realize like a switch in your brain goes off and you're like okay this person's not
crazy and they've been abducted like this stuff's actually just real then it freaks you out because
you're like uh-oh am i you know so i i i feel that on the abduct i don't want to get abducted man
no i don't want to ever see any of these things in my bedroom same same but i do think there's a
huge difference between that and like being inspired by some like cool craft in the sky like i
think yeah kind of chill yeah i think it's and for me that was like a that was like a beautiful
like what kind of great experience what did you see exactly although i will say abduction experiences
i think over 50 are often described as positive so or yeah over 50 are are are positive at least
in the free edgar mitchell study but oh okay i saw because whitley's is a horror movie yeah i know
i know and a lot a lot are and a lot again if it goes back to that like droid gray thing where
it's like we do not fear but then they're like bleeding everywhere and they like put a little
thing in you and they black out and it's like oh god that doesn't sound good at all um my uh ufo
experience well i had i had two that like really stand out and that are one was in laurel canyon
and i talked about this on julian dory's podcast as well where it looked it looked like a school
bus or something like it was like nothing like prosaically that i ever see and so that's why
i'll call it a ufo i don't know you know if it could have been aerospace but it was
hovering above the treetops at like you know 40 50 feet it was it was going across the treetops and
then the uh the woman i was with she said that she saw the thing like descend down like uh across
the the treetops in laurel canyon i didn't see that but what i saw was like it was like this
like kind of tesseract like rectangle shaped like school bus like thing that like i've just
never seen before ever and was so weird and the way it came about was also weird too because
aliens had just come up in our discussion so it was like one of us was like do you believe in
aliens and like and then at some point i was like ah yeah i'm kind of super into aliens actually
i think it's really interesting and then i was like i kind of i'd be interesting to meet an alien
and then she goes um it'll come when you least expect it and this is the weirdest part of the
stories we walk by a guy who's has a metal detector and it's like sun a little after sunset
or sunset in laurel canyon and it's like why does he have a metal detector he's like looking for
something and it says it'll come when you or she said it'll come when you stop looking for it and
he's like looking for it this is a little weird yeah and that could be again me noticing too
many patterns but like um then we walk and we just see this little clearing and then the thing goes
over what color was it it was gray metallic and uh yeah it was like seemed like i don't know it
wasn't making like enough noise where like the amount of weight that it was carrying like you'd
expect like an absurd amount of noise yeah like apache level like 10 apache level you know so
super super strange and it was around a time in my life where i was experiencing a lot of kind of
like interesting synchronicities and like things would kind of pop into you know that was when i
was around the time when i met diana pusulka actually and like i started to kind of take
take more of a dive down the down the rabbit hole and the other time i was doing holotropic
breath work in silver lake with a friend a friend who's i i won't out him but he's a prominent
investor who's like as rational as it gets like he's actually really interested in like philosophy
and you know academic science and stuff and like the way he described his worldview is like
the natural philosophers like david hume super nanome chomsky like he couldn't be more like
the material world is what it is like he's kind of like a material world like a materialist atheist
you know and we had just gone surfing and then we're back at his spot in silver lake and i want to
teach him holotropic breath work which is i love holotropic is the best and uh we're doing it and
he kind of like five minutes in like your your hands can kind of clam up it's like a common thing
and like you get into like an interesting state and all of a sudden he looks up he's like what is
that oh my god two metallic or like one above him one above me they look like they're way too
high to be you know prosaic aircraft i i wouldn't be able to tell you like what you know 60 000 80
000 but like they were high up and they were like bobbing like hovering and uh he go this is so funny
initially he goes i goes what i go what the fuck do you think those things are and he goes
i think those that must be one of those like deep black you know lockheed crafts or whatever
and i'm like interesting and then a second later he goes dude those are not like of earth
how long ago was this this was 2020 2020 yeah this is either that was either the um the laurel
canyon one was 2020 that was either 2020 or 2021 okay either late 2020 or early 2021 yeah
holy shit yeah yeah it's interesting the only thing i've ever seen was with chris bloodsoe
so you saw u of oh yeah i mean i don't think you don't think it was nothing like that it was
just like a ball of light okay like what he said what he the stuff that he summons and he was
trying to do it when you were with him yeah he was praying and do you i don't know like okay
gun to your head you're wrong if you you know you're wrong and you die okay would you say that that
was like human aircraft or prosaically explained ball lightning or whatever or like some kind of
celestial like otherworldly thing i would say if i had a gun in my head i and my my best guess
yeah would be that it's some sort of natural phenomenon that happens in the atmosphere
that we just don't that i just don't notice because i don't stare at the sky enough yep
because me and steven were out there for two hours trying to find something okay praying to
the heavens and then we saw this thing it was definitely not an airplane yep i know it wasn't
an airplane what it looked like we have a video it was a it came off of the horizon it was like a
little ball of light came up off the horizon where the water met the the air and it came up
started going this way then got really really bright then got really really dim
and then just fizzled out so how so how would you explain that from a scientific perspective
i don't know yeah i don't know ball lightning something like that like a like ball lightning
some sort of atmospheric anomaly yeah but was there anything that would you know cause ball
lightning i had no idea i don't know i don't know the science behind it but like if i was till the
i know it was not an airplane yeah yeah yeah and the way it was moving was definitely showed that
it wasn't an airplane because we saw airplanes that were flying there was there was airplanes
flying off the beach or off of the ocean on to land to land in tampa airport and they had
navigation lights flashing and stuff like that they were obviously following a specific flight
pattern and this thing was not doing that didn't have the flashing lights it got brighter dimmer
fizzled out to nothing came up there it is came off the atmosphere so this is the horizon of the
can you see the horizon down there where it's like because it's so dark it's like one more time
it's in north korea no this is here out here there it is oh there's something right on the water
right on the water thank you thank you if you could flash for us that's an airplane on the top
that's not uh-huh i'm getting it right there now it starts going to the right
it's still in here and now another one above it see yeah and it's zigzagging that one fizzles out
look at this one on the left look at this one look how bright it's getting wow here someone
needs to look through this it's very bright thank you oh you see it it's right there you see it
that is definitely an orb i'm tracking it here do you want to look yeah and then it fizzled out to
nothing let me find it yeah fade it in and fade it out they were seeing it with the naked eye i
didn't see it until i put in his little psionic camera thing that sees in like the dark but like
maybe it's something to do with that camera but i don't know also they were seeing it with their
naked eye uh-huh but like i don't know how do you explain that i don't know i gotta talk to somebody
who knows about like this stuff i mean i don't know do you see how it comes off of the horizon
like that though that's crazy yeah do that again steve yeah because that's is that water rewind
that's water yeah go to the very beginning yeah so what is the controller too so we can see the
horizon watch watch look at that what yeah yeah yeah yeah
it was so far away you know it was like how many how far away would you say that was steve
i think the from our vantage point the horizon is probably like three miles
yeah we kind of start going to the right too yeah yeah and then it kind of goes back it kind of
zigs it yeah like what flies like that i don't know i think there's something there's definitely
something to what he's doing like what he's doing is absolutely i agree legit and real i don't know
how to explain it do you sense interesting energy when you're around him like do you just like feel
it like i don't know what to attribute that to i don't know whether to attribute that to whether
i'm i am just sort of being affected by the energy and that's just a normal thing like it's just his
vibe that he gives off yeah you know and it's just affecting me like affecting my soul in a way where
i'm like i'm in it and i'm believing it in the moment i'm like oh my god wow this is
fucking blowing my mind this is real what is this yeah or like like i said is this something that
you could just go anywhere and stare at the sky all night long and see this stuff all the time
that seemed anomalous to me at the very least that doesn't seem like if you were to do some like
meta study on like the probability of seeing that even in a two-hour period where you're staring at
the sky extremely low yeah what is that right that's weird now i'm not saying that that's
definitely ufo an angel an orb i don't know but but it i think it's worthy of a investigation
yeah and then like detractors would say that like maybe he sets somebody up with a boat and a drone
outside there but like off the beach do you get that vibe from him i don't at all no like i get
i get you know maybe everybody in ufo world or a lot of people are credulous and high on the openness
scale i don't from my you know conversations with chris blood so i think he's a good person
me too and and and also he had no idea where we were going to dinner that night we just went to i
told him a random restaurant i took him to on the beach he didn't know where it was and i said or
afterwards i'm like you want to go to the cross of the beach and see if we can do this he's like oh
yeah let's do it i got my camera with me and his daughter and his wife and his his uh his his
daughter's wife were also there yeah and and he just did it yeah i don't think that's a hoax man
no it's not something going on there's something going on and the wildest thing
is all these people that are attaching themselves to them which is like the craziest thing crazy
people where if i mean dude like we're in like a cold war with china why would we be spending
those sorts of resources on a guy who's seeing orbs you know in north carolina outside his
backyard if it weren't something actually kind of profound and interesting like why right like
because these guys are we're not just connecting dots here like this is like legitimate stuff
yeah yeah like this stuff is all documented that the people that are that are visiting him and
befriending him yeah jim semivan is like very well respected at the cia yes he's like pretty
i think high up and like he spent a lot of time with chris bloodsoe yeah i think they're good
friends yeah so yeah it's interesting that combined with the fact that that video is completely
went unsearchable in one in an instant that's wild on youtube that's weird and we're like i was
good like after that thing dropped i would go every day you probably do this where you just i
searched chris bloodsoe on youtube every day yeah for like the first week just to see where it was
ranking right it was top for the first week the day it dropped you couldn't find it you would
you could go a thousand pages deep and never find it it was just it was just four or five or six
history channel videos of him with on the history channel you want to know something funny
you could type in david grush to this day i'm not to toot my own horn but the video i did with him
is the best video that he has oh i agree and like you can't find it you could type in david grush
on youtube and it's news nation rogan a bunch of other things and it's my thing is unsearchable
and in five days or six days got well over two million views and then it just got throttled
and and everybody i mean i'm working with yes theory on it they have nine million subscribers
on youtube and i'm showing them the stats like the click through rate and average view duration
they're like we've never seen anything this high like what like what the fuck and like you watch it
and it's like very watchable yeah and it's just here we're going through right now it's like we're
searching david uh with the c is that it yeah but go to dave david uh grush have you seen it before
uh i don't know search go down look there it is bro that looks good we're back baby it definitely
was it and like i have an email chain with google about where it wasn't so like here's what i have
the receipts that it was unsearchable this happened to my whitley streber episode too only for the
first two weeks okay after the first two weeks they put it back well also go on incognito i do
want to see if it's the same because you open up a new because you've seen the video open up an
incognito browser yeah a new private window yeah whatever but you're saying that it can get off
get off brave get off brave go to go to chrome yeah sometimes what they'll do is they'll make
it invisible on search for the first two weeks when it's going to get shared the most and go
viral catch traction the most after the first two weeks you're already posted your next video
then they'll put it back so they can plausibly deny the fact that okay so we're good now we're
number two now type in chris bledsoe yeah let's do that
which is all it's been a year now so it's not as relevant but yeah scroll down that's my boy chris
randy made an epic one keep going keep going just go faster you'll be able to you'll definitely
notice it if it pops up see those history ones were the first ones to pop up last time and yours
just just nowhere to be found and you know it's funny there was even a guy who re-uploaded my
full podcast on his channel with him reacting to it that was popping up what yeah oh shoot it's
really good yeah that was the same with the grush thing for me originally it was like all these like
like analysis of the video videos were ranking high it's now now go back to the top steve nuts
man and yeah yours was like the first big one go back to the scroll of the very top it's still the
most viewed i'm pretty sure go to the and get out of the search thing see where it says filters on
the far right yeah filtered by most viewed yeah it's probably yours top top no yeah right view
count yeah view count 3.9 yeah no that's you yeah yeah nasa's forbidden alien wow holy crap wow wow
that's wild man and you have in your tags and stuff you have like of course yeah no like i said it
was the number one search result for the first something like two weeks that's so it's crazy to
see mine number two yeah right well dude i i swear to god no i know the guy youtube literally
told me this yeah he told you that exactly that mine was like fell off a cliff views wise yeah
and it went completely invisible went completely invisible yeah and then yes theories they say okay
this is crazy yes theories they say it's the best stats they have on any video and it's one of their
lower it's like in the lower 25 viewed videos it only has 1.1 million views which for them is
2.1.2 or 1.1 million views which for them is extremely low like they have crazy crazy high
viewed stuff yeah and the stats are like off the charts so like they're also like super
conspiratorial about them and they're like the most like kid-friendly do-gooder like they're
like the best vibes like they're not and like they're not breaking rules they're not breaking
rules and like when they're like yeah we're getting throttled like i'm like oh yeah
yeah people some people are are speculating that the uh the trump thing is gonna do like some sort
of a trust bust on youtube and and force them to stop regulating this stuff so much and stomping
on content well dude trump made that like misinformation is bullshit like you know it's
like this like speech or whatever like right when he got elected i loved it to me i
misinformation is so condescending yes who is the arbiter of misinformation like why are you
why do you decide you're so wrong you've proven to be so incompetent in the context of the pandemic
and covid yeah and all these other things like the history of american false flags why are you the
arbiter well like why bbc trusted news initiative cnn you can say what is misinformation you don't
think for yourself like it's ridiculous so let everything out and let people decide yeah let
people decide what they think is bullshit and what they think is real yeah no the the um the
mike ben stuff really illuminates all that disinformation misinformation stuff and how
they go to like other countries and like force them to regulate stuff and they basically hold
the corporations like they pit them against like maintaining their monopolies overseas like okay
well if you're gonna if you're gonna censor this stuff we'll let you keep your monopoly in europe
right like dude that stuff is crazy it's crazy and speaking of the that in the context of the ufo
topic i should say the usaid funded the intercept we know that for sure ken clippenstein
came out with basically leaked dave grush's uh medical records and uh and that is what like
kind of marginalized grush for a for a while i mean i think most people don't really like realize
it's bullshit i mean the dude like it was an afghanistan combat veteran was deployed and like
his buddy like died next to him was like mortared and stuff like it's just fucked up like it and
that's what they're in like so like you know when he would drink occasionally he would like go
through that he would resimulate those feelings for him and ken clippenstein who's working for
a usaid funded publication is leaking these medical records right after grush testifies
before congress to discredit him it's just weird man yeah that is super fucking feels really
coordinated god man yeah the usaid thing is like such a nuclear bomb for the for the government
yeah like that that stuff is just bananas and how it's like you can't escape it it's too big it's
too big to to squash we've just been living in managed reality yeah for decades yeah yeah yeah
spending spending two billion or how many billions of dollars on on trans operas in
the ukraine and like all this stupid stuff they're funding everywhere like yeah god damn ian carroll
has been doing a great job of talking about this stuff this he does like crazy deep dives on us
aid and all this stuff he's awesome yeah he's dope have you have you um are you familiar with
like the history of google and serguey brin and like google being incubated by the cia and nsa
you were telling me some stuff here i mean i know that uh men x right was like the darpa
search engine that kind of dovetailed with google but otherwise i don't you tell me yeah so no
there's a um i don't know much about it other than this like crazy article i read on it recently
about this guy forget the guy's named uh it was on substack i think and he wrote um he did like a
super deep dive and it's all connected to um serguey at stanford was and the guy that he was
working under were literally funded and visited the whole time and incubated by cia and nsa people
that were visiting him and like checking in on him with the search with the page rank system
and all this stuff and giving him stuff that was created by darpa like it's all connected to darpa
and saic and like all this crazy military industrial complex stuff i say i see was
you know based in palo alto yeah yeah so like it's a it's so like it basically where did you
learn all this from these from the stuff that i read wow and it's it the implications of it is
that google was quite literally funded and created by the cia and darpa so what does that even mean
like how do you like well you know you know like oracles first contract was with the cia yes and
like i do think a lot of this stuff gets created in the black right well so it's palant here too
right like palant like like like i understand that i understand why you would want to create companies
that you're you're literally you're you're doing it in reverse instead of creating a company and
finding clients you're you're finding a hole or you're finding a need that the government has
a government who has billions of dollars in in resources to invest in this stuff find a way to
do it better and you're basically creating a company that already has a built-in client
the u.s government which is like essentially what palantir is right or what elon's doing with space
i think it's what it ended up becoming i think originally it was like around like some of the
fraud detection stuff they were doing at paypal or whatever dovetailed with the software for
palantir and then i think the cia became one of the first customers right um but i don't think
it was created in in conjunction with right but i'm just saying if it was me and i was if i was
one of these guys that was creating one of these crazy companies right that was doing surveillance
and and whatever the hell it does like i would say we have a huge opportunity to make millions
of dollars off the government doing this stuff because we can do it better than they can do it
right i think if you've even had guys in here like andrew bustamante who have literally said
palantir is way better than all the stuff that we have at cia like we use palantir
like it's it's it works way better right right so like right it's a great business proposition
yeah to create a company like that yeah but like find out who wrote that article about um google
i think the i think the title of it was um how google how google made or no no it was how the
cia created google interesting and it's on sub stack i want to give this guy credit there's um
while you're looking that up there was a project at darpa called life log and it was like you know
like networking all these people and like their friends and like their friend networks and i think
it was shut down in 2003 or four right before facebook started so i do find that kind of
interesting too but i don't i have again i have no idea if there's a connection there yeah but it is
no this isn't it steve it's uh you don't have to type in um did you type in sub stack after oh yeah
you did keep going uh i mean medium medium that's it right there yeah that's it i'm sorry i messed
up this is it oh you can close that close that bottom thing and you'll be able to see who it's
by at least credit the author how the cia made google by naf nafis ahmed ahmed nafis ahmed dude
this is mind-blowing it's a two it's a two uh there's two articles like a series of them
i can't wait to read this but it's great man interesting blew my mind wow well i always found
it interesting like they were kind of i mean it makes total sense especially with the snowden
stuff in 2013 like prison bull run all that stuff came out and it's clear that the nsa just had like
backdoors into like all of these big tech companies and then they had they the nsa had a program i
think at the time called heartbeat which is like you can like basically query anybody's you know
data or whatever like in like this like centralized database repository so yeah we know that that was
a thing at the at the very least but i found it interesting when google like uh as part of
project maven like wouldn't work with the u.s government and then simultaneously they were
going into china like that same year and so there's like something i'm like how coordinated is this
stuff and if it is coordinated you know is it are you talking about the thing where recently
right where google came out publicly and said that we're not going to work with the government
u.s government to to it was some sort of like a part of some war they basically came out
publicly 2017 okay yeah 2017 2018 yeah this was like a big public thing that interesting interesting
well they were the biggest donors to kamala number one donor yeah man corporate donors so yeah dude
yeah so it's funny like we both you know are so dependent on youtube and i do i'm like it does
make me occasionally nervous because it's like it does i'm grateful to elon musk man so as you know
who else was a huge donor to kamala was um what's his name alex carp you know who that is now alex
carp was the ceo of palantir of palantir yeah that's really interesting really interesting that
i didn't i wouldn't suspect that he i mean i read that i read there's a new york times piece that
came out on him really recently that's fast when they're interviewing him about this stuff and he's
like he donated to kamala yeah he was literally saying in there how he donated millions of dollars
to um the democrat the democratic party and um he's always described himself as a like left-wing
guy right yeah he's like super into hagel and like you know very like a almost like a neo-marxist
or something yeah but then but then it's also peter right they're like really good friends like
they've known each other forever since college from back in the day yeah that's stanford law i
believe yeah yeah um yeah so but he's also like he doesn't have any any sort of hesitation in
in working with the u.s government to advanced american supremacy yeah i think they're like
mission in many ways just like they they want to protect the free world yeah and uh you know i
think they are responsible for a lot of uh you know big threats to the u.s uh you know going down
and i think that's a pretty good thing yeah um yeah i know i know there are a lot of conspiracies
about them oh there's so many conspiracies bro they're mostly and that's what the other
people don't understand it's like for me they're mostly a black box like i don't really like
right interact with right right right too much but yeah yeah i mean i've met like have you heard of
whitney webb oh yeah yeah she goes deep on the i know on the peter teal stuff she's like dude
she like frustrates me because she's clearly really smart and showing a ton of courage
yeah like going deeper on like epstein networks than like anybody else which is epic and then
now she's like and now it's all you know peter and and palantir whatever it's like
no it's not and your book is so convoluted it's almost like if you wanted a psyop to throw people
off the trail for epstein it would be that book like it's so complicated and again i don't want
to like it's it's an it's an amazing i haven't read it yet i've tried to read it okay and it um
and it does she makes all sorts of amazing connections it's like a thousand pages long
yeah it's crazy yeah and she's she's doing an amazing service i think and uh so like very
net positive whitney webb but like there's certain areas where like it feels like she's just anti like
anybody who's rich and powerful like anybody like she's anti elon you know with all the stuff he's
doing around free speech right and the usaid and reading them out of our institutions like who do
you want to do that you need somebody that powerful to do that yes so who's like ultimately like
politics like is where like the battleground takes place and like it's a power game
and you need the people with who are the most powerful like who probably made certain
expedient alliances to get to where they are yeah like doing things to like get anything done
and i feel like she's super like if you if you are not yes so cynical and if you are not like
you don't pass some like crazy purity litmus test you are the devil or whatever and like
i would just say like look yeah like maybe everybody at the elite strata or whatever has
like you know had to you know at times make unholy alliances right but like whose side are you on and
i think i think like some real good is being done in this like new trump admin and with with elon
and tulsi and like tulsi and rfk like i mean yeah those those two specifically like really
i think were on the side of truth when it was unpopular specifically rfk jr i mean i love that
guy i think is epic yeah um so yeah i mean i'm a fan of whitney webs but i do think she could just
be so like ideologically purist at times totally um but yeah i'm glad she exists yeah yeah she's
definitely she definitely does good work but like yeah that stuff gets the rabbit holes are never
ending when it comes to that stuff if you don't like you know you have to follow like it's not
just it's not black and white right like you can't just i guess you can you can you can shred anybody
you want for anything and find out every bad thing that somebody has done anybody recognize like the
net positive that people are doing as well 100 anybody at a certain level of power unless it's
like the cirque du soleil dude who like was like you know started from like with a homeless troop
of circus people or like the patagonia founder like occasionally you'll meet somebody where it's
like you got nothing exactly but like anybody in the elite world of business politics government
yeah i'm sorry i can't name too many people where it's like there aren't certain things that you
you know had to do you know and so it's it's it's a human nature it is it is unfortunately there's
a political game that has to be played to get shit done in washington yeah you have to play that
fucking game there's no way around totally and i i don't want to fucking do i mean i don't want
to do it either yeah fuck no it's that being in politics now like i grew up actually being like
maybe i'd want to be in public when i was really little maybe i'm interested in politics it'd be
cool and then now i'm like it's a selector for the worst people just the worst like just sell outs
like just spineless but the people who are just obsessed with optics yeah and uh yeah it sucks
yeah it's weird shit it's weird shit for sure well dude thank you for doing this brother we
almost had four hours what time is it what time you're playing okay yeah we gotta end it right now
okay i gotta go jesse michaels thank you brother that was fucking amazing danny this was epic bro
thank you for having me yeah man uh american alchemy on youtube aka jesse michaels where else
american alchemy on youtube and then uh go to whop.com w h o p dot com slash jesse michaels michaels
with no a and that's like my patreon equivalent oh we're gonna do epic debates there and it's
gonna be really fun we're gonna host all sorts of awesome conversations and that's where you get
like some really good stuff we'll link it all we'll link it all for everybody you're the best yeah
there we go exclusive content and then yeah on youtube as well under jesse michaels amazing thank
you brother we appreciate you we gotta do it again hey i'm down anytime i'll bring you down when
there's waves let's go yeah we gotta surf dude yeah exactly all right goodbye everybody later