And as we turned left on the, not a hard left, just a dog leg left, there sat this object
on top of November 5 that was about 10 feet in the air, directly on top of that blast
door that was the size of a Walmart building.
It was huge and it was a sphere.
I sat down with Mario Woods, a former U.S. Air Force security responder.
In 1977, he was stationed at Ellsworth Air Force Base in South Dakota.
Then, aged 23, he experienced an incident that would change him forever, literally leaving
him with missing time, marks on his body, and a collie locked in catatonic shock for
hours.
Literally could not get a breath of air.
It was just all-encompassing.
So here it is, my full interview with Mario Woods.
So who are you?
Hello.
My name is Mario Woods.
I currently live in Southeast Georgia.
I'm 69 years old.
I served in the Air Force from 1975 to 1983 and in 1977 had quite the experience on November
was a Minuteman II, 1.2 megaton weapon in the ground, in a hardened structure, in a
silo just north of a small town named Newell, South Dakota, which is 30 miles north of Sturges,
which most people have heard before.
This is a High Plains area, a buffalo running terrain, seen them a few times also.
One o'clock in the morning changed my life at week of November, we say 18th in 1977.
And you were stationed at Ellsworth Air Force Base?
At Ellsworth Air Force Base, that's correct.
And what was your role there?
What were you doing?
Security police, assigned to the missile squadron.
You have about 800 security police officers that work the site and about one-third are
assigned to aircraft back at the main support base of Ellsworth, the actual Air Force Base.
All the missile sites themselves are manned by six-man teams and there are 150 Minuteman
II missiles with 15 launch control facilities is where you live and you act as a response
team while on duty on a 12-hour shift to respond to any and all given alarms or launch facility
checks or anything that an ordinary police type duty would be.
Not for our sake, but for the context of the audience, do you have any mental health history
prior to your sighting in 1977, your experience in 1977?
No I do not.
I was part of the personal reliability program also for sensitive nuclear equipment.
Can you explain what that is?
Yeah, anyone that works around any type of nuclear devices, weaponry or construction
of or the storage of nuclear components, whatever it may be, plutonium, uranium or anything
that's used in that particular field, you have to be cleared and granted a clearance
in order to do it.
If they detect anything that's abnormal with how you may react up to and including
life if you have to in preservation of keeping that ours or saving someone's life.
They really analyze you deeply to see if you can't do that.
And you have to report if you're taking any sort of medication or any sort of diagnoses
in the past dealing with mental health.
Correct.
They do random blood tests, urinalysis, everything.
We didn't have gum swabs back then or the tests were quite different back in that day,
but there was no leniency in that.
Okay, so you're in Ellsworth Air Force Base, it's 1977, you have a partner that you're
working with?
Yeah, his name is Michael Johnson, he's a real light-skinned black guy.
He told me he was from Chicago, Illinois, and we only worked together that one day.
He was working vacation relief for my partner whose name was Steve Welchel, who went to
North Carolina to get married.
So he had 30 days in which to do that.
So in the interim, while we went on a tour into the field, mind you, your main base is
Ellsworth and you report there are SATAF, our operations facility, is at Ellsworth.
And all the three squadrons meet there for this huge guard mount as we depart from there
on buses or helicopters if the weather's too bad and they can't travel on the road.
And we go out to our respective launch control facilities where we live for three days at
a time and come in the morning of the fourth day.
So set the scene for the night in question, what are you doing?
Really nothing.
We had gotten out there probably about 9.30, 10 o'clock in the morning.
Usually if you're working the night shift, which we were assigned to, which was 6 p.m.
to 6 a.m., we try to lay down and take a nap, but you know, that young and strong and vibrant
I didn't really see the need to do that.
So during the day, I just stayed up and did some other things, played some ping pong or
something and that night we went on duty at 6 p.m.
Of course, we go in and we get all of our code tables issued to us and all that stuff.
Or when we're dispatched, it can be either or.
And I guess it was about 9 o'clock, 9.15 or so.
I smoked cigarettes then, so I just thought I'd walk outside and have a cigarette and
it was between 9 and 13 degrees outside.
So I have my long johns on over my fatigues and I just walked outside and you know, you're
talking prairie land as far as you can see north and east and west and you don't see
south because the buildings behind you.
And I see this light off to my east at about a 30 degree angle and it looks like a mini
moon.
I honestly thought it was the landing lights or some type of landing lights for B-52 bombers
because the main base supported aircraft, uploaded aircraft of B-52s and they often
flew sorties or test runs across the prairies at night, usually around 300 feet.
So it was like a low level flight, right?
It was pretty cool to see that.
That's what I thought it was.
I thought they were coming to me.
That's why I couldn't really gauge the distance.
I mean, I thought five to seven miles and I'll stick with that at about 30 degrees,
but it never changed.
And I kept looking at it, looking at it.
Now, if I extended my hand this way, it covered the circumference of the light I was looking
at.
How far away was the object?
I would guess five to seven miles.
And the reason I say that is at the end of this, I can make that correlation because
you got to have things that put all this together.
And it was just so strange.
It was as if there was a light right out there a few miles away from you and you know it
doesn't belong there, but it's not coming near you and it's not going in either direction
anywhere else and there's no noise associated with it.
It just sits there.
So that's where I was with that and I'm smoking a cigarette and I thought, literally, I thought,
what the hell is that?
It can't be.
Is that B-52s or is it helicopters?
We did have helicopters back then, but I've never saw them fly at night like that.
So again, I just thought it was two B-52 bombers together so close, one behind and a wingman
like that that I just took it as that.
But I held my hand up like this and it covered the light, the circumference of the light.
But if I did my fist like this, then it was larger than my fist was.
And I thought that is really strange.
How can that be?
When I sailed with my father growing up, I went to sea with him a couple of times during
the summertime.
He could do that.
You can't do that today, but back then, you know, a chief engineer could do that.
I went inside the facility, went into the flight security controller office, which was
just right to the right as you open the front door.
And Bill Holloman, he was a staff sergeant and he was talking to his wife back at Ellsworth.
And the toggle switch or the rocker switch was on the wall just behind him, right next
to the entrance to the elevator door where the officers used to go down the elevator
to the capsule.
And I said, hey, Bill, I said, there's something out here strange in the air.
I said, some lights.
I said, do you mind if I flip the lights at this thing?
He just looked up at me literally and he had that big old gray phone back to his head.
And he just kind of waved me off, you know, like, go ahead, do what you want.
So I just honestly, no SOS or nothing.
I just flipped it off and on, off and on, off and on three times.
And I ran back outside and I was probably 20, 25 feet away from the door and just a
little bit to the east of it, of the door, of the front of the door.
And just watching it, a couple of minutes went by, maybe a minute and a half.
And all of a sudden this thing goes out, on, out, on, out and on, and it just sent shivers
up me.
And I went, wow, they do see me.
So I literally thought, okay, because I've had them do wing waves at me before like fighter
aircraft or helicopters, they'll do a little swing like that if they see you on the ground
and as security policeman, you're taught that.
You are taught hand signals and flashlight signals.
You know, for aircraft, if you need to be rescued or you're trying to aid them getting
to the ground or what have you, you know, you, you are trained on that.
So I just thought it was really cool and I thought, all right, well, let's carry this
on a little bit further.
Cause still it was in the same location, not coming closer, no sound.
So as I went in, I said, Hey, Michael, didn't know Michael from Adam's house cat.
It's the first time we ever worked together and he was just simply come out, sent out
to work vacation relief from my partner.
So I went and I said, Hey man, there's something in the air you need to come and look at.
And now he worked missiles also, but on a different flight.
He was usually at a different location.
He didn't work in November and he outranked me by two months, by the way.
So he would be driving the vehicle and I would be the passenger or the team member.
So he kind of looks at me for a minute and really is not too excited.
I said, come on out here, man.
You got to see this, hoping it would still be there when I went outside.
So he comes outside and I said, hold on right there.
We walked about 20, 25 feet and I said, look at that.
You see that?
He goes, yeah.
I said, I just flashed the lights at that thing and it flashed back at me.
And he just looked at me as in disbelief.
So I said, stay right here.
And I ran in there real fast and I said, Hey Bill, you got to come see this thing.
Cause he and I, we went back a ways and we knew each other pretty well.
And I don't know what kind of discussion he was in with his wife, but he chose not to
come out and stayed on that damn phone.
So I flipped the lights again, same sequence, blip, blip, blip, blip, blip, blip, three
of them three times, ran back outside about two minutes pass and it goes out, comes on,
goes out, comes on and stayed on twice, three and two.
That's right.
And uh, so he just kind of looked at me and looked back at that and I said, what do you
think man?
I don't know.
And I said, I'm going to do it again.
I'm going to do it again.
Maybe it'll, I said, do you hear anything?
Couldn't hear nothing.
He didn't hear anything.
He didn't seem to be too impressed.
I must say that he just, it didn't seem to really get ahold of him the way it did me.
I was excited about it.
Still not knowing what it was.
I said, it's got to, I said, it's got to be B 52s.
No reply.
So I ran back in again and I did the same thing.
He stayed right there, flipped it off, flipped it on, flipped it off, flipped it on, ran
back outside.
I know Bill Holliman thought I was a nut by that time.
So I get back out there and it flipped off and it did not come back on and it, but when
it did come on was about, it was about 30 seconds or so it had moved just a little bit
north, but it had moved further westward, like from that position to this position,
say from the, say from the three o'clock position where I was visualizing it, seeing it maybe
to the one 30 position, something like that.
And it came on and it just stayed right there.
Never heard anything.
Never saw any type of flame or anything like an afterburner or nothing.
It didn't move.
It just was right there and he goes, Hey man, he goes, he just said, I don't know.
And I said, what do you think it could be?
Oh, whatever, whatever.
And he walked back inside.
So the last time I went in there and flipped the lights at the thing, came back out and
then that would be the fourth time.
And it was out and I didn't see it again.
It was, when I came back out, it was gone or it was out.
So I, I just shook my head.
I just took it as well.
I guess they went that way, you know, maybe flying up toward or over toward Bellefouche,
which is about 30 miles away, north and west of our location.
More north of that's North Dakota, you know?
So I mean, we were in that proximity in that high Northwestern area there.
And so I just went back inside and I guess all this time from like quarter after nine
to about nine forties, when all this transpired, you know, maybe nine 35, it's hard to be exact,
but I try to be, and I went in and started playing some cards, watching TV or something
or he didn't want to do anything.
As I said, we literally didn't know each other and we didn't, we spoke very little.
And other than the fact that I knew, you know, the area in November, you know, that site
and all the missile sites where they were located, which are 10 of them, he was just
there to fill in.
So we watched TV until midnight and that signal comes on, it used to be looked like a radiological
signal used to come on at 12 o'clock when all the three stations that we have would
go off the air and then it would have that loud noise, you know, that signal.
Static.
Yeah.
So that happened.
So he just turned the TV off.
Nation was a different place then believe me, was in a different place then.
And I guess it was about 12, 15 when as I was sitting down, I think I was looking at
a book or something, I hear the alert phone in the flight security controller's office
go off.
And that's the phone that's directly connected to the launch control people downstairs, two
officers downstairs.
And it sounds like, and it rings until you pick it up.
You got to snatch it off the wall and of course, Bill Holliman did that.
And I hear him saying, yes, sir, yes, sir, yes, sir, sit for November five, which is
a two-pronged alarm.
It's an above ground and a below ground sensor that has been affected.
And as I said, the temperature was between nine and 13 degrees that night.
So it was cold.
So I had on my long johns, fatigue pants and shirt and my, I had on bunny boots because
I knew I was going to be doing some walking because you have to do a certain type of route
around the facility on foot inside and outside the fence line, which is a good walk.
And in snow, it gets kind of a little dicey because it just does.
But anyway, so we got all of our equipment.
We had our weapons.
We had our code tables.
We had our ditty bags, which is what you carry all your stuff in.
And the F-154 pickup truck was sitting directly outside our front door.
We keep it plugged in because it gets so cold there that it will freeze up the coolant in
your engine, or they also have a way of keeping the transmission warm with a plugin.
So unplug that.
We were set to go.
The vehicle's warming up and we got our safety briefing and everything that we needed and
off we went.
And I'd say that was probably right around 12, 20, 12, 25, and it was a 15 minute travel
time to November 5.
And strangely enough, that was the closest launch facility to our launch control facility
where we lived.
It was the closest one as the crow flies.
It was only maybe five and a half miles away, but the way that you had to get there made
it probably 10 miles or eight and a half, 10 miles somewhere in there.
So as we left, we go through the gate out to the end.
These are all clay roads.
You can go from one interstate on the other on the clay road and they're maintained by
the state.
They're very nice.
Got to the intersection, hung a left.
There's no traffic.
Believe me, there's no traffic.
And next intersection turned left and it's four and a half miles from that intersection
up to Highway 79, which runs down to Newell.
So you're going uphill as you go down in this little depression area, you're going uphill
toward the highway bed as they build them high as the snow and ice runs off of them.
And I just happened to look to about my four o'clock position straight that way where November
5 was located.
And when I did, I see this pulsation like an orange, yellow, and white type glow coming
off the ground from miles away should have never, never seen that before.
And I said, Hey, Michael, I said, check this out, man.
I said, you see that glow over there?
I said, look, look, I said, can you see that?
He didn't say anything yet.
And as we got up to highway 79 and we turned right, then we're on top of that plateau.
And now that four o'clock has become like a one 30 again.
And I said, look at that, man, I'm telling you, that's that object.
And why I said that, I don't know.
He just said, whatever, man.
And he said that to me a couple of times that night, whatever, man.
So as we've traversed down highway 79 toward Newell to a stop sign, there's one stop sign
and one stop light in Newell and the population then was 230 people in that town.
And it was on the entrance and the exit on highway 79.
Every time I entered Newell population was 230.
When I left, it was 230.
So now it's 600 and something as I was there in 21.
But as we went downhill, I lost sight of that pulsating glow.
We went down to the stop sign.
We took a right and the road goes out about a mile and a half and then a dog legs back
to the left.
And as we turn left on the, not a hard left, just a dog leg left, there sat this object
On top of November 5, that was about 10 feet in the air directly on top of that blast door.
That was the size of a Walmart building.
This thing was as big as this building you're in right here.
It was, it was huge and it was a sphere.
It had an energy source that, that moved around it.
Like, like you'd see pictures of the sun, how it's just like boiling.
I don't want to call it plasma, but I don't know what, what really to call it.
There were no tail sections, no, no, no portholes.
There were no thrusters.
There was no leading edges of any kind, no wings, tail, nothing that we would associate
anything in the air with.
It was a complete sphere, but on a magnitude that is just hard to even comprehend.
As you know, I'm always on the hunt for things that help me stay sharp, focused and full
of energy while I'm diving into life's mysteries and making this show happen.
And I've got to say, mud water has completely transformed my mornings.
Back in the day, I used to struggle with that post coffee crash and let's not even get into
the caffeine jitters.
Mud water gave me the smooth, steady energy I was missing.
It's packed with functional mushrooms like lion's mane, chaga and reishi, plus turmeric
and cacao all working together to keep me focused, calm and grounded.
Honestly, it's like coffee went on a yoga retreat and came back zen.
What I love most is that it's not just about replacing coffee.
It's a whole new ritual.
It's a simple, nourishing way to start the day.
And I actually look forward to it every morning.
Every ingredient is USDA certified organic, vegan, non-GMO and there's zero sugar.
It's energy that doesn't mess with your sleep or make you question your life choices at
3 a.m.
Ready to make the switch to cleaner energy?
Send to mudwater.com, that's M-U-D-W-T-R dot com and grab your starter kit today.
Right now, our listeners get an exclusive deal up to 43% off your entire order, plus
free shipping and a free rechargeable frother when you use code Jesse.
That's right, up to 43% off with code Jesse at M-U-D-W-T-R dot com.
After your purchase, they'll ask you how you found them.
Please show your support and let them know we sent you.
Keep your energy natural and refreshing all year long with mudwater because life's too
short for anything less than clean, delicious energy.
So we pulled up to this thing about 60 feet on the access road to the site itself.
Yeah, I think the fence was either 10 or 12 foot fence with big opening gates on it.
And we pulled up at a 45 degree angle right where the cattle crossing is located because
all these ranchers own this property and the property was leased from them to put these
missile sites on back in the day when they built them.
So the cattle can't come out into the main road.
It still happens, but it really decreases that from occurring.
So we pulled up right at that cattle gate and immediately upon doing so, immediately
upon doing so, it was as if a light came down that just about blew my eyeballs out of my
head.
You could literally almost see the veins behind your eyelids.
It was as if, I don't know what kind of energy that was, but whatever was released or put
down our way just completely almost disabled you just from the brightness.
It was like living in a welder's light for a few moments.
And then the atmosphere just vacated, couldn't breathe, literally could not get a breath
of air.
That was from my excitement.
I don't know if it's from adrenaline, I'm 23 years old, I was in excellent shape.
I could flat foot 25 miles in full combat dress and smoke a cigarette at the end of
it.
Didn't bother me a bit.
Literally I was in that kind of shape.
And I was just so taken.
Michael Johnson, I never remember him looking up at the thing, but for me, I was at a 45
degree angle and I'm looking directly out his window and part of the back window, this
is an F-154 pickup truck, a 1975 or 76, I can't remember which, but the square body
type pickup truck with western mirrors on the sides of them, two wheel drive vehicles.
And the only thing I knew to do was to ask for relief.
And where did that come from?
I have no idea where that thought or impulse came from.
You pray to God or Jesus or just relief generically?
I think he was in there and I just asked for relief from what I was experiencing to breathe
because I didn't think I was going to be able to take another breath of air.
And I grabbed my flashlight, which I've gotten ridiculed before.
It was an aluminum black 3D cell flashlight.
I think it was made in Japan, I'm not sure, but it was a great tool and they just started
making them.
Now Maglite didn't come out until 79, I had this in 77, it was given to me as a gift.
And I rolled the window down and I reached up with my right hand and I grabbed onto that
mirror, pulled myself up on that window seal because I was so afraid to step out of the
cab of that truck.
Now I'm fully armed, why would I be afraid?
I've never been afraid to do anything, especially in my duty.
I was so afraid of what I was experiencing, I didn't know how to deal with it.
I pulled myself up on the window seal of that truck out of that seat and I grabbed my flashlight
and I had a glove on my left hand and I had my flashlight in my right hand and I had my
hand on the blue bubble up on top of the glove and I just flashed that flashlight at this
thing like I did at the facility, I guess, I don't really know.
And as soon as I did, it felt like I got relief, it felt like there was relief.
And I just slid back down in the seat and as I slid back down in the seat, I noticed
dust particles and stuff and the way in which that cab was lit up that's hard to describe.
It seemed like everything was in slow motion.
Like the dust that was in that cab circulating from the vent work was like it was in slow
motion movement.
I was looking at it, it was like sparkles or something or like glitter.
It was like that.
And I thought, what's happening here?
What is this?
And I was trying to breathe, I was trying to talk to Michael, got no answer from him
as he was just stuck or glued to that steering wheel and he was just bathed in a blue white
light.
You know, the light intensity never honestly went away, it was just all-encompassing, it
was just all surrounding to a point where you're like trapped in light.
There's nowhere to go, I mean, there's nothing you can do about it, you just, I don't know,
I just felt like somebody had me right where they wanted me for some reason.
These thoughts and all this that I just described went by in just a couple of seconds, not minutes,
but just a couple of seconds.
All this just happened so fast, faster than what I've just told you and then this black
ball about six times the size of a beach ball looked like if it had vents or something
on it, not round vents, but these long, long like lines coming down the side of it, just
it didn't touch our truck, but it shot right down in front over the hood of this F-150.
And I don't even know what to say, but it was so fast and so whatever it was doing quick
that it just bounced around from every location on the truck, front, back, left, right, in
front and then it was just gone.
And I still don't know how much time has passed.
Then I became afraid and I made sure I rolled my window up.
I put my M16, when I slid back into the truck, I put my M16 between my legs and I was holding
onto the barrel.
I don't know where my flashlight went.
I just knew to secure my weapon between my legs and I held onto the barrel and this permeating
smell, I have no idea where it came from because as I said, my window was up and I know his
window was up, so it had to come through the ventilation duct work, I guess.
But it permeated the vehicle like, I mean, stench smell, bad ammonia, like you want to
roll the windows down, you want to step outside and get some fresh air.
Some of the cleanest air on the planet runs through South Dakota year round, but this
was like standing in a, I don't know, in a bottom of a boat or something, you know, where
they catch shrimp, I guess, and dump them there, but put them there.
I shouldn't even say that, but anyway, it was overwhelming.
When I smell that, I just got a real strange feeling from within, like something when you're
afraid or when you're scared or something because I knew that wasn't normal and I know
I'd never smelled that before, I only associated it with what I smelled in the past trying
to make maybe a visualization in my mind what it could be.
The light never stopped, the pressure did, we could breathe again or I could breathe
again.
Michael Johnson, he never said anything from the time we rolled up to that site, anything.
The last thing he said to me was on the top of Highway 79 when whatever, man, as it was
glowing over in the far distance that I saw this pulsation off the ground or what I took
ass off the ground from where we were from driving there.
And so when that happened, I felt as if I was becoming sleepy or tunnel visioned or
something.
I kept shaking my head as I relive it.
As we're sitting here right now, I kept trying to, I felt as if I was going to go out.
So I was trying to hold my breath and squeeze, like pilots do that and G-suits to keep the
blood in their head, but I felt as if I was going to pass out.
And I started getting this tunnel vision effect in a way where I couldn't see and it was just
getting smaller and smaller and it was black on the exterior of that visual that I was
looking out the front window.
All these thoughts are running around in your brain and this is all taking place and just
a couple of minutes, not 10 minutes, not even five minutes from what I understand.
And as I'm blacking out, I know I feel something on my right side.
And I turn my head and I see these four, I'm going to call them beings.
And they are not walking as you and I walk.
They are just gliding across the ground.
Maybe I don't know how high off the ground.
I couldn't really see that, but they have these little uniforms on.
And the one on the far right, he had some type of a small one in his waist belt.
I've got a drawing of it that had a yellow tip on it, some type of a yellow tip.
And it really got my attention.
And I was, and I just couldn't believe what I was seeing, but the one behind those three,
the front three were the same size, exactly the same size, looked exactly the same.
But the one behind them was a chest and a head taller than the little guys.
And he had this thing on his chest right here that pulsated the same color as what was on
that little one.
And when I saw him, then I was afraid, then I felt fear, maybe just visualized fear.
I don't know.
I didn't do anything to me that caused fear other than where I was and what I had just
gone through.
And then I went black.
I just went, that's the last thing that I saw in my mind.
And just a second went by and literally I came, when I came to, my weapon was between
my legs and I'm still holding on to it.
And I just looked straight up like that and right out the windshield of that 150 in his
total blackness.
And I thought, where, where'd all the light go?
Where's no, literally, I don't even know where it was.
We were, I said, Michael, Michael, where are we?
What happened?
Where's November five?
Cause this, this lit up, it has lights on it.
You know, they're like, like pole lights and has those types of lights on it at night.
This is a standalone facility.
So even if external powers cut, this thing takes over and has a generator run itself,
right?
No answer from Michael.
And I kept yelling at him, Michael, Michael, what's going on with you, man?
And I pushed him in his shoulder really hard.
I even, I put my finger in his ear after a couple of minutes, I shoved him, shoved him,
checked his pulse.
He was breathing.
I couldn't get anything out of him.
He was as if he was in some type of a state that I didn't even really know to have the
words for, as if he was, his eyes were open and he was breathing and his heart was pumping,
but he was just stuck on that steering wheel.
And I, I, I tried, I don't know how many times to get him to say something.
I said, snap out of it, man.
What's going on?
What's wrong?
I got frustrated with that.
And I just popped the door open, little lever on the side, I popped the door open and I
stepped out trying to get in my mind where November five go.
Cause that's where we were.
And this was a, this was a, a very serious alarm.
So that, that reason had to be found out why that thing alarmed where, how it did in that,
in that alarm configuration.
And when I stepped down, I stepped in mud with those bunny boots on and I went, what
the hell?
How is this?
And then to my right, where your chair is located, maybe a foot further, there was a
wall there at about a 45 degree angle and it was white and it went up about, I don't
know, as far as I could see like 50 feet, but my eyes got more accustomed to the darkness.
And then when I looked in both directions, not knowing exactly where I was on the compass,
it was as far as I could see that direction, as far as I could see that direction and up
about 50 feet.
When I become acclimated to the, to the darkness, had no idea where this was.
I said, Michael, come on, man, you got to wake up, dude, we're, you know, we're in
bad way here.
We got to find out what the, what the hell's going on here, you know, nothing, nothing.
I even tried pulling his hand off that steering wheel and he was just, he was just, I don't
know how a person can stay that tense and for so long that they don't cramp up.
I would cramp up doing that, but he did.
The next thing that I knew was I hear WSC to November one, that's us WSC November one,
what's your location?
And I just, I said, are you going to get that thinking that would snap him out of that here
in that radio signal, a radio call for us, he didn't answer.
And I picked it up and I said, senior Airman Woods WSC, I said, I don't know where we are.
And he goes, do you need medical help or do you need assistance?
And I said, I don't know, sir.
I said, I'm fine, but my partner won't respond to me.
I said, he's awake, breathing and well, but he won't let go of the steering wheel and
he's just sitting in a driver's seat just like he is stuck.
He's just like in the frozen catatonic state.
That's the word that I had never heard when it was told to me catatonic state.
And that's correct.
He was.
So when I, when I finally got out of the vehicle again and walked and looked and I'm talking
where did all this mud come from with this temperature, because everything else is frozen.
As I said, that wall was at about 50 feet high and at this strange angle, like 45 degrees.
Well, it was the backside of the New Lake reservoir dam.
And that is about on the map, about eight miles, eight and a half miles away from November
5.
Now we only had two wheel drive vehicles and where we were positioned behind that dam was
in the very center of that dam wall at the, at really at the most center point.
And at the far end was the slew gate where they control the water flow and allow it to
go out.
If it gets, if the reservoir gets too full and in front of us was the rest of the dam
and it, that road ran north and south wing security control told me to maintain one minute
security checks.
So they were trying to triangulate our location.
Now I had never done that in tech school, but I'd heard of it.
I may have read something about it, but I'd never done it or been part of that, that training.
So I didn't know how it was done.
So I did what they ask and I probably made, it probably made, I don't know, I probably
made 20, 25 checks before they got to us.
And as I was doing that, I noticed it was getting light to the east and that was the
sun coming up.
And then it dawned on me, well, man, we got this alarm last night at 1215.
And I looked at my watch and it was after 6 AM.
So we have all that missing time and I can't explain any of it because for me, it was just
what I saw, what we experienced, what I smelled lights out.
Next thing I know, we're sitting behind the new Lake reservoir dam miles away, miles away.
Sergeant Garza, there were three alert teams looking for us.
So that's six security policemen from three different sites, whether they use the primary
or the backup alert teams, I'm not really sure.
And in 2021 discovered that not only did they, were they searching for us, but wing security
control or the base control or whoever they were asked for federal or state assistance.
So they sent out two deputy officers from Sturgis and one state trooper, that area was
his area.
And I've got a guy named Steve that's working on, as he is a state trooper today, who that
deputy or who that state trooper was, it was on duty at that time.
And two of the three are passed, but one last name Kellogg is still alive.
And I'm trying to make contact with him.
Did Michael Johnson ever make it out of his catatonic state?
Your partner?
No, not while we were there.
When Sergeant Garza pulled up, he pulled up within say 60 feet, I guess he didn't want
to get in, get into the, to the snow area that we were in.
He pulled up and I walked around the back of the truck, walked out toward him.
And I said, I said, Hey, Sergeant Garza, how's it going?
I said, what's going on?
He said, Mario, I can't talk to you about this.
He said, I'm just here to escort you back to November control.
And I said, okay, but I need help with Michael Johnson.
And he looked at me kind of strange.
He said, what do you mean?
I said, I can't get him off the steering wheel and he won't talk.
He won't say anything.
Well, you know, I've never dealt with anything like that.
Or anybody else has that I know over somebody's, you know, locked up frozen in some type of
state of our catatonic state, hanging on to something, you know, usually you can, you
know, I literally couldn't believe how hard it was to get that man's hands off that steering
wheel.
I really, I couldn't believe it.
So we unbelted him and did that.
We slid him across the driver's seat and into the passenger side, belted him back in.
He just sat there with his hands down, looking forward and I kept talking to him thinking
at some point he would just feel fall free, you know, or whatever he was experiencing.
But again, this was a two wheel drive vehicle and walking around that vehicle, as I just
described on the left side or driver's side of that vehicle, about four and a half foot
away from that door was a big drop off.
It's there today.
And that is the, the holding pond for anything that comes out of that dam.
And it's pretty dead gum deep.
So had we gone in there, driven in there, I'm just, this is a what if now, had we driven
in there, that road's only five feet wide, there's no way that this two wheel drive F
150 forward would road tires on it.
Not even any big mud tires or anything, they didn't even have those back then, would be
able to turn around.
We were just in the only position we could be in to drive out of that dead gum place
and I drove out of it and I never went over any tracks and it hadn't snowed anymore or
anything had, nothing had changed since, since we were there.
When I left out of there, it was the only set of tracks coming out of where we were.
One set of tracks, but had he opened that door and stepped out of that vehicle or I
had, you'd have gone right down with now, you know, wouldn't have probably just slid
down in mud, but it was down pretty deep and that it was just amazing to me how we were
in the right position to exit there.
That's important to me, uh, trying to explain it to myself, how, how this took place.
So follow them back to the launch control facility to November one.
They escorted us all the way there and then, uh, two of the three teams dropped off and
I guess Garza or one of the teams remained, I guess they had to have, when we were going
to be removed from the site and taken back to the main base of Ellsworth, which is about
55 miles away.
And I didn't know that at the time they had to have our replacements immediately there
that you can't be understaffed on any kind of launch control facility.
It has to be fully staffed at all times.
So when we pulled up at the site, my flight chief was there, Master Sergeant Hawkins or
Master Sergeant Joel Gray, Assistant Flight Chief was Tech Sergeant Hawkins, the, um,
facility manager.
He was a tech sergeant.
Yeah.
The two officers that were on duty, they were off duty now and they were above ground.
They had been relieved.
Their replacements were underground, uh, Bill Holliman, the site cook, uh, and of course
you had, um, one of the, the one, uh, security response team that remained him and his partner.
So they took me in the day room and I told them when they came out to meet us, the gate
slides open.
I pulled in right in front of the flight security controller's office and they just descended
upon the vehicle.
Well, we got our, got our bags out and all that stuff and they went to the passenger
side and I said, I don't know what's wrong with Michael.
I said, I can't get him to speak.
And I said, we had a heck of a time getting them off the steering wheel.
Nobody said anything at that point.
They took him, put him, uh, put his arms over their shoulders and they took him to the back
room.
I think in the, in the, uh, facility manager's quarters, I don't know what they did, but
that's where they took him.
They took me into the day room where I walked into the day room and mind you, I'd been up
the entire day before five o'clock in the morning till we had guard mount traveled,
you know, to get out there then stayed up all day, went all night long until this happened.
And uh, so now it's probably somewhere around, um, I'm going to say seven 15, seven 30 in
the morning, uh, and we had just departed new Lake reservoir dam and I'd never been
there before.
I never, I never knew that place was even there and it's a little north of November
control and it's sitting back off the road about four and a half miles.
So it sits way back up on the prairie and I honestly had never been there before nor
knew about it.
And uh, so they started banging me with questions and what did you see?
What did you do?
You know, how did you do this?
Uh, you communicated this, you didn't report this, you know, what was wrong with the site?
Just all these things were coming at me and I was answering every single one of them.
And they believe me, there was a bunch of questions.
You just don't go missing on a, on a, on a nuclear missile site for, for five hours
and not answer questions.
It's a big deal.
Did you get the sense when they were asking you questions that they had seen things like
this before or like it was this completely novel thing where it's like, what the hell
happened here?
We have no idea.
Like we have no idea how to even, we have no pattern recognition for this.
Well, there were rumors years before I got there that something happened down toward
the Badlands in the 66th area and where two security policemen were found, uh, out of
their vehicle.
The vehicle was, you know, some distance away from them.
Their weapons were distance from them and an opener prairie and they, one was found
completely with no clothes on.
The other was just about like 90% unclothed and I don't know what happened to that.
But there, there were always talks and rumors about things in the air or things on the
back of the runway at Ellsworth, you know, B-52s uploaded bombers that are ready to go
uploaded on the alert pad.
And uh, what did they use?
F-86s at one point or a couple of times to chase these objects away.
And I think there's several reports of that.
One of the guys that I know, uh, who's an S-16 pilot, uh, Chris Lato, we were talking
about, we were talking about that one time, uh, but anyway, they questioned me up one
side and down the other.
And uh, I, I, I remember telling, uh, Master Sergeant Gray, I said, I can draw some things
if you'd like me to.
And um, that the question never really got, I don't know if it didn't get to him or answer
to or what happened, but, uh, he just, they just kept asking questions and I, and I got
to the point where it was just, everything was just at one time coming from every space
in my mind, questions about the whole deal.
And I said, Hey, I said, I got to go to the restroom just to get away from it for 10 seconds.
I just wanted a little bit of peace just for a few seconds of trying to cope with what
I had just seen, lived through and experienced as this is nothing I ever had before.
And I went to the restroom and I opened up the stall door, which is still there today.
I went right back to it in 21 and I just went and sat on the toilet and closed the door.
And you know, it was a regular stall door, doors about that high up off the floor, blue.
And these, these facilities were extremely nice.
I mean, you could, they were, they were not, uh, they were very well maintained and extremely
nice.
And I was just sitting there on that toilet thinking about what I had seen and, and what
had transpired.
You know, the thought hit me.
I didn't even strike the site and that's the procedure that you do when you arrive at the
facility that you, that's required for you have these steps that you have to follow to
eliminate whatever threat there is there, but to assess the entire situation and report
that back.
We never reported anything back like that, you know, and we didn't, I don't even think
we used the radio from moments of arrival and I really don't.
I can't remember if we did.
And all of a sudden, Jesse, I get this ringing in my ears that was as if somebody struck
a Liberty bell right next to my head.
I mean, really I have to emphasize that cause it was like, it got my attention.
I don't know if I reached up and put my hands on my ears or what, but when it happened,
lime green to me, like pea green.
And I didn't, uh, it was as if my vision was changing or some part of my visual acuity
was changing and I closed my eyes.
And when I did, I had this feeling.
I was leaving my body literally.
I was, you know, I thought I was dying.
I said, I guess this is, this, this is how you die.
And every time I closed my eyes, I felt as if I went without going anywhere.
I felt as if I kept going lower within myself and I knew there was a clear channel to exit
me through my feet.
I knew there was, it was a map.
There was something there that I could leave if I so chose to do so.
And it scared me to death.
It's literally scared me to death, man.
And when I opened my eyes at last time, I saw four fuzzy feet walking by pause, walking
by the bottom of that door with a set of Cochran military boots behind him.
That was a dog handler and his drug dog.
So you know, they had gotten one that they had gotten them to come out 55 miles out from
base to go through all of our stuff, make sure there's no drugs involved.
And I said, man, I said, I'm glad to, I'm glad to see you because he didn't know what
I just experienced.
And I said, my Diddy bag is out there in a day room.
He says, that's all right, Mario.
We already have it.
I don't know who he was, but he knew my name.
I don't know if he had just been told my name or what, you know, I played a lot of
tennis back then and he may have been somebody I played with.
But, uh, I said, I'll be out in just a minute, man.
He goes, yeah, no worries, man.
He says, you're all good.
Just come and check on you.
That's what he said.
Just came in to check on you.
And I said, thank you.
So they, they left her.
We're leaving.
And I opened up the stall door and I just went to the sink and mind you, I still have
on my long johns and my fatigue pants and shirt and, you know, same clothes.
I was in about 30 hours now.
And I just turned that faucet on as ice cold water.
And I just literally just drowned in myself with water.
I was just soaking wet because a master Sergeant Gray said something to me as I came out
there and he said, what'd you do?
Climb in the sink or something like that.
And I, and I did, I don't even know if I answered.
I just said, yes, sir.
Um, so I, I think I had a towel in my hand and he said, well, he goes, get your stuff.
He goes, we have to go, we have to go back to the SATA building.
That was our main operations building on Ellsworth.
And I said, yes, sir.
So I grabbed my stuff and immediately I said, well, what about Michael Johnson?
He said, don't worry about him.
He'll be going with Sergeant Hawkins.
I said, okay.
And I really wanted to talk to him, but immediately upon arrival at
that site, we were separated right then and there.
And I don't know what good it would have done because he wasn't coherent
or wasn't answering or anything anyway.
He hadn't said a word.
Nothing, not one word that I knew of, not one word.
He hadn't said anything to me or to anybody else that was there.
And I don't know how they transported him, you know, other than him telling
me that Master Sergeant or Tech Sergeant Hawkins was going to take him to the base.
Right.
So I got my diddy bag and loaded up and, uh, got my weapon, everything.
Off.
We went to Ellsworth and it was about an hour, 10 minute ride back to Ellsworth.
We went in through the back gate at box elder and went straight to the
SATAP building and he escorted me the entire way armory turned in, turned
in my weapon, all that stuff.
And, um, which was normal procedure, you know, um, went to Ralph East
breaker's office under escort.
And of course, when you are called in like that, you do a formal report in
where you literally bang on, knock on the door frame or whatever, even if the
door's open, you knock on the door frame and then your commander, whomever
tell you can enter the room, you enter the room, go directly to his desk.
You know, he was together at attention, you know, report in, you know, senior
man was reporting as ordered, sir, you know, and, uh, he told me at ease, but
he didn't tell me I could sit down.
I never forget that.
I just thought it was strange, you know, and I, and he had to
know how long I'd been up.
I mean, I was, I was weakened.
If I may say, I just felt really weakened in a different state, not
knowing what I experienced, I was still wet from an hour and 15 minutes ago
from the sink, you know, so it was really strange and, uh, he asked me
some questions and he said, uh, I remember him saying, sounds as if
you've had an interesting evening or night or something like that.
And I said, yes, sir.
And I looked to my left and there's, there's a total of five people in that room.
There's the deputy base commander who I don't remember his name, but next to him
was a man in a gray tweed, uh, suit with a hat and the hat was under his arm.
Then there was a captain, uh, Jack Reed, OSI next to him was this new OSI guy
named Rick Doty.
Interesting.
Yeah.
So, and do you have any speculation as to who the guy in the gray tweed suit was?
I was never introduced to him nor told his name.
And I only found out, uh, Jack Reed was a captain in OSI.
He was the lead OSI officer on Ellsworth at that time.
And, uh, through an email that Rick Doty sent me after about five years of
trying to, trying to get him to answer my emails or talk to me, because the first
time I saw him was on ancient aliens.
And I said, I know that guy.
He was at my debrief.
I was a counterintelligence officer for the air force office, special investigation.
I was personally fascinated by the fact that Richard Doty had been involved in
the aftermath of Mario's case.
I knew about Doty because of a great book called project beta by Greg Bishop.
Doty was an air force counterintelligence agent, basically tasked with performing
a psychological operation on an innocent researcher named Paul Benowitz, who had
seen an exotic craft at Kirtland air force base.
Doty convinced Benowitz that he was in touch with aliens, even receiving
signals on his computer.
This eventually drove Benowitz into psychiatric hospitalization.
So the fact that Doty was part of Mario's debrief is fascinating, seems very
important and requires follow-up by some brave souls.
And up to that point, I had nobody.
Yeah.
I had had nobody that could say, yeah, they were there or whatever, you know,
what have you, I tried running down my old flight chief and assistant flight chief,
but with no success or anybody else.
And especially Michael Johnson.
Some money has been spent trying to locate Michael Johnson.
We looked in hospitals.
We've looked in can't find him anywhere.
No, sir.
And I reported that the arrow in March of a 23, I think when I spoke with them.
Did they ever follow up at all?
I don't know.
They never got back with me.
Four hours and 19 minutes.
I spoke with them.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
And they set up to get a copy of everything which had been, you know, talked about.
They say they don't record it.
How do you, how do you, how do you send somebody a copy without recording something?
Come on.
That's ridiculous.
Can you write that fast?
No, but I mean, it's also like, and there's not, there's more than one person
sitting there also.
Oh my God.
But I mean, you're the government agency tasked for investigating UFOs and you
don't record your conversation.
It's absolutely absurd.
Yeah.
And then two weeks later is when Kirkpatrick went on and said there was no substantial
evidence.
Uh, can you contact Michael Johnson's family?
I don't have any way.
I don't have any, any numbers or anything.
He said he was from Chicago, Illinois.
Believe me, every resource, including other law enforcement officers that I know
today's technology have not located him yet.
Neither has arrow.
So what, what was your interaction with Doty?
Nothing.
Not one that we'd ever spoke or anything like that.
He was directly reporting to, uh, Captain Jack Reed next to him.
Okay.
So that's fascinating, right?
That this guy who's clearly this disinfo agent, you know, at least in the
context of Benowitz is showing up seven years earlier, eight years earlier in
your case, and you don't know why he's brand new then.
So as a person that's very high in this whole thing said, those were the days
that when he was probably honestly not, uh, changed in any way, perhaps.
I just want to say that the right way.
Cause we w you know, we, uh, I email him once in a while, um, and he'll answer me
back, whereas it took me about five years to get him to even do that.
And then we got to be on a, a cast together.
So real quick, just context, he now has come out saying he's reformed and he
apologizes for, you know, his malpractice in the past.
Uh, a lot of people are suspicious of that reform.
It does feel a little bit.
Sometimes to me, like he's flooding the zone with this info.
Like he'll talk about, you know, six alien races and it just seems extremely
speculative and not based on any sort of evidence, very weird.
Yeah, it's, it's, uh, it's more than I know how to swallow.
I only know that, uh, what I witnessed is my incident and, uh, anybody that I
could get that's, you know, that was there has some idea of it or that I knew.
I've done everything that I can to try and locate them.
And he is the only person so far that I have found alive.
And mind you, I'm 69 and I think he's older than I am.
I think, I think that's what he told me that he was in his 70s and I have no idea.
I mean, when I saw that thing the other day about him saying he was, it was from
78 to 88 when he was an OSI really, really bothered me.
And that was just last week that I saw that.
And, uh, I'll try to find the program again and I'll send you something about it.
Did you have any biological after-effects after you had this experience?
Well, I, uh, I, if you want me to, I'll, I'll explain that because I get sent over
to the, uh, flight surgeon's office after this entire debriefing takes place and
questions and like you wouldn't believe, uh, from my commander.
And I just relayed everything that I just told you with the exception of what I
saw or what I thought I saw at the side window of my vehicle.
Had I said that I saw these beings, they would have immediately removed me from
the PRP personal reliability program.
I'd have lost my clearance.
I'd have lost my job.
I'd have never been in the missile field again.
And I was a newlywed at the time and I needed a job and I loved what I was doing.
I just had no, no idea that something like this could even happen.
So did you lie about what happened to you?
No, I did not lie.
I just simply did not tell them what I saw out that side window.
I told them everything else, the size of the craft, you know, and, and how
we came upon it and flipping the facility lights at it and every, I told
them the entire story up to the point where what was out that window, I
never said a word about, so I had to write that in the report also, but that
was after about an hour and a half, almost two hours of this, uh, debriefing
in the commander's office.
And once that was done, he said, well, we're going to have the flight
surgeon take a look at you.
I said, yes, sir.
Okay.
So, uh, they loaded me up in his staff car and took me over to medical.
And I'd never been in a flight surgeon's office before.
Thinking, oh boy, well, you know, what's, what's this going to be?
And I'm still wet.
Like I said, I'm still damp from the water, the basin bath, I call it.
And, uh, I stripped down to my underwear and my, and my, and a T-shirt or something.
And there was a nurse in the room and there were two flight surgeons.
And that was the time.
And when they had these, uh, these gray, like separating walls that were about
five or six feet high with this little waving glass at the top of it.
So if you walked in another room over there, you could see heads, but you
couldn't see what was going on.
That used to be like a big, like a room divider or something.
And that was important because the guys from OSI, they were on the other side
of that, of that wall, of that, that panel.
And I knew they were there.
Uh, and as the doctors, you know, started, you know, asking me questions, uh,
it was one tall and one short, uh, they tested my ears, eyes, nose, throat,
looked at my joints, my hands, my fingers, you know, just literally everywhere.
And, uh, then they'd like walk over a few feet away and they'd talk a little
bit and I couldn't quite hear what they were saying.
And the nurse was just over to my right.
And, uh, came back and the one of them grabbed a, you know, a latex glove
and he puts it on his hand.
And I just thought there's a nurse in here and then he snapped that thing.
You know, I just thought, oh, you know, really I did.
I thought, oh man, you know, we're looking forward to this.
And, uh, he goes, uh, everyone woods.
You mind if I take a look at your gums?
And, uh, that was the, that was farthest from my mind of
anything in that room that day.
And I said, excuse me.
He goes, yeah, I need to, I need to look at your gums, your teeth.
I, I, that was better than the alternative.
I said, sure.
Okay.
So, uh, I just sat right there and he just opened my mouth and he just took
his, his index finger and his thumb.
And he just went all the way around by gums and my teeth squeezing tops and
bottoms that I mean, really took his time and spent time up here in the front
under my tongue, just pressing down like on the bottom, like the floor of
your jawbone or something.
And, uh, took him a couple of minutes and believe me, if somebody puts their
fingers in your mouth for a couple of minutes, it's strange feeling.
You know, it's not something that you want to repeat or have repeated.
Why do you think you checked that?
I have no idea.
I have honestly no idea.
And when he stopped, he popped the glove off.
He says, um, you know, you have a couple of burns on your body, right?
And I said, excuse me.
He goes, yeah, above your right eye and on the back of your right hand.
Well, I didn't have a glove on this hand.
And then my beret came down like this, you know, as my beret was on my head
and it burned me right above my eyebrow, right there.
Now I did have those air force glasses on.
So now I think that's why it had a strange curve in it in that, in that
little sunburn, but he says, we need to take a skin sample.
And I said, Oh, okay.
And they pulled out the nurse had this little tray, uh, with two types
of, uh, our two little, uh, stainless cylinders on it with cork tops on it.
And I guess the tool was inside the little cylinder thing.
He popped that off.
He went up here and he just clipped a piece of skin off there.
And he took the whole tool and he stuck it right down in there and put
a cork on it, laid it on that tray.
I felt it, you know, didn't feel like much, just a little clip.
I mean, like clipping a nail or something, you know?
And then he did it on the back of my hand once over here.
And once right over here, same tool.
I don't know if they could pick up two different pieces of flesh, but
it does, we use the same tool, but it in the other one corked it and did that.
And they walked over for a second and talked a few more moments.
And then they turned around and said, uh, thank you, you know, but, uh, you
know, you're done, you know, you can go back over to the commander's office.
Now you can get dressed.
I said, yes, sir.
Thank you.
Okay.
So when I looked back up, OSI had, they had, they had gone.
So there was a driver in the, in the, in, uh, Colonel Spraker's vehicle.
He was waiting on me when I got dressed and went back out there, uh, I got in a
vehicle and went straight back to Colonel Spraker's office where OSI was there.
So Colonel Spraker, uh, asked some more and every time I would ask about Michael
Johnson, they tell, they kept telling me, don't worry about Michael Johnson.
He's fine.
Really bothered me.
Yeah.
It just, I just.
It almost sounds like they're covering for something.
And, uh, Oh, when I did go back to Colonel Spraker's office again, I had to
go and do a formal report in again and, uh, do everything I was told.
Then he told me I could sit down in front of him, which I did.
And then the, uh, the captain Jack Reed walked over to his desk, Colonel Spraker's
desk and handed him the paper and he said, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I walked over to his desk, Colonel Spraker's desk and handed him the paperwork.
And, uh, at the same time, Colonel Spraker handed me these reporting forms.
I don't know what, I don't know the number, but he handed me these,
he handed me these forms.
He said, I need you to write down every single thing that happened on that site
tonight from the time you got this alarm to the completion, you know, and I went,
Oh, I mean, I print very well and I'm pretty detailed and I'll be happy to do that.
Again, I omitted what I saw at my right window, so I never got a copy of that.
They would not let me have a copy of that.
And, um, which I found kind of odd because anytime, any other time, you know,
you get article 15 or something, you get a copy of it, you know, something bad
that you've done, and again, I felt as if I'd done something incorrect or wrong.
Cause I knew I didn't strike that site.
And that seemed to be a big question is why didn't you strike this site?
Uh, of course they had some, they had to have somebody address that alarm.
I don't know who or how, but they did.
But then Jack Reed walked over and handed him this other piece of paper
as he was putting mine down.
And it was, uh, like a non-disclosure agreement, but I don't even think
they had that terminology then.
I just think it was something that I was told for one, this was a,
this was now a classified incident.
That's what I was told.
And I was agreeing to that and that I would not speak to any type of, uh,
they didn't even use the word social media.
It was like media people at any time.
If anybody comes into the missile field, you don't talk to anyone period.
You don't even tell your wife.
And now she thought it was odd because I should have been gone, come back
in the morning of the fourth day.
I had just departed the day before then this happened that night.
And then I wasn't allowed to call her until about three o'clock when
everything was said and done.
And I agreed to that agreement.
So Rick Doty's job, what he later said when I questioned him about it was
he was there, he was brought in to go over, sent over to the flight
surgeon's office to pick up our medical records, mine and Michael Johnson's.
Now I had no idea Michael Johnson was even over there.
If he was truly there or not, I'm really not sure.
I never saw him.
I didn't see Michael again.
As I said, for about 18 days, but, uh, he was there to study.
So you did see Michael 18 days later.
Yeah.
He, he was there to pick up just our medical records and bring them back to
his officer, which I find, I just find indifference with that, you know, there
had to be something said about what just happened.
I mean, for one, it was an incident of security being that we didn't do what
we were supposed to do and we had five hours of missing time, they have to
account to that for somebody, somebody higher than that base commander or
deputy base commander and that, and that squadron commander, they had to address
somebody say, right, Pat or wherever they have, they have to up channel
reporting has to take place that incident.
Um,
so I was able to call her at about three o'clock and she picked me up and she
sees me, I got a bandaid up here and I got one on the back of my hand.
What happened?
I can't tell her.
And I, and I had to stick with that.
And I said, just something happened.
And I said, my partner and I, we were brought back in, you know, to, well,
I'll go back out.
So I got extra days off.
We'll go back out on the next rotation, but I never went back to the women
control.
They sent me to kilo control under the scrutiny of my flight chief and
assistant flight chief and the OIC, which was the flight control team.
And the OIC, which was a lieutenant over all the missile, over everything
out there in that sector.
Um, and he had a, he had a hit, not a name, but he had a, um, a terminology,
not a flight chief, but an officer in charge, uh, the flight operations.
I'm not sure.
And he stayed there, uh, at kilo control.
And of course I was a member then never a team leader again, until the day I,
nine months later, I got my assignment to go to Korea.
But getting back to that about two and a half, three weeks later, we're living
in, it's called Haines way apartments.
They're still there today in Rapid city.
I get this bar none kid you not.
When that not came with that door, I knew it was Michael Johnson.
I knew it was that man and I'd never met him or had him in any kind of a, other
than sitting in the cab of that truck, which I know he only said like three
words to me, whatever man and outside too, or I don't know what it is.
And that was back at the site when I was flashing the lights at it.
That's all he'd ever said to me, other than the fact that, uh, in the day
room or on the way out on a bus, he'd said he was from Chicago, Illinois.
Uh, his, he was not married and he lived in the barracks.
I knew that he knocks on my door open.
I said, Michael, how you doing, man?
I said, come on in here.
We got to talk, you know, band-aids are off.
Had no more marks.
It was sunburned kind of thing.
It was more Mark.
What he did, what he took off than there was when the skin healed.
So, which was nothing.
I'm old Tampa boys.
I'm used to sunburn, you know, I look like this in the summertime, but, um,
he came in and I said, I introduced him to my wife and I said, all right,
this is what we're going to do.
And he looked at me and I said, I want you to draw what you saw and
I'm going to draw what I saw.
Now I hadn't drawn anything up to that time, other than pyramids and
trying to find out what the hell a pyramid, what it is, what it does
and what's supposed to be or why.
Real quick, before you say what you both draw, was he in a normal state again?
He was, he was talking, it was cool.
And like, okay.
Yeah, he was, he was cool.
He was still reserved, but he was cool, you know, cause we didn't
really know each other that well.
And, uh, so he comes in and he meets my wife and I think I put him at the kitchen
table, we had a round kitchen table and I sat at the coffee table on the couch
and I started drawing, you know, the craft, what I saw, you know, and.
We, we talked about, you know, what we heard, what I heard everything.
He saw the craft.
He saw the black sphere in front of the vehicle jumping up and down.
He smelled the smell.
He heard, do not fear.
He heard all of that and saw every bit of it, but couldn't do nothing about it.
It was as if he was just literally turned off and couldn't respond to anything.
He felt everything.
I ran that finger in his ear that deep.
I felt really bad about that, but I just wanted him to know that I was trying.
I was checking it.
He knew that I was checking him from what, you know, what was going on, you know,
but he couldn't do nothing about it.
He couldn't undo himself or just move.
So how'd you guys leave it?
So did you draw, you drew very similar things?
Yeah, we drew the exact same pictures and everything.
Could we see the pictures and show the audience?
Well, I, I, I do have the drawings.
Yeah.
I don't have them from him, but I've got my rendition of them.
That's remarkable.
And then after that, what happens between you and Michael?
We were there an hour, hour and a half, and it was a good, good,
and it was good vibes all the way through.
He had some tea or something and we talked some more.
We said, Hey, well, we need to get together again and chat some more.
You know?
And he said, yeah, I agree with that.
That was the last time I ever saw him.
You couldn't get in touch after that.
No, she tried.
No.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
I don't know where he went.
I don't know what happened to him.
I don't know if he was sent somewhere else.
It wasn't eight months later.
Well, it was about seven months, six months later, I got promoted to an
NCO non-commissioned officer buck sergeant.
So I know he had to go, he, he outranked me by two months.
So he had to be upgraded also or promoted to an NCO.
And, uh, have you tried looking up his records?
Yeah, everything, anything and everything.
You can't find anything.
I can't find a damn thing.
Do you think the guy in the gray tweed suit, you know, I think Bob Jacobs
talked about two guys in great tweed suits.
I think he was a GS government service employee.
Okay.
And so he was probably Bob and I talked about that too.
So he was probably the highest ranking guy in the room.
Yeah.
Well, I don't know.
I mean, for GS service perhaps.
Um, but, uh, Colonel Spraker was the highest ranking in that room.
And I don't remember the rank of the deputy base commander.
If you have 170, you know, people seeing a thing around nuclear bases and they're
all told to sign non-disclosures after they see a thing, what do you think the real
number is given how many thousands of people have worked at nuclear bases, you
know, in the 70 year plus American nuclear program history?
You think it's over a thousand?
It has to be.
I would say that anybody even today where then they're, they're still active.
You know, uh, Ellsworth has been decommissioned on the missile side.
I think that was in 1992 and the only missile that ever flew out of the
ground and the minute man program was at November two, where I was located,
not during my time, but in the sixties.
And I believe it flew for five seconds.
It was detonated, you know, a dummy warhead, you know, they just, they
wanted to make sure that it would launch out of the silo.
That's all.
Mind's eye view from every one of those sites are standalone sites.
Those missiles are standalone with that launch control facility.
So when each launch control facility, you've got 10, 1.2 megaton missile
systems sitting in the ground all around you.
I mean, up to miles away from you.
As I said, you know, November five was the closest launch
facility to November control.
If you have the technology to shut off one missile or to alarm one missile,
would you not know that that's the shortest response time?
And this is really reaching, but why didn't they set off November 10 or
November nine up by Castle Rock or why didn't we know why was it they didn't
have no time to spare or what they just set off November five and knew we were
coming, I literally, I really do think that, I mean, I don't think it was
they knew, I think they know they can see the power grid under the ground because
everything out there is underground, everything.
That's why they, that's how they keep power on in the wintertime.
They built underground all these years.
Also the response on the human side for you feels oddly routine.
If that were like the first or only incident that had ever happened, you'd
think that, you know, the, the superior superiors would be freaked out, right?
Like it's like you have nuclear missile silos, like, you know, these are, you
know, it's, it's, it's, it's our, you know, top of the food chain when it comes to
American defense and offense or so we think there are other variations and I
think they in turn gauge our overall knowledge on splitting the atom and
what's in those two hemishells, what source we're using, where it's no matter
if it's plutonium, it's uranium or what it is.
And I worked at those facilities too.
I was with USDA for quite some time also as a security inspector.
So I've been through a lot of these laboratories.
I've been to Los Alamos, Sandia, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, the Y-12
facility, Oak Ridge gaseous diffusion facility and general electric neutron
devices where triggering mechanisms were built, RTGs.
So where, where, where were you at GE, Schenectady, New York?
No, Largo, Florida.
Okay.
That was their DOE facility, which is now decommissioned.
They don't do it any longer.
They made the triggering device there that, that is used that you can see on.
It's clear whatever's going on on the UFO side is very interested in not only
nuclear weapons, but it seems like nuclear energy, anything in which we use an atom
for, but I honestly think that they gauge our intelligence on that in some way.
And that's why they're so closely scrutinized.
The other thing that's funny, I think they have a sense of humor.
And the reason I think that is when you get all these sites that are shut down
and everybody scrambles together, they're all offline and everything, like what
happened to Robert Salas for instance, and his commander, the flip side of that
is when one of these sites alarm and start its countdown as it's going to launch.
So the response to that, once you're dispatched, if, if the launch crew wants
to dispatch you, if they're really worried because they have an override also that
they can do something with, and I don't know exactly how that works, but they're
dispatch you to the site with your F-154 pickup truck and all your goodies.
You've got your diddy bag, your weapon, your stuff.
You're ready for it to be out there for two weeks.
If you have to, every time you leave, you can stay out in that missile field
for a very long time period.
The missile is counting itself down.
It's going to launch.
You take, and you go to the site, you open up the gates, you drive your
vehicle right up on top of the blast door, which is at ground level, right
on top of an octagon shaped nine ton door and sit right on top of that site,
right on top of that blast door, put your vehicle in neutral.
If you can find a rock big enough, chalk both tires, just chalk one front, one
back so it don't roll if there's a little bit of lean to one of the, one of the
doors or something, so I'll be retold.
Grab your stuff, get off that site and set up a one mile ECP entry control
point and wait for further orders in hopes that if this thing cannot be stopped
or overridden, when that, when that blast door blows out from underneath that
vehicle, it's going to fall down on top of that, on top of that rocket.
And all it's in hopes to do is to damage it, to offset its guidance control.
So it'll just go off aimlessly like a scud and crash.
That's what it, that's what they do and get down to 10 or 15 seconds and it
stops, then everything's normal again.
Crazy.
And people rolling up on these sites have sometimes seen those
crafts and they blow away.
And then that happens, you know, I would venture to say that there were
800 security policemen at Ellsworth airport space while I was there.
That's standard configuration.
That's not an operational readiness inspection or anything like that.
They were just normally 800 or right there about security
policemen, law enforcement and, or security.
Anybody that worked on that missile field, I would say, I would say one out
of every four has probably seen something in the night sky because everybody
works rotating shifts, whether they report it or tell their partner
about it is up to them, but I'd venture to say it's that frequent.
That's why, and that's just that Ellsworth that doesn't include
Minot, that doesn't include, uh, uh, Malmstrom or Effie Warren in Wyoming.
I've been told or asked just recently if I'd appear before Congress and I, and I
would, I would appear before Congress and I know that's pretty hair raising for a
lot of people, but when they get all the scientists and all the pilots and everything
else out of the way with these huge credentials, I was just a security
policeman at 23 years of age.
I have a high school education, have some college.
I've been most mostly technical schools all my life.
And I really try to read a lot and do a lot of things to educate myself further.
It just didn't work out for me being able to do the things, you know,
going to college and so forth.
When they're done with all of that and they want a real up close and personal
account, then they got to come to me sooner or later.
And you don't have to put that in that, in this, but you know, that's what
somebody from up there told me.
I said, eventually they got to hear somebody that's had a close and
personal, uh, time with these things.
So being that I was on duty, I was a prime candidate for that as I've been told.
And I wish I had more witnesses.
I wish there were people that could just pull up out of nowhere, you
know, that were there.
But you know, there's just so much time has passed, you know, we've been through
so much with COVID and everything else.
I don't know.
What about, what about the guy you said you were buddies with where you ran in
and you started signaling what you thought was a B 52 at the time?
What was his name?
Bill Holliman.
Are you still in touch with Bill?
Well, I know it was William, William something Holliman.
We called him Bill and he was from North Carolina.
I have searched how many names are the last name of Holliman.
I don't know.
And that's the only way I've even, but have, did you even speak to him one
on one after that being like, remember when we signaled the thing, I was never,
uh, I never went back to November control.
They sent me to Kelo control.
They just completely separated us.
I never saw Michael Johnson again until about, uh, three weeks later.
So they just separated you and how far is Kelo control from November?
Well, yeah, honestly, it's a sister flight, but it's where the supervision
hang their hat at nights.
Instead of us being at November control or any of the, or Oscar flight or any
of the other flights where you don't have the supervision of a flight chief
and assistant flight chief, uh, you do it Kelo.
So they have a way of monitoring, watching every single thing that you do.
And also the OIC.
And so you just never saw Bill again?
Uh, no, maybe a guard mount once or twice.
Hey Bill, that kind of thing.
Just passing.
You ever say, Hey Bill, you know, what about that?
I wanted to, but it never really presented itself.
And there were a couple of other guys there, even that Sergeant Garza.
Uh, I'd love to have spoken with him again because, uh, and he was from Texas.
I remember that we talked about it and, uh, cause I was just that
close born in Port Arthur, but I was born in Virginia and my parents
and they moved to, uh, to Port Arthur.
My dad could ship in and out of there.
And you received a hypnotic regression about all of this, right?
I did.
I certainly did.
Um, uh, Bob Upton did my first one and Yvonne Smith did my second one.
What came out?
Uh, well, the, the, uh, the inside of the craft, what was that like?
I I've got some drawings of it, but what I saw or what I experienced in my mind,
uh, was not all pleasant.
And these, these were the, the one that was messing with me was a very tall one
that was doing the, you know, one thing to me, whereas in regression number two,
I found out that Michael was laying opposite to me and there was one of the
short ones or small ones between us both.
And, uh, he was facing one direction.
I was facing the opposite direction, kind of like, like that would be.
And, uh, what were they doing?
Were they doing taking samples or?
Well, the tall one did something to my wrist and I kept telling him how to hurt
me and he, and, uh, he told me, he said something, you know, we don't hurt you
or something like that.
I don't remember.
I'd have to go back and listen to it again.
I, I don't even listen to my first regression session for a year.
I was so afraid of what I, what I would hear or what I would find out or what I
would see in the actual incident itself that when I, when I sat down from inside
that window, I want you to know that the words do not fear travel through my body
like a vibration, like, uh, uh, like a hiss, a telepathic, I don't know, but I
kept hearing over and over, do not fear, do not fear, uh, do not fear.
And was it a good vibe or bad as far as your, it was, it was, it was complete.
It was as if, you know, when somebody says something, you'll say, uh, what or
huh, there's none of that.
There's no misinterpretation of someone speaking to, you know, exactly what's
being said, was there, was there sort of a sense of their intention as positive
or negative, or was it assuring, assuring, I think no matter what you see visually,
do not fear.
And that's what we seem to have the hardest problem with is what we're seeing visually.
If you had kind of a best guess, do you think they had positive intentions or
negative or I think they had positive, but they fulfill their mission, whatever
that mission is, whether it's to obtain DNA material or what have you, or some
kind of a programming or I don't know any, whatever they want to do, they're
going to do outside of like the obvious, which is you experienced this kind of
crazy paranormal disruption in your life.
Uh, did this kind of, was this an inflection point or did it change your
life in a dramatic way afterwards?
How so I had to find out everything about archeology and pyramids.
And so that was just something that it almost felt like it was installed
inside of you or downloaded.
Yes.
And why, still today, why do you think you became so interested in that?
I have no idea.
Do you know that, um, the air force, uh, paid for this movie called star gate.
Have you ever seen this movie?
Absolutely.
So, you know, there's a star gate in the pyramid.
It's sort of this portal, this like time travel machine.
Do you think that might be related to, you know, why you're so interested in
pyramids?
I think they were power generators and whatever they generated power to was
worldwide, and I think it was at a time in which we have been completely blacked
out from, have you heard of Christopher Dunn?
I have.
Yes.
An engineer.
Yes, I have.
What do you think of his theory?
I think his theory is absolutely correct.
Uh, Robert shock.
And I think, absolutely.
I think, uh, the erosion marks on that grace finks and everything else around it.
Can you, can you recapitulate or can you retell Christopher Dunn theory
just for the audience?
Well, the, the archeological tools in which was used to create, uh, and, and.
Carver cut this granite or not in the archeological, uh, array of tools of
copper and wooden chisels today in some form of, of, uh, advanced mathematics
was used in order to create what they did.
And even just the placement of the pyramid, great pyramid itself.
I mean, the entire plateau is the only place they can support that way.
And the entire plateau was built before the pyramids were placed on top of it.
So who had that technology and what was used to who, who, who mandated that?
What Pharaoh woke up one morning after his dates and whatever else he ate and
he said, ah, let's build that plateau so it can hold, uh, how many millions
of pounds is this thing way?
I have no idea right now, but I mean, 750 feet from edge from corner to
corner and what 432 feet high.
Is that right?
Uh, on 13 acres.
I mean, how, how can that be?
Do you think the beings you experienced are aliens or do you think they're humans
or what exactly did the alien, what exactly did the entities you encountered
look like?
Oh, they look like grays.
They look like the small grays, but the one behind them, I guess you would
classify him as a tall gray on Whitley Strieber's book communion.
Of course, the first time I saw that picture, I froze in my, I froze in my, in
my stride and I had to have that book and, uh, Barnes and Noble or wherever
it was at the time when it came out.
And I literally, before I opened the first to the first page, I literally
just sat and stared at that picture for many hours before I ever even read his
book.
Do you think that there, there's actually a line from communion by
Whitley Strieber where, uh, it's like this weird joke, you know, he actually,
I think he or his wife comments on how ugly, uh, the aliens are and the alien
turns back and he goes, uh, someday soon, my dear, you'll look like us.
So it's this implication that actually we're kind of turning into these beings.
In 10,000 years, will we have these smaller appendages, our little fingers,
our little toes, how will our bodies be at that particular point in time?
You know, how will our diets change?
How will light change?
How will radiation that affects our atmosphere today?
How will it change in the future?
How will it change us completely as we become a space faring civilization?
And we will be in, you know, whatever, whenever that could take place, we,
we will do that.
Uh, how will that change us without the gravity that we, that we undergo today
and, and the things in which we live with today, you know, radio waves, 5g,
everything has an effect on you.
So you think these beings could be us from the future?
No, I don't think they are.
I don't think we're going to be there.
I don't think we're that lucky.
So what do you think they are?
Do you think they're from another dimension or?
They could be.
I mean, the technology is wide open.
Anything you can imagine probably is.
What was the craft like?
So you're, you're in the inside of this thing.
What did it look like?
A beehive.
Beehive.
Yeah.
How so?
Well, there were, uh, from my looking around as I did in that playground, like
I always try to take a mental picture of something, they were just multi-levels
with, with all these small grays everywhere going to and fro and doing
whatever they were doing.
I just got to look for a moment and I was following one and even the
floor and the boards around the bottom of the floor, uh, had energy was
everything emanated power in some way.
Uh, the walls, uh, was there a humming associated?
Not that I can remember.
And it almost felt like the tall gray was maybe in charge of these smaller grays.
Absolutely.
In that room.
Another thing too, I was not on a table.
I was, uh, from my memory, I was on some type of a, uh, I was like wrapped in a
triangular kind of, uh, beam or something that was body length, about four foot in
the air and, uh, as like a, a, a strange light would not a strange light.
It's even hard to describe, but it was as if I was inserted in something that
was some type of a force field or some kind of a, a holding field that they
could move you around in like a gurney without wheels, a table without a back
or, or wheels or legs attached to it.
And I felt as if, you know, they, when they reached in or when he lifted my
arm up, lifted me up right here on my wrist, you know, it exited that, that
pyramidal field or whatever it was above me and it was in his atmosphere at that
time, uh, in my, in hypnosis, that's what I saw.
The other thing was, this is mess interesting.
I, uh, I'm taken to a room when I first get there, I'm taken into this room.
If you can call it a room, everything's generated, everything's power gen,
there's power on every wall, every nook and cranny, where no buttons or, or, or
places to insert a tape or anything like that, but the whole place is like, is
powered and there were all these old things like a sewing machine table with
a singer sewing machine on it, those old 50 style lamps that went from the floor
to the ceiling and had bulbs sticking off of them like that, TV and a cabinet.
It was like an antique shop for future.
Yeah, like a museum and a, and a, and this is, uh, uh, old wooden box radio.
And I found that to be so cool because I ended up buying a, a US RKO radio
in a mahogany cabinet that worked with tubes from a rancher there in South
Dakota that I wish I'd have never had wooden knobs and everything on it and
worked beautifully and, uh, that from that, from when I saw that I had to
have one of these damn radios, I don't know why, but this one was much nicer
than what I saw, but iron, a steam iron standing.
I drew pictures of, of, of it, the best of my recollection of everything.
And then I was told in the, in the very back of the room, there was a round
window, but it looked like, it looked like it was a, it was a round window
with a slice taken out of it, like a pie without, with a slice removed from it.
And I was told I could go look out that window, but I was too afraid to walk
over there and look out of it for some reason I didn't, I don't know why, but I
mean, but I felt at ease, but I still didn't want to know, or didn't want to
see out that window, something really bothered me and about looking out that
window.
And I was told that twice that I could go look out the window and I didn't.
So then I was told to follow and to follow when I did, I followed a small
gray in front of me, little eggs and, uh, like a little gray type, uh, like
spandex suit or something on, on, I guess.
I mean, these, these things are so foreign to you.
There's this, this whole visual concept is so foreign to you.
It's very hard to find words for a lot of it, even after 44 years.
And it's just difficult.
And I went, I followed him, went, turned left in this small little opening
area and went into this room where it was just fogged.
And then that's where my memories end, but that's where the thing was done to
my wrist and then I don't know from that point on, I had seemed to be right
around the end of it.
Did it feel like a dream-like state or did it feel physical in this
hypnotic regression?
Oh no, it felt physical.
It felt real.
The, uh, the first time I was hypnotized, which was, uh, Robert Upton, Bob
Upton, uh, I had, I had a pretty bad time because I never, I'm not a person
ever thinking that I could be hypnotized to start with.
I'm pretty strong-willed and, and, uh, I feel as if I'm common-sensed also.
And, and I just thought, oh, hypnosis is for someone else.
It's just not for me, but, uh, Robert wanted me to try it.
So I said, okay.
And, and, uh, the funny thing, cause, uh, we had been through a hurricane
just prior to that down in Brunswick, Georgia, and I had some roof damage
and deck damage on the back of my home.
And they were reroofing my house that day.
Now, what a day to be hypnotized on by this guy who he came up from Jacksonville,
67 miles south of me.
And, uh, he's like the, uh, lead, uh, hypnotic regression person for a
move on at the time.
I don't know if he still is, but he has my admiration.
I couldn't do his job.
And he didn't get any sort of weird sense from him that he had ulterior motives.
No, no.
Now, now Robert Hastings had given him a set of questions that he was
going to ask me and he told me that.
And I was fine with that.
They were reroofing my home.
So you'd imagine there's like 15 people on my roof and I, my, my
home has got a really steep roof.
I couldn't do it.
I can't even climb up there anymore.
But so they're literally peeling off plywood and replacing plywood,
nailers and everything else.
Things being tossed, run up there.
I never heard a single, a single air gun going off during that hypnosis session.
That's why I knew I was hypnotized.
I never heard any of that, but he took me down to a level.
He had a way of doing it that evidently worked.
But once I did and I confronted what I saw, I, uh, it really upset me a great
deal, literally come into face to face and, and smelling that smell again,
hearing those words again, uh, maybe I was, I got that deep into it
and I never thought that I could.
Uh, I don't know if a person's mind has changed as we had said earlier.
I don't know if that's what happens, but
was it cathartic at all, or was it just purely painful?
It got painful.
It really did.
I mean, when, when, when I visualized and saw what was being done in my wrist
and the way in which it was being done, it just, I mean, he could have
cut my whole arm off, I wouldn't have known the difference.
I couldn't, there's nothing I could do to stop it.
You know, I mean, it could have been the end of my life right there.
And that's how, that's how.
Did you know implants as far as the puncture?
Well, I have no idea.
And those are on the other side of my body anyway, or those pock marks that, um.
Do you still have the marks at all?
Yeah.
Can I see him?
Sure.
Right there.
Add these socks on.
Wow.
Wow, wow, wow.
Yeah.
Those look.
I mean, just like perfectly vertically aligned.
Well, I had a doctor who's no longer with us, but like so clearly not like a spider,
but like too, way too big for that.
Like, you know, yeah.
Well, what would you say?
Like, like a couple of centimeters, maybe a centimeter.
Dr.
Mark Goll, um, he, he did, I had back surgery years ago and he did that.
And we had talked, we had taught, he was a really great guy.
Unfortunately, COVID took him way too young as it did many, many people.
And we were sitting in my backyard one night and after he had looked at this
and he said, you know, he said, I'm going to be honest with you, Mario.
Cause I wanted to get something from him recorded, you know, and, uh, didn't
have that chance to, the last time I saw him was probably 2019 and he has some
family issues and had to go up north and where he got COVID and he died and, uh,
his kids went to school with my kids at Frederica Academy on St.
Simon's Island, uh, in Georgia.
But he said, you know, what perplexed him was that there was no known life
saving event that he could think of even including up to a car accident that
anything would be put in there or down here to either put in something or take
out something he said, and they're exactly the same depth and this in the
same size, you know, top to bottom.
He said, so I find that really odd, you know, cause they, I told him the
whole incident what happened and he just, he's like, holy crap indicates
a technology or paradigm of our medical understanding.
And if you look at this up close under a microscope, which has been done
from a pair or a magnifying scope, it has a little dimple right now, right
in the top of it, like a, like you drop water in a, you know, drop a rock in
water and it goes, that little dimple is right in the middle of both of them.
That is really, that is really strange.
So I don't know when these happened.
I honestly don't, I don't remember healing from them.
Uh, I didn't say it happened during my incident in 77.
I don't know where they came from.
Do you feel like you have a mission associated with this interest in
pyramids where it's like, you know, at the time at which you're, you leave
this earth, you want to accomplish something related to the pyramids?
Man, that's a great question.
Yes, I would like to know the answers.
I would like to see those tools, you know, as, uh, as Christopher Dunn says,
I would like to see those tools.
And finally the admission that they had tools far greater than
what we ever have imagined.
And I think just like melting rock in South America and so I could say human
and some of the other facilities where these rocks are, you know, 13 sided
and just an inch and a half and stuck in a hole is two feet deep all
the way through the entire rock.
How do you do that without softening that stone?
Do you feel like, do you feel like these sites globally?
I feel like this is what Graham Hancock and Randall Carlson, Robert
Shock, all these guys are kind of getting into this idea that maybe a lot of this
ancient geological, you know, architecture, megalithic architecture,
that's precociously astronomically aligned in a way that we don't even understand
today and it lines up with, you know, ice age or pre ice age, uh, you know,
kind of vernal equinox.
Absolutely.
And so do you think that a lot of this architecture was, these were maybe
kind of celestial ascent chambers that were star gates to another world?
Sure.
And maybe things were getting kind of gnarly or cataclysmic and
they were portals to elsewhere.
Elsewhere.
Totally believe that.
Have you ever seen the Netflix show dark by any chance?
I've seen some of it, I believe.
So it involves, uh, missing people around nuclear bases and
a secret time travel program.
No, I got to see that.
Yeah.
You should check it out because, um, I wish they'd call me.
I'd like to know, you know, Lawrence, Lawrence Bell is so Bell aircraft.
So they broke the sound barrier in 1947 X 15, Chuck Yeager.
Exactly.
And so there's an article in 1956 where they're saying we're going to beat gravity
and it's right around the bend.
And Lawrence Bell's quote from this article is, uh, we are already working
with nuclear, nuclear fuels to cancel out gravity.
And so you got to think if, if time travel is possible at any point in the
future, it's probably always been possible.
Right.
And so where would we discover some sort of time travel program?
It would probably be co-located with nuclear programs.
Absolutely.
So, and then how would you affect timelines?
You might do it with, you know, particular people who represent kind of nodes or
whatever, who get interested in things like pyramids after, you know, their
encounters.
And so do you think that, you know, that's a possible explanation that maybe
a future time travel program represents an overlay over all of these nuclear sites
in a way that somehow, you know, might profoundly shift humanity and might also
keep us alive.
Because if you think about where is the center of the apocalypse, it's these
nuclear sites.
I mean, where, what, what's going to dictate the end of the world or not, you
know, it's going to be these sites.
So I have no idea.
These are crazy speculation, but so gravity is, is very related with time and
general relativity.
So, you know, Lawrence Bell is right.
And they're kind of using nuclear fuels to cancel out gravity.
Maybe you're using nuclear fuels to mess with time too.
It just makes you wonder how much technology that has been buried somehow or
another has been removed from our everyday conscious thought, you know, and
why was that removed?
Did we get so dangerous to ourselves?
I mean, unfortunately, I wish we weren't so warlike because you don't believe
something that I believe in.
We're supposed to go to war over that.
I just, I just, I just disliked that so much, you know, and religion, you know,
I don't want to get into that, but what you believe is fine with me.
Yeah.
What you believe is fine with me.
What I believe is fine with me.
And why can't it just be that?
Do you think that, yeah, sorry.
No, no, no.
I do think that this technology that we're speaking of, even though we don't
know it truly exists, it points to its existence in some way.
And one day I think we will find the magic key somewhere.
There's a craft.
If it hasn't already been discovered, it's sitting in a cave somewhere or under
the ocean somewhere under a ledge somewhere, or maybe even circling the
planet invisible that we can't see.
We're going to run into one day.
I don't know.
Well, maybe it'll happen sooner than maybe it'll happen sooner or later.
And I, I just hope I honestly do.
And I get asked this all the time.
Well, you think they're going to come and defeat us and take us over.
And, and my answer is always the same.
Look at any civilization that's out there comes here within their own
lifetime and leaves and goes back in their same lifetime, that's 10,000
light years advanced to us.
That's what Carl Sagan said that bar none.
That's just 10,000 light years advanced to us.
So think about that.
We're like the ants in an ant bed and they're standing in there looking
at us, you know, I often think about the reverse visualization that night when
I was flipping the facility lights at that, at that craft, whatever it was
at the time to me, what would I have thought in my mind had I been up there
looking down at this rectangular shape site, somebody's turning off and on
the lights real quick and succession.
Why would I flash back or wait a minute?
How, how does that person down there see us up here?
Why would they know that we're not supposed to be here or we're
just up here observing?
How would they know that?
Do we find out who this guy is or a person is I should say, or what?
I don't know.
I've done that reverse thing a couple of times to try to give answers to myself,
which always end up, you know, with a zero, I'm right back where I started.
But I do want to say that where new Lake reservoir dam was,
it's a Pythagorean triangle from November one, November five, over to
new Lake reservoir and back to November one control, I believe based on that
position of new Lake reservoir dam, that's where that crap was.
It was over that body of water when I saw it, why, I don't know, but there's,
there's always some type of a, there's a lot of sightings over water.
Yes.
And the deepest part of that reservoir, I think, is only like a
reconstruction right now.
Cause I've been talking about it a lot for the last couple of years.
I don't know if that's done anything, but, um, the people in Newel are really good.
And I, I, while we were there, uh, doing that filming, there were, uh, a couple
of individuals we're out on Ormond road.
That's the road that November five is on.
It's a dirt road still today.
And there's a golf course off to the left side of the road.
There's a golf course on the left side of the road, and there's a golf course
still today.
And there's a golf course off to the left side of it.
When you, when you turn out a new on the Ormond road in that day, you know, the
town's so small that when we arrived there early in the morning to film, all
these people started seeing us.
So they, you know, news travels fast through there and they're great people.
I've always, I've always had a lot of respect for those folks and, uh, great
cooks to great Western Plains cooks, man.
I cook some good food, but, uh, you would not believe the parade we had going up
and down Ormond road watching this film.
And it was the strangest thing because I had not been back to November
five since that night.
And the producer did not want to go directly in front of November five site
itself, because, uh, there's now like a small cattle processing facility on it,
built on it, cause it's built on the bedrock and when they detonated and
collapsed the silos in and, and returned it, they left the fencing
and the rock base there.
So these ranchers used it to store hay on or do something on their cattle.
The fencing is all still there.
We could have used another site, but instead they went about 150
yards, uh, to the east of the site.
And we were looking into a plain field, you know, while I'm holding up my
drawings and the drones over my shoulder, taking pictures of them.
I just felt that not very good.
And, uh, but when I got out of that vehicle and walked toward that site,
man, that feeling came over me.
I about went to my knees and, uh, and hypnosis when, uh, Robert Upton
finished that hypnosis, something was wrong with me.
And about four days later, I went to, uh, my, uh, pulmonologist, uh, and I was
in AFib and, uh, so I had to go in the next day because my heart was out of
rhythm, never had any heart problems whatsoever ever in my life.
I've always been an athlete.
And, uh, of course they put the, the patches on and shot me and sync
resynced me, I guess, and, uh, about a week went by and I started thinking
about this thing over and over again.
Boom, I went right back in AFib.
So I had to go back and do it again.
And, uh, then they put me on medication.
So I have to take medication, you know, and anytime you go into AFib, I guess,
they, uh, it puts you on a blood thinner.
Do you regret having done the hypnotic regression?
Cause it really gave me some insight, you know, and then, and it made it
a lot easier when I, when I, uh, did the session just last year or year
before last with, uh, Yvonne Smith in California, do you ever experience weird
electromagnetic effects with your body or like what sort of stuff, like a light
going off or something when I walk in a room with fluorescent light fluorescent
light, I've got a little, a little light fixture it's named Honda phones dying
quickly, anything like that.
No, I have had some other strange things go on though.
Uh, Robert Hastings.
I talked about that with emails vanishing everywhere, you know, off the
cloud and everywhere else just wiped clean.
I've had that happen, uh, as is he, but, um, yeah, I've had several incidents
where that has really bothered me.
Then the night of, uh, December 17th, 2017, uh, my son was in his room.
He was, he was home from, from, uh, working, uh, he was working, he was
in living in Florida, came on the visit.
Uh, and it was right at 4 11 AM.
And there's, that's also another thing about waking up at certain times
of the night, one 11, three 33, four 11.
Uh, it's just, it's just strange how that, how that happens.
But, uh, I pay attention to it.
And, uh, I have a room in the back of the house because I, I worked
12 hour shifts, so it rotated.
So sometimes I'd have to, you know, sleep during the day, you know, till
3 PM, get up to go in for a 6 PM to 6 AM shift, you know, so it was rotating.
So I had to have it darkened out so you could sleep.
You just guys can't sleep in sunlight.
I don't know anybody that can, but, uh, anyway, I was, I was there sleeping
and had to get up for work and all of a sudden I opened my eyes and I had
this, I'm standing at the foot of my bed.
I have, I have never been a person to sleepwalk ever in my life that I know.
I know ever.
And I'm standing at the foot of my bed, holding onto my bed frame with my right
hand and directly in front of me, there's about a four and a half or a five foot
whole diameter in a North wall of my bedroom.
And on that, in that circle that vanished immediately, like sparks
flew off either side of it.
That's like, what the hell?
Anyway, as soon as that, as soon as that flashed out or went away, all the
lights in my house started flickering just all over the house.
And then the strange alarms started, I started hearing them and my son
popped through my door and he goes, dad, what the hell's going on?
He goes, what's going on?
I said, I don't know, son.
He goes, what's those alarms?
And I said, I don't know.
I grabbed my pistol.
I didn't know why I was going to clear my house, you know?
And, uh, which I did.
I couldn't explain what I just saw and hadn't even verbally said anything about
it yet, and it was just right here in front of me, uh, and mind you, just two
dressers that were partially that had a, that were partially gone or in
that dark circle that I saw.
And so I cleared my house and the, and I go into the kitchen area and the, all
the lights were just like, just barely on, like they're just like the candle
light all throughout the house and the stove, the oven, the microwave and
refrigerator, they have low voltage alarms on them, which I never knew.
That's what the alarms were.
They were all going off.
So everything seemed to be normal other than the fact that the lights were on.
I tried flipping on lights and they wouldn't come on.
They just come on barely and just flicker for a minute.
And I just turned it back off, you know, but the stuff, but the light over
the stove, it was doing that every light, every electrical component in my
home was affected, everything, doorbell system, everything.
So I went back and talked to my son.
I said, Jake, I said, what the heck was that?
What the heck was that, man?
He goes, I don't know, dad.
It's weird.
He gets, it's really weird.
You can call them and talk to them about it.
So I said, well, I'll call Georgia power in the morning when I get up, you know?
So I, I just put everything down.
I laid back down and just thinking, you know, uh, what was that?
And about eight o'clock, my son pops through my door and go, he knocks first.
He says, Hey dad, he goes, George powers here.
I said, what?
He said, yeah, Georgia powers in the front yard.
And I live on an acre.
So to my, to the street from my front porch is about 200 feet.
And, uh, so I got dressed and I hobbled out there and these guys are out there
working on the, where the power distribution comes into my home and it's all underground.
My home was built in 97.
And, uh, so I found the supervisor.
I said, I said, Hey, I said, how you doing, sir?
I said, I told him my name.
He goes, is this your house?
And I said, yes, sir.
He just looked at me.
And, uh, I said, wow.
I said, what happened?
He goes, um, he just looked at me and he said, uh, well, he
lost, he lost power, lost the leg of power.
I said, dang, does that up?
Does that mess up the whole neighborhood?
He goes, he looked at me.
He says, no, he says just your house.
I said, what do you mean?
He goes, well, you lit up our board downtown like the 4th of July out here.
And I said, well, how did I do that?
We were all asleep.
You said, I don't know.
He said, but we're going to have to replace this leg.
So you have power in your home.
He said, come on, I'll show you something.
Say they had already taken this big dolly and it had like transformer equipment.
I've got pictures of it.
Call Robert Hastings.
First thing they take this transformer thing on, on a dolly, take it to
the back where my meter is and they jumper in to that meter box.
So to establish power or a, uh, what do you call it?
To, um, uh, refine the, the power going in my home instead of, instead of just
two legs, it gives it a third leg.
Somehow it converts it.
And I don't know how that works, but I got pictures of it and he said, you'll
be fine till we can come out and replace that wire.
And, uh, it took them about two days, three days and they were back and they did it.
But, uh, I just kept questioning what I had seen and what had happened and why
that happened and ours was the only house affected a couple of weeks later.
One of our neighbor's kids come by that.
My son used to play with, he stopped his truck.
He's got an F one 50.
He says, Hey, Mr.
Woods.
And he's been in my backyard.
These kids have had parties.
They all shot bows and arrows together, BB guns, name it.
You know, we do all that stuff, ride motorcycles.
He goes, Hey, Mr.
Woods, he said, um, I was cutting my grass and he waved at me and I'll
stop and I stopped and he stopped.
And he goes, Hey, what was going on there?
Uh, last week or so when all those lights were in your backyard.
And I said, what are you talking about?
He just, he didn't hesitate it for a second.
He goes, he goes, your backyard was lit up like a Hollywood set or something.
He said, like those great big lights, they say up in the air.
He says a whole backyard was lit up.
I said, what do you mean, man?
He said, yeah, it was four o'clock in the morning.
He was leaving for work.
That's how he saw that.
And I said, well, you know, I've only got two spotlights right there
on the corner of that room outside.
And I said, uh, and on the corner of the back and the lights over the, on
the rear patio, you know, he goes, I don't know, but it was lit up
like you wouldn't believe.
And I just, I just kept it to myself.
I said, man, what did happen?
Really?
So what would they, what interests could they possibly, they would have in,
you know, in a 65 year old man or whatever age I was at that time,
what, what could they possibly want?
I mean, what do you think?
I have no idea.
I honestly don't have a clue.
What do you think?
What do you hope the world gets from your testimony?
Understanding perhaps or possibility of, uh,
perhaps not to fear as much.
And, uh, not to think that they're here to defeat us because they were, we
wouldn't be having this conversation right now.
They'd have done it long ago.
Anyhow, do you think they're hybridizing themselves with us?
Could very well be depends upon their, maybe their situation on their own planet.
Maybe they're overcrowded perhaps, or they're something's dying there or
progression through space.
You know, you can't always get back to the starting point.
You know, maybe they have to occupy worlds along the way in their great expansion.
Well, it sounds like even on Ellsworth that it was kind of an open secret that,
you know, a lot of people had had some interesting experiences before you, Mario.
Do you think, you know, I was talking with Robert Hastings and you know, he was
noting that he had 167 ICPM security personnel, radar operators, guys on, on
bases like yourself who've experienced crafts.
And then I remember I asked him, I was like, you know, Robert, uh, what
percentage of these people have had close encounters of the third kind where
they've actually met beings?
And he said something like seven or eight, but then he said, I didn't ask
anybody, those were the people that volunteered.
And I think about the culture of secrecy and humility, uh, when it comes to
working at nuclear bases, if you have seven or eight people who you're just
incidentally finding out are having, you know, close encounters with the third
kind and actually seeing beings, it's probably over a hundred of the 170.
It's probably a, you know, a massive, uh, you know,
never alone, always with a partner.
You were never alone in any nuclear facility.
It's a two man rule.
It has to be two of you at all times.
Are there other cases like yours that you've found out about where the
partner sort of seems to disappear or go missing?
Terry Lovelace and his partner, Toby.
Cause Terry's still around, right?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
He's a great guy.
But Toby's gone.
Toby's gone.
He, uh, Terry told me that he, he literally, he never fully
recovered after their incident.
Now he was not on duty.
They were simply on a camping trip.
And is Toby like in some facility, mental health facility, or is he just
like, no, no trace of him.
Terry can't even find him.
No, no, no, he was available.
And, uh, of course the VA, uh, they were giving him, you know, whatever
pills or whatever to help his anxiety.
And, um, from my understanding, he had a really bad drinking problem
from that period of time.
And, uh, some people, I guess that's the way it affects and it's really quite sad.
Uh, and he was a real light-skinned black guy also.
And we talk about that correlation between us and our partners.
And it happened the same year.
Also in that movie, close encounters, a third kind came out.
I, I went to see it in rapid city at the theater, you know, on
main streets, still there today.
Uh, or the building is, I'm not sure if the theater is or not, but I think it is.
And, uh, that part where, uh, Roy Neary is crossing the railroad tracks and,
and he's looking at the map, got the flashlight in his mouth and that light
pops on, if you'll notice during that period of time, his body was, it was
as if he was being, um, whatever he was hearing or feeling was talking to him
or programming him on the inside.
He's a literally, he's doing some kind of a weird, uh, uh, I should say
receiving of whatever is, is giving him.
And you can see it and he portrays it very well.
And it really made me think a lot, because when I saw that movie is as if
what's going on in a missile field right now, not just to me, but to these
craft are out there, there's cattle mutilations going on, Linda
Moulton house in the area.
I tried contacting her like 20 might've been before that, but she got my email
into our 2014, I had sent something to her and, uh, she worked at a station
in Denver, Colorado was, you know, like, I don't know if she was in what kind
of news she did, but she was investigating cattle mutilations all
throughout the Northwest where we were.
And, uh, of course we were told not to speak to any media people whatsoever.
But the point is that, um, when he underwent what he did under that light
before that craft let him go, it seemed to put something in his mind, which
really struck me before it stopped, you know, and moved, I had to literally
get up out of my seat and I ran out and sat on the curb on main street in
rapid city, cause I, I, what I just saw felt as if it was a direct replay of
what I just went through only a little bit different where, you know, the
crap was above him and these little guys came up to the side of our vehicle.
Just that, just like that.
And it's really hard to deal with, you know, often it feels like, um, the
ear bones are messed with the bones dealing with balance and orientation.
And then this is a interesting kind of connection around them.
Checking your teeth.
My buddy made a documentary on this guy, Andre Puharich and Puharich
helped start the MK ultra program.
So it's like CIA, Yugoslavian guy.
What is he?
Is he, I think he was read something about the guy with that name.
I'm pretty sure I did.
Yeah.
He's either he's like, yeah, Eastern European or Russian.
Maybe, maybe Yugoslavian.
And, um, yeah, he was at Northwestern and he had, you know, the Roundtable
Institute at Maine where they were sort of summoning stuff.
And then he was also, he had this actually school of space children in
upstate New York where he was, you know, studying all sorts of telepathy
and download channeling.
Actually, the book Star Trek came, he had this one, uh, channeler
named Phyllis, Phyllis Schaeffer.
And, uh, she wrote a book called the only planet of choice that was
channeled and she was in communication with the nine quote unquote, which
is this council of, you know, possible ET beings and they were talking about
the earth as a bottleneck of consciousness.
We have to get past this bottleneck in order to ascend whatever fascinating
stuff, but, um, interestingly, Puharich found this guy who was sort of
schizophrenic and he was hearing voices in his head, but it almost sounded like
the voices he was hearing were similar to like what somebody would describe in
an alien telepathy experience where they were, they were getting, he was getting
kind of immediate downloads and Puharich was studying him and they realized he
was a construction worker and he was working with, uh, you know, sawing
metals or whatever.
And so they found these fine, uh, you know, metals in his teeth and that
somehow in Puharich belief was that, um, extremely low frequency radio waves
were actually responsible for thought in a way that's upstream or connected with
the acoustical waves that, you know, represent our normal cognition.
And so maybe they were checking your teeth either because they were worried
that you were already receiving downloads or like in touch prior to this
experience, or because they thought the implant where they would communicate
with you on a go-forward basis might be there.
Wow.
I've never even thought of it that way.
I, some people said they were looking at you maybe for radioactive contamination
or something like that.
You might be right.
I mean, this is my, my hair.
That really does make sense, man.
I mean, you got to look at it all.
You can't, you can't discount anything.
Cause you're dealing with a technology that, that don't sit on couches, you
know, that, that can speak full volumes through your cellular work in your body.
They don't need to communicate.
I mean, they have no, that's something that's their brain is so far past that
they don't have to speak words to you.
And their language is, is probably where we say, and, um, um, man, like
there's none of that in that.
Yeah.
They have those conversations.
It's direct route access.
And you never ever will forget that feeling and that sound ever.
Yeah.
It's almost like we have this meme library that was, is installed or something.
You look at like Descartes demon, like maybe that's actually more true than
not where, uh, the Cartesian 3d time bound plane is sort of controlled, uh,
at least as far as the veneer that we see and, uh, the shade, the shades of that
we're seeing shadow of play of something higher and, uh, that something higher
might communicate, be able to communicate on a much more direct level and also be
able to, um, shade or, uh, you know, in Plato, you have like, you know, it's
like, don't trust your senses, right?
Right.
You have to contemplate virtue and you can ascend out of the lower world or
whatever, there's much more and, uh,
I only want to read any of that.
Yeah.
And, um, and you forget your primordial self and maybe in experiences like this,
you sort of, you know, you get back in touch with it, but maybe, maybe some of
these beings are, yeah, you know, I was at, I helped put offs house not too
long ago and on his bookshelf, he had this book called daemonic reality.
And it was like, you know, like, I don't know, I got to read the book,
but it's, it feels like the implication is like our low level reality is kind
of controlled by some sort of, you know, Gnostic traditions.
You might call it like a Demiurge where, um, we're not seeing, you know,
ultimate reality.
I think in Lou's book, I found the part where he talks about some of his
superiors, where they have this demonic, uh, direction thinking these things were.
Yeah.
It's called the Collins elite.
Yes.
You know, versus where Lou was in his thinking, which I agree with a hundred
percent, I've been told that several times, well, you know, these are just
demons, these are just angels and demons, you know, all right, well, what's
your definition definition of an angel?
That's what, yeah, in my book, I mean, I would just look at somebody that says
that, you know, I'm not saying it doesn't exist, you know, I, I, I'm serious.
And I've, I've seen something in my time too, after our mother passed away
and that really, uh, an apparition, I'll just say, and it was my mother's
apparition and my brothers both saw it.
And, uh, uh, and that established me, you know, that night I said, and
we all talked about it.
Our mama was standing in that kitchen in a lightning storm.
Her figure was there, not her face, but her figure was there.
And at two o'clock in the morning on a thunderstorm night in Tampa, Florida,
a couple of days after she died.
And that's the truth.
But I, I, I totally agree with what you, what you're just saying there.
Cause I think that, uh, I always associate it to when you're in your mother's
womb and you're, and your dad or your mom, or you're one of your aunt's been
down or your brother's future brother or sister leans down and starts talking
to you and you're in your mother's womb, you know, baby hears that that to me.
Uh, directly related to what I kept hearing, do not fear that I recognized
it and, uh, the accent on that voice sounded as if, uh, something off of, uh,
what was that, um, Hogwarts or what, or what, what do you call it?
Um, yeah, Harry Potter, when that snake is talking to him, like that,
that's the way those basilisk.
That's the way those words rolled.
Do you like, I can't even do it.
Do not fear, do not fear and elongate it out.
Not just those words, uh, how short I was, do not fear it.
I still can't do it right, but it, it, it gets to every part of you in description.
It gets to every part.
You just feel it radiate through you.
And before joining Ellsworth Air Force Base, what was, what was
kind of your motivation?
Why'd you get into this?
Uh, honestly, uh, I should have probably gone in the Navy.
Uh, my father was a merchant seaman and he sailed with Texaco, sailed all of
his life, seen USOs, um, he was in a car accident in 73 and lost his life.
And I just turned 17 years old, uh, when that happened.
So it literally changed the entire configuration of my family.
And my thoughts prior to, I wanted to go to the, uh, maritime Institute.
I think it was in some part of Connecticut.
I could be mistaken.
Uh, and I wanted to become a captain.
I didn't want to be a chief engineer because I saw how dirty my dad would get.
Or I'd go down to an engine room of a ship that he was on at port and see him
climbing up out, out of a cylinder of a, of an engine.
So, you know, the size of these things are massive and, uh, I always
respected that a great deal.
But for me, uh, growing up in South Florida and, and Long Beach and other
places, I, uh, always had this aspiration for things that flew.
So whenever the Cape was launching and that kind of thing, I always went
outside either to see him or go with a bunch of friends, go to Cape
Pinaveral to, you know, to watch a rocket launch.
And originally I didn't want to go.
I wouldn't even think about security police.
Uh, but, uh, I'm colorblind.
And after I passed all the tests to work on rocket engines, cause I
thought NASA is my goal, right?
I, uh, was in the hallway at the aphid station in Jacksonville, just a young
guy, long hair down here and, uh, this little staff sergeant, she came running
up to me, she goes, uh, Mr.
Woods, she goes, we got to, we got to talk to you for a minute.
And I said, what is it?
You know, I was ready to go.
I was going to go back home to Tampa.
Uh, and she told me, she goes, uh, I need you to talk to somebody.
And I said, okay.
So I went back with her when in this office and there was this gentleman
standing there and I think he was like a tech sergeant, he six, he seven,
somewhere around there and he goes, uh, Mr.
Woods, he goes, I need you to look at some things.
And he opens up this sample book.
Like you would go pick out carpet, you know, with all these
different colors of carpet, but it was wiring.
And he said, show me the, the, uh, purple and yellow, uh, intertwined wire.
And I just looked, you know, and really I couldn't do it.
And, uh, he let me do that two or three times and he goes, that's why
you can't wire a rocket engine.
So it made perfect sense to me.
So of course I did score good on my ASPAP test.
So she asked me if I'd be interested in some other things.
And I said, sure, let's have a look.
So they had videotapes back then.
And, um, I looked at a couple of them and then I saw these guys
rappelling out of a helicopter, you know, fully clothed, fully armed,
you know, and it came out on fast ropes.
And I said, and they had berets on their head and I said,
that's what I want to do.
So that's how I ended up in security police and loved it.
So you want to be a rocket scientist?
Well, I wanted to do engines, rocket engines.
Yes.
I have a tough job.
I used to always launch rockets growing up as a kid.
Did you?
Yeah.
They were 98 cents for, you know, the little rocket engines, you know,
fuselages were all made of like, uh, paper towel rolls or something.
What do you think sparked your early interest in rockets and space?
Uh, I I'm sure that what I saw in 1961 at D Queen elementary
school in Port Arthur, Texas had something to do with it.
Uh, where'd you see in 1961?
Uh, my, my mother, uh, was taking me to my first grade, uh, school,
which was D Queen elementary.
And, uh, we were about the fifth or the seventh car back in line.
And I'm on the passenger side in the, in the front seat, no seatbelt.
We didn't do that back then.
My sister was in the back seat.
Of course, my mother's driving and she stopped short of the car in front of her.
And she says, look, Anthony, look at those flying saucers.
When's the last time your mother ever said something like that to you?
I mean, I'm just six years old, five and a half, six years old.
And I, I just couldn't even fathom what she said.
And they were right over a church, just maybe 25 to 50 feet in the air.
And there were three of them.
They were beautiful, prettiest craft ever seen in my life.
I can picture them in my mind right now.
My sister and I talk about it all the time.
And, uh, the thing that struck me was they were there long enough to where I kind of
did a really strange scan, looking around at people always kind of anything worth
memorizes and memorizing is worth looking around for a moment to take a quick mental
picture of it, if that explains that.
But we had a playground directly across from the school that the road was blocked
off and all the kids, everybody met out there before class time, every eye and arm
and hand and pointer finger was pointing in the air and then looking back to the
left at the side of the school, we didn't have AC back then.
So the windows were always open.
There were people, it was like a four, maybe five story building at the time.
It's been since rebuilt.
Uh, um, but anyway, all these people were pointing out the windows and the
grades went from kindergarten to 12th grade there.
So everybody, including teachers were looking outside and the strangest part
about it, it was over the directly over this church that sat right on the corner
of Dequeen Boulevard and the schools here and the church was there.
So they were just right here and we were right there next to it.
And my mom, she opens her door and steps out.
And my sister, I remember her saying, mom, I'm scared.
She says, it'll be okay, honey.
They're not here to hurt you.
That's what she said.
And I grabbed her by the other hand, we were hanging there watching them, you
know, and probably watched them for a good couple of minutes.
And they were white silver craft, standard saucer configuration with a dome on top
and a dome on the bottom, but they had these lights that went around the outer rim of it.
And they were all in, they were all synchronized and it was extremely fast.
It was so much to take in as something you've never seen or didn't, it couldn't
even know existed, but it felt so normal.
It looked so normal, like somebody was checking in on us.
If that's the word and when they left, it was all at one time straight up, if
there would have been clouds, they'd have punched holes through those clouds.
And they were just gone.
It just literally just went from that big around to this big around and out of your
sight.
And the strangest part about that, everybody on that playground in the school, in
school, nobody said a word about it.
Everybody went right back to what they were doing and never mentioned it.
All day long, have you talked to any of the witnesses since other than my sister, my
mother has since passed long ago, but, uh, uh, Port Arthur, Texas is a long time, a
long time ago, but, uh, I've never forgotten that.
So it's really, really something that's remarkable.
Did you feel changed after that at all?
Or in some way, my sister and I talked about it.
I just think the visualization of it and what it could possibly mean to a six year
old definitely has, and, you know, changing effects on what you've known forever.
You know, not questioning God because I believe in God and, uh, and, and, and my
savior, but I, I, it just changes you.
It, it, uh, opens your eyes or your mind into what is, or could be.
And that might've gotten you interested in space and rock, possibly that sort of
thing.
Yeah.
Interesting.
I don't think that, I don't think they come without a reason.
I, I, if I can just say that, I think, I think they have great effects and there's
seems to be this thing with the number three, what it could mean.
I don't know.
I know, I know Tesla had a real strange thing concerning the number three and
I've read a lot about him.
Um,
well, it's, yeah, it's a sort of Jesus died at 33.
Alexander the great died at 33 in Freemasonry of 33 levels.
Why do you think, why do you think that?
It's, it's such a, it's such a, like, like a life-changing event that seems
pretty, pretty bizarre that people won't, especially in 61, when you haven't
seen that many things in the sky.
No, ever other than aircraft with propellers.
There were no jets, you know, I flew on a bunch of them.
So even at a young age, but yeah, that's very true.
I, I, I always, I always wonder if just being in the proximity of these things,
if they're, if they're pulsing or emanating some type of, uh, some type of,
uh, uh, not energy, but a wave or, uh, something that might be inducing to
humankind, uh, maybe in the thought of them or, or, or some, some kind of idea.
Uh, you, I don't ever, uh, very few people that I've spoken with or call me
have ever run from a craft or if they've seen one, uh, up close and personal, but
it just amazes me that it just seems to be the normal thing when a person does
see it and then they later recollect and, oh, it's something different now, you know.
I don't know if your mom was so nonchalant about it, like that feels so
shocking, especially when you have your two, two young kids with you.
Uh, she had seen things before she said.
And, uh, and she literally didn't elaborate on any of it, but she said she had seen
things before in a Rocky mountain, North Carolina, growing up as a, as a kid.
And of course my father was from Benaca Honduras and he's seen so many things I
can't even in the, in the jungles and in the ocean, and he used to always tell me
of, of, you know, an entire crew of 29 or 30 men seeing something exit from the
water and come up into the atmosphere and bolt off, you know, and I just let it go.
I never really thought too much about it at all.
And, uh, if you, I don't know if you've ever heard of the Marine
Sulphur Queen, it was a ship that sank in 63.
Was she, uh, she left port in Port Arthur, Texas.
That was the first ship I ever went on as a child at five years old.
My father served on that vessel and had two cousins on board.
And, um, he had a job with Texaco at that particular time.
So I went with him to, he was getting his things and going up that gangway.
I lost, you know, they didn't net the gangways back then.
And I lost one of my shoes and I was so fearful of, I have my dad by the
hand, probably broke his fingers, but, uh, I was so fearful of falling through
the steps and into the water, you know, cause it was at nighttime and then she
sailed and she was gone just a couple of days later and they never found anything.
But one nameplate on her said Marine Sulphur on Miami beach and, uh, don't
know what happened to that vessel and all hands were lost.
So two of his cousins went down on that ship.
Since I did the documentary last year and wrote my book, I've been
amazed by the number of people who've told me that the phenomenon of sighting
these objects and having these weird experiences that I suppose you could
call them paranormal, it runs in the family.
Mom had it, dad had it, granddad had it.
It's quite common, isn't it?
Yeah.
I mean, and so I would, I wouldn't turn it into a movie script of some
sort of magical ability.
It's just, if it's a feature of intelligence, uh, then, uh, no surprise
that it gets passed down family to family.
Mara, you have an amazing story, man.
I'm super grateful for you.
And I try to, to bring every single part of it out every single time.
And I just want to be as factual as I know how to be, whether it be the
incident itself, hypnosis, what I saw, what I drew, what I feel.
And I don't try to embellish any part of this, any part whatsoever.
I never will do that.
I just need Michael Johnson.
Yeah.
I need Michael Johnson.
Anybody out there, we got to, yeah.
Every single, and there's quite a few now podcasts and every single
network I've ever been on.
I've always asked if anyone knows Michael Johnson, I don't know his middle initial.
Uh, he told me he was from Chicago, Illinois.
I went on, I've been on all, you know, on every social media that I could.
And also TWS, which is together or together, we serve military stuff,
trying to find people from that time.
And a couple that I have found that I knew that I've known, um, I
can't get an answer out of them.
Yeah.
And I can see their picture and their rank and how, how long they stayed in
the service, it gives you those dates, but I can't find, I can't make
communication or contact with them.
Have you made any money off of, you know, you're telling your, your
account of what had happened to you?
No, I don't have a book.
I would like to try to do an audio book.
Uh, and someone, uh, close to me suggested that I've never done that.
Have you faced any pushback from the colleagues or the press or people
are mostly people just grateful that you've told your account?
Uh, you know, I've had a couple of people say something before, like,
you know, this guy's smoking something.
I wish I was, I wish that's all it would have been, but either as
Robert Hastings once said, he goes, Mario, either you were in the right place at
the right time or the wrong place at the right time, but you were there no matter
what and he coined it for me and I have the greatest respect for that man ever.
Yeah.
Well, it's super clear just speaking to you, how matter of fact you are and
how, uh, yeah, just descriptive the account is, I mean, I, I, I feel like
I have decent pattern matching when it comes to people bullshitting me for a
job, I, you know, invested companies and stuff, so it's like kind of the ultimate,
like the only thing, you know, you can't be an expert in everything and you kind
of just have to be sussing out people.
And so, uh, you passed my test, man.
And I'm sure you did the entire audience at Mario really appreciate it, man.
This was amazing.
And yeah, thanks for your time and for your service and, uh, for, for going public.
Ambassador.
I've heard that word before.
Ambassador, ET ambassador.
I've heard that before.
I don't know.
It's true.