Fringe opinions on Bitcoin and UAPs four or five years ago
are now increasingly normy.
The reality of non-human intelligence
was fully out there.
Yeah, it was so weird.
Now it's coming in, and now you got psionics.
It's like, oof, well, that's the new thing out there.
But that's probably also coming in.
Consciousness and light beings and meditative practices.
It's like we're rediscovering a lot of ancient knowledge.
It's just being reinterpreted through our modern frame.
What sort of disclosure are we gonna get?
And also, what is the curve that you think
is behind these data points?
Is it the non-human intelligences, alien civilizations,
and some advanced spacecraft coming here
to monitor us curve?
Is it time travelers?
Is it crypto-terrestrials?
Is it inter-dimensionals?
It does feel like this sort of Pandora's box.
You have hope, but then there's a whole lot of bad stuff
that comes with it.
Not all knowledge is just, oh, this is a rainbow.
Oh, this is forever knowledge.
There's no guarantee that the box of knowledge
humanity's dipping its hand into
is gonna be like good knowledge.
Bitcoin and UAPs and AI, these are fully at the center
of what's gonna drive major strategic dynamics
over the next few years.
["Different Parts of the Brain"]
Different parts of the brain have different activities.
But you know that, don't you?
["Different Parts of the Brain"]
New people that you rule out.
Maybe you should interview me.
["Different Parts of the Brain"]
I'm here with Matthew Pines,
who is the executive director at Bitcoin Policy Institute.
I think if I were to handcraft a podcast guest,
you would be it.
You just are always such a deep wellspring of knowledge
across many, many domains.
And so I'm very, very excited to have you here
as things get very weird in 2025.
Yes, sir.
Thanks for having me.
Absolutely.
I mean, there are a million ways or places to start.
Maybe the one thing I was sort of kicking myself
for not talking to you about after our last podcast
was Bitcoin, and now you're at the Bitcoin Policy Institute.
So where do you think we go from here?
There are chatters of a strategic reserve.
Obviously, Trump has made promises on this front.
He was in Nashville at the Bitcoin Conference
earlier this or last year, rather.
And yeah, where do we go from here?
I guess I'll step back and maybe to bridge
maybe most of your audience, right,
from the UAP community to the Bitcoin side of things.
And it's something like ironic
and maybe not so ironic similarities
between the evolution of Bitcoin
as like a sociological phenomenon
and how it sort of played a role in our politics
and the zeitgeist as a symptom of maybe
what are these other dynamics taking place in our society.
And then the similar sort of evolution of UAPs.
They were both on the sort of fringes
of what's considered acceptable,
considered taboo in their respective domains.
Like if you're a financial advisor,
five, six years ago, it was just anathema
to even talk about Bitcoin
as a serious investment opportunity, right?
And the folks that were attracted to it
would tend to be sort of heterodox thinkers,
folks that didn't necessarily trust
in institutional authority,
had a much higher risk tolerance
or had a much higher degree of confidence
in a particular vision of the future, right?
And so the Bitcoin culture that got started
has this sort of phenomenology
is almost of like a cult religion, right?
It's got this sort of founding figure
that sort of gifts this protocol to the true believers
who have sort of formed this astrological vision
around it, right?
Sort of hyper Bitcoinization.
They were sort of an outgroup.
They were kind of not the normal sort of folks
that went through a traditional
sort of meritocratic professional track.
For whatever reason in their background,
they were attracted to this idea
of sort of an open monetary network.
And so they sort of went in
and it formed this sort of unique culture
and it has Bitcoin podcasts,
it has Bitcoin conferences and influencers.
And as social media has developed,
Bitcoin has become this own community, right?
And then as Bitcoin became more and more
of an adopted asset as the network grew,
it obviously grew in total market value.
And then it became much more of a political force.
And then politicians started to get engaged
and it started to be like a regulatory conversation
that was triggered around Bitcoin
and the broader digital asset space.
And so the Bitcoin concept sort of went from total fringe,
heterodox, somewhat taboo topic,
and it's sort of been on this trajectory towards
inside the Overton window.
And now you have essentially President of the United States
saying he wants America to be the crypto capital world, right?
So that is a kind of remarkable evolution
for something to go through
in a relatively short period of time.
And I think that there's some interesting parallels
to that kind of trajectory for Bitcoin and the UAP topic,
right?
I think whatever underlying reasons
for that similarity we can explore,
but just as a first level set of observations,
similar sort of fringe, somewhat taboo subject,
people are attracted to it via some idiosyncratic mix
of their personal experience and their professional
or psychological sort of focuses.
And it has its own insular sort of canonical lore
and influencers and podcasts and conferences.
And it has also undergone this evolution, right?
From since 2017, where it was completely somewhat fringe
and kind of this outgroup culture,
and then had gone through this period of,
gradual semi-official legitimization, right?
So starting with the New York Times articles
and then progressive engagement,
correlated to direct sort of legislative engagement
and acknowledgement as well.
And it just so happens,
like one of the course sort of senators involved in
on the pro crypto legislation, Senator Gillibrand,
is also the same Senator who's been involved
in some of the initial sort of UAP legislation.
The Gillibrand-Lumis bill on the crypto side
and the Gillibrand-Rubio amendments on the other side.
And they happened around the same sort of time period.
And now we're at this particular moment in time, right?
And heading into the first few weeks
of the Trump administration,
where both Bitcoin as a policy issue
is pretty highly salient in a topic of contention and focus
at the senior and most levels of the administration.
At the same time, UAPs are also like increasingly
of such subject of White House level, cabinet level,
like discourse and speculation, right?
The speculation Bitcoin community is like,
how serious and how pro Bitcoin
is the White House really gonna be?
Who's really gonna,
what sort of executive orders are gonna be passed?
What sorts of pro Bitcoin policies
are gonna be put forward?
The same sorts of questions are happening on the UAP side.
How serious is the administration about disclosure?
What sort of pro UAP cabinet secretaries
are gonna be confirmed and how forceful
are they gonna be in executing
on that pro UAP policy position?
Very similar, right?
We've got potentially pro Bitcoin cabinet secretaries
and the question is like,
how pro Bitcoin are they really gonna be?
And in many ways, often they're the same people, right?
Like you have Tulsi Gabbard at DNI,
who's apparently pretty pro Bitcoin
and also now I think her testimony
was talking about sort of UAPs explicitly
in her opening statement.
Do you think she'll get confirmed?
I don't know.
I'm not an expert in handicapping the Senate.
I don't know, 50-50.
I mean, it'll probably be decided
but by the time this is aired,
so whatever prediction I make will look.
I think she's like slightly above 50%
in polymarket or whatever, so.
Yeah, and I think I haven't seen most of her full testimony
or what the reactions were,
so I can't necessarily judge
because it depends on how the senators
perceived her testimony and what the media reaction is.
But yeah, but just stepping back,
so I just find a remarkable sort of fact
about our political economy
and our sort of the sociological process underway
that these two sort of outgroup somewhat fringe topics,
UAPs and Bitcoin,
also just my personal preoccupation
for the past five, six years,
like thinking intellectually about these things
in a very serious way.
But, you know, and for me professionally,
these things started out on like the side,
just things I was interested in.
I just happened to be really sort of obsessed
with these two topics,
like not for any particular reason
or like why they were related to each other,
just that's sort of how my intellectual interests
sort of evolved.
And then they both kind of been embarking on this process,
you know, the last four or five years,
kind of coming into the Overton window
and now becoming subject of very serious sort of policy
deliberation and decision now
at the highest level of the U.S. government.
And so that's just like the way I would start.
It's just like these are,
you seem like these are disconnected phenomena.
There must be some underlying reason.
I don't know if we could dig into speculation
about why these two things are all happening at once.
At the same time, you also have AI,
I think also undergoing the similar evolution
you look at, right?
The blog posts about artificial super intelligence,
these sort of less wrong, hyper rationalist,
effective altruist movement was they're kind of fringe
in group, you know, internet conversations.
They had their own canonical debates and war
and, you know, little internecine, you know,
factions, et cetera.
Same thing with Bitcoin.
You had sort of factions split off about the, you know,
the core vision about what Bitcoin is.
You have factions in the UAP community, right?
All these sorts of things develop these same dynamics.
And then the AI question has gone from those blog posts
to now, like, again, strategic level conversation,
stock market swings 10% in a day
because one Chinese lab, you know,
releases an AI model, right?
This is where we are now.
And I think Bitcoin and UAPs and AI,
like these are now fully at the center
of what's gonna drive major strategic dynamics
over the next few years.
So it's one of those things where if you
wanna try to read the future,
and I have been obsessed with trying to understand
what's really going on and what's likely to happen
in the future.
And you kind of have to pay attention to these things
coming in from the tails.
These like little bubbles of phenomenon,
whether it's this idea of AI,
this prospect of Bitcoin monetizing,
the prospect that UAPs are not a total fiction.
It's like the what if AI turns out to be a real thing.
What if Bitcoin monetizes significantly?
What if UAPs are real?
Like each of those things individually
has massive strategic implications
and they all happen to be, you know,
leaning towards the yes, right,
of that what if at the same time.
And that's what I think is a strategic change
that a lot of people that are maybe embedded
in a set of mental models that they anchored
five, 10, 15 years ago,
are just not well positioned to keep track of
and then to anticipate the changes that might be coming
in the next few years.
Yeah, it's almost like it's the total energy
of the system equals potential energy plus kinetic energy.
All of those things have huge potential energy buildups.
And it's just, yeah, it's unclear how exactly it pans out
or, you know, not to mix physics analogies,
but how the wave function collapses or whatever.
But there's sort of, you know,
a lot of possibilities with these things.
And it's almost like, you know,
the history of the last 50 or so years
has been the history of successive bubbles.
And like in the 70s, you could say,
like real growth really started to slow.
80s and 90s was kind of like, you know,
financial deregulation bubble.
Early 2000s, you had the real estate bubble,
globalization bubble or whatever with NAFTA,
maybe in between those two.
And then in 08 was this big watershed moment.
And then 09, Bitcoin, you know,
read Satoshi's white paper and it's this like,
they're sort of gambling with our sovereignty.
Satoshi seems like this very kind of,
anti-Wall Street, anti-big finance,
when you had Occupy Wall Street at that time as well.
And so this is a weird way to put it,
but it's almost like the last bubble
is always the money bubble.
And so like Bitcoin is an arbitrage
against the money bubble.
And maybe the real last bubble is like the reality bubble.
And like UFOs are somehow like, you know,
like that's bursting and that's why UFOs are just,
you know, they're not, you know, some deeper ontology,
but they're like the first thing to like peak its head out,
you know, once the reality bubble starts to sort of dissolve.
Yeah, I mean, it's fascinating.
I guess my first sort of hot take reaction to that
is thinking about, again, money is just a concept
and it's an embedded concept
that's reified in human institutions at a certain scale.
Right, we have money like things
at all scales of human institutions,
like social organizations.
Like if you don't have human institutions,
you don't have money, you just have, you know,
people living, you know, hand to mouth
and scraping out subsistence existence.
So as soon as you get to some basic level
of human social organization,
you get something like moneyness as an institutional concept
that gets instantiated and reified
in different, you know, technologies, right?
The technologies that can instantiate that concept of money,
whether it's seashells or yap stones or gold certificates,
you know, ledger balances at international institutions,
like, you know, everything from special drawing rights
at the IMF to then Bitcoin, which is a sort of, again,
like a instantiation of this, you know,
but taking advantage of the ambient technologies
that are now available to a digital society.
And so this is just the process of evolution
of human societies adapting different, you know,
basic sociological sort of primitives,
but now the possibility space of what they can do
expands as their technological capabilities change.
So now you can realistically maintain something
like a consensus distributed ledger around the world, right?
It wasn't possible until you had the basic technologies
of the internet and public private key, you know, cryptography.
And so this is where the basic primitives
that Satoshi put together and he published
into the sort of the, you know, 2009 as an open source.
And that's a bit, we should drive this home
because whenever I speak to kind of boomer financial people
or whatever, they act like that's not a big deal.
Like, what is it, the Byzantine general problem or whatever,
like the double spending thing, that's not a big deal.
It's a huge deal.
Like the idea that you can create digital scarcity.
And then, you know, there are all sorts of possible derivatives
from the digital scarcity,
but just the digital scarcity itself,
which Bitcoin is the kind of archetypal example of,
is sort of really important
because software doesn't usually operate like that.
And so that's like really interesting.
It's like it was the first real computer science breakthrough
that became a meme, right?
And so people have hard time trying to reconcile
both the mimetic aspects of Bitcoin
and the hard technical scientific breakthrough
that it embodied, right?
Well, they also have trouble swallowing the fact
that like our other financial institutions
are at all mimetic themselves
and that you upend the old mimesis with some new mimesis.
Well, this is where we get,
often you get into these interesting debates
that turn into philosophical questions of like,
what are human institutions?
What are these human concepts?
Like how real is the state as a concept?
How real is the promise of a state
to pay back its debts a thing,
which is essentially what money is in our system.
And it's like, these are socio-technical systems,
not so you get to like jargony,
but like in a sense, all money is an interface
between human belief and the physical world, right?
Which is what intermediates the actions
that human beings take as a result of their beliefs.
And so that's just what humans are.
It's what we do.
There's been philosophical debates
about how much reality you assign
to like these different concepts, like money.
Is it a thing?
Is it just a social fiction?
If it's all just a matter of mutual belief,
then can we all just decide to believe something different?
But again, it's interface between human belief and reality.
You can't just believe anything, right?
Reality imposes, you know, exogenous constraints
on what that belief can do in the world.
Doesn't it all just kind of come down to,
you know, who has a monopoly on sacred violence?
Who can perform sacred violence?
And the government is that at the limit.
And so, you know, it's like,
it all ultimately is like sort of taxation
is like a version of that.
If you don't pay your taxes,
you end up in jail or something.
The Max Weber kind of deconstruction view of the state.
I mean, that's getting deep into political philosophy.
I don't think it's interesting
to have like a particular strong view of like,
you know, the build up this tower of institutions
that anchor these webs of mutual fictions
that we call, you know, these collective beliefs.
The state, the constitution, the social contract.
These are all higher level kind of shared fictions
that we all agree in as a sense of mutual consensus belief
that we will continue to keep believing them, right?
States break down when that embedded assumption
that everyone will continue
to basically believe the same thing tomorrow
about those, you know, shared fictions breaks down, right?
When you don't actually trust,
that's what trust essentially is at scale, right?
Can Bitcoin serve as a head?
Because I think about the last like five years
and this idea of like modern monetary theory,
like as long as your debt is denominated
in your own currency, you can sort of like print it away.
And like, once we start to talk in those terms,
it feels like that's sort of the beginning
of the end or something.
Like that doesn't feel good.
And so is Bitcoin like, is it, you know,
this fully decentralized thing or, you know,
presumably Trump wouldn't get behind it if it was.
And is it actually like a hedge, you know,
as far as like ensuring, you know, solvency
from the United States perspective on a go-forward basis?
Well, again, those are trillion dollar sort of questions.
I don't have a, you know, high confident answer
to how it's really gonna shake out.
But I think it's important to think about Bitcoin
as an emerging institution, right?
That is a novel type of institution
that we haven't really seen before, right?
It's a global decentralized, open,
meaning there's no gatekeeper to access, you know,
your ability to transact or hold it.
It doesn't require a third party
to sort of validate your transactions
to secure your rights in the network.
You can essentially do that with essentially math
and open source software.
So this is a kind of novel technology
that can form as a predicate for an emerging institution
that started off fully peer-to-peer,
again, kind of crypto anarchist, internet forums,
dark web markets, you know,
Ford thinking investors, et cetera,
and is now engaging at the level of nation states.
And so we're seeing this, you know, quite dramatic.
And for me, just fascinating interplay
between these existing state institutional structures
and super state institutional structures,
say like the ECB or the Bank of International Settlements
and the sort of international norms between central banks
as well as major pools of international capital,
which are, you know, these are institutions themselves, right?
And they formed as a result of decades of sort of evolution,
right, within a certain global context,
especially in the post-war era,
especially in say the post 1990s,
kind of neoliberal sort of capitalist,
sort of US sort of dominated global system.
And then in comes Bitcoin as this kind of thing
from left field that is now, you know,
as again, it's sort of emerging into first order
just as an asset that like those existing institutions
can buy, right?
So BlackRock has their ETF and they're now pitching it
to their clients and saying to sovereign wealth funds,
it's prudent for any institution
to hold between two and 5%, right?
So they just view it as it's an asset, you can hold it,
it provides diversification benefits
because it's volatility, it's, you know,
correlation is ads overall kind of say,
like improves the sharp ratio of the median portfolio.
So they're thinking that from a purely investment asset,
it's like as a novel asset,
it's now gone through this hyper speculative phase,
it's now in its institutionalization phase,
and therefore it's a safe thing
to sort of prudently diversify into
as part of a portfolio sort of allocation decision.
But that belies like what's really happening
underneath the surface,
which is, okay, you have this weird,
it's not just an asset, it's this network,
and it's a network that no one really controls, right?
That's the secret, right?
There really isn't some,
you can't just go to the Bitcoin CEO
and get them in a room and say like,
do something different, right?
It's like there's nobody to bring in,
there's no throat to choke, right?
You can get the head of Coinbase,
you can get the head of BlackRock,
you can get the head of, you know, any company,
and you can bring them into a room and be like,
we want you to do something different.
There's literally nobody to go to.
Is the one sort of devil's advocate argument there
is like the identity of Satoshi?
But even there, it's like,
he can't do anything to change the network.
I mean, he has a certain cult of personality.
So you think it's a he.
I mean, I think people recognize it in his correspondence
as most likely male.
I think that's pretty accepted.
Do you have any theories?
Oh man, the whole, so who is Satoshi question to me
is kind of banal, but I don't, I mean,
I find it fascinating.
I mean, it is fascinating, again, as a historical question.
I think though it's really, you know,
I think he's dead, to be honest, whoever it is.
That's best for people who are pro-Bitcoin to say.
I mean, it's interesting.
You can go back to like the early history of Bitcoin.
Like Bitcoin didn't come out of nowhere, right?
In fact, Satoshi even cites, you know,
like David Chaum and Wei Dai.
Nick Szabo.
And so, you know, he was taking different pieces
that had already been put in place
and trying to stitch together this, you know,
it solved this unique problem, right?
The double span problem.
And took the proof of work sort of concept as well.
And so added in difficulty adjustments.
So it was this kind of melange of things
that no one had to put together in just the right way.
And yeah, I mean, the most relevant,
there's like two main things that would be relevant
if Satoshi was still alive and could like intervene
sort of Deus ex machina, right?
Into the present day context.
Like one is just his actual holdings are enormous, right?
Enormous.
A million bitcoins.
So just his decision to move coins or spend coins
would have a massive market impact, right?
And then the question is if he would try to insert himself
in Bitcoin development conversations,
he would obviously immediately become, you know,
like first among equals, right?
If not the dominant force in terms of debating
on any future changes to the protocol.
And that would turn Bitcoin's development ecosystem
potentially more like how Ethereum has evolved.
We still have Vitalik,
who's the charismatic singular founder personality
who's very active and makes his opinions known.
And the rest of the community defers to his opinions.
In fact, there was this recent shakeup, right?
With the Ethereum foundation and it kind of, you know,
acrimony between developers and debates about
this very complicated development roadmap
that they've laid out.
And that would introduce new risk, right?
Like the basic risk profile of Bitcoin
as an open source sort of software project, essentially,
that operates on this sort of rough consensus mechanism
is it's very hard to change.
It's very resistant to change.
It takes enormous amounts of time and broad consensus
to make even relatively trivial changes to the protocol
because it's functioning essentially as digital gold, right?
It just doesn't change.
And so that's, you know, this debate
that actually is really interesting within Bitcoin
is this sort of ossification debate, right?
There are some folks that think Bitcoin
should really just never change, like at all.
Literally no tweaks.
Like anything you change is a risk.
And then some people would think,
well, there are some long-term things
about the nature of the protocol,
these like little additional features
that would really unlock a whole bunch of additional
capability for say, time-lock sort of, you know,
sort of very constrained smart contracts, right?
Ethereum is kind of a more turn complete language.
And so there's some issues with that,
but it gives a much more open expressivity
to what you can do on the blockchain.
Whereas Bitcoin is very much a very discreet.
If it's trying to be a gold analog,
I don't know if you need to do much more than, you know,
what you've already done.
I mean, there are a few design,
I mean, the design was pretty, pretty perfect,
but like there are some flaws you could point at,
like the, you know, I don't think he anticipated
ASICs chips, for example, or like, you know,
like extreme concentration in the chain itself, you know?
I mean, it's held up well.
I mean, from when he was mining on a laptop
to when now you have like, you know,
massively capable special purpose, you know,
integrated circuits that have been designed
just to run the algorithm.
And the difficulty adjustment is the true genius, right?
Cause it doesn't matter how much energy you throw at it
in two weeks, it's going to automatically adjust
to take into account any breakthrough
in the hashing technology.
And so that is, but the interesting thing about Satoshi
is that if he was still around and he decided to say,
hey guys, like, I was just chilling out, but now I'm back.
And I've got all these great ideas
about how to improve Bitcoin, right?
That's been the story of Bitcoin for a while now,
especially in those first few years where it was like,
oh, Bitcoin's great, but like, you know, it's too slow.
The block size is too small.
I want to add these additional features
and I'm going to fork it, yada, yada, yada.
And there's always like Roger Verri, all these additional,
the block size wars were all about this.
Bitcoin cash is the true Bitcoin.
And so that was part of the whole risk of Bitcoin
in the very early stages is you didn't know like,
which Bitcoin would win, right?
And so it's been this, you know,
process of historical accretion and consensus over time,
kind of this sort of like a physics process
of kind of sort of condensation,
where it's like you have something that's really hot, right?
And it's floating between many different states
and it's cooling down, right?
It's like a phase transition
and then it starts to lock in, right?
And we haven't, I would say we haven't fully locked in.
There's like still pockets of, you know,
where the crystal lattice is still somewhat fungible, right?
Maybe there's like, you know,
small little bits that could be added here
to add additional features,
but it's clearly in this process of kind of cooling down,
right?
It's like the big bang, right?
The big bang early on, hyper, you know, plasmas,
and maybe even though like the forces themselves
are like all unified in this big soup
and the boundary constraints of the universe
were pretty wide.
And as it cools down, like, you know,
gravity splits off and then electroweak force.
And then it's like, you get the phase transitions down
and then it, you know, becomes transparent to light,
you know, 300,000 years.
And then boom, you've got basically
most of the degrees of freedom
are now kind of locked in for the universe.
And then the rest of the story of the universe can play out.
So I feel like Bitcoin is, it's like,
there was the big bang of Bitcoins, like a launch.
And then there was this process of kind of cooling
and condensation that took place.
And, you know, it was uncertain at that point,
exactly, you know, whether the block size wars
would turn out in one direction or the other,
whether Satoshi would really be gone,
whether, you know, any given year,
the probability would go down,
but it was like pretty high early on.
Like, is he gonna unmask himself?
Is he actually gonna just say,
hey, it's got you on the CIA guys or something?
And every year that goes by,
it's like this process of cooling and accretion.
And that has, as that happens,
it sort of, it takes the risk off the table.
And then, you know, as that occurs,
if you take the risk off, then its value goes up.
As its value goes up, its volatility generally will come down
because it doesn't take a whole lot.
It takes marginally less new capital to change the price.
The volatility comes down.
The risk tolerance of the next marginal buyer, right,
is now triggered.
And so then the value goes back up.
And that's basically been the process
we've been going through to the point
where you've got BlackRock now,
essentially, you know, shilling it to their clients, right,
and talk more with funds.
So this is this fascinating process,
but unless you're really paying attention to it closely
along that path, all that you really see it
is like when it hits the media narrative
and its characteristics sort of hype cycles.
So you see it, you know, going through these 2013 bubble,
2017 bubble, right, 2021, 22 bubble, right?
And maybe now we're in another bubble cycle, right?
These are these characteristics that are four-year cycles
that we've seen Bitcoin go through.
So the person who's just observing that kind of passively
through whatever media filters,
there's like an activation function
that it's now Bitcoin pops up on their feed or whatever.
It's like, oh, it's another bubble thing, right?
And it just keeps coming back in order of magnitude bigger.
It's like, you know, some people early on saw this
as like a trend and they picked up on it
and they've been handsomely rewarded for seeing this trend.
Others catch on later,
but like it's clear there's a structural dynamic playing
taking place here, which I think is now like impossible
and really sort of a matter of strategic malpractice
if you ignore it.
Like there are presidents and national leaders
and sheiks and kings having active discussions now
about what should they do about Bitcoin?
Like how should they approach Bitcoin?
Like that is just a fact of our geopolitical
and a monetary state of affairs.
And so you could just be like, oh, that's absurd.
This is another bubble.
Okay, but it's like sort of like the UAP question.
Some people see the trends,
pick up on these data points sort of off the curve
and they're naturally inclined to pay attention to that
and they suspect something is happening
that's not just total noise or a complete fiction.
And so they pay attention to it.
And then new data points come in
and that start to stitch together what seems to be a trend.
And you try to interpret what does that really mean?
Is this a trend going towards disclosure?
Is Bitcoin trend going towards nation state adoption?
But it's, when you're early on
and you only have a few data points,
it's like an absurd extrapolation
to confidently predict an outcome.
But more and more data points
are essentially aligning onto that trend line.
And that's going back to the very start of the conversation.
That's the thing that I've been intellectually
very fascinated about is just paying attention
to those initial data points sort of off the curve,
speculating on what trend that might represent
and then paying ever more and more attention
as more data points start to come in
to confirm the trend.
And it seems like in terms of Bitcoin
going on this sort of global adoption
now becoming a geopolitical asset trend.
And then UAP turning into like, this is a real thing.
And like now we may be facing
a much more salient public discourse
on the reality of UAPs and not even intelligence.
Those are just things.
Do you ever notice that the best gifts in life
are the ones that you don't just receive,
but the ones that fit seamlessly in your day
and make them better?
Whether you're enjoying the latest American alchemy content
on the move or just tuning out the world for a moment,
Raycon's everyday earbuds are the perfect pair.
I've been using mine nonstop,
whether I'm editing, making calls, out for a walk,
they've become my go-to.
The 32-hour battery life means I never have to worry
about scrambling for a charger.
And with multi-point connectivity,
I can switch effortlessly between my laptop and phone,
no more reconnecting every time I change devices.
But here's what really makes them a game changer,
active noise cancellation.
Whether I'm working in a noisy cafe or trying to focus,
these earbuds let me zone in on what matters.
And they do so in a way that's honestly better
than any other earbuds I've used.
I've also been loving these cool protective case covers.
Check out this design.
It compliments the earbuds colors perfectly.
It's cool that Raycon offers different designs
so you're not stuck with something generic.
You can actually pick a look that matches your style.
Not only do these look great,
but the new quick charge feature gives me 90 minutes
of battery in just 10 minutes of charge.
That's huge when I'm in a rush.
And they also support wireless charging,
so I never have to take the case off when charging.
And listen, Raycon gives you premium sound
at half the price of other top brands.
If you haven't tried them yet, now is the time.
So go to buyraycon.com slash Jesse Michaels.
Again, that's buyraycon.com slash Jesse, M-I-C-H-E-L-S,
to get up to 20% off site-wide.
That's 20% off everything on Raycon's website.
That's right.
You'll get up to 20% off everything on Raycon's website,
including 20% off of all headphones, too,
when you go to buyraycon.com slash Jesse Michael.
Click the link in the description
or go to buyraycon.com slash Jesse Michaels now.
Well, it's a good segue.
Where do you think that goes?
Today, I am releasing an episode with Jake Barber,
who's this firsthand UFO crash retrieval witness
is probably not even doing him justice.
He's an operator.
But the one that he describes is, well, he describes two.
One is an egg-shaped UFO,
and the other is an eight-gon,
like kind of like not quite an octagon,
but like eight sides on the surface,
and it's sort of this black metallic thing.
What do you think of his testimony?
I thought that was remarkable.
Again, we've been kind of on this ratchet
where every few months something new clicks, right?
And it takes the overall conversation.
Again, people that are paying attention
to every little data point here on this curve.
I think there are some people that were,
again, this is where the debates come in.
What sort of disclosure are we gonna get?
And also, what is the curve that you think
is behind these data points?
Is it the non-human intelligences, alien civilizations,
and some advanced spacecraft coming here
to monitor us curve?
Is it time travelers?
Is it crypto-terrestrials?
Is it inter-dimensionals?
Do you have a leading theory?
I mean, I know you have your Wolfram physics stuff,
but do you have a theory ontologically?
It's because this is really interesting.
What is disclosure?
I think for a lot of people,
it's like we just need high-resolution footage,
and then you see the footage,
and you're like, I don't know what I'm looking at.
And so it's this thing where it's like,
you don't really want the thing you're asking for.
You want a broader worldview.
You wanna understand the ontology behind the thing.
And I think there are a couple of other details
associated with the Jake story
that are worthy of mentioning.
One is he retrieved this Aegon craft via his helicopter,
and it was hanging by a rope.
And he locked onto it with his consciousness,
and it gave him this interesting feel,
this divine feminine sort of feel,
and it made him emotional.
And then the other thing that he says
is that they use psionic assets in the government
to basically, and we should probably change the wording here.
Maybe whoever's doing this should change the wording,
but summon these UFOs into people's
sort of field of consciousness.
And then presumably these things at some point land,
and material might be used or something.
The whole thing is so strange.
Yeah, and this is where ironically,
the Bitcoin thing is trivially easy to model by comparison,
because the stipulated phenomenon
that you're trying to model and understand
is just the adoption of this asset,
like essentially a collective belief
that this is a real thing,
that other people will continue to believe it's a real thing,
and that different layers of people and institutions,
sovereign wealth funds,
institution pools of capital,
governments, national leaders, et cetera,
will just continue to basically believe that same thing
over into the future.
So it's not like you don't have to construct
a whole bunch of crazy sort of second and third order
or sort of underlying hypotheses for what's going on.
It's sort of just out there in your face,
and you're just making a prediction
about that continuation of that trend.
With the UAP thing, it's vastly more complicated,
and vastly more fraught.
Because just to that point,
and back to my point about what sorts of,
when you're trying to interpret these different data points,
if you're assuming you don't know the truth,
which is almost everybody here, maybe even everybody,
you don't really know what's going on.
All you see is what people are saying, right?
And you have the assigned degrees of credence
to these different statements
that are coming from apparently credible people,
and I think he's extremely credible.
I think he's got the professional bona fides.
He is who he says he is.
I think he's being entirely truthful
in describing his experiences
as sort of essentially a delivery man
in his crash retrieval program.
And you got, but then you've got to,
but that doesn't answer really the object level question
of what's going on, right?
It just gives you a data point
that you need to stitch together into a comprehensive model
that you need to put together with all these other
sort of highly fraught
and inherently uncertain pieces of information.
And so this is where,
this is what gets extremely difficult for almost everybody
to construct such a model,
because you have these two main questions here,
which are the most foundational questions
of human existence, which is like,
are we alone?
And like, what is consciousness, right?
Like separately, enormous, like unknown questions
that are like almost at the core of who it is to be human,
like what it is to be human, who we are,
like what is our history?
What is the nature of intelligence in the universe?
Are we unique?
Are we special?
Is there a great filter?
All these sorts of questions.
To answer that question,
you have to put together a lot of disciplines
existing science and speculative sort of,
frontiers of physics to understand,
well, what's the structure of reality, right?
Is there a multiverse?
Is there just this unfolding of time?
What are the boundary constraints of physical reality
that any intelligence is gonna be constrained by?
And then the specific kind of contingent processes
that give rise to intelligent life,
how common are those given the population of stars,
et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
How can we ever get high conviction in any given model?
Your idea that there's like branchial space
that these UFOs might be able to hop across or whatever,
and we're in sort of this more constrained,
really ill space, like how is that at all?
I mean, that's the process of science, right?
But how does it become falsifiable?
Like even, and by the way,
I think Jake's testimony is completely beyond reproach
as well as far as like the details,
and I find him to be an earnest, good person.
But like, it was a question of like,
what are these things, like when they're coming down,
what are these things and is falsifying
or corroborating this even seeing an object?
Like is that even, like what is that then?
Like you're probably gonna have no idea what it is.
It's gonna be emitting some radiological stuff
and then you might get a little hurt
and you might have put it in a lab
and it might exhibit some weird properties.
And then at that point, what do you do?
What does that mean?
I mean, this is where, I mean,
I studied physics and philosophy as an undergrad
because I was fascinated and not obsessed
by this sort of the boundary layer
between science and philosophy, right?
Which is essentially philosophy is what we really
don't have systematized theories of knowledge for, right?
So the philosophy is sort of scouting out in the forest,
just trying to find the path, right?
And then you find the path and the scientists come
and sort of clear the path, right?
And so the frontier scientists are the first ones
into that like overbuilt, highly, you know,
you have thorns everywhere, right?
But at least the philosophers have sort of said,
yeah, I think there's a path here.
This is basically the conceptual almost map of definitions
that we're gonna analyze these more foundational concepts
like almost create new concepts, right?
Philosophy is often organizing human thought
and systems of concepts to just help even ground hypotheses
that then scientists can generate
and to have to go out into the world
and refine as like real systems of knowledge, right?
So this is process of, you know, exploration
into this dark unknown that humanity has found itself in.
And so this is this basic, you know,
challenge of reality is what it is
and we are just, you know, flesh puppets
with some, you know, higher cognitive capacities
and this like being itself, what it's like to, you know,
feel in sort of phenomenal first person subjective awareness
that sort of lights up the machine inside.
And it's like, okay, well, we're clearly,
like on a first pencil's basis,
we've got to do a lot of work
to try to understand reality, right?
It's not gonna just be handed to us.
We have to do a huge amount of like conceptual development
and scientific exploration to try to map on to reality,
right, whatever models we have in our head
to try to create a map to reality
is gonna take an enormous amount of work.
And the challenge, like the confrontation
that UAPs present to us is they force us
to try to basically almost short circuit
what would otherwise have been if they didn't,
if they weren't here, probably a much longer process
of like human conceptual refinement
and scientific investigation
to understand what's the nature of reality,
like what are the physical rules that constrain existence
and what is it like to be a human subject
or what's like to be a conscious subject at all?
And that's, you know, that's what the Barbara story
kind of really uncomfortably forces people
to put together, right?
Because it's not just this alien or UAP or NHI question
of like advanced technology from another civilization,
but it's that and apparently this aspect
of human consciousness that can directly engage
and almost project and interface,
merge with that higher intelligence slash technology, right?
And so those are very separate domains
of sort of scientific and philosophical modeling
and sort of inquiry, which is like fundamental physics,
nature of intelligence in the universe,
the boundary constraints, right?
That we think any advanced civilization
is gonna have to work within,
that's gonna constrain the types of technology
and propulsion systems and many materials
they're gonna be able to construct.
And then there's, well, like what is consciousness
in reality, right?
Is there, is it a universal field
and we're just fragments or shards?
Is there some sort of more, you know,
sort of panpsychist interpretation that you would give
and what's the sort of psychophysical relationship
between consciousness and the physical world
that could be, you know,
intermediated with advanced forms of technology, right?
And then there's this question of like, well,
like is it just computational functionalism is true
if you just instantiate a certain pattern,
is that all you get?
Is consciousness or is it consciousness
is actually the substrate of reality?
It's sort of what stands underneath physics.
Again, these are words that I'm spewing, right?
But like the words we think means something about reality.
But I think the history of philosophy and science
is that the words we are using at any given point in time
are only like barely like trying to map on to reality
as it goes back to Kant, right?
It's like, we have a certain phenomenal description
of reality that's kind of first person subjective field.
It has constraints, it has to, you know,
conform with some rules of rationality for Kant
that is, you know, these are the rules
that any rational mind would have to obey.
And so the universe will then reflect itself
in a regular organized way to that person,
to that, you know, subjectivity.
But that doesn't actually imply that like reality,
what he called nominal is actually that, right?
That feels so important for understanding what science is.
And like you mentioned Jonathan Gerard,
this Princeton researcher that works with Wolfram
is kind of taking up the mantle there
and has all sorts of interesting ideas
that might actually end up applying to UAP, who knows?
That's sort of your contribution.
And I heard him on an interview with Kurt Jaimungal,
shout out to Kurt Jaimungal, great interviewer.
And he was talking about Newton and Leibniz
and like how vector calculus kind of reign supreme
as defining the way in which we've conceptualized the world
for, you know, call it the last 400 years,
350 years, whatever.
And that on a go-forward basis,
maybe a more computational understanding of the world
will be how we kind of model the universe.
And I would just say that I think he's right,
but I would also say that like all of these things
are like maps and they're not the territory.
And so like, you know, yeah, you have these sort of
heuristics for how you understand the world.
And then maybe there is something more fundamental
about consciousness itself.
And like, it's gonna sound so cliche and trite,
but like the UAP stuff points to this,
like going within, reconciling with, you know,
the ugliest parts of yourself, your subconscious.
You know, Carl Jung would say,
until you reconcile with your subconscious,
you call it fate.
And like, you have these mystery rituals
for, you know, thousands of years
where like the top thinkers, like Plato,
like all these guys like went, did these mystery rituals.
And it seems like it was to gain access
to knowledge of their primordial soul, noesis.
And so it's like, you know, we can have these mental models
and like, we can, you know, draw stuff up on chalkboards
and then you can like, you know,
falsify it in a lab or whatever,
but like maybe there's something extremely fundamental
about like going within.
And like, I don't know, like the Monroe,
like the gateway stuff, like there are different paths,
but like it's sort of, yeah,
there's something actually really important about like,
you know, confronting oneself
in this sort of Joseph Campbell style hero's journey.
How do I slay?
How do you slay that dragon in me?
What's the journey I have to make?
You have to make, each of us has to make.
You talk about something called a soul's high adventure.
My general formula for my students is follow your bliss.
I mean, find where it is and don't be afraid.
The lesson of most faith traditions in general,
and even, you know, modern day, say new agey,
contemplative, transform meditation, et cetera,
they've all tried to grapple with the nature of like,
what it is to be a human subject, right?
And the language, the vocabulary,
the conceptual frameworks have evolved.
It was, you know, a certain structure
that fell in terms of like the human soul,
you know, kind of this is the embodied sort of light
of God or whatever.
And then the material world is this sort of, you know,
empty, again, kind of just a stage
of sort of lifeless objects, right?
And then there's this,
a lot of people have this sort of folk duality metaphysics
where what's in my head or kind of consciousness
is sort of this unique substance that is, you know,
somehow more primitive.
And then there's the physical world,
which is just sort of lifeless stuff.
I think it's a primitive metaphysics.
I think there's a, you know,
to go to like a Gerard slash Whitehead
sort of, you know, more syncretic view is,
you have this dynamic computational process
that's unfolding in his way.
It's a sort of a multi-computational process
that's unfolding.
And you can describe that in a formal way,
a hyper precise way to make, you know,
predictions about, you know, extensions in physics.
And that's what physics and science is about.
But then you have to get a metaphysical interpretation
of that, you know, model, right?
And to account for phenomenon that are not gonna be,
that are not gonna be amenable
to the same sort of mathematized formalization
that's a hypergraph rewriting system.
And so there's a aspect of reality that is,
what is it like to be a person, like a thing?
We all have a first-person subjectivity
that seems very real to us.
And there's certain people like Daniel Dennett
and sort of Patricia Churchland
and that sort of school of philosopher of mine
that just deny the reality of first-person subjectivity
that qualia aren't real, right?
It's all just words we say.
We don't actually have anything that's like to be us
or there's no such thing as redness.
I think that's dangerous.
Yeah, but that is a very strong philosophical view
that it's been very successful
because of a technological paradigm
that seemed to support it over time,
which is this idea of just programming, right?
This idea of just writing down abstract instructions
on a computer can unlock huge amounts
of complicated behavior.
And like, you know, what looks to be now
in these AI systems, like approaching human level,
you know, output, right?
Or sort of mimicry in some sense.
And so that has, from a certain naive perspective,
well, if we can construct purely computational systems,
you know, just, you know, big weights of numbers, right?
Sort of doing matrix multiplication
and they can spit out, you know,
yeah, this is the Turing test.
They can spit out outputs
that are fundamentally indistinguishable from human output.
Well, then maybe we should just believe
that that's all that we are, right?
And, you know, but of course, at the end of the day,
to get this philosophy of mine argument,
you have to go back to like,
if I punch you, it's gonna hurt, right?
Like, that's not something I can write down
in any sort of system of formal equations.
There's just an irreducible feature of existence
that only is accessible to a first person,
you know, subject that is real.
And, you know, that's like the first branch of the tree
that philosophers of mind divergent.
And then there's different branches
that people have taken over time.
But I think this is where, for me, again,
I come from this somewhat analytic philosophical tradition.
But at the same time, there's been, I think,
a weakness in that tradition.
It's been very austere and it's obsessed
with hyperformalism and sort of making these
very restrained and couched arguments.
And then the rest of society just wants to understand
and gets like, get to a first level understanding
of what's really happening in the world.
So you have these other,
you have these different traditions, right?
That are, you know, go under like sort of new age philosophy
that goes back to, you know, kind of Hegel and Schelling
and kind of the German romanticists, you know,
have sort of been reinterpreted over many decades
and then kind of give birth to this sort of modern
sort of metaphysics.
It's very popular in the UAP community, right?
Which is consciousness and light beings
and meditative practices and it's like we're rediscovering
a lot of like ancient sort of knowledge, right?
It's just being reinterpreted through our modern frames.
It's all ancient.
And belief systems.
But even then it's like those ancient belief systems
were just, those were just the new age philosophies
of the day, right?
Like I, again, I, maybe I'm just,
this is my training or juxtaposition.
I like to have, I want to try to take that as a guide
to then try to systematize and formalize as much as I can.
Well, what does that say about reality, right?
We're just using words when we say, you know,
consciousness or light energy or look inside, right?
Those are, well, what was that?
That's very true.
Like you need to stitch it together
in a cohesive worldview that is on the one hand,
scientifically rigorous and formal and on the one hand,
you know, philosophically speculative and exploratory.
But you need to always have to like
try to pull those threads together.
Well, it's always funny when people say, you know,
aliens are just angels and demons.
And then I ask them what's an angel and what's a demon.
That descriptor is in no way helpful, you know,
more helpful incrementally, you know,
compared to an alien or whatever.
And so like you're equally completely clueless
in both cases and you're just sort of like,
it's almost more of like a political polemic
that you're trying to say, you know,
it all just goes back to a tradition,
but you're right, in many ways,
the tradition is just as impenetrable
as this new agey veneer that, you know,
we have or whatever.
And I think fundamentally we need to create new concepts,
new worldviews that are based in a scientific practice,
but are not restricted by the prevailing,
what I would call sort of metaphysical assumptions, right?
So I think that's right.
And then I also think, you know, the concept of Lindy.
Yeah.
You know, like, you know, something's expected
or something's current age is a, you know,
predictor of its, you know, future age.
And so like it's every generation's, you know,
job to sort of kill off bad ideas.
You know, the ideas that are like not that good,
don't survive that long.
And so like, on some level,
I do understand kind of hearkening back to older traditions
and saying it is all just like this stuff,
like you're not discovering something new,
because it actually does give you
at least fuller metaphor phenomenological,
like, you know, social map of like our understanding
of this stuff, how we've interacted with it.
And it doesn't, you're not throwing out any progress
that's made in the past as a result of, you know,
whatever interactions we've had with UAPs or, you know,
these things or consciousness or whatever.
So I do think, you know, it's like Alcibiades was like,
was killed for like, you know,
talking about the mysteries at Eleusis or whatever.
And traditionally, I think some of these things
that we're touching on now in the UAP context,
you, if you, if you attempt them
in some sort of like willy nilly way,
like things go very bad for you.
And so like, you know, I think,
I think it's actually kind of important to know that
and to not just like wholesale, you know, democratize,
like Stephen Greer, who this was a total mixed bag,
I think in many ways is being vindicated now actually
for his really good investigative work.
But he's of the mind that you can just like,
sort of try to call these things in.
And it's like, I don't know about that.
I don't think that's a good idea, but what do you think?
Well, this is why I think a greater crime
than the like alleged legacy program,
technology, secret science, secret physics crime,
is this what you could somewhat interpret
as a spiritual crime.
I would view it as more, you know,
essentially a philosophical crime
and people think that's a trivial.
But for me, a philosophical crime is the highest crime.
Because it's like, what is the highest pursuit of humanity
is to understand reality.
And to do that, you need to have as much access
to whatever clues reality will provide to you
to then stitch together in an ever evolving
and uncertain basis, like a picture of the world, right?
What is really happening?
Like what are the core phenomenon
that I need to account for, right?
In a coherent picture of existence.
And if there's an entire set of phenomenon
that the US government or other entities
have just been, you know, intentionally withholding
that would provide, you know, ammunition for
or ingredients to construct a much more integrative
and holistic view of reality,
then we're all impoverished fundamentally
and almost spiritually metaphysically
in my sort of more neutral language.
And that is, that's more for me of like a,
an abrogation of an insult, right?
And like withholding classified physics,
like that's a problem.
But that's like, it's a problem
underneath this larger problem, right?
It's, because then I think what's what you need to move,
you know, overall human civilization forward
is you need to have everyone operating
on as close to a basis of truth as possible.
Yep.
Like systematic, you know, error compounds over time
and leads to pathologies and usually catastrophic failures.
And like proper institutions are always,
always about trying to get as close to reality as possible.
Right?
Like ultimately, if you want to have an effective,
you know, organization, a company, a product,
a belief system, it should be like,
you should be trying to get it close to reality.
But is not the biggest sigh up of all the idea
that the government has a greater metaphysical
or ontological understanding of reality at all
versus these locally useful techniques
where they can like, you know, derive certain benefits
from interactions or whatever.
Like, I think those are two very different types.
Yeah, no, 100%.
I don't think the government has like a secret
sort of scroll of knowledge, right?
I agree, yeah.
That's like, we are the truth keepers
and we're holding the truth back from people.
It's more like they're withholding basic facts, right?
Tons of data.
Like apparently something like human capacities
for conscious engagements with advanced technology
is a thing that's like a real phenomenon in the world.
Do they have like a fundamentally, you know,
grounded ontologically, you know, close to the metal,
you know, theory of physics and metaphysics
that accounts for all of that?
I'm highly skeptical, right?
I am too.
They figure out some tricks and some protocols.
They realize that there's certain individuals
that have an inherent predisposition for this.
They maybe have figured out genetic, you know,
lines that are just naturally disposed for this.
They figure out maybe some cocktails of drugs
to give to people in a training regiment when they're young
and then they get them into these programs
and they, you know, I basically adapted almost
on a like trial and error basis.
Let's dive a little into that
because that does also seem to be coming out now
and it's not, it's really strange
and it's not something you can like really paint over.
It's hard to put lipstick on that pig.
That's a weird thing that the government
has been systematically finding high-sciability,
you know, mind over matter capable children
across the country for decades
and basically doing parapsychological experiments
with them where it's like collapse a sine wave
or, you know, look at this material.
Do you react to the material?
And then like, yeah, inducing certain stress states
so they can, you know, be more functional
as far as these out-of-body experiences
and trying to garner esoteric information from them.
What do you make of all of that?
And do you think, I mean, how prevalent was that?
Is that how, you know, how big of a thing is that?
If you put a few things together
and you're trying to construct like a scenario here,
it is interesting, right?
So imagine for the sake of argument
that the psionics capability is real, right?
Well, then you got to have to ask some basic questions like,
well, what's the effective range, right,
for a given psionic asset to perform a certain operation,
whether it's to summon down, take control of,
pilot, engage, communicate, you know, whatever.
Like it's, you know, it's, yeah, again,
your assumptions there could be everything
from they can read across the universe
or they have to be within line of sight
within like a kilometer or somewhere in between, right?
So if you assume for the sake of argument
that there's some, there's some constraint, right?
There's some physical distance
where the operational effectiveness
of the psionic asset is constrained,
then okay, you have a global, say, you know, operation.
You need to have a global footprint of those assets
to perform activities where you never, you know, who knows?
Maybe there's certain activities that you need to have
in certain parts of the world to detect UAP, like NHI craft.
But if it's true that there's some ability
for humans to control this technology,
well then you also have to build into this scenario,
this hypothetical that we haven't been able
to like fully reproduce, like reproduction vehicles, right?
That are, you know, all these crazy mini materials
or whatever, but if we have our own, say,
fully intact craft and we know how special site
psychic pilots can fly them,
well then you have to build a scenario
where there are non-human craft being piloted by humans.
And then you have to build into that scenario,
well, if American or contracted associated American groups
can do that, well then maybe adversary groups can do that.
And so then if you're in this scenario
where there are actual non-human craft, you know,
who is maybe operational locations you're trying to monitor
or, you know, you would just need to have a presence
around the world because you don't really know
what they're going, what's going on.
And or you have, you know, human groups that are, you know,
piloting using psionic capabilities,
non-human craft that they've recovered
and then start to operationalize.
And then, and then it's like,
so there's this crazy exotic scenario built in here,
but then it's really not that different
from a traditional military ISR global sort of,
you know, competition, right?
Where you try to get as close to your adversaries
operations as possible to monitor what they're doing, right?
With as much of a deniable presence as possible.
So you would use your covert special stuff to do that.
And you would get, you know, near your adversary,
China, et cetera.
And then if there's a disaster, you're like,
oh, we're worried about these assets being burned
or they're really valuable.
So we need to get them out.
So that's, that's the evacuation procedure, right?
And then it turns out these Marines
stumbled on the evacuation and that's okay.
How do I create a scenario that explains
a psionic asset team with a non-human craft in Indonesia
that's witnessed by Michael Herrera, right?
And a prima facie absurd thing.
But if you load in things from Jacob Barber's story
and a basic SOP about how any sort of operation
would be constructed, right?
That's based on those facts.
Okay, you can come up with a plausible explanation
to that inherently implausible scenario.
Well, it's funny.
I said, I was like, you know, maybe it was this like
human trafficking psionic asset transfer operation.
He was like, or maybe, you know,
the program was like running out there
and they were like trying to get out
because the earthquake had hit.
So it's kind of like what you said,
like they were like, you know, evacuating
and they sort of ran into Herrera's unit.
I mean, again, just taking the facts at issue
and trying to construct a plausible story
that's consistent with these other pieces, right?
If you don't put the other pieces together,
it's very hard to tell a plausible story.
Yep.
But yeah, but that's the part that's,
I think people are increasingly hinting at, right?
You could go back to Grushin and Carlinel sub-rosa Cold War
to retrieve or reverse engineer the stuff.
Well, the psionics part is a part of that retrieval program
and reverse engineering program.
Well, then there's gonna be a sub-rosa Cold War
for psionic assets around the world
to retrieve and reverse engineer and control,
you know, human intelligence.
Like that's just like a slight modification
of the original Grush statement.
Yeah, totally.
Well, do you have a base case on how far we've come
when it comes to actually reverse engineering these things?
I am, I'm open to the possibility
that a lot of technology has been inspired
that would be considered very advanced
from the state of like what's in the open domain,
different parts of the tech tree, advanced materials,
I think, you know, would probably be the most likely candidate.
I also think the psionics thing
is certainly probably the most, you know,
most people wouldn't think about that
as reverse engineering, but for me,
it's like clearly inspired technology, right?
It's like there's a certain way of activating,
engaging, training, enhancing certain human capacities
to perform operational capabilities, you know,
that are military intelligence, you know, related.
Like that's, that would,
I don't think we would have gotten that potentially
without these things, if that's true,
which seems increasingly likely to be the case.
Antigravity, the whole Thompson-Thompson,
you know, Brown stuff is,
it's a tougher thing for me to stretch to at the moment.
Like could we have sort of inspired prototypes
like the Pais stuff that we have a drawing board ideas on?
Probably.
Do we have the engineering acumen and materials
to operationalize or even develop prototypes for that?
Like, you know, on our own tech tree without, you know,
grafting something on from a non-human craft.
I'm skeptical of that.
Cause I think, you know,
even if we have a theoretical foundation
for say vacuum polarization or this sort of, you know,
extended electrodynamics, you've got these,
like this coupling with high,
like extremely high magnetic field
sort of frequency variations
and you're doing some crazy topological insulators, right?
With the sort of missile man stuff.
Like there's like, I think we have hints
of where we can explore, you know,
potential next moves on propulsion and materials.
But I just think you have to build a whole stack
of technologies and stacks of physics
and engineering knowledge
that I just don't think we're anywhere close.
So even if we think we have like the physics,
the theoretical physics worked out,
I just don't think we're close
to having like the engineering,
like materials stack built up yet to realize that.
But this is where I think
there's an interesting middle ground scenario,
which seems to be lent more credence
by what the sky watcher folks like Jordan
in particular was saying.
If you take a story, which, you know,
I have no evidence one way or the other,
but I think he's a credible person.
But he says explicitly, it's like the psionic activity
isn't, it's like a mind meld with this conscious craft.
And effectively there's like control modules
that you essentially take over.
And it's like this sort of, you know,
this orb that's a conscious sort of AI, you know,
super craft thing that's just,
it's just waiting to be kind of like, you know,
not hijacked, but kind of like, you know,
if you're ready, you can sort of, you know,
take me for a spin, right?
Like let's do a little mind meld
and then I'll show you how to like
zip around with your consciousness here.
And if that's, you know, again,
hard pill to swallow from a certain scientific
and metaphysical perspective,
but if you just take it at face value,
well, that would then make more likely a scenario where,
you know, we can control non-human craft
without having the ability to make them, right?
Which almost wouldn't explain
why the retrieval program is so important, right?
Because we actually have really no hope
of truly reverse engineering our own, you know,
super luminal, anti-gravity, whatever, right?
But, you know, the real constraint is
whoever gets the most of them has the most of these things.
Right, and so it's like, you know,
the production rate of F-35s
versus Chinese hypersonic missiles is like a, you know,
it's like, who's got the most, the range,
it's always about parity, right?
And if nobody really has the ability to manufacture them,
then the only strategic, you know, measure
is who's be able to get the most,
train the most stasonic assets,
and then operationalize as many of these craft as possible.
Well, then that would put an intense strategic pressure
on these great powers to do that.
Right, and it would also, I think,
create an immense competitive pressure
within these same institutions
and their associated contractor ecosystems.
Because it's like, this also would explain
the whole weird parts of the Barber story
where it implies there's like contractor teams
and mercenary, you know, you know,
we're like retrieval units,
all kind of competing over this stuff.
Yeah.
In that sense, like, you know, Lockheed and Northrop
or SAIC or whoever that you presume
is involved in this stuff,
neither of them has a real competitive advantage
on creating like new units, right?
Like F-35s versus whatever.
The only differentiator between them is like,
who's got the most, you know, who's got the most stuff?
Who's got the most assets and, you know,
both sonic assets as well as craft.
And that's just, that's a competitive, you know, dynamic
that you could see these institutions, you know.
Well, all of this is predicated
on this sort of Philip J. Corso narrative
that like you can derive any sort of material benefit.
And when I say material, I mean, literally like materials
benefit that can work its way
into any sort of existing technology stack.
And so I guess that narrative specifically,
which actually seems to be getting
sort of more and more corroborated again,
Jason Sands going on Rogan.
And, you know, this could be circular reporting, who knows?
But like, he was talking about radars, you know,
high powered radars at Roswell and White Sands
actually disrupting flight paths of the crafts.
Rogan actually expressed skepticism,
but it actually sort of makes sense
from like a physics standpoint that radar might disrupt
some, you know, exotic craft like this.
And, you know, the stuff comes down and then, you know,
it gets collected, it gets taken to Roscoe Hillencoder
who's the first director of the CIA.
And then Philip J. Corso, who is the, you know,
chief of the Army's Foreign Technology Exploitation Desk.
He is given the material and that material
is systematically doled out to the private sector,
namely Bell Labs.
And so he says everything from Kevlar lasers
to the transistor, you know,
or maybe it's not just the transistor,
maybe it's like some sort of thing essential
to integrated circuits and fiber optics.
Like all of these things are derivative
of these materials from Roswell.
Do you believe that?
I mean, it's hard, like I haven't done the deep analysis
of that, but like, as far as my shallow understanding
is there's no major like gaps if you tried to like
retell the history of that tech tree development
from transistors to fiber optics.
Like it's, there's no like mysterious, you know,
oh, like all of a sudden we now have this new thing
that like nobody has an idea where it came from.
There was like patterns of individuals
working in discrete research units
with like a tech antecedent that then was modified
with a certain technical, you know,
breakthrough that then was merged and you get this,
you know, what seems like a characteristic
tech development tree.
And isn't there a patent on transistors
from like Munich in the 1930s or something?
Yeah, I mean, there was, I mean,
a lot of people since the beginning of electricity
and the knowledge of basic circuitry
and the related equations was like,
okay, there's just an engineering question like,
can you do this in a cost-effective way
and, you know, to get the right materials
and then start building some of these devices.
It wasn't like, oh, we don't know how to make
integrated circuit and fiber optics is like,
oh, this is crazy advanced.
It's like, okay, you just need like
sufficiently transparent crystal glass
and you just need to like, you know, protect it
and then have a way to generate, you know,
a photon source that's correlated to some analog circuit
and you can just generate signal.
Like these weren't like magical things.
They had a characteristic antecedent
and there's no mystery embedded in it.
And I think part of that whole Corso thing,
I think is, you know, I don't know if it's intentional,
seems like disinformation, seems like passage material.
Do you think it was?
I don't know, I mean, but it would make sense
if it's like, you're worried that this idea
of there being non-human intelligence,
you know, technology unknown origin material out there,
you want to try to like throw a shaft at the Russians
or whoever who at that point, and it seems like you like,
they know that we know that they know
kind of sort of thing that this is going on.
And so you're not trying to convince the Russians
this isn't real.
You're just trying to obfuscate to the Russians
and maybe puff up your chest
about what you figured out, right, about this stuff.
Like, oh yeah, we figured out all this stuff.
Well, it's funny.
He was also Corso on the psychological strategy board
under Eisenhower.
So it was like all military psychological operations
where like, it was Gordon Gray
and it was this other guy, Charles Douglas Jackson
and you know, Philip Corso.
And a lot of the early alien lore
comes from that nexus of people, which I find interesting.
A lot of it was, I mean, there's even a,
I believe a memo from Walter B. Smith
who I believe took over the CIA in 52, 53.
And he's saying, you know,
how do we use the UFO phenomena?
And I always find this interesting
because he doesn't say, let's make up the UFO phenomena.
He says, you know, the whole memo is predicated on the,
you know, the tacit acceptance of this.
Actually, he's like writing about it
in this sort of banal way.
Like, of course there's a UFO phenomena.
Let's figure out how to kind of operationalize it
against the Soviets.
And so, yeah, do you think that that's been done in the past?
Yes, I mean, I think the best cover stories
are based on a germ of truth
that you distort and you mix in with a bunch of untruths.
And that's what makes it a good operation.
So it makes it effective
and enduring counterintelligence operation.
Do you think Bob Lazar is an example of that?
Like, what's your belief on Bob Lazar?
So Bob Lazar, for the audience,
claimed to have worked at S4,
which was, you know, a special compartment of Area 51.
And he was recruited there
because he, I guess, slapped like a ramjet
on the back of a Honda or something.
And then he met Edward Teller serendipitously
and he gets recruited to this program.
And he claims that he was working on, you know,
a craft that looked like Billy Myers,
who was a Swiss ufologist.
And he would describe the sports model,
so the saucer-shaped craft.
And he describes certain frameworks
like Gravity A and Gravity B
as far as working on the craft.
And it's with remarkable level of detail and lucidity
that he's described all this stuff.
And he came out in Rogan and sort of talked about it.
But there's some weird things in his history and past.
And I've actually become increasingly of the mind
that the prima facie story is real.
But then I don't know.
Is it passage material or, yeah?
Yeah, I think it's the same sort of thing,
which is there's probably a germ of truth
in what he's saying.
But I think it's very, very hard,
maybe impossible to really carve out.
Is it 10% of that?
Is it 80% of that?
I don't think it's 0%.
I think now that I've had to sort of update my prize
very significantly to the reality of these programs
and the reality of non-human intelligence
and these related technologies,
then it seems somewhat irrational to be like,
oh, well, the first guy to say that is just wrong.
Yeah, right, right, right, right.
You kind of have to be rational
and sort of reset your assessment
and take all the kind of cruft in the personalities
and the different narratives
that have been shaped over decades
and just kind of like go to first principles,
be like, well, without anything else,
it does raise the probability
that he was telling the truth, right?
If it turns out these programs are real,
then it raises the chance
that he was involved in some capacity.
But it doesn't at all endorse
or force you to raise your credences
in all the other things he said, right?
Which clearly have aspects of embellishments
and kind of changing sort of details over time.
But so you can get to this nuanced picture,
which is parts of his story are probably credible
and then parts are very not, right?
And I think it's more of a historical story at this point.
Like, I don't think it's much more
in the way of disclosure information
you're gonna get out of that episode.
Do you have a belief on what's true and what's not
or sort of anybody's guess or?
On him or just in general?
On him, I mean.
No, I mean, I think it's likely that he was involved
in some parts of the program, these like things.
And maybe he was, and I think it's plausible he saw craft.
But I mean, you look at all these other stories,
it's so compartmented
and the people that are brought in are brought in
with a very particular reason.
And it seems clear that they're only told
what they need to know.
And then a lot of what they're told
is likely disinformation
that's not really related to their function, right?
Like, you would not tell just every piece of the puzzle
like what the puzzle is, right?
You would tell them how to draw what the borders are.
And then the rest of the puzzle,
you'd probably come up with a total cockamamie story for it.
Cause they don't need to know, right?
But you need to tell them something.
So you say it's from Alcicentauri,
you say it's gravity A, gravity B,
you tell them all this stuff.
It's like, okay, like, but he's got a very narrow thing.
He's like more of a technician.
He's just got to lift certain things
and go to certain places and just, you know,
there's certain physical things that have to get done,
but he's not the grand genius
that's supposed to figure out the basic physics here.
He's just being told a story.
Again, that's just like a hot take.
I think what's interesting is in the Jacob Barber story,
it's like, yeah, like he knows what he saw.
He knows what he experienced, but he's just a delivery guy.
So he can kind of tell you with a high degree of fidelity,
like what was under the cone of light from his helicopter.
But like, he can't tell you
what was happening under the bunkers.
He can't tell you what was happening
with these research institutes and this, you know,
sprawling disconnected compartmentalized archipelago, right?
And so there's an elephant here
and each, you know, these individual cases comes out.
It's like, oh, this is the toenail.
This is the tail.
This is the tusk.
And you're like, I think there's an elephant here,
but how big is it, right?
Is it one elephant?
Is there actually five
and they're touching different elephants, right?
This is the part that's very hard to discern.
You've just got this like soda straw
of apparently vertical experience
mixed in with potentially disinformation.
Like who knows what the corso stuff.
And this is the detective story.
This is why it's, you know,
human beings, we love these sorts of pattern matching,
especially certain cognitive phenotypes
where we'd love to just obsess.
Like some people like doing puzzles, right?
And so you're just like, oh, is this one puzzle?
But it's like, it turns out somebody was screwing with you
and just mixed in a bunch of other puzzle pieces in there.
It's like, well, you're going to have trouble.
And that's what they think this is, right?
Like somebody just mixed a bunch of puzzle pieces
from different puzzles together.
And, you know, some people will just be like,
oh, it's all, there's no one puzzle here.
This is all just noise, right?
And then there's some people who are just like,
oh, wait a second, I think this is the one puzzle
I need to figure out
and I just need to throw these other pieces away, right?
And that's a lot of work.
And you never really, there's no guarantee of success
because you don't know what the ratio is.
Like you can be there all day.
Speaking of puzzle pieces,
you're one of the few people who've spent in-person time
with this guy, Harold Malmgren.
And Harold was a top presidential advisor
for the four presidents for, you know,
JFK, LBJ, Nixon and Ford
and did various other amazing things
just in a kind of, you know, prosaic governmental context.
But he's also just been dropping bombs on the internet,
saying all sorts of really interesting stuff around,
you know, his investigations of,
you know, he says that he meets Lawrence P. Geiss,
who's, you know, Jeff Bezos' maternal grandfather
by adoption, who runs, you know,
the Atomic Energy Commission's Albuquerque branch.
And, you know, he's sort of briefed on, you know, UFOs
and that there was a UFO that came out of this, you know,
Bluegill triple prime tests from the Marshall Islands tests.
And so, you know, you spent some time with him.
Did you learn anything interesting
by just being around him?
And did you find it, yeah, did you find it credible?
Oh, yes.
I mean, that I can start with for sure, for like 100%.
Like, yeah, he is like a living legend.
He's probably done more for America
than like anyone I've ever met, right?
Just in terms of just the duration of service,
as well as just the level of impact, right?
Like holding Curtis Lemme back
from potentially nuking during the Cuban-Military crisis.
It's a big deal.
Big deal, you know, not somebody,
he's not a guy who's gonna like humble brag about that, right?
He just did it when he was like 27.
And it's just part of his, you know,
he's like, he's a quiet kind of civil servant,
sort of technocrat by nature.
So he's never one to kind of pat himself on the shoulder
or kind of, you know, be a braggadocio
about his achievements.
And he was never title obsessed.
It was never, he probably could have been
multiple different cabinet secretary type roles.
And he was never, you know, about the ego.
So I think that's just,
yeah, I think there are people like that.
I'm not sure there's that many people like that,
but like those are unique, special people.
It's a rare breed, yeah.
It's a rare breed and it's also why I think
he was trusted by so many different, you know,
presidents and senior leaders over, you know,
many, many years.
And it's why when he says things,
it's from a position of like being in a,
an enduring role,
an enduring roles where he's given a huge amount of trust
by multiple presidents.
And he's an enormous cache, enormous reputation.
Like he spent his life serving the national security state,
you know, from the early sort of Cold War,
anti-ballistic missile sort of defense planning,
all the way to like international trade,
negotiating, you know, trade treaties,
being the sort of the back channel with the Soviets
and the Chinese and just, you know,
playing at the geopolitical level at the highest,
at the highest, the highest level.
And so he's got an amazing reputation.
He was a national consultant.
Like this guy could have just, you know,
could sail off into the sunset,
never say a word about UAPs.
And, you know, his name would be in the history books.
He's written books.
His legacy would be secured.
And the fact that he's, you know,
very insistent on bringing his thoughts to the public
and his historical interactions with these, you know,
important figures in the early Cold War
on the subject of UAPs explicitly
and non-human intelligence and UFOs is a remarkable thing.
Like this guy has nothing to gain
about talking about this stuff.
And he could be enjoying, you know,
retirement and just chilling out, right?
The fact that he is very focused
on trying to bring some of his knowledge
and his experiences to the public,
I think should draw attention, right?
Should have people perk up and take notice.
Yeah, and he has these, you know,
arresting, you know, anecdotes about talking with,
yeah, Lawrence P. Geiss,
who told him the like of their efforts to retrieve UFOs
out at, you know, around Los Alamos.
And similar with Richard Bissell,
who told him of their efforts to retrieve
and figure out other world technologies.
And Richard Bissell was number two at the CIA
and helped form Area 51 and was kind of like,
I think CIA liaison to Skunk Works
because they were doing a lot of work together.
Yeah, and then, you know,
Harold has been a trusted confidant to multiple presidents,
you know, helped, you know.
And I think there's an interesting part of that
Cold War history, especially under Kennedy,
which, you know, who knows?
We'll see, we'll get more information
on those Kennedy-related records.
Yeah.
Which, interesting sidebar,
I found it noteworthy and people should go back
to the Joe Rogan interview with Donald Trump,
where Joe Rogan is talking to him
about the Kennedy assassination records
and, you know, prompting him to commit
to whatever disclosures of those records, et cetera.
And then Trump leads the transition of the conversation
from, like, Rogan talking about JFK records
and how many people are interested in them.
And then Rogan goes, and then Trump goes,
many people are also interested in
the people coming from space.
And he looks up at the ceiling.
And then Rogan, who's like, huh, goes,
like, you know about that?
And Trump, with a somber look, goes,
I know a lot about that, a ton.
And then Rogan tries to prompt him.
And, you know, Trump kind of, I think, realizes
he's kind of said too much.
And then he sort of pivots to talking about
how Area 51's a tourist destination
and the most beautiful pilots come to him
and talk about seeing anomalous things.
Pilots with crew cuts.
Yeah, crew cuts, the most beautiful,
the most handsome pilots, the greatest pilots,
the greatest tourist, you know,
secret research projects in the desert.
What do you think Trump knows?
Well, that was a fast, so I think he said,
many people are interested in the people coming from space
and he looked up.
And then he sort of, I think he tried to walk this back
because I've never been a believer, you know,
he sort of tried to dial it back.
But that was an odd turn of phrase for a president to use.
And immediately after, like without any, like, you know,
apparent prompting by Rogan, like in his brain,
there's a bunch of neurons that have JFK, you know,
associations and apparently those neurons
are like really close to his UFO neurons
and they just fired.
And they sort of, you know, in his free association,
the UFO subject is just close, you know,
in his cognitive matrix to JFK.
So that, if you're trying to like, what does Trump know?
Well, that's telling me like what sorts of concepts
and memories are embedded in his prefrontal cortex
and his amygdala and whatever, right?
Or his hippocampus actually.
And it seems like through his verbal utterances
that JFK and UFOs or specifically people coming from space
are connected in his mental relationships, right?
Can you fathom as to what that relationship
might be in Trump's mind?
Well, that is a really interesting question.
And this is where I know those folks like Jeff Cruickshank
have done like the forensic historical kind of deep dive,
look through the Kennedy archives, like the library,
kind of, you know, records, the declassified JFK records,
which are, you know,
obviously historical vertical material.
And then you have these much more contested materials
like the MJ-12 documents, which, you know, are enormous
and, you know, highly disputed.
But you can find these interesting correlations
between say calendar, you know, entries and diary entries
and some interesting overlaps there.
Jeff is obviously much more tuned to those details,
but they overlap with this sort of period of time
where there's a lot of just immense.
And we talked about this in the first interview
of just like that period
is there was a certain power structure in place in the US,
right?
There was extremely like, you know,
go back to the Fukuyama institutional lot,
sort of like these guys were climbing to the peak
of that kind of institutional creation, energy, power,
the Dulles brothers, you know,
kind of this whole system, right?
That kind of won World War II
and then created this post-war architecture.
And then allegedly had access to these advanced materials.
Like at the sort of, that was the core
of this kind of potential strategic advantage
they wanted to amplify.
And they were a small group, right?
They weren't like, and they thought of themselves
as like the guardians of American, you know,
strategic interests.
Like democracy was kind of a second order concern
for them, right?
There were higher order strategic considerations
for ensuring that America dominated the global system.
That was what was in their interest
and their institutional interests, that was their focus.
And to the extent that if Kennedy was threatening that,
that would be a challenge to that power structure.
And, you know, that's the allegation
is that the power structure, you know, retaliated.
And that's, yeah, we'll see if we get information on that,
but like there seems to have been
this sort of increasing arrows pointing in that direction.
And so you're just implying that that power structure
in the world in which the UFO thing is real
and there's a lineage of, you know, government relationship
with that UFO, you know, phenomena,
it would probably be that power structure
that would kind of hold the keys, so to speak.
It's like, there weren't that many presidents
that you could say were like independent of the system.
And here comes Kennedy, who's this kind of, you know,
darling media guy, he's, you know, pretty boy.
Who the power structure, right?
If you want to use the general term to refer
to a whole constellation of different actors.
And institutions at the time that, you know,
wielded influence and dominated American politics
and our economy and the global system,
you know, thought that essentially his daddy
got him the presidency, there was a deal made,
the mafia, the sort of, you know,
the machine in Chicago, et cetera.
And that, you know, if there was a basic,
implicit understanding that the president was there
to serve a certain set of interests,
and that if you deviate from those interests,
well, they essentially, you're betraying the deal, right?
And if you go too far, say to do a detente
or denuclearization or even cooperation on space
and these alleged potential UFO technologies,
well, that would cut straight to the core
of that apparent deal, essentially.
Oh, you reneged, like deals off,
you don't get to be president anymore.
That seems like conspiracy theory,
but like that seems like, like more and more
of the evidence seems to be pointing in that direction.
It's plausible if you look at the historical record
that seems, you know, and that might be part of what,
you know, the reason why like Trump had this embedded
in his brain is like JFK and UFOs are linked,
is that, yeah, that might be part of it,
that there are records apparently
that would link those two things.
Yeah, so let's touch on the, Jeff Crookshank
is this Australian intelligence officer,
and he's reviewed the footage from these Johnston Atoll,
also Marshall Island's tests, specifically of these,
I think ICBM, it was actually defensive interceptors,
and they were, they had X-rays in the nose cones,
and, you know, one went off, I think it was around,
it was October of 1962,
I think it was around the Cuban Missile Crisis.
Yeah, November, yeah.
Maybe it was November.
Yeah, I think it was directly after.
And it was, it was at midnight and the thing goes off,
and out of the plume, you see this material like tumble out,
and there's a video of this that you can see today,
and then there's also a video of that, you know,
material tumbling out being superimposed
with a white triangle, sanitized,
and so he's done this deep dive
where he shows that Harold Malmgren actually ends up,
you know, in Los Alamos getting debriefed by Lawrence Geese,
who's the, you know, Atomic Energy Commission's
Albuquerque director, and then a month later,
you have JFK come out himself,
and so that's not really that normal for JFK
to come just check on this, you know, it is Los Alamos,
but it's like, why would you go out and visit?
And so, you know, maybe, you know,
if Malmgren's saying that he's learning about UFOs
from Lawrence Geese, presumably, you know,
the guy he's advising, the President of the United States,
is coming, you know, that timing is not a coincidence,
and JFK's probably learning about the UFO question as well,
and then the other piece of evidence is you have,
you know, Howard Hunt is?
Yeah, he's the sort of CIA, you know, wetworks guy.
Yeah, wetworks guy, agent provocateur,
and like all but admitted he was like involved
in the JFK assassination and a whole host of other things,
but like, you know, wouldn't implicate Dulles
because he was, you know, so quote unquote,
loyal or whatever, and his lawyer,
I think is a guy named Douglas Caddy,
and Douglas Caddy in an interview says that,
you know, he would persistently question Howard Hunt,
like what was, why did they actually take out JFK?
Why did they take out JFK?
And at the end of that questioning,
Howard Hunt says it was the alien presence,
and so what do you think?
I mean, well, and yeah, I think even Harold has tweeted,
you know, you always got to have notifications on for Harold.
You know, he just drops these things,
he's just like, here you go.
And yeah, I think he explicitly referenced
how he had gotten reports from the triple prime test,
which, yeah, I believe it was the gold encased.
They took a lot of gold out of Fort Knox
and they just basically put it around this nuke to do the,
I think it's Bram Shillung,
or basically generates a sort of X-ray burst,
which, you know, amplifies the ability
to essentially fry the incoming ballistic missile.
And apparently got reports of this object
that had fallen out and was retrieved by the Navy,
and then Harold, like, requested more information
and was denied that,
and then goes out to Albuquerque to get ground truth.
And then a month later, roughly, I think,
JFK goes on his first visit to that same lab, essentially.
It looks like he was doing the advanced, you know,
wait, we're not getting the full story here in Washington.
Like, Harold, you're my guy on the ground,
like, figure out what's really going on here, right?
And at the time, there was a lot of inter-service rivalries,
I think, between these different,
you know, branches of the military,
which, you know, I think Curtis LeMay
had his own vision for, like, nuclear everything, right?
He had, like, crazy plans for some doomsday weapons
and just he wanted to go whole hog, right?
And he had, you know, and he had his whole power base
and the Navy, you know, wanted to have their own power base
and so they would have an incentive
to kind of hold this as their trump card.
So I think there's a lot of institutional rivalry
and, of course, the Atomic Energy Commission,
Division of Military Applications, Geiss,
was there to kind of be the main belly button
on all things nuclear and the military,
but, like, more fundamental research.
So they would ultimately be the,
and I think Rush has alluded to this, too,
like, they would be the ultimate custodians
for any sort of R&D effort, right?
But there's probably a complicated bargaining position
between these different services
and the Atomic Energy Commission.
But, yeah, I think this is part,
points to a part of American history
where these, you know, very, very, you know,
conspiratorial, sort of, conspiracy fodder material
is all tied together in a tight knot.
And here we are, you know, coming up 70 years,
80 years later and it's, like, still, like, a pressing matter.
Yeah. Like, what happened?
Yeah.
And who knows, like, Trump has signed this executive order
to get a plan written in the next, like, week or so
to disclose more JFK records.
Tulsi Gabbard, on her testimony,
says she's going to be focused on that,
as well as the anomalous health incidents stuff.
Again, with any topic, you can try to address it
from the question of what should have been your prior
for that type of thing, and then what is now your posterior
for that sort of thing, given a historical, you know,
testimonial evidence.
It's always better to start with a prior.
And it's funny, like, if I, like, you know,
introspect on my priors for this broader topic,
I actually think my naive prior for the reality
of, say, psi abilities should have been,
I don't think I actually did this, you know,
baseline assessment before I was forced to now,
like, create a posterior belief.
But it's like, I think my prior for the reality
of psi phenomenon should be higher,
given my metaphysical sort of commitments
to something like protopanpsychism
as an integrated metaphysics
underlying a certain theory of physics,
than the prior for the reality of non-human intelligence
coming from another star system.
Because to motivate that prior, I have to account
for a whole bunch of, you know, interrelated hypotheses
in my model about the processes of intelligence
and the history of 13.7 billion years of the universe
and the number of star systems that are nearby,
potentially panspermia in a, you know,
a local ring around the galaxy of maybe 10,000 stars
that were all together in a stellar nursery.
And we had, you know, asteroid bombardments
and so there's maybe like, you know,
a one in a thousand chance that like,
there's an advanced sibling system to us
that was like, you know, born around the same time
that gave us, you know, primitive genetic material,
but, you know, was correlated then
to our proximate neighborhood in the universe
and would also have a reason to engage with us.
And our cosmological models themselves
are just patchwork upon patchwork.
Like, there's like a scaling problem
of your physical model of reality.
And so like, if you get, it's like a, you know, rocket
that's like two degrees off course,
you end up like, you know, 99 degrees off course very soon.
And I think that's basically like our understanding
of like Cartesian space, you know, and like, you know,
space overall and the planets and stuff.
It's pretty shaky and it's very recent.
Yeah, I guess my larger point was,
I think if you just ask the average person on the street,
what's more likely, aliens are visiting us
or psychics are real.
I think people would go, well, they're both crazy,
but I think aliens are probably more likely to be real
but I think that's purely just an availability bias.
No, the psychic thing is there's so much more evidence
like you're saying.
Yeah, but it's just an availability bias
because of what sorts of media narratives we have.
We've seen a lot more alien movies than some psychic movies.
That's right.
And so people just think, oh, well, you know,
the only ambient facts I have to form that prior
if you ask me that question is,
it seems like aliens are a thing that people talk about
and it's in the movies all the time.
And yeah, like the universe is big,
but like I've never read anybody's mind.
I've never had my mind read that I can think of
or I never moved an object with my head.
That seems, you know.
And then the funny thing is,
I think if they were to truly audit themselves,
they'd be like, there was that one time
I kind of read somebody's mind, but.
Well, and in a certain sense,
most people's folk metaphysics is physicalism, right?
Which is essentially, you know,
a branch of that would be the computational functionalism
of, you know, Dennett and Churchland,
which is just almost at a metaphysical level
eliminates the reality of consciousness.
Therefore the basic idea that then there can be
other degrees of freedom in reality associated
with just pure consciousness as a phenomenon
is just ruled out, like by assumption, right?
In your model of metaphysics, that's just not a thing, right?
And so anyone claiming that to be a thing
is just like, it's not an empirical question
of I need to look out into the world
to see is this a thing that's true.
It's ruled out by my metaphysical assumptions, right?
Therefore it must be absurd to even claim such a thing.
So you need to, that question forces you then
to inspect your metaphysical commitments
about the nature of consciousness.
Whereas the question of aliens is, you know,
people that are physicalists,
computational functionalism, you know, adherence.
It's way easier to then motivate, oh, well, yeah,
like we exist, like we create rockets.
Somebody else could exist and create rockets.
There's no metaphysical question at issue there.
There's just a question of time and complexity
and propulsion systems and, you know,
the probabilities associated with star systems
that could, you know, incubate life,
interacting with each other on time scales
relevant to our civilization.
So that's somewhat of a scientifically grounded question.
And this is why the UAP question, the Jake Barber story
is very confronting to a lot of people
because it forces you to really intellectually
and very seriously engage at this metaphysical layer
that even most people in a lot of the, say,
like the semi-serious professional commentariat on UAPs
that take the story of anomalous UAP objects
very seriously, you know, button themselves up
as being, you know, sober journalists
or rational people who inspect the evidence
and look at, you know, government reports.
And, you know, they go, oh, well,
there's lots of evidence that we have anomalies,
but it could be hypotheses X, Y, and Z.
But the size stuff, oh, that's off the table.
That's crazy. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And it's like, well, that's not really
a rational approach, right?
Because a rational person starts
with their metaphysical assumptions
and then builds up from there.
I was into the size stuff before I got into UFOs, so.
I mean, winding roads.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But that's your other point about, you know,
how do we have certainty on any of this?
We really don't, right?
We're always trying to hold together a lot
of what amounts to very noisy
and hard to anchor together pieces of information.
It's why the OAP subject is like human science
and culture and sort of our pictures of the world
have evolved, at least to first word,
on an incremental basis over our history.
Like, we've just been going through this,
like maybe there's been a hidden hand seeding some things
or downloading people or whoever is,
maybe there's a second order process
that's sort of guiding human social
and, you know, our scientific organizations over time.
But, I mean, you could just look at history
and it's not obvious there was like a, you know,
there's lots of inspirational moments and big geniuses,
but there was a tower of knowledge
that took a lot of time and effort to create.
And it was like difficult experiments,
some smart person noticing something
and then being like, huh, like Galileo with the telescope
or, you know, Newton and figuring out,
okay, we can use calculus to look at these,
you know, the sort of planetary sort of observations
and basic tricks of, oh, we formalize knowledge with math
and then we construct experimental apparatuses.
This is the enlightenment project
and that's what we've built civilization on.
And the thing about the UAP question,
it's like, if it turns out that all of a sudden,
since maybe the 30s or 40s, you know,
allegedly we got some material magenta crash
into the post-war era is when we got subsumed
to these larger systematic industrial academic bureaucracies
and there were hypercharges,
our civilization got, you know, more and more technology.
It's like, oh, okay, you've got this potential accelerant,
right, but it's like a nonlinear thing.
You've got access to craft and beings potentially.
That's just like a nonlinear, like,
we don't have the systems, like our systems of knowledge
have not been built to like, to deal with that, right?
It's like this lump, right?
And we've been trying to maybe absorb it or chip away at,
but it's probably just this rock sitting
in the middle of the snake.
You know what I worry about a little bit
is the idea that in the 40s and 50s,
the US government's stand,
these aerospace prob contractors started to fuck around
with this stuff and they couldn't get it to work.
And it's been this sort of like really hard,
cumbersome process, you know, from then till now.
And we were never supposed to have it in the first place.
And whatever beings exist on the other side of this,
you know, I don't know if you saw this Jason Sands,
one of these whistleblowers who was, I guess,
part of the counter Intel was, you know,
perimeter security for the program.
And he sort of saw this like blue alien being
at Nellis testing range in Nevada.
And he was a part of James Fox's, the program.
He just went on Joe Rogan.
And I think that maybe the most important part
of that interview, he says, they want their stuff back
and they're gonna kill everybody involved in the program
if they don't get it.
And that's pretty freaky.
And so, again, I have no mental model
or understanding of any of this stuff,
but like, what if we weren't supposed to have it
in the first place?
And what if, you know, they're gonna come back for it?
Again, it's one of these hypotheticals.
It's hard to know like what to deal with it.
But I do find it interesting.
It's like people, like the legacy,
you say that like we use the term legacy program
and it's now become like this term of art.
But what we're sort of referring to is
like a particular pathology
in a modern state institutional structure, right?
That it maybe became pathological as a result
of coming into possession of some of these materials.
And then the sort of, you know,
some threads of knowledge
that were sort of teased out of it, right?
That maybe the psionics knowledge
or maybe inspirations in meta materials
or novel propulsion systems
and potential weapons that could be created.
And that like hyper pathologized
a portion of our military intelligence system
that essentially delaminated.
We talked about this in our first interview
and it sort of delaminated and it kind of,
it's like the ring of power golem, right?
It's like starts off as happy, you know,
well adjusted creature.
And then as a result of having access to this, you know,
totem, this sort of, you know,
this metaphysical object almost
of super advanced capabilities,
it completely distorts them into this golem institution,
right?
So it's like the rings of power,
that's what they do, right?
And it's an interesting counterfactual of like.
And passing the test is never taking up the ring
and thinking that you are above the corruption of it.
It is just not holding the ring, not putting the ring on.
That is the test.
Well, this is, well, again, this is where I'm,
again, I always weigh these antinomies of like,
you could go that direction,
but if you take that logic,
then it's like all of technology system
was like the Kaczynski thesis.
It's like technology is inherently
corrupting for civilization.
Man in a modern technological civilization
is a contorted, distorted, pathologized,
exploited version of, it's like,
we've all become golems,
regardless of alien technology
from a certain philosophical standpoint.
And therefore to de-golemize humanity,
we need to return to a much more agrarian,
primitive state of nature.
Some people can make an argument for that,
but like, you're gonna give up a lot along the way.
Yeah, I don't believe that.
So for me, it's a spectrum.
It's not like a binary.
And like, for example, hypotheticals,
think about some of the more very different institutions
that humans have created over the world or over world history.
Say, Socrates, Plato's, Agora,
or high councils of scholarship
in the scholastic era in medieval Europe,
enlightened, or circles of sort of Buddhas,
sort of inheritors, people that were committed
to spiritual transformation, intellectual scholarship.
They weren't connected to war fighting institutions
and state bureaucracies, or sort of financial institutions
associated with some sort of elite network.
Their institution was focused on knowledge,
wisdom, higher purposes.
If you had systems of sort of secrecy
and reverse engineering that were guided by those people,
would you get the same sort of blue beings being like,
I'm not dealing with those murderers and barbarians
on the other side of the hill, right?
And I think that's the binary 51 that Sands alleged,
was you get a much more enlightened interrelationship
between, hey, this is a really interesting technology.
We would love to use this to further our civilization
and bring humanity to a much higher plane of being
and fulfillment and flourishing.
Instead of creating platforms for nukes, right?
I believe that.
I think Seek and Ye shall find and fuck around
and you'll find out.
If you cut to the core of the parapsychological stuff,
you can instantiate it in its most primitive form
in this random event generator experiment.
And it's just basically the random event generators,
how much can you affect
a random quantum mechanical process, right?
And the more heart-centered and aligned you are,
the more you can, and I don't think you can fake that.
So you can create a program around trying to get people
quote unquote more heart-centered,
but your meta objective is to weaponize all this shit
and to be a billionaire or whatever.
It's just not gonna work.
It's gonna fail on you in the end.
And so you can lie to a bunch of people about it
and it'll be the myth of Faust or Prometheus
and you'll blow up.
And so I do really believe what you just said,
which is if you really want the good stuff to happen,
you actually do have to look within and change yourself.
If you're buying into this sort of model,
the parapsychological model where your ability
to render reality is commensurate with some sort of,
again, this is really loose,
but internal coherence or growth or whatever.
And you can't really operationalize that locally,
but for some kind of dystopian objective,
it's just not gonna work.
So let me throw a hypothetical at you, right?
This is the, let's say, I'll create an SAT analogy here,
is like exercise and diet is too ozempic
as alien, say, psionic-inspired practices
is to like Buddhist asceticism, right?
It's like, is this a shortcut?
Is this a cheat?
Yeah, the point is there are no shortcuts.
Like in this model, there are no shortcuts.
So yeah, you're shutting down your pancreas of, you know.
Yeah, like the ozempic,
it gets you what you thought was an outcome,
but there are side effects that accrue
that essentially undermine the value of that outcome
that you thought you were aiming for.
That's right, yeah, yeah.
No, I think that is a good analogy
with higher cost on the UAP side
than, you know, whatever organs malfunction due to ozempic.
But yeah.
But then it's like maybe, again, this is where I stress,
and again, this is almost like the sky watcher thing is like,
this is the inherent tension is like,
there's a certain folks like you
that have been paying close attention to this,
have gone down, again, this variety of rabbit holes
and come to this realization that it is,
that is you need to sort of have this self-reflective
orientation that there's no one weird trick
or shortcut to enlightenment or whatever.
But the average person doesn't even know
that that's even a thing that they should like care about.
And do you need to have essentially
what amounts to profit motivated
or financed efforts to sort of broaden awareness
of that thing in and of itself, right?
That stimulates and catalyzes
a much wider swath of humanity too on that journey.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But that's almost like, what is disclosure?
Is disclosure just the sort of,
yes, non-human intelligence is real, like deal with it?
Or is it a, hey, there are now veridical clues
about the structure of reality
and the nature of human consciousness
that everyone needs to be aware of
in order to pursue their existence in the world
in a way that ideally brings more flourishing
and fulfillment, right?
But it unlocks, this is the tension between technology
and pure spiritualism, right?
Is I don't see this as like a binary or as like a trade-off.
Like there are technologies clearly up-leveled humanity
to the point where you and I can have a conversation
on your best that we wouldn't have been having
or be able to get access to knowledge
and social relationships.
And again, kind of personal satisfaction
that would otherwise have not been possible
without the predicates of modern technology.
And so, again, I'm fundamentally maybe I'm a fence-sitter.
It's like, there's always a gray zone of you can go to,
like the ring of power can always corrupt.
It's like, the question is, is it really a ring of power?
Or is it, like reality ultimately
is just what it is.
And humans are trying to understand it.
And that process of understanding doesn't,
is not guaranteed a good outcome for humanity.
Like we can put our hand in the box
in the, whatever is it, is it Bostrom, right?
It's like, there may be knowledge, dangerous knowledge, right?
Like not all knowledge is just, oh, this is a sunshine.
This is a rainbow.
Oh, this is like forever knowledge.
It's like, this is world destroying knowledge, right?
Like there's no guarantee that the box of knowledge
humanity is dipping its hand into
is gonna be like good knowledge.
Does that mean you stopped dipping your hand in the box?
I don't know.
No, no.
Well, so I think that technology is,
you can't go back.
You can't do the Kaczynski thing.
I think it's a forcing function
and it's a sort of a generic template.
And there's a forcing function in that, like,
your ability to manifest results in reality
as a result of the technology is like,
the latency is like, much lower.
And like the multiplicative effect is much higher, right?
Like you can like scale these things.
And so I would just say, you know, like the,
you know, it's like Peter Thiel went on Joe Rogan.
He was like, you know,
these things have to be angels or demons.
It's not that they might be demons or angels.
They must be demons or angels
if you have faster than light travel.
And both of those seem pretty crazy to me.
So I would just say,
if your intention is not like, you know,
updating or, you know, growing or, you know,
being molded in this sort of positive way
and there's not this like introspective feedback loop
commensurate with advancements in technology
or like putting your hand in the box,
then you're fucked.
But I don't think, you know,
keeping your hand, you know,
out of the box at all times is like,
that's like the right answer.
So that's the way I would put it.
And I don't know who's,
I don't think there is a master plan for this,
but I almost think the Psionics thing,
while it's maybe more indigestible
for the media and consumer,
is critical to try to steer
whatever chaotic disclosure path we're on,
you know, towards the maybe more beneficial outcomes.
Because if that aspect of this whole story
was like continually suppressed
and always just pushed off to the side,
it was just always, you know, only centered on,
you know, many materials,
anti-gravity, vacuum polarization,
Einstein carton, torsion terms,
like how do we engineer space time?
How do we develop, you know,
that's effectively, you know,
that's only one half of the story.
And it's the half that's the more likely to go wrong
in the way that you're, you know, worried about, right?
It's like, we're more likely to try to develop
faster weapons and missiles and, you know,
let's go colonize, let's try to take an asteroid.
Oh, what you, that means now
somebody could create an anti-gravity device
that can move an asteroid and blow up the whole earth.
Like, that's a problem.
That's black box, that's a black ball technology.
But on the other hand, in the consciousness side,
I think, I don't know, like,
because people haven't necessarily treated it
as seriously as it needs to be,
I don't know if as much analysis has gone into like,
okay, you dip your hand into the consciousness jar,
like what black balls are in the consciousness jar, right?
If there's, you know, secret physics jar,
dip your hand into the secret physics jar, you know,
oh wait, we get to have maybe positive energy sources
that, you know, we don't have to burn fossil fuels,
we don't have to exploit the environment,
but oh, but now we, you know, anyone can just like,
zip around and take an asteroid and throw it at the earth.
It's like, that's probably bad,
but maybe we can have better defensive systems.
But now you've got this whole new game theory
of kind of the capability space
that you have to reparameterize.
Consciousness though, because we haven't,
it's like, you know, at least with aerospace technologies
and space war and space economy, we've got models,
we've got, you know, the game theoretic dynamics,
the state and non-state, you know,
kind of capacities to try to operationalize
and it would be highly disruptive,
but it's like, we can even,
we can sort of start to create frameworks.
The consciousness thing, you know,
because we've put into this wooey jar of ineffable,
somewhat, you know, very, you know,
like, doesn't seem like a systematized thing, right?
And when you have systematized capabilities,
that turns into technology.
That's what technology is.
So if it turns out that like,
the program or other people have figured out
that there's a certain part of the brain,
that if you tickle in the right way,
or you give the right drugs or whatever,
that now like remote viewing is now 10x'd, right?
Or clairvoyance is now activated
in a much larger sort of population or these,
you know, these nonverbal autistics
that the whole Kai Dickens, you know,
it's a little search, Lepithy Tapes has looked into that.
I know you've interviewed her.
It's like, okay, imagine that,
imagine you were able to essentially, you know,
take that capability, but activate it in,
in not a nonverbal, but like just, you know,
somebody else in slightly more,
with a slightly more neurotypical sort of cognitive setup.
And what does that do for our social norms, right?
If you're, if you can read each other's minds, like,
like, I mean, that would probably be, ironically,
the one failure mode for Bitcoin,
is if it turns out remote viewing is like hyper accurate,
then like the security protocols for private keys
needs to change.
You've got a complete bi-directional transparency,
you know, people would be able to remote view the cue codes,
like it would be-
Yeah, there'd be all sorts of, you know,
countermeasures and there'd be, yeah,
second and third order changes to a lot of things
with our basic assumptions around what humans can do,
see and know or communicate is very different than what we-
I just, I think we're in the stone age on this stuff.
I always go back to this one line
from the Kai Dickens telepathy tapes,
where one of the kids, I'm forgetting exactly which one says,
mom, you don't get my powers if you lie.
And like, there's something so profound
and important about that.
And like, it's like this, you know,
it's so easy for us to kind of, you know, import our own,
you know, oh, let's just isolate, you know,
the technique and turn it into a science
and make it repeatable, turn it into math somehow.
And then there's something actually
about like the deeper ontology,
when you like hear what they're saying,
they're talking about God in this like extremely intimate way.
And by the way, you were earlier
than anybody on the telepathy tapes.
But yeah, like that seems more important than, you know,
this sort of like need to just turn it
into this like locally repeatable science
as far as actually even making the thing work.
But then even me saying that,
like I'm not helping anybody by saying that.
Like you literally just have to like fix yourself
before you like get into this stuff.
And a whole nother thing,
it's you have to like bridge yourself
into these different scenarios.
But like if something like the Jason Sands scenario is true
and there's essentially like part
of our technological exploration of these phenomenon,
whether it's the, you know, more technical aspects
or the, you know, the psychotechnical aspects,
that that's essentially like a semi-regulated human activity,
regulated by non-human intelligence per,
at least to my perspective, like unknown norms, right?
I'm sort of behavior.
Like what's a permissible experiment
that we can run with that technology?
Like are there, it's like, in a certain sense,
you could interpret that cautiously optimistically
that there is some sort of regulative framework
that's unknown to at least to me
that is keeping guardrails on our exploration.
Like we dip our hand in,
we start to pick up the black box
and some NHI hand goes, nope, right?
Or we start to try to weaponize consciousness in a bad way.
And they're like, no, you get turned off, right?
Like I think there's even been accounts in the toilet.
I think they can do that.
I think it's a three body problem.
They can just shut us down whenever they want.
So in a certain sense, it's like,
okay, well how many tries,
how many runs at that fence, right, do we get, right?
As like a learning, you know, mode is like,
okay, they're gonna test the fence.
That's natural, every human civilization tests the fence.
But in an intelligent civilization
that keeps testing the fence,
that looks like they might try to break through the fence,
well, they need to be put down, right?
That's the implicit threat.
But you know, also like opportunities like,
oh, if we recognize the fence is there
and we like stop trying to test the fence line,
it's an inherent challenge to our sovereignty
and our place in the hierarchy of being,
but it then removes the existential risk.
And it means that, okay,
as long as you recognize we're in this fence,
that we can sort of continue to develop ourselves
technologically and maybe, you know, psychically
in a garden, essentially, right?
And then when we reach a certain level of maturity,
where we're let out.
Well, that is, I think the garden or the fence
is like materialist reductionism.
And like you see like with saints, for example,
as they sort of like lose their own
like materialist reductionist worldview,
not that like many of these people existed
pre-materialist reductionism,
but like as they start to ascend into like higher,
it's kind of, you know, again,
I'm using really vague words,
but like interactions with the celestial or whatever,
they sort of freaks them out
and they have to like look within,
they have to reform themselves
and it's the sort of like two steps forward,
one step back process.
And so I do wonder on some level,
like, you know, I've for example,
been so pro disclosure up until now
it does feel like this sort of Pandora's box
and Pandora's box in the sense that like,
you know, you have hope,
but then there's like a whole lot of like,
you know, bad stuff that comes with it.
I mean, I think this is where we're, you know,
we need new institutions,
which are fundamentally just more accreted,
more formal structures of norms
and human sort of collective beliefs, right?
Like this is a phenomenon that we need to construct
an entire new institutional framework around, right?
Not just a, you know, not just a, you know, an LLC, right?
You need like, you need actually novel institutions
to confront this novel phenomenon.
I think the institutions that we created
or kind of that we, you know,
we sort of wrapped around this information, you know,
were essentially our military and scientific institutions
wedded to the state apparatus in the post-war environment.
And those are certain institutions
set up by certain people with a certain mission
and mandate and psychological orientation to the state
and their class and their military and scientific
and intelligence prerogatives.
And so that, you know, that institution was what was,
what was now sort of absorbed to this technology
or this phenomenon and had to understand it,
try to apply it, et cetera.
But if you were like starting from scratch,
like that would not be the ideal institutions
you would want to give like that,
that mandate of like how to level humanity up, right?
By minimizing risk and maximizing opportunity
for collective success and flourishing, right?
Given whatever constraints that might exist.
And that means like, you truly do need like
blank sheet of paper, new institutions, right?
From the bottom up, right?
New institutions to study it, to finance it,
to organize around it, to diffuse it,
to create new norms around it.
Like that's a massive human project that we have even,
because no one who has a collective acceptance
and disclosure is a thing coming,
but like the big project of post-disclosure
is gonna be, you know, creating new institutions
or adapting or likely existing institutions
or some combination of the two,
to carry forward that project, right?
So you think we should build a Bitcoin,
exotic physics and spiritual development foundation?
Is that what you're trying to say?
You know, this is the game is take all your side quests
and turn them into the main quest, right?
It's like, you know, I've been on the geopolitical
and cyber, you know, intelligence sort of, you know,
main quest and then Bitcoin has now become the main quest.
And then UAPs were the side quest, you know,
like the next logical move is just to make them all
the same thing, right?
Now, I don't know how to do that, obviously,
but I think it's going back to the very beginning
of the conversation is interesting phenomenon
that like Bitcoin is a sociotechnical system
and has elements.
It's a core technical breakthrough.
It's a, you know, it's a piece of software
that people are running, you know,
but it is also, it's a meme, right?
It's a set of collective beliefs.
And the interesting thing about Bitcoin,
the reason why maybe it's like,
have this like hyper acceleration in terms of its adoption
and then kind of this reflectivity is that
that mimetic sociotechnical system has an endogenous asset
that essentially gives the believers
of that sociotechnical systems potential,
more power in the world to spread that,
to spread the gospel essentially, right?
And so there's a flywheel embedded
into sort of this mimetic machine.
With the UAP subject, there really isn't that flywheel,
right, that's built in.
You have podcasts, you have advertising revenue
for people that are interested in this thing,
but it's not like that big, right?
But obviously I think in general,
I mean, the Bitcoin community will like, you know,
cast me as an apostate,
but I think ultimately the UAP question
is more important than the Bitcoin question.
But I think, you know, the fuel to create
the new institutions you need in a post-disclosure world,
I think will actually come from Bitcoin.
Makes sense, yeah.
I think you have, and you know, my buddy Zell,
he gave me these numbers.
He's like, if Bitcoin monetizes to the level of gold,
right, you know, relatively on a global, you know,
say market cap or sort of market value basis,
then you'll have roughly equal numbers
of Bitcoin billionaires and say fiat billionaires
in the world. That's wild.
Which is kind of a unique historical circumstance, right?
That you have this new class of very wealthy people
that all basically believe very similar things
and are also very heterodox thinkers,
they're relatively young,
and they've now had success in building
a sort of a novel global non-state institution
that's now given them a lot of political power, right?
And they're probably interested in lots of things, right?
They're probably curious about the world.
And they're not wedded to, you know, particularly,
and they probably want to have an impact with that wealth,
right, what do you do?
You have a bunch of Bitcoin, like congrats, right?
Go on your island, like chill.
Or like maybe you should invest
in the deepest secrets of the universe
and like help unlock humanity's potential.
That would be cool if the billionaires
weren't just posturing around who has a bigger yacht
or whatever, you know, buying private islands.
I mean, wouldn't it be like amazing just to endow
like a, yeah, like a research syndicate
and a institution that is like,
imagine if you had the philosopher kings of ancient Greece
with alien craft and billions of dollars.
That would be awesome.
So yeah, I think that would be really, really cool.
Just like, I think that some of the,
what I worry about, you know,
as far as what might be happening now
is like this like need to like operationalize.
Like you have no priors on the history of success
on the program itself.
You have very little priors.
It's just this black box.
And you're like operationalizing these like little things
kind of as an extension, like this sort of private,
you know, public partnership de facto thing or whatever.
And like, I worry about that if you don't have
like a good mental map of like what's going on overall,
just like I would worry about like the government
doing things without any sort of mental map,
just because like your only mandate is like national security.
And so I do think like having the, you know,
modern Plato's Symposium is like a fantastic idea.
And just people who are good-willed or earnest,
just trying to figure, having to have, figure out a map
and then aligning yourself with the good stuff.
And then you can like, you know,
get a little more operational after that or something.
I think there's definitely a, you know,
a path dependency here that could go wrong
in many different ways, like building new institutions
that serve their original, say like naive original mandate
is a difficult process, right?
We've seen this go wrong, like in many cases
where you create something, it's really well-motivated
and then it gets distorted or bent over time
or internally corrupted or distracted.
And it's very hard, right?
I think that's just, there's no one weird trick to do that.
But it's a project that it seems like, you know,
I don't think we're ready to do that right now,
but it is a project that I think you would need
to focus on in a post-disclosure environment, right?
I think right now we're in this moment where we're not there.
And so it's like, well, how do you catalyze disclosure
without waiting for big daddy government to give it to you?
Well, you have to now do it on your own.
And that's essentially what I think the Skywatcher team
is trying to do is essentially we're trying to collect
with, you know, private resources and our skills
and knowledge from our aspects of engagement with the program,
you know, enough information to convince, you know,
a marginally more subset of the population
of the reality of this phenomenon.
And disclosure is not like a, you know, like,
oh, this is disclosure.
It's a process that unfolds, more and more people
just leveling up their priors on more
of these different hypotheses.
And eventually you get to the point where,
oh, there's a billionaire here, there's a billionaire here,
there's a billionaire here, there's a bunch of scientists,
there's a bunch of academics, there's a bunch of policy people.
And they all now collectively look at each other
in this kind of this, you know,
preference falsification cascade and they go,
oh, this is a serious thing, it's real,
it needs to be seriously addressed at scale in a novel way
like our existing institutions can't really confront.
Like, oh, you got to think like Rand,
they can do some things.
You've got some venture capital people,
You've got academic institutions,
you've got, you know, Gary Nolan at Stanford.
Everyone's trying to take their own pieces
of current institutions and trying to contribute
to some, you know, initiative,
Soul Foundation, et cetera.
I think it's all necessary and admirable,
but it's clearly just these raw individual
heroic initiatives, right?
And clearly the ultimate question is so much larger
than what, you know, individual heroic efforts
are going to be able to accomplish, right?
That's a necessary just first step.
But like, if you're really, you know,
trying to put yourself in this post disclosure,
whatever that is world, you know,
it's going to catalyze a lot of change
and a potential lot of, you know, disruption
to existing institutions.
And I think it's important that you have the germs
of new institutions that can kind of, you know,
act as ballast, right?
To kind of absorb that.
And I think, you know, I'm not shilling Bicoid here,
but it's like, Bicoid is interesting
because it has these features of it's a global,
non-state, you know, socio-technical system
that has its own endogenous network, endogenous asset
and, you know, third party free sort of, you know, network
with a lot of people with a lot of capital embedded in it.
So it's like a substrate that you could potentially
use to catalyze, you know,
nucleate different institutions, right?
That are somewhat orthogonal
to the existing institutional structures, right?
They have relationships too, right?
They're not like completely on an island,
but it's a degree of freedom that didn't exist before.
And there might be new possibilities
between mixing and matching old and new together
that could, you know, provide a basis
to do something different
that these institutions just hard, right?
Like the classic Francis Fukuyama curve,
you can read his book,
Political Order, Political Decay,
brilliant diagnosis of kind of human history
and the sorts of different social institutions,
governance systems we've created.
And they historically all follow this similar pattern, right?
Where there's, you know, founding, you know,
partners of the state or even religious organizations
and they're imbued with energy.
They're successful because they solved some aspect
of a novel problem in the environment
that the existing institutions couldn't, right?
So they now have the alpha, right?
They're now creating something new
and they've figured out, you know,
a new niche to expand and explore
and they can build something, right?
A new institution.
And it gets momentum, it gets energy.
They're creating something.
They have a sense of purpose and vision
and sort of founding,
it's like the founding fathers of America, et cetera.
Like those are idolized because there was, you know,
that's like the, you know,
they were creating this novel institution called America.
And then there's some, you know,
process by which those institutions
start to increasingly formalize.
At the beginning, they're very personalized, right?
Say it's Satoshi, right?
Everyone knows like that's a person.
Hal Finney, that's a person, right?
You know, the founding fathers, those are people.
Like their individual decisions
made a huge amount of difference.
Like the Federalist Papers and Declaration of Independence
and these initial amendments to the constitution.
These were like, again, like going back
to the Big Bay analogy,
like there was a lot of degrees of freedom
and those initial founders were like the first,
they had a lot of first mover advantage
to kind of condense that space down
and then create a structure
that could create a possibility space
for lots of other things to evolve.
But in a political kind of evolution,
like in Fukuyama's terms,
you know, that starts to get settled
and then the next generations kind of refine,
optimize, formalize, depersonalize as institutions, right?
Now it's like a bureaucracy with, you know,
titles and roles that get handed down
on a result ideally of merit.
It's not just like the brother or cousin or son
that takes on that role.
And that's a formal modern institutional structure
and that usually works for some time
until like any institutional structure,
like software code, you know, you start from scratch
and it usually does what it's supposed to do.
Over time, you have to, you know, edit, add additional,
you know, modules or make, you know,
a new program comes in and slap something different on
and it starts to develop, you know,
what's called Bohm's law, which is like rot software.
Software tends to rot like on like a mathematical curve.
And I think the same thing with the human institutions
which are systems of norms and rules,
basically embedded into a certain institutional framework.
And so you get to this point where the rules
basically start to become overburdened
and they are increasingly rigid
and they can't adapt to what ultimately, you know,
world is chaos, world is change.
And so human institutions that go through this pattern
eventually start to lag reality, right?
And then there's inefficiencies,
there's costs that start to accrue over time.
And you get to this critical point in any institution
where the systems of rules become too rigid
and they can't adapt to reality.
And the lag, the gap between essentially their design
and the need for them to perform
given the external environment becomes too great
and they're very brittle.
And then you get a shock.
You get a war, you get a famine,
you get a cyber attack now, like who knows?
Something happens and it breaks the institution.
It's like a nonlinear change.
And then everyone realizes,
oh, this is not gonna work anymore, right?
And then, you know, everyone along the line is sort of,
okay, kick the can, kick the can, kick the can.
It's worked well this far.
You know, that curve will just keep going.
I don't wanna have to make the hard choices on my watch,
right?
Like just make it someone else's problem,
you know, in the next election, et cetera.
And that works, you know, up until it doesn't, right?
And then the institutions really break
and then there's a crisis.
And then you have to make a call.
You either, eventually just like,
it's like post-Soviet Russia where it's just,
the institutions are completely demoralized
and just taken apart and, you know, privatized
and the mafia's takeover.
And you really degrade society back
to a very like pre-state state, right?
It's warlordism, essentially, fascinalism.
Or you recognize that crisis coming
and you realize you need to kind of like bounce, right?
You need to create new institutions, right?
That can sort of take that crisis energy and direct it,
you know, formalize it and then create new founding,
you know, teams to sort of, okay,
now we can build something out of this crisis, right?
And so if you think about, you know,
the disclosures being this kind of recognition
that the legacy program is rotten, basically,
in more ways than one, maybe bureaucratically,
institutionally, maybe also morally rotten.
And it may be in the process of breaking, basically, right?
Everyone's defecting out of it, right?
That's what seems to be happening.
That's also what you see happening
when other institutions break, right?
People look around, they go, oh, well, like,
this isn't gonna, my future isn't here anymore.
Like, I gotta get out.
Like, now it's the first,
whoever was out first basically wins, right?
It's how, you know, police organizations
take down mafias, right?
You sort of chip away at it until everyone realizes,
oh, wait, like, my boss is gonna turn on me.
So I better be the first one to rat or whatever.
So you get this nonlinear cascade collapse.
And if that's what's happening here, okay,
it's gonna be good from one perspective,
like the rotten institution is failing,
but that can go really wrong if you don't have, you know,
in mind new institutions that you wanna, you know,
start to nucleate that can sort of take that energy
in a much more positive direction.
So maybe that's, you know,
that's sort of the motivating conceptual framework
to think about how do you do that?
How do you build institutions to,
that can take into account the whole pluralistic
diversity of perspectives on what's really happening here.
It's not like a new religion that's gonna,
because that could be the failure mode, right?
You get factionalism, you get people that just in the chaos,
you know, pick on one thing
and create a new religious institution, right?
That's what we'd like to do.
We need certainty of belief.
But that's how you create cults,
that's how you create, you know, internal division,
you essentially state decay or collapse even.
And so how do you, you know, avoid that, right?
Ideally, you wanna maintain what we currently have built
in terms of modern, pluralistic, you know,
scientifically grounded, you know, social organizations
that now have to sort of adapt and reconfigure to address,
you know, maybe a new possibility space
for technology and humanity itself.
And that's a non-trivial thing to do,
but I don't know, I think it's like an important project.
And you look around, like, who's got the money to fund that?
That would be like crazy enough to try, right?
I actually think it'd probably be like a bunch of Bitcoiners
that would be willing to do that, right?
They'd be like, we kind of did that, like with Bitcoin,
like this is the next bit, right?
We're gonna do that next.
So that might be a bit of a LARP right now,
but I don't know, it's non-trivial to me
that in the next few years,
you could see something like that could get created,
I think it'd be kind of cool.
Well, I'm curious to see where things go from here, Matt,
and I feel like you're on the forefront of so much of it,
and yeah, it's an exciting, wild time.
I have a feeling 2025 is just gonna be
one of the weirdest years we've had, maybe in a millennium.
I mean, I think it's a safe prediction at any given year
to say this will be the weirdest year.
I think that just, we're just on that curve.
Yeah. And just, you know.
It's getting weirder and weirder.
Yeah, and so like,
it's more about the derivative of weirdness.
Is that gonna accelerate?
I think it might be a step-wise leap, but I don't know.
Yeah, well, that's one little personal commentary is like,
this is the interesting thing is,
you know, going wrapping all this together,
like the Bitcoin, the AI, the alien, these things are,
if you imagine there's kind of this,
there's this median distribution of opinion,
what's considered kind of inside the orbiting window,
and it's a distribution,
and there's some ineffable sort of zone outside,
where if you're outside that zone,
you're either a conspiracy theorist, you're a fringe,
kook, you're, you know, just, you're out there, right?
And then there are things that are like legitimate,
but like kind of, you know,
still considered somewhat impolite,
and that's like almost like Hedena syndrome
sorts of stuff, right?
It's like just inside the over the window, but disputed,
but people say it's a kooky thing, but lots of people,
yeah, but now it's increasingly a serious thing.
And what's fascinating is the individuals, right?
And maybe myself, right?
I've sort of gravitated to sort of stay on that,
whatever that liminal zone is,
I think, I don't know, psychologically,
but I'm just attracted to that part,
like things that are coming in
off of that side of the distribution.
But you almost think of it as like a wave,
because I think that whole distribution
of itself is moving, right?
And so ironically, if I like picked a certain point
on that curve and just stayed there,
like what my like fringe opinions on Bitcoin
and UAPs four or five years ago
are now like increasingly like normie, right?
And so it's like, if I don't like constantly try
to look further out, right?
It's like, oh, the reality of non-human intelligence
was like fully out there.
Now it's like coming in.
And now you've got this new, now you've got psionics.
It's like, oof, well, okay,
that's the new thing out there.
But that's probably also coming in.
So like this whole curve I'm looking at,
I'm like, and I'm just,
I didn't know what the shape of that curve is.
All I know is like where I am sort of on it,
through like, I get sort of subtle feedback on Twitter
and professional and semi-professional networks
of like, where am I on this curve?
It's like a clue to how fast the median shape is moving.
And it seems like that whole shape is moving
this direction, right?
Which is, if you take any stats class,
like if you move the mean of a distribution,
like the tails explode, right?
There's like an asymmetric like effect.
Like if you cut off the left side, right?
The right side explodes, right?
And so there's just like a statistical analogy here,
which is even if it's like a subtle movement
in the mean perception of these things,
like the effect on the margin,
especially what that threshold is,
is changing much faster.
Yep.
I think that's what you see now.
That's what your podcast think represents.
Yeah.
I think that's like,
that's the alpha of the Josie Michaels podcast.
Well, it's funny to watch these like people
who have credentials that well exceed mine,
but they're like, they have to like call me
like on signal or something, you know?
And they have to just be like, you know,
okay, maybe there's something here
send me some papers on it or whatever.
They can't like kind of like fully like own it
because it's like too fringy for them.
And so it's like this,
and then they do some like hedging thing publicly
where they're like, we should look into this,
but there's 99% like nothing there.
And then you just watch them like crumbling,
like over time, like as they realized
everything's just way weirder than they think.
And there is something nice about like
not being in that, not having to play that game,
like not having to like optics or, you know,
care about optics or like posture at all.
If any of these weirder frameworks are real,
you can't have your talented STEM students
just growing up not thinking they exist.
Like that doesn't work.
Again, in the world in which like we're at par
with our adversaries, which you'd have to assume
that we kind of are at least as far as
the basic existence of the frameworks.
But that's back to my point about like
the median moves a little bit
and like the tails move a lot.
Like that's an example of the tail moving a lot.
And the thing is, you've done venture capital,
you've done investing, you know,
if you're doing intellectual investing in this sense,
if you're only paying attention to the mean,
you're missing the movement on the tail.
And that is where the dramatic change is happening.
You have to be looking there and you have to say,
okay, well, that is a pretty dramatic shift
that portends an even more dramatic evolution
the next year or two.
Yeah, and it's like that, you know, like Timur Karand,
you know, that is this like Duke professor
who talks about like preference falsification.
And it's always this like very quick cascade.
So it's not preference falsification,
but it's like, you know, the mean shifting will be,
you know, very fast.
Like it'll happen at the tail and then it'll like bulge out
and then it'll just like, it'll accelerate much quicker,
like sort of exponentially quickly.
And then all of a sudden the mean will be like
in an entirely different place like after that.
That goes back to the whole like,
you need to have, that can be a disruptive process, right?
Cause like a lot of the social institutions we have
are framed around like the mean, right?
It's like everyone believes, you know,
this is the basic architecture.
This is the assumptions around next week, next month,
next year, 20 years, my retirement, my kids,
et cetera, et cetera.
Like I just did a state planning this morning, right?
It's like very practical trusts,
how to make sure my kids get what I get, you know?
It's like, okay, I have to plan 20, 30 years.
And that's like, okay,
a certain psychological orientation to the future.
But then you've got this other, these other developments here
and even I who pay very close attention to it,
it's very hard to try to stitch those together.
Oh, it's extremely hard.
It's like, how do I, you know, I need,
I know I need to do this.
This is like what I need to do, right?
But like, I don't really know
what 20, 30 years is gonna look like.
Put it all in big time.
That's an insane, like it's just so much,
it's like a event horizon.
Do you think- Which I can't really see.
Do you think like, you know,
I think FDR bought like a huge percentage
of like the gold supply and like put it in Fort Knox
and then post Bretton Woods,
this is a total oversimplification,
but you could say that a lot of American foreign policy
was just like governed by the need to
have somewhat control or like friendly, you know, eyes
on like some percentage of like
the world's crude oil or something.
Yeah.
Do you think that Bitcoin becomes that now,
especially if you were to get these sort of like
breakthroughs in energy,
like say you get something weird on the UAP side,
you get some break, you can say you get,
you know, over unity, you know,
or you get free energy or something,
and you know, fusion works, you know, at scale.
Then would Bitcoin become this like all of a sudden,
you get this like crazy game theory dynamic over Bitcoin
where like that becomes the new oil,
which was the new gold or something.
Well, yeah, and I think there's a few things.
One is, I don't think Bitcoin is UAP proof,
but it might be UAP resistant in that sense.
I don't think I'm sure you can say anything
is UAP proof.
I'd say like disclosure proof,
maybe is a better way of saying it.
And like I think I had like a semi-tongue-in-cheek tweet
like four or five years ago that's like,
what's your UAP hedge?
Hashtag Bitcoin.
It was a response to this like FT Alpha article
that was talking about like financial stability risks
associated with UAPs disclosure, right?
Uncertainty, technological paradigms being changed,
granted assets, sociological, religious,
institutional disruptions, et cetera.
Whole kit and caboodle.
Which is interesting, right?
From an investor's perspective,
which is you wanna hold your money for the longterm.
Most people have a balanced weighted assets
of like sovereign debt, right?
Mostly treasury bonds.
Maybe some people have some gold, right?
It's the old standby in case things get totally crazy.
You've got diversified equity exposure
to make sure there's any technology changes, right?
New paradigms, whether it's big tech,
you've got energy utility plays,
and then maybe you have your flyer 2.5,
two to 5% Bitcoin kind of like thing.
That's probably the new investment sort of,
you know, sort of distribution.
If you, you know, no one can predict
what will really come out in terms of technology
or the diffusion or the rate of change of these paradigms.
But even if you just get one or two big changes, right?
Say you do get, not free energy,
because I don't think that's physically possible
in the universe.
Let's just think of it as free energy.
But you get extremely high energy return
on energy invested sorts of, you know, systems.
Maybe you can draw energy out of the vacuum,
but there's no such thing as free energy.
You actually have to do some amount of work,
but it's gonna be like a high payoff
relative to your, you know,
whatever engineering devices you have to put together.
And we're not even sure if that's physically possible
because you can do Casimir to just get, you know,
to do this, but that's a reversible process.
You have to like, you can't develop an engine
based off of that, at least not to my knowledge.
But then say you do get something like anti-gravity
or some novel propulsion system
that allows you to pull forward, say,
the feasibility of asteroid mining at scale
by 10 or 20 years.
Like that's now on the horizon
for just conventional propulsion.
And we know that if you can do asteroid mining,
you can probably get like, you know,
massive amounts of these right now,
very scarce resources don't become scarce anymore.
And, or if you get a ore extraction and refining technology,
some sort of laser thing that can just, you know,
blast out of the ore and isolate all the gold.
Well, maybe you go from a process that right now
generates 2% of new gold in a year
and keeps gold as a old standby scarce reserve asset.
If now you have new technology allows you to create
five or 10 or 20% new gold every year,
well, then gold's viability as a reserve asset
that's scarce enough goes away, right?
So new technology can finally change
the sort of monetary predicate of our global system.
And sovereign debt is sort of what serves
as the global reserve asset right now.
And if you read Ray Dalio's new book,
we're kind of in the sort of end game
of that kind of sovereign debt crisis
where we're now paying more on interest
than we do on our defense.
And we're heading to the point
where you get this reflexivity where now
the Fed cuts rates on the short end
and the long end goes up by an equivalent
of maybe even more.
It's a classic symptom of sort of late stage debt cycles.
And, you know, it's very hard to get out of those
without essentially monetizing the debt,
financial oppression, capital controls,
it's usually what you see, right?
You have to, you know, inflate the debt away
or you risk cascading defaults and great depression.
So you've got to effectively cap rates,
run the economy hot, try to devalue.
But the more debt you have,
the more of a pain you have to impose,
you've got to isolate sources of capital
and impose losses on them.
And so they're gonna be fleeing to,
and that's usually, you know, essentially
that's the bond market that has to get effectively,
you know, taken out back in shop, right?
Like, and usually the governments don't forecast that,
they don't give people clues, it just happens.
That's how you make sure the sheep are all in the pen
and then you call the herd.
So you're gonna have to anesthetize
the global bond market,
the global sovereign bond market in particular.
It's not just the US,
it's basically the whole world at this point.
And so there's gonna be this movement to,
you know, harder assets that are harder to do that to,
right, so gold and Bitcoin,
that's kind of become almost consensus now
among major institutional investors, Ray Dalio, et cetera.
You know, I think right now the basic ratio
is like a five or 10 to one gold to Bitcoin allocation
in terms of the level of trust,
you know, in the institutional levels
between gold and Bitcoin.
But that seems to be the posture, right?
In fact, there was a story in the FT
that the London gold vaults are basically being emptied
because a bunch of, you know,
it's all moved to New York essentially
because they're worried about tariffs
but I think there's other things going on there too.
So people are repositioning at scale.
In fact, one quick anecdote on that,
the Swiss army sort of signals intelligence guy
gave a quote to a pretty niche satellite magazine
several months ago about how they were noticing
that certain synthetic aperture radar satellites
that were flown by the US and China
were intensively monitoring their territory.
It's like, what do you use synthetic aperture satellites
to do, they're especially X and C.
Super high resolution.
Super high resolution since you train mapping
so you can detect, you know, sub-millimeter deformations
in say the shape of a mountainside,
the settling of the building or trucks moving in and out.
So if you are removing large amounts of gold,
say out of Swiss vaults
and moving that around the world,
that would be a thing of acute intelligence collection
interest to both US and China.
Where's that gold going?
You know, gold's hard to track otherwise, right?
There's no blockchain for gold.
And a lot, if you look at just the balance
of disclosed transfers has been a huge amount
of imports to Saudi Arabia from Swiss
in terms of the gold account.
So anyways, that's a bit of a sidebar on the monetary side.
But this is-
Wait, wait, wait, we gotta close that loop.
Yes.
Well, no, so this is, I think-
Are they trying to sell gold and buy Bitcoin?
Well, that's a separate question.
I have heard that in the Emirates, for example,
explorations of, you know, trying to,
there's a lot of, say there's a ton of gold
and other scarce assets, you know, art and whatever
that has just been tucked away in Swiss vaults.
Swiss banking secrecy laws have been changing,
especially after the Russian invasion.
And essentially, you know, large pools
of what you call shadow wealth
is no longer feeling safe in Switzerland.
So they're trying to go back home, right?
In Saudi Arabia, in the Emirates or other wealth countries
or in Asia and Singapore, Hong Kong, et cetera.
And so there's been a reconfiguration of where, say,
the hidden wealth of the world wants to go.
And they're realizing now that actually,
if you just want to hold gold in a Swiss vault
for a hundred years, it's been great, right?
But at the moment, you realize it could be seized
or sanctioned as a new risk premium attached to it.
And then you want to move it.
Well, it's super expensive to move, right?
It's extremely expensive.
And then actually you'd be like,
oh, well, if I could just sell the gold by Bitcoin,
I can then teleport the Bitcoin
and maybe buy back gold, essentially,
there with a local importer.
And maybe that fee, actually,
that transaction cost is cheaper
than actually physically transporting the gold.
But then if you're doing that,
you might be convinced to just keep five or 10% of that
in Bitcoin along the way, right?
Oh, maybe I don't sell it all back into gold, right?
That's an extra convert, that's an extra transaction fee.
Maybe I'll keep some of it in Bitcoin, right?
So I think that is happening now.
There's institutions, I think,
being set up in the Middle East
to facilitate that type of trade.
Do you think you see game theory play out
on the global scale with Bitcoin?
So you have smaller players like Bukele of El Salvador,
who I think would buy Bitcoin tomorrow,
and you hear rumors about stuff in Saudi Arabia as well.
But I think they're kind of waiting for the US
to kind of take the lead on some of these things.
So if we create a strategic Federal Reserve
or a strategic Bitcoin Reserve,
does that sort of tee off this,
every other country needs to kind of get in line
and get coordinated on their Bitcoin policy
and start to buy it?
Yes, I think that is happening,
but in a very nascent and very,
everyone's looking around sort of stage.
Nobody's bolted out to be at first at the door stage,
but everyone is definitely looking around.
I was in Abu Dhabi, I don't know,
two months ago for a Bitcoin conference there,
and it was more like a geopolitical summit
than an industry conference, right?
There were delegations sent there from multiple nations,
like GCC nations,
and their explicit mission from their national leadership,
reporting directly back to the king,
the minister of finance, the central bank head,
was what does this new administration
really think about Bitcoin?
How serious are they about shifting
in a pro-Bitcoin direction?
And not just on the strategic Bitcoin Reserve idea,
but just in general doing this 180
that we're sort of seeing in motion.
And then what will that mean?
Again, these governments, they're not traders.
They're not trying to like time the trade.
This is a strategic orientation
they're trying to anticipate.
Well, how serious do you think the American government is now,
the new incoming administration when it comes to Bitcoin?
They're very serious.
I mean, Trump has said explicitly,
and he's, you know, about US being crypto capital of the world.
He's very serious about this pro-Bitcoin policy.
We'll see what that manifests practically
in terms of, say, executive orders.
We have this working group
this issue of a stockpile of digital assets,
most likely just Bitcoin, and also stable coins, right?
So though I think strategically there's a synergy
between stable coins, essentially dollar pegged
crypto euro dollars that trade offshore
on open blockchains mostly,
and are essentially like IOUs in crypto world
denominated in dollars, right?
So they function just as like a dollar,
but you know, on an open blockchain.
And these will be mostly Ethereum based, you think?
So yeah, there's some, yeah.
Well, Ethereum, a Tron is a very popular,
but there's a, now that was like very nascent.
I think now there's a lot of focus on the regulatory side
to pass laws that would allow say banks to issue stable coins
and get in on the game.
And that would, you know, create this regulatory perimeter
to essentially expand the dollar network.
Stable coins also have this feature
where if they're properly regulated as they would be,
you know, forced to under this law
would be fully reserved, right?
With high quality liquid assets,
specifically treasury securities, most likely short term.
But if they're banks, they could actually term that out.
So you'd have new buyers of, you know,
basically it's a new balance sheet capacity
to absorb new government debt.
So you expand stable coins around the world,
which are right now about 200 trillion,
sorry, 200 billion, right?
They're about 2.5% of the T-bill market.
I think it's very plausible if they pass this legislation
within a few years, you could see that tax.
And then just stable coins themselves
are basically giving the US government
25% of their role on the short end.
What do you mean by that?
Meaning about 25% of their annual financing capacity,
well, like requirements for short-term bill issuance
would be absorbed by the stable coin issuers
that have to reserve the expansion
of the stable coin sort of issuance.
You know, it's an IOU,
they have to have an asset to back that up, right?
Viability asset matching.
And so you expand the dollar network,
again, you're sort of penetrating parts of the global South
that don't have access to correspondent banks
where remittances and, you know, Western Union
are very expensive.
And so this would just be like an accelerant
for I think global development,
as well as the expansion of the dollar network
helps the US government on the margin finance itself.
So kind of win, win, win.
And Bitcoin to first order is what drives the expansion
of the global sort of stable coin market.
It's what you use to trade in and out of Bitcoin.
And so if the unit price of Bitcoin is, you know,
much higher, you need much more stable coins
to just facilitate that trade,
let alone the additional activities in the crypto ecosystem,
some of which are more speculative than others.
And so, yeah, you can see the synergistic flywheel
developed between Bitcoin and stable coins
that starts to take on a geopolitical dimension.
And then Bitcoin is, you know,
seen right now essentially as a speculative reserve asset
that's complimentary to gold,
but because it's much more volatile, right?
It's prudently, you know, risk weighted, right?
As a much smaller proportion of your overall portfolio
in say a sovereign wealth, you know, portfolio.
But it is now like a non-zero thing, right?
And so as its total value likely increases,
its volatility likely decreases,
therefore its risk weighted, you know,
allocation should rationally go up.
So it's just like sort of positive feedback loop.
Yeah, and so actually the Bitcoin Policy Institute,
the organization I'm proud to now help lead,
actually has a fellow named Matthew Ferranti,
who's a economist, trained PhD at Harvard under Ken Rogoff,
who's an economist for the US intelligence community.
And he's written a white paper for us,
which is the case for Bitcoin
as a central bank reserve asset.
So I would encourage folks to read.
Is Satoshi either rolling in his grave
or extremely pissed off at that prospect?
This is the thing, is like, you know,
eventually Bitcoin is now,
is gonna play the geopolitical in the sovereign level.
And it does open up these larger questions.
Okay, Bitcoin is non-state money,
but when states start to hold it, what happens to Bitcoin?
Yeah, totally.
And then also you get this wealth transfer,
so that's like this really interesting thing.
But it is sort of anathema to like the initial, you know,
spirit maybe.
I mean, you can say that you read the early forums
and how Finney was calling for a Bitcoin price of 10 million
and thought that states would buy it
and it would just be like a global money, right?
And the question is, the argument was more,
is there a central issuer that can control the supply
or censor transactions, right?
The government owning Bitcoin
does not change the supply of Bitcoin,
it doesn't restrict anybody's ability to transact.
They're just a participant in the network
like anybody else, and they're subject to,
it's rule set as much as everybody else's, right?
And so this is the thing, you gotta,
there are more second order effects though
that are important to assess.
And as BPI will think,
we'll be taking a very close look at these,
which is more on the nuance associated
with the development ecosystem,
which is this rough consensus model,
you've got Bitcoin developers,
you've got kind of this community of folks
that are very invested in Bitcoin technical development.
And there's always a lot of, you know, conversations of,
you know, it's an open source money project, right?
There's just code, right?
And so it's like what sorts of BIPs,
Bitcoin improvement proposals are gonna be considered.
And, you know, that conversation was happening
at some levels, and then there's big companies
that get involved, and that potentially changes
some of the inherent dynamics
associated with that consensus model.
Now you've got, say, Bitcoin miners are a big constituency.
There are certain things that they would rather see
versus other things.
Whereas the individual user or developer or custodian,
like they all have their own interests in Bitcoin, right?
And those are gonna be reflected
in the kind of the dynamic political economy of Bitcoin.
And now states, right, as they buy Bitcoin,
they're gonna have a view, right?
And there's no monopoly power,
but now there's some multi-level bargaining
about, you know, the future
of this open source money project, right?
And the game theory of Bitcoin has always been,
the incentives always align in a positive direction
that works to Bitcoin's benefit, right?
Like the miners and the users and the algorithm
are essentially, they structure the game theory
of the incentives around this protocol
that makes it a stable system, right?
And so, again, I have no crystal ball,
but that's what you gotta, you know,
that's why it's not already 10 million, right?
Is because there's some inherent uncertainty and risk.
If everyone knew that it was gonna become
a global reserve asset seamlessly from here to 2040,
then that would be priced in, right?
It's clearly the market has some uncertainty about that,
right?
And we're gonna see on a path dependent basis,
like how it actually evolves.
Well, it seems like a pretty constructive setup,
both for Bitcoin and for UAP.
And we'll see where things go from here.
And I really appreciate your time, Matt.
It's always a pleasure and an honor and a lot of fun.
Yeah, of course.
All right.