It's not like trying to summon a spirit.
You're summoning essentially technology
that has consciousness to it.
Well, that platform came into that craft itself.
So this thing was either anti-gravitic itself
and how it basically merged in together.
Could this just be like an occult thing
that's been going on for hundreds of years?
I mean, how do you think they learned?
They were actually two of the guys
were actually talking about either,
hey, should we smoke these guys right now?
You know, that's what they kept saying.
Do you think realistically pulling these technologies
from these black programs
and putting them into the hands of people
who don't know what the fuck they're doing is a smart move?
James Allen, the documentarian of Mark McCandalish
and the Flexliner story.
He was diagnosed and dead
of an aggressive form of cancer in about three weeks.
Yeah, the UFO stuff's cool because they fly.
The medical shit, the stuff that we could also do
with this technology is gonna be far more advanced.
The
different
parts of the brain
have different activities.
I'm here with Michael Herrera
and I couldn't be more excited to talk to you.
This has been a long time coming.
You were a former Marine who experienced something
just really fascinating in 2009 in Indonesia in the jungle.
And it involves craft that prosaically is not understood
as far as how it works.
And also seemingly special forces,
we don't know if it was special forces,
you don't describe them definitely as special forces,
but a team with prowess and wherewithal
as far as the machinery they're using
and how smooth they're operating,
that also seems like at another level
and they're kind of apprehending you when you see this craft.
And so I'm very excited to talk to you.
I know it took a lot of courage for you to speak out.
And then we have Sammy UAP Gerb as well here,
who's a legend, has an amazing channel,
goes as deep as anybody when it comes
to actual legacy operations from like a core detail way,
just the facts.
And so very excited to have you, man.
You guys have done a great show together too.
And if you guys want like very low level details
as to what went down, drawings, pictures, illustrations,
extremely detailed accounts, go to your channel
because you have some great stuff with Michael.
He's very thorough, which is something that's very rare.
Especially in this space, it's extremely rare.
Correct, and that's kind of the thing
why it made easier to talk to you
because you were actually able to connect the dots
and see and compare notes basically
to what you've experienced with talking to other people.
I mean, your story had been floating around for a while
and people were pretty dismissive of it
until our mutual friend, Joey is not my name,
started to reach out to you and speak to you.
And he got me in contact with you
and you were able to provide quite a bit
of interesting information, including direct evidence
from yourself and Joey that you met up with a,
who you referred to at the time as an insider,
who now turned out to be Jake Barber.
Correct, and that was the thing
that I was kind of weirded out about.
So in 2023, when I testified with the National Press Club,
obviously I got in touch with a Greer, actually in 2018.
So I went to an event that he had in Boulder, Colorado,
and listened to his lecture, things like that.
I was saying 2017 because the ex I was with at the time,
I met her in 2017, but then I was like, okay.
And then I started thinking,
because there's been some people on Twitter
that was 2018 because one of the volunteers was there.
So I was like, okay, so it is really 2018.
And I had listened to his lecture,
and then I ended up going up to,
he was doing a book signing.
So I went and got a book
because that was the only way to get in front of him.
At the time when he was doing book signings,
he doesn't do that anymore
because people can get very crazy.
I've seen it firsthand.
It's a little hysterical, but this subject
brings a very interesting crowd with it,
which is something I don't relate to whatsoever.
But I mean, to who of their own?
So I had told him, I'm a former Marine.
I had witnessed something such as like
a drug running operation using this kind of technology.
Do you know anything about that?
So I was trying to get his attention.
He was kind of like, yeah, I've heard a lot.
But then when I said that, he told everybody to shut up.
And he stood up and handed me his card,
and he was like, don't tell anybody this information.
Don't relate to anybody.
Just keep it between us.
Contact me when you're ready.
And then when he did the first episode of Sean Ryan,
is when basically he was talking about
the whistleblower protections
and going through the system
to basically go through that route.
So I was like, you know what?
That might be time to actually pull a trigger on this
and see what can come of it.
This is the Gallagher Amendment
around whistleblower protection.
NDA, National Defense Authorization Act.
Yeah, it's part of the National Defense Authorization Act.
And that was coming into 2023, I think,
is when they passed that.
And there was some rendition
of which we were trying to do 2024
with the whole amnesty period for six months.
And then obviously,
eminent domain with some of these technologies
and assets that these black sides have.
So when I approached,
I got in touch with Greer again,
sent him an email, said,
I don't know if you remember me.
And he goes, I know exactly.
And I remember exactly who you are, which was weird.
So he gave me his phone number.
So I called him.
We basically talked for about an hour,
just kind of went through what I've already discussed
publicly, which was essentially
that we were a part of 31st Marine Expeditionary Unit
that was tasked out to basically respond
to a humanitarian assistance operation
out in the Philippines, which was Operation Katsana.
And then what ended up happening was we were the only ship,
which was the USS Denver that got routed out
to the western part of Sumatra in Indonesia.
And which was a little weird,
but you know, of course,
I've never been on a mission before that point.
So that was kind of the first one for me.
Why were you guys rerouted?
It was the only ship,
but that was the orders we were given.
I don't know specifically why.
There was speculation.
And then when we actually got briefed at the,
in the ward room,
that there were some Obama's family members that were there.
So they had some SEAL team that was gonna be there
to retrieve those people if need be.
That's interesting.
Because Obama lived there from age six to 10,
I believe. I believe so.
With his mom or something. Yeah.
And so there were some relatives
and they were gonna get them out
because what happens in that part of the world
is when there's a natural disaster happens,
usually these terrorist organizations
or these insurgent groups
will typically try to take over that area
and inflict harm, chaos, ransom,
I mean, whatever they do.
And so they were afraid of that.
So that's why they sent a reactionary force
to basically go coordinate the area off
and then go deal with that,
which we didn't do too much of that.
All we basically did was try to provide security for an LZ
so that way they can keep,
you know, we can keep if there were people there,
which this particular LZ didn't have anybody there,
which was weird.
For the audience, what's an LZ?
Landing zone.
It's more like a hasty LZ.
So hasty LZ means it's a hasty landing zone.
So it's something that wasn't like prepared ahead of time.
Like we're gonna plot here and this is where we're gonna go.
It's just like, here's the clearing.
This is where they're gonna land.
At least it's how it felt.
Pilots can probably attest to something different.
I don't know.
And then basically that's when we disembarked the helicopter
and for us, it's like, okay,
you're gonna have the tactical advantage,
take the high ground.
So that's what we decided to do.
And I wasn't the one who was in charge of all this,
so it was weird to not have the comms
because everybody's talking about that.
I was not the one who set up.
Maybe the squad leader,
whoever was in charge of that point had something.
So you guys had no comms, no signals.
To my knowledge, no.
I don't remember anybody having that.
We could have had a little radio or something
that the sergeant that was there at the time said.
You're sent into the jungle alone basically
with your unit.
Correct.
So it's like a fire team plus two, so six guys.
And so we ended up seeing this craft,
which.
That's amazing.
Who made this?
So I was actually looking for other accounts
of octagonal craft that people may have seen.
So I did a quick Google search,
came across this on Etsy.
And so some, I can't remember the gentleman's name,
but I ended up getting in touch with him
and told him who I was.
So he sent me two of these.
One, I signed for him and sent it back to him
so he can have that.
And two, because he hooked me up with two models.
But did he make that to spec
or he had already built that?
No, he made this to spec.
So this was after the fact of what I came forward with.
But this essentially is what we saw.
It almost looks like a fractal.
You have kind of an accentuated version
of the eight-gon or octagon shape on top
that's like a pyramid.
And then you have a less concave version in the middle
and then like an even less, more kind of spread out version.
And this is off from memory because what people,
the SOS was like a very matte black,
but then it was also transitioning
like a light matte gray.
And I don't know if it was we were going down this hill
and we could still kind of see it
and maybe sun was hitting it to an extent or I don't know,
but it was basically like it was changing colors.
But this panel right here, whatever these are,
were basically the very vantablack,
which was the blackest I've ever seen anything.
It was like light could get absorbed into this.
Almost like a black hole or something.
Kind of, that's the only way I can describe it.
Or vantablack is this car, this BMW car.
The paint that they did that it basically absorbs light.
It's very crazy stuff.
So that's what that reminded me of.
But I estimated that this thing was probably about 300 feet.
And when we ended up getting into this clearing
is basically when we were intercepted by this force.
So Aero put out a report that was completely false
because I didn't say it was US special operations.
That never came out of my mouth.
What I hypothesized is that they were at some point
because the tactics they used,
they already had the drop on us
by the time we even noticed them.
So yeah, you got, you know, armchair generals out there
who said, oh yeah, I wouldn't have done that.
I would have fired on them.
It's like, yeah, good luck with that,
but get pulled over by a cop and have a weapon
and see how fast you can reach him
while he's already got his drawn on him.
We'll see how well that works for you.
You know, FAFO.
You and your fellow Marines,
you did not have rounds chambered.
No, we did not.
When you were encountered in like a pincer formation.
We were in condition three.
So all we had was a magazine insert.
So all you have to do is hit the charging handle
to chamber around.
But if we're sitting there patrolling,
this is the funny thing is there's a lot of optics
that are played and stuff like this, right?
So it's not like you're wanting to use this now.
Granted, Indonesia is the second largest terrorist capital
in the world, but it doesn't necessarily mean
that you're gonna encounter any kind of bad guys,
which we really didn't encounter that.
And for these operators who we encountered,
who's to say that they're really bad?
Because the difference is if we were to do
an operation ourselves, and we had people,
we had no idea that we're armed coming up to us,
I'm pretty sure we'd react in the same way,
especially if there's something that's going on
that we either need to protect people,
protect assets or something going on.
We're not gonna have the same kind of welcoming,
like, yeah, go ahead and take a look, guys, you know?
Before we speculate on what was going on there,
just the core details, how long did you get a clean shot,
like a look at that craft?
Several times, because while we're being held up
at gunpoint, which these guys are at standoff distance,
it's not like they're sitting there pointing a muzzle
right at your face like this close,
because, you know, that's only Hollywood that does that,
and these guys are smart enough,
just like in the military,
you're gonna be at a standoff distance,
so nobody can get the advantage of you
trying to disarm you, whatever it might be.
So, but frequently dealing with these guys
and dealing with that craft, it's just going back and forth.
So, like, how long is this process
where you have a clean look at the craft?
Is it like, it's minutes, it's not?
It's minutes.
Okay, wow.
It's nothing like substantially long.
It's just enough because, like I said,
these trucks were coming up,
which were either Tundras or F-350s,
more likely they're probably Tundras,
but the only thing I could make out
was that it was some sort of heavy duty truck
that was built on that, some sort of chassis,
that was big enough to pull these containers.
And how close are you to the craft
while you're being apprehended?
Maybe 150, 300 meters, if that,
because the way, like, this clearing was pretty big,
but this craft was enormous.
And there was, because even in the rendition,
there's like a platform below the craft.
And do you have any, like, first intuitions
as to what that served as,
the platform versus the craft itself?
Well, that platform came into that craft itself.
It lifted off the ground.
Now, when you're looking at it like this,
I mean, of course, you can see
that there's, like, a metal pole there
to basically hold this up up top,
but there was no metal pole or nothing to support that,
right, so this thing was either anti-gravitic itself
and how it basically merged in together.
So it's something like, it's very,
like, there's Air Force cargo planes
that basically detach the fuselage
so that way they can just roll the plane off,
load up everything, load it, and then just take off.
I'm, I can't even speak today.
I'm hypothesizing that there might be
the same kind of concept, just something very quick.
They just load up, get whatever they want,
and get the hell out of there.
And so these guys apprehend you,
and what sort of equipment do they have?
Do they say anything interesting?
They're obviously talking about they want to smoke us
or what should we do with these guys?
They're making threats.
We can get lost out here.
We can, you know, take you anywhere pretty much.
We can kill you.
Should we shoot these guys?
You know, it's going back and forth.
There was only just two of them talking with us,
but you could tell by their dialects
that they were American.
You can tell by their facial expressions
that they were, you know, they were serious people.
How many are they versus how many are you?
So there are six of us and there are eight of them.
Okay.
And they, like I said, they were split off.
So when they kind of approached us
when we were going down in a tactical column,
there were four and four on each side.
So they basically almost have what they call a nosebleed.
So they basically had sectors of fire like this.
So for them to fire upon us,
it's not going to take as many rounds
because they could just hit us instantaneously.
So these guys knew what the hell they were doing.
And that was interesting, you know,
having thought about at least
what these guys' backgrounds could be,
then Jake comes forward, which is interesting,
especially his background and his people, you know,
so very good guys, by the way.
But these guys in particular,
I mean, they were so fluid and so smooth,
it's like they've done this several times.
It's just protocol.
They just know it so well.
It was just very fluid.
Hey guys, I wanted to tell you
about my new favorite piece of apparel.
These are called the Perfect Jeans.
They're literally the perfect jeans.
I used to wear jeans all the time
and they're kind of rough
and not super stretchy or breathable.
These are extremely comfortable.
They work in casual environments.
They work in work settings.
They come in six different sizes
from 26 inches to 50 inches
and they're all around just amazing.
For a limited time,
our listeners get 15% off your first order
plus free shipping at the perfectjean.nyc.
Again, that's the perfectjean.nyc
or just Google the perfect jean.
Use code Jesse15 for that 15% off.
Again, that's code Jesse15.
That's 15% off for new customers
at the perfectjean.nyc.
After purchase, they'll ask where you heard about them.
Please support our show and tell them that we sent you.
Fuck your khakis, get the perfect jean.
So when they apprehend us,
they basically take our weapons from us
and they're just taking the magazines out.
They're checking to make sure
there's nothing wrapped in there, which there wasn't.
I think they may have said something about that too.
And because there's no way if they would have engaged us
and we have to raise our weapon up and it's not chambered,
well, yeah, you're gonna have to rack around in the chamber
and then flip it off safe on fire
while they already have their safe.
You could hear them flip them off
and then basically just, they could have got us.
You heard the safeties flip off.
Oh yeah. Wow.
And did they have any other equipment?
They had something that was like a biometrics,
it's like a bat system
because that's something that we were kind of
taught a little bit on how to track people,
see biometrics tracking.
And so when insurgents were having this used on them,
it takes fingerprints, it takes pictures
and all that kind of stuff.
They had something very similar to that.
And then they had like a-
Did they take photos or fingerprints?
They were trying to take,
so they took our CAD cards out of our pockets,
which we always have our CAD cards in our left breast pocket.
And so when they took that out,
they were trying to scan them and I don't know if it didn't
work or whatever, they were getting frustrated with it.
And then this is when they took out another device
that looked like a modern day smartphone, very thin.
And then I've had people that were formerly of the CIA
tell me that these are CAVCOM devices that they use.
And that's basically what they were able to translate
and get that information to whoever had it.
Cause they knew who we were after that point
because they had our IDs, had our names,
had our ranks, everything.
So as that's going on, they're searching us down,
which I had before making that trip down the hill,
I had a little Panasonic camera
that I actually took pictures of this thing
with from a top view, at least because there's some parts
of it that were obscured because of vegetation.
And I also had pictures of the helicopter,
like one of them was when we were on the ship
and I had all these photos that I took,
even out of town and all that.
And they didn't find it in my dump pouch, which was good.
Cause then the whole time I'm thinking like,
I got something that can fucking prove this.
It's not just fucking hearsay, right?
And so...
What do you have that could prove it?
The pictures.
You had the pictures and that was in your pouch.
That was in my pouch.
They never searched that pouch.
So I was a saw gunner by trade.
So that's what we always had was, you know,
everybody has a pouch, but typically I just had like
drum mag pouches instead of a regular M16
or M4 magazine pouches, which I had a magazine pouch
right here just in case we had to use magazines
for the saw because it could take both,
belt fed with magazines.
So as they're going through us,
they're basically searching us up and down.
And then they're basically just threatening us again,
just kind of roughing us up a little bit.
And then that's when the trucks started coming because yeah,
I'm paying attention to these guys that are doing this stuff
to us and then all of a sudden I'm paying attention
to these trucks that we start seeing them pull up
and they have these trailers on the back
that have this HVAC system on the top.
So that was the suspicion I had that it was drugs
because some of the heavy equipment industry
that I do deal with, they have containers that do that
for like vegetation or for like food or for equipment
that needs to be chilled, wherever it might be.
So I'm like, okay, I think it's drugs.
So they drive these trucks onto this platform here,
which is you can see like when the trucks are going up
that the trucks were getting smaller,
which was able to kind of gauge the size a little bit.
And then they were loading it on.
I mean, I don't see how they,
I didn't see how they actually took the trailers off.
They drove onto this platform that like seemingly levitates
and it didn't make any noise.
It didn't make any noise.
You said it makes like almost like a base.
Like the whole thing itself did the whole time.
And it's something that's so different
that if somebody was to recreate it accurately,
like Joey kind of did the same thing,
which was very similar.
Correct.
And it was something like that
because it wasn't a traditional propulsion system
by any means, it's not like a rotor inside something.
And so you got photos of the craft.
Yes, I did.
I took video and photos.
When we were on top of that hill
is when I took photos of this thing
and it was obscured by some vegetation.
And that's what caught our eye
because it was something that was very abstract
from the rest of the environment is changing colors.
It was like, is it a building?
What the hell's going on?
And I wasn't the one who made the decision
to go down there to go find out.
And when you were on top of the hill,
you couldn't see the trucks or the operators.
Nothing.
Couldn't see people.
Because like I said, it's very dense jungle,
very thick vegetation.
There's some clearings, of course.
There's some, what I can remember at least,
which mainly was a vegetation.
I can't tell you if there's mountains or hills or anything,
which I remember there being hills, of course,
when we were flying, it could kind of peek out.
But other than that, I don't know exactly where we went
or where we landed to or anything like that.
And I know there's been people that I've been trying
that I've asked for help to see if they could find the LZs
and to no avail, they can't
because there's no information on them.
And the F-350s or Tundras or whatever these trucks are,
they're attached to, it's like containers with HVACs?
Yeah, they're, yeah.
What do the containers look like?
So it's like a kind of like a shipping container
a little bit, but a little bit more reinforced
if you want to call it that.
And that's what I hypothesized it was drugs.
It was just like, you know.
And so it also had things that are like Pelican casings
on the back of the actual truck beds themselves.
So there could be weapons,
there could be other things in those things
because they're very airtight
and they seal up from moisture pretty well.
So it keeps everything dry.
So yeah, it could have been weapons.
It could have been anything,
but we mainly would put weapons in those.
So I'm assuming they did the same thing too.
And so when we saw the last trucks go up
is basically when this whole thing happened
with the platform raising up
and then the craft lowered itself
and then it went over the tree line
because it was like literally on the ground
or not on the ground, but it was hovering on the ground
but it was low enough that it was actually lower
than the treetops.
So this thing rose up past the treetops
and then it shut off to the left.
But prior to doing that, because it's rotating
and it was rotating in a clockwise motion.
So you can start seeing these lights appear
on the very corners of this thing
which were red, yellow, green and blue
is the only things I remember seeing.
And then this thing just shut off
and it was just like a black blur.
So extremely fast.
Extremely fast, fast enough that obviously it
for some reason did not disturb the vegetation around it.
There was coconuts in these trees
that could have easily fallen off with rotor wash
or exhaust wash from low flying aircraft.
That didn't happen.
And obviously it didn't make a sonic boom either
because of how fast this thing flew off.
So it was just like a black blur.
That's incredible.
I mean any estimates on speed or is that just really hard?
I mean several thousand miles an hour.
I've never seen anything fast like that.
I wanted to be a fighter pilot too.
So I know what aircraft and how they move
and I can tell you all the armament
that can go on these things.
And this was never something that I ever would
think I would ever experience.
Did it shoot off inland or towards the ocean?
Towards the ocean.
And any sort of ruffling of the treetops?
Nothing.
It almost like felt like it was.
It was almost like it was on set.
Like its own environment.
Nothing that could react to what our environment was.
And so this is important I think to tell the audience.
Like ETs are never mentioned in the context.
The core details of this story
have nothing to do with extraterrestrials.
And did you have a first instinct
on whether this was man made or not of this earth or?
Two things.
Prior to that I didn't believe in the subject
and I ridiculed a hell of a lot of people for it.
It was like you guys are fucking crazy.
They make movies great.
Of course the movies they come out
are all fucking terrifying and shit.
So it's like you can imagine a xenomorph
or that exists and what it would do here.
Or the thing from John Carpenter's
and something like that.
I mean fuck that shit.
But you know.
Did you ever encounter it in military context before this?
No.
Yeah okay.
So like literally zero context.
Zero context and it was one of those things.
So I didn't believe in it.
I never saw anything like that.
Did you ever suspect we had aviation technology
that was that advanced?
I mean I've heard about it like the Aurora for example
which was something that was hypothesized
which is very interesting.
But it's just like spy planes like that
but nothing anti-gravitic or anything.
And then you know so that day confirmed
that we had this technology because it was man made.
You could clearly tell it was man made.
It wasn't like ET.
And then some of the stuff I've seen recently
with ET craft photos or you know even doing CE5
with Greer and a couple of other people
and you can kind of see that it was
nothing you could really describe.
It was just like an orb or it was just like something
like a very bright light but it was very pure.
It wasn't like a drone where you could see
like you know blinking lights or nothing
but it was just a very, very pure light.
That's extremely important for the audience as well
where like whatever the ET stuff
and we don't even know if that's extraterrestrial
but it doesn't seem to be like prosaic nuts and bolts
like we're building it.
No, it's not.
That stuff, I don't know.
It looks at most like a plasma orb
if you had to like you know compare it
to something that is man made.
And it's often extremely ephemeral,
weakly entangled with that.
Maybe there is some sort of sensor pickup
but things like this where you see a thing
sort of hovering there, fly off, people interacting with it.
I mean that seems mostly of the man made variety.
Why would ET be trying to help out these guys?
Out of anybody, you know?
That's kind of the thing that I repeatedly say
because it's like no, 100% was man made.
Based off of that, I can confidently tell you
and I know for a fact recently
throughout the last almost two years,
I know for a fact we have reverse engineered technologies
and that's where the big secret is
is because they don't want people to know that
because then they have to explain to the whole world
and why we're still on fossil fuels,
why are we still having to depend on oil
and gas for our vehicles or even medical technology being
is it could be further advanced,
which I've been exposed to.
And everybody gets confused to think that Jake's team
has access to this technology.
It's like, no, this was somebody else
that was in the programs that was on a geneticist level
that was dealing with this kind of stuff
that has this technology.
I'm even hearing this
because I've heard you on a couple of podcasts,
Gerbs and Sean Ryan's,
and I think maybe the most overlooked detail
is the mission itself.
It feels weird.
It does.
It's like, okay, Obama's family is mentioned.
You don't have comms.
Do you ever think you were sort of set up
or there was something around the mission itself
that was a little funky?
It could be entirely possible.
I don't know.
I wasn't planning this mission
or planning anything like that.
I don't know.
It's very odd and it's very weird.
It's not typical,
but again, this is the first experience
of going on a first mission since I was freshly in
at that time.
So that was the first mission I ever did.
So it's like, okay, it's kind of like
just put together really quick.
That's what it felt like.
Because I think this is important to touch on too.
This wasn't with your normal fire.
No, it was not.
Your squad leader, your fire team leader
has spoken out against you before on public,
but this wasn't with your team.
No, it was not.
And this wasn't a special mission.
No, there's no secret mission with this.
This is basically almost like a working party.
And it was good because we just wanted to get off the ship.
And that's all it resulted.
So yeah, if we do LZ security or loading up boxes,
well, yeah, it's better than being cramped up on a ship.
Do you ever think,
because later Jake Barber back channeled with you,
and I think he dealt with the transport
of high value targets.
He did.
And so do you ever think that maybe this
actually had something to do with Obama's
Indonesian long lost family,
and they were actually being transported
on these conditions?
I don't think so because when,
so now that everybody understands the mission
at least with what we encountered,
now I can kind of go into talk about how I met Jake.
Yeah.
Okay.
Real quick, before we get into that,
what happened to the photos?
Okay, so good question.
So what happened was we ended up going back to Subic Bay
after that whole, you know, the mission,
we ended up getting ship, going back to the Philippines,
basically regrouping for the rest of the fleet.
We pull into Subic Bay.
So we have like, I think four or five days of liberty there.
So I had my camera.
So, you know, which these guys also had their phones,
which I don't think they took them with them.
They may have, I don't remember,
but I had my locker secured when we were going out into town
and we were supposed to report back, excuse me,
at nighttime, right before, you know,
I think 10 o'clock is when we had to be,
or 11 o'clock, I can't remember.
But ended up going back that night,
the first night we were out,
and then I go into my locker.
And so of course there's nothing,
there's the cameras out in there and I look at my rack
and then there it is, because I had the top rack.
And there it is and the battery is missing
and the memory card's missing.
So I had another battery in my locker.
So I went and got that, popped it in,
tried to turn it on and it wouldn't work.
So I threw it away.
The other guys that were with me were missing their phones
and some other stuff that they had.
And that's to remember what I can remember,
at least with one of the guys was there.
But that was very weird
because who else would have access to that?
And the lock was not broken.
So I don't know how they jimmied open that locker
with that lock on it unless they popped it somehow
and took that camera out because that camera was secured.
And then I get back and there it is.
Just completely disheveled and you can't turn it on.
It doesn't work anymore.
So there goes the evidence of that.
So somebody knew what was going on.
And then obviously this Air Force Lieutenant Colonel,
if that's really who it was,
but if somebody is, they had an Air Force
dress blue uniform with ribbons, a shitload of them.
They had jump wings.
They didn't have no pilot badge or nothing like that.
Then they had Lieutenant Colonel Insignia,
which is a silver oak leaf.
And he was at the CP and basically threatened me.
What's CP for the audio?
Control point, or command post, sorry, not control point.
So it's a command post.
And this was back when we were in Camp Hanson.
And so there was nobody there.
So this is back stateside?
No, no, no, this was in Japan or Okinawa,
Okinawa, which is Japan, but still.
So when that happened, so it happened to all of us,
but it wasn't at the same time.
And that's basically when he had made a sign in NDA saying,
you weren't gonna talk about this.
The only things I remember on it were TSSCI,
and Indonesia were the only thing.
So I remember putting my social security number on there.
I remember putting my first and last name or middle name too.
And then he told me flat out that if you talk about this,
you can go to prison or you can be executed over it.
Shh.
Fellow alchemists, it's a new year,
and that means it's time to get organized
and take control of our financial wellness.
For me, Rocket Money has been an absolute game changer.
It helped me uncover all sorts of subscriptions
I totally forgot about.
Like a few, I had no idea I was paying for months
after I stopped using the services.
With Rocket Money, I canceled these in just a few clicks,
saving money instantly.
Rocket Money is a personal finance app
that helps find and cancel your unwanted subscriptions,
monitors your spending, and helps lower your bills
so you can grow your savings.
Seeing all your subscriptions in one place is such a relief.
You know exactly where your money is going.
For the ones you don't want anymore,
Rocket Money can help you cancel them.
No awkward phone calls, no hassle, just savings.
Rocket Money also gives you a clear view
of your expenses across all your accounts.
You can create personalized budgets,
track your monthly spending trends,
and even set goals to save automatically
for big purchases, paying off debt,
or just building your savings.
It makes staying on top of your finances
easy and stress-free.
Rocket Money has over five million users
and has saved a total of 500 million
in canceled subscriptions,
saving members up to $740 a year
when using all of the app's premium features.
Cancel your unwanted subscriptions
and reach your financial goals faster with Rocket Money.
Go to rocketmoney.com slash Jesse today.
That's rocketmoney.com slash Jesse.
So it was a scare tactic because the thing is,
even people in the government I talked to on this,
Senate Armed Services, for example,
there's no protocols that would allow
for something like that to happen
unless you were working on a program.
So I don't know whether this was just a scare tactic
to basically just say,
hey guys, we haven't forgotten about you.
Also for the audience's sake,
I do think it's important to say,
you haven't made any money
off of coming out with this story.
And in fact, I know this about you
and I know you know this, Gurb, too.
You have a pretty successful business
out here in Colorado.
Multiple companies.
Yeah, multiple companies.
And so if anything, you're sort of losing money.
I mean, I don't know.
I've had the, you know, I have Rolexes.
That's one thing I collect.
That's another business that I do with, you know,
obtaining watches and trading them up or selling them.
You know, it's a good side hustle
if you can find the right buyers, of course.
But, you know, it's one of those things that
I have to grind to make money
and the best way to do it is with my companies.
You know, this doesn't,
I'm not getting paid to be here today.
I don't get paid for interviews.
I don't get paid to go have meetings at Cap Hill
or anything like that.
I sure as hell don't get paid to go attend
Greer's events to either, you know,
speak at some of them
because something may be valuable.
And that's kind of the thing that, you know,
I wish I was making more money
because who the hell wouldn't want to make more money,
but this isn't the path to do it.
So the thing that I tell people is just like,
you know, you'll know people by their deeds.
You know people based off their actions and what they do.
And what I'm trying to do
is basically solve this problem we've got.
I remember hearing your story
around that National Press Club event.
And my first reaction is,
this is the weirdest of all the testimonies.
And so I didn't know what to make of it.
And then my second like meta-reaction is like,
maybe it's the most likely to be legit
because it is so not like a script you would write.
Like, it's so weird.
It is.
There's so many loose ends
where of course you're signing up
to get accused of all sorts of bullshit,
you know, by just telling the story.
All of us who are going through this get accused of it.
It's nothing new.
I don't pay attention to it.
I don't care what anybody says.
Yeah.
Doesn't do anything.
They're not paying my bills.
I mean, this is the problem with people these days
is they put too much validation into people
who realistically hate to say it this way,
but don't matter.
Why am I going to care what a cab driver or a bouncer
or some random person walking on the street
that I have no idea exists until just seeing them,
why am I going to put more emphasis on what they care about?
Or because somebody says something on Twitter
who is hiding behind a ghost account
or like, I'm not going to put effort into that.
I put effort into what I'm doing as best as I can,
which business is my first thing.
That's my livelihood.
That's how I make money.
And I've lost contracts.
I've lost business because I've came forward.
So if anything, it has hurt me.
Yeah.
So you come back to the US
and this is what, 2009, 2010?
2009, yeah.
So probably 2009.
And then, yeah, getting back probably 2010, early.
How long do you stay silent on the topic
and what convinces you to go public?
So at the time, like I talked about meeting Greer in 2018,
I kind of hinted around that.
My ex I was with at the time,
I told her a little bit of the reason
why I was wanting to approach Greer.
And then, so she kind of heard a little bit of it,
but then when I came forward fully
through Greer's press club event,
but also he had a two-day event before that too.
This is where Jake was basically, where I'd met Jake,
but I didn't know it was him, if that makes sense.
He introduced himself, but I had no idea
it was this gentleman.
And so he, I mean, he's, you know.
So that was the first time you had ever come out
was this national press club event with Greer.
And you can add color to this as well,
because I know you know a lot about Stephen Greer.
He had held a similar national press club event
like two decades earlier or something.
Yeah, this was in 2001
and he hosted a panel of whistleblowers
and it's an excellent video.
I'll draw attention to Mark McCandlish
and the alien reproduction vehicle flux liner
we talked about.
It featured individuals such as I think Donna Hare
from NASA who talked about NASA scrubbing UAP photos.
And he also had an accompanying
2001 disclosure briefing document,
which is an excellent piece
and features so much whistleblower testimony.
So this was kind of the first time
he did a symposium like that since 01.
And just also broadly, Stephen Greer was the guy
over the last three decades,
if you were gonna come out and say anything on this topic,
he was kind of the only game in town in many ways.
And there are other researchers
that you like to talk about,
Bill Hamilton and others prior to Greer
who've set a lot of the foundation for what he talks about.
But he was kind of the guy for somebody like Michael
with his experience to come to.
Not only that, but there was a long period of time
which may continue today
where researchers give Greer witnesses.
And so researchers say, these are witnesses,
this is their name, number, and background.
And one example is Bill Hamilton giving primary witness
Brad Ass to Greer back in 97.
So he's doing a more modern version
of this National Press Club event.
You're speaking at this event.
Jake Barber, who's recently come out,
again, this Air Force vet who claims firsthand retrieval,
is there, but he's there trying to infiltrate Greer
on behalf of legacy UFO programs.
And so what happens?
Well, you know, so it's interesting.
So I wake up to this message from Greer one morning
and he sent it to me like two o'clock in the morning
because he stays up pretty late.
You know, he tries to be,
he lives in obviously the East Coast
and then he's like, lives off a West Coast time
which is odd, but that's his schedule.
So I go to bed pretty early
when I don't have anything pressing
because I like to get my rest.
And then the next day, I mean,
my days are usually crazy as it is,
but so I wake up this message and it's literally,
hey, this gentleman, you know,
I'm not going to say the alias that he was using
because I don't want that to be out
because then all of a sudden it'll just,
good to create problems.
If Jake wants to speak about that,
then Jake can speak about it on his own accord,
but I don't want to put anything in front of him
that he doesn't need to be concerned with.
So he says, this gentleman knows what you saw,
but here's his contact information,
get ahold of him when you can.
So I'm like, oh shit.
So I sit on that for like a day and a half.
I'm just thinking like, what should I do?
Should I just blow it off or?
So I get in touch with him.
So I call him, no voicemail can be sent
or anything like that.
So I'm in text message.
So all of a sudden he kind of goes off
a little bit in detail.
Wanted me to come out West to meet with him face to face
and he can explain what it is that I saw,
what he knows about it.
I said, they'll take my security into consideration.
So, cause we got picked,
I got picked up in a armored vehicle,
which was pretty bad ass.
And this was after you had met him
at the national press club,
after you had-
Yeah, I was introduced to him,
but I wasn't introduced to him
as the guy who knew what I experienced.
So you had met him,
but you didn't connect the dots
that that was this guy who Greer was talking about,
who knew a little bit more about what you had experienced.
Okay, I got it.
So, you know, and the thing-
Do you remember that interaction though
at the national press club?
Oh yeah, like I told him a little bit
what I do business wise and all that.
So he's kind of asking me questions,
but you know, he looked like,
I mean, cause everybody's seen what he looks like
when he wears glasses and he's wearing like this suit jacket
and the kind of stuff like that.
He kind of looked like a geek a little bit,
you know what I mean?
So he's like, okay, this guy, you know,
this guy's just probably something that I'm with this,
but here's a former tier one operator
that's, you know, a bad-ass guy that,
I mean, I wouldn't double cross that guy.
He's just, the guy's a,
him and his team are very good people, very good guys.
So, so he talks about the security aspect of it,
which he'll pick me up in an armored vehicle,
which was pretty cool.
And so we were trying to negotiate when I can fly out.
So we got a time scheduled.
So I ended up booking the flights and telling them,
this is when I'll arrive.
And, you know, basically asking him,
where should I fly in and where do I, you know, fly back?
So he had told me basically how to set all that up.
And then he had transportation waiting for me.
So he gave me this gentleman's number.
And so they picked me up.
And we drive from the airport to another location.
And we go to this pretty cool place
and where Jake was at, like an office.
Okay.
And-
Where are you?
Well, I'm just going to say it's in California.
Okay.
But that's all I'm going to say, right?
I'm not going to give specifics to where this location was,
which is hard to do because, I mean,
there's people who research this and by all means research
that figure it out.
You're going to find some interesting stuff.
So we go to this particular place in California
and he's, so he introduces himself again
as this alias, right?
And so he ends up sending a driver to go get us lunch,
which was cool.
And so he ended up knowing what I wanted, which was weird,
but that's on a separate tangent.
He knew what you wanted food-wise.
This gentleman did because I told him I wanted some Subway
because I haven't had that in a while.
But he knew the exact order that was your favorite order
or something?
Okay.
So they had like a little dossier on you or something?
I don't know if that's what the case was
or this guy was.
What would make sense in the context of Jake even saying
that his initial role was to red team
or infiltrate through his campaign.
And I mean, it's speculation, of course.
He told me personally that what his role was
after the fact of getting to know him
and getting information from him
for almost the past couple of years.
But this guy that was with him was a very good person,
very good guy.
And I mean, everybody that I'd known through Jake
was a great person.
So we ended up going into this office building
or not really an office building,
just like an office, like a conference room.
So we sit down, he tells me, okay,
go ahead and take out your phone and put on airplane mode
and set it off on the side.
So I do that.
And then actually prior to that,
he pulls out this wand thing.
It's like this box with this loop.
And he says, so he went over it himself and was like,
go ahead and take it and do it to yourself.
We heard the beeper go off on that wand
because it went over the phone and it reacted.
So he's like, oh yeah, go ahead
and put on airplane mode and do that.
So he's making sure it wasn't chipped
or had any kind of listening devices
or something like a wire, for example.
So then we sit at this conference room table
and he's explaining to me what it was.
He explained the containers, he explained the program P3,
which P3 is not the real program designation,
it's just what they call it.
Which was a psionic potential predisposition.
Okay.
And so, yeah, what?
Which, I mean, it sounds very far out there,
but being in these shoes for the last almost two years
and understanding that consciousness
is really the key to this whole thing.
If you want to understand how these UFOs operate,
you need to understand the consciousness better.
And so who, yeah, what was in these containers?
Because he thought initially it might've been drugs.
I thought it was drugs
and he has said I was completely wrong about that.
And what is he telling you?
He's saying it is basically these people
who are psionic assets who have been screened
from third world countries that they use them.
Because there's different groups that are recruited
out of the United States to participate
in different parts of the world.
And explain what a psionic asset is.
These are people that are,
they have a psychic ability to an extent,
to my understanding,
and they use these people to basically hook up
to this advanced technology,
whether it's NHI technology, ET craft, if you will,
and basically either summon them
or call them in and invite them in.
And then the dark part about this whole thing,
because everybody started getting wrapped up
in the human trafficking.
That got slapped onto it.
Now understanding how the dynamic is now
where these people volunteer for this kind of work,
because one, it's, if you hadn't,
I know if you guys had the opportunity
to participate in something that was mind blowing
with this technology, would you guys accept it?
I'd be, I'd want to know more.
I'd be cautious.
What about you?
Be cautious, but if it was in a sense
where you're participating,
because everybody's like, oh,
these people are dying and all that,
well, why aren't you complaining
about people going to the military?
Because you're taking risks going to the military too,
where you could die.
Or hey, you want to drive a race car for a living,
you happen to crash, well, that kills you,
you play professional sports,
you could always get screwed up.
You know, when I did competitive bodybuilding,
people talk about the risk of being
on performance enhancing drugs.
Well, let's even just super basically for the audience.
So these psionic assets are,
what are they doing vis-a-vis UFOs?
They are basically getting into a cognitive
or a state of consciousness to attract these craft
to appear at these certain ranges in this organization,
not Jake's team.
So everybody needs to understand
that Jake's team is completely different
from what this organization does.
And this organization will then sometimes target them
with these EMP weapon systems, their scaler,
and they knock them out of the sky.
So you're sort of baiting the UFOs to come in
and then you're knocking them out of the sky.
That's where Jake's team would come into need
is because his team would get contracted
to go pick up these vehicles
and then transfer them to a facility.
Okay, so you speak at the MPC,
you're then contacted by Jake
and you're then taken to a location.
Now what about the other five Marines
that experienced the eight gone possibly
reverse engineered craft with you?
What have they said?
Because I'd have known, but I wanna take that off.
Only two of them have reached out after the fact.
The other three have not.
And I don't think they're going to,
and I frankly don't think they ever want any part of this.
Now you, I can attest to this,
what have you personally seen?
Because I've shared some communication with two of them.
What did you see them do?
Yeah, both from communications,
like between you and them that you've showed me
as well as Joey trying to speak
to these two specific Marines.
They always, every single time say, leave me out of it.
I don't wanna talk about it,
but never once have they denied it.
You've offered to actually show us some of these texts
while obviously removing any personally identifying
information with your communications
with one of these Marines.
You saw the unredacted before, right?
Yeah.
To make sure you did too.
So you know the names, you guys have seen them.
Yes, we've seen the names and yes, yeah.
Fellow alchemists, Lucy breakers are changing the game
for nicotine users.
If you're looking for 100% pure nicotine product
that's tobacco free, Lucy breakers are where it's at.
Each pouch has a cool twist.
Inside is a capsule that can pop to release
an extra burst of flavor and hydration.
It's a unique experience that makes your nicotine routine
more enjoyable and convenient.
As someone who delves into the most heretical thinkers
and ideas of our time,
I appreciate products that challenge the norm.
Lucy breakers do just that.
My personal go-to flavor is mint.
Whether I'm deep into a podcast discussion,
exploring new frontiers or brainstorming ideas,
throwing in a Lucy is an easy way to keep the day moving.
Plus the flexibility and strengths lets you choose
what suits you best.
Let's level up your nicotine routine with Lucy.
Go to lucy.co slash Jesse and use promo code Jesse
to get 20% off your first order.
Lucy has a 30 day refund policy if you change your mind.
Again, that's lucy.co and use code Jesse to get 20% off.
And here comes the fine print.
Lucy products are only for adults of legal age.
Every order is age verified.
Warning, this product contains nicotine.
Nicotine is an addictive chemical.
Thanks so much to Lucy for sponsoring today's episode.
Okay, so this is, which side is you, Michael?
Okay, so I'm the light pink text
and this guy is the purple text, right?
Okay, so he says, sounds good, bud.
Says, hey man, this is asking too much of me
and it's not worth the risk.
And this is presumably after a phone call you got a sign.
I gave him a phone call from when I was instructed
by some people in the Senate Intel,
try to get ahold of him to see
if he wants to actually talk to us.
Okay, so you just spoke, you asked him to come out.
He said, hey, this is asking too much of me
and it's not worth the risk.
My family and military career far exceed
anything you are asking of me.
It's not worth my life or jeopardizing my family.
You need to get out of whatever you are in
and don't get me involved.
Presumably it's a-
Yeah, I can't view it because it's a screenshot.
But he basically after that says,
don't ever ask me to do this shit ever again.
That's what he said the last part, right?
This was another guy that reached out to me
through LinkedIn after he saw my Sean Ryan appearance.
And again, Gerb and I both have seen the names.
But squad mate, right?
So what the fuck else does that mean?
Saw your interview, my email is blank, right?
So I sent him a message to check your email.
Sends this over.
So what's up, buddy, how are you doing?
He says, I'm doing good, brother.
Saw that you're getting the word out, mad respect.
He said, it means a lot hearing from you, brother,
especially since we were close.
And then he says, yeah, brother, keep the faith.
There is no borders lines that they won't cross.
He says, well, I have a spot for you on my team.
So basically if you wanted to get involved with us
trying to do this.
And that's pretty much it.
And you guys saw when it wasn't redacted,
you guys saw the names, you guys saw that nothing was.
Yep, and you said, well, I have a spot for you on my team
if I go after trafficking ops.
So that's the human trafficking.
Yep, if that is the case,
because there's some people who reached out to me,
they're combating real human trafficking
in Africa, South America.
He's obviously trained.
So if he wanted to participate in doing that kind of stuff,
I got people reach out to me.
Hey, you want to part of a task force?
And he says at the end, sounds good, brother,
keep posted, be easy, stay safe.
Yep. Wow.
But yeah, it says, yeah, brother, keep the faith.
There are no borders nor lines that they won't cross.
Yeah. Yup.
And then he's going to say,
it's hard that you're getting the word out.
Yeah, the word.
What is he talking about if he's not implying
that he knows exactly what you're talking about?
That's exactly it.
The original Daily Mail article on you
posted just a screenshot of one of the Marines.
I know who it is.
I'm like, leave me out of this.
I have a family, I'm still in the military,
something like that.
Like, I don't want to speak about this.
Yeah.
But you've showed many further.
Well, I have shown, yes.
And I have reported though, or not reported,
but I have provided a Senate Select Committee
on Intelligence all those messages.
Because why would he be afraid to help?
What's the repercussions if he helps?
Obviously with what we experienced.
Why would the other guy be appreciative of me
bringing this out, getting the word out, as he says?
So what happened to the other three?
Are they just completely off radar?
Maybe, I don't know.
I'm sure they're aware.
I mean, most people are, you know?
But I mean, it's up to them whether or not
they choose not to.
I completely understand I'm the one that jumped
the gun on us.
So far, they have not contributed in a sense,
at least that it was able to give me the messages
that they sent me that I can provide to say,
what the fuck would they be talking about?
If this wasn't real, they would be saying,
no, what are you talking about, dude?
But the fact they're not denying it,
the fact that they're against it,
such as they don't wanna talk about it
because of the ramifications, the first clue.
Second clue, why would they be acknowledging
and getting the word out?
The only person saying this never happened
was your fire team leader, who was?
I got two other Marines who say otherwise.
Right, the fire team leader was not on the mission.
He was not on the mission.
I don't know what he was doing.
If he was wild, you're in it.
Sorry, go for it.
Yeah, I didn't wanna get you off.
But no, you know, it's just, you know,
to him, they can think and believe whatever they want.
I don't care.
It doesn't ruin my mood.
It doesn't do anything different.
It certainly doesn't derail my mission
of what I'm trying to achieve,
at least with the transparency with this,
to get this problem real then once and for all.
It begs all these questions of like,
if we're engaging in black ops in the jungle in Indonesia,
and you guys just kind of happened upon this thing,
how many other remote locations where, you know,
you just never expect anybody,
any passerby to kind of encounter this stuff,
is this going on?
Right.
Well, I mean, like I've been told,
Jake's even aware too,
that there's several different sites all over the world
that deal with this.
And you know, Southeast Asia being one of them,
third world countries, Mexico being one of them.
And so, because in your Sean Ryan episode,
Sean uses the term human trafficking.
Correct.
And so there's this big debate,
because I interviewed Jake,
and you know, it's just like this question of,
there was, I believe it's tsunami warning at the time, right?
It wasn't a tsunami warning.
So the thing is, everything already happened.
Oh, so this was post tsunami.
This was post earthquake and tsunami.
So then, were you guys,
because the Sean Ryan thing, it was like,
there was like, you were almost taking advantage,
or the quote unquote tier one operators,
whoever they were, were taking advantage of the fact
that this was a disaster zone.
Correct, that was a theory.
That was a theory.
Or it could have been that their operation
was compromised somehow,
and they needed to get away, or whatever it might be.
I mean, it's just.
Do you have a bias in either direction?
Do you think they were sort of rounding people off?
I'm just neutral about it,
because of being in this situation,
and now understanding, at least to my knowledge,
of what takes place now.
Yep.
I had a negative, excuse me, outlook on it at first,
because I didn't understand it.
The more I talked to Jake about it,
the more he was able to put it into reference
on why it made sense.
Now, is it something that is agreed upon?
No, because they're using children,
and that's bothersome.
I don't know anybody who would feel good about that,
because I don't have kids, but if I had kids,
they were getting plucked into these programs,
and being subjected to this kind of stuff,
I would have a problem with that,
and I think anybody in their right state of mind
would have a problem with that, too.
I agree.
So, there's some trade-offs with this,
but what people have to understand,
and they vilify these legacy programs
like nobody's business, like they're all bad guys.
It's not the case.
It's the best and brightest this country has to offer
that get pulled into these programs
to basically make our country better to an extent.
Now, there are some breakaway parts and factions of this
that take their own routes,
i.e. Jake with his initiative with what he wants to do,
which essentially make everybody understand
that the legacy programs are not all that bad,
but also have another outlet for people to pay attention to
as far as making contact with other civilizations
and inviting them in and basically assessing
the data that they collect, which is public to an extent
because this is what they're talking about doing.
If you are baiting a thing that seems like
it's coming from another world or planet
or inter-dimensionally or whatever this is,
and then zapping it out of the sky,
if you know it's bad, that's fine.
If you don't, shouldn't we have some caution
around doing that?
There should be some sort of system,
diplomatic or whatever you would say,
but this is the thing, as you know,
if you're in the military or you're in some sort of capacity
where you're taking orders,
you're not really in a position to think necessarily.
You're just gonna do what's instructed for you to do.
And I feel the same way is probably perpetrated
in people in these programs to an extent
and to think the same way.
This is a reason why they cross-deck into these agencies
because they still have the same structure.
They still have the same type of orders that are given
or things like that.
Yes, you're more free-thinking, but at the same time,
you're also doing sort of the same work,
but just in a different capacity.
So if you're taking orders to say, hey, this,
whatever comes into range, take them out.
I don't think anybody's gonna argue with that
because the amount of pay that comes with this
and it's your only opportunity.
And these guys get paid pretty good.
Yeah, well, this isn't necessarily blaming the operators
who are involved at all.
No, and that's the thing is that they're told one thing
because the management level of these
know what's going on to an extent.
And this is where it comes into either they're doing this
for their own personal benefit or their gain
for whatever group they control,
i.e. through money, coercion of certain things.
But again, this is speculation, but at the same time,
the facts are is that we are shooting them down.
Yes, they are facts.
And regardless of everybody out there says,
I've never seen this happen.
Well, yeah, you're not going to.
You're not a part of these programs.
You're not a part of anything
that's gonna get you into this
because the people that are involved with this,
they don't like to talk about it.
They like to do the work and they do what's required of them.
They get paid a lot of money to do it.
And some of the work, a lot of the work that they do
is probably very fun.
They probably get to do things that are not normal
that nobody in this room gets to say
that they get to do, right?
Do you think because you hear rumors of the psionic assets
having sundowner syndrome or health effects or whatever,
and you get, I mean, I think this goes back
to ancient esoteric practices.
And it's sort of this thing where if you're not
of an extremely pure, internally coherent state,
then you get a reflection of the pain that's inside of you.
You're gonna manifest whatever you're projecting out there.
I think that's realistic.
But what we're talking about
is not like trying to summon a spirit.
You're summoning essentially technology
that has consciousness to it.
Now-
What's the distinction?
Well, the difference is, is obviously
if they're extraterrestrial that have a consciousness,
they're coming from a different star system.
That's what's different.
Do we know that?
We don't.
This is the, now they may know that
based off of however they're interacting.
Could this just be like an occult thing
that's been coming out for hundreds of years?
How do you think they learn?
Who?
Groups, they learn from the occult.
Sure, interesting.
The secrecy aspect of this is,
you have different fraternities or secret societies.
I mean, everybody knows I'm a Freemason.
I've talked about it, but everybody speculates
all because I'm a Freemason,
I'm a disinformation agent or something,
or I'm a part of the New World Order.
And then they see the SDG pin that I wear,
which everybody says it's the World Economic Forum.
Sorry, I am too poor to be one of those guys
and I do not fit whatever they need.
I think this is an important discrepancy to bring up too.
When Jake discusses Skywatchers
and some people on the Skywatchers team,
the P3 assets are quite engaged with what they do.
They're happy, they're former military,
or they're well-treated individuals.
When we first did our interview in summer of 2024,
what you knew at the time was that the P3 assets
were essentially treated like trash,
given drug cocktails to interface with the craft,
treated like garbage.
How does this leverage connect?
So here's the thing is I think there's speculation
because one of the things is because they're given drugs,
doesn't necessarily mean that they're treated like trash.
What it does is it allows them to operate
at a higher level of consciousness,
even though there's some disassociation with it,
or if there's other trauma-related things
that happen early on in their lives,
or they induce it somehow.
Granted, this is not what Jake's team does.
The operators he has on this team
do not do what these legacy programs do.
It's completely different.
So everybody thinks that if Skywatchers
participating in the same type of operations as Legacy,
I hate to break it to you, it's not even remotely close.
It's much more peaceful, it's much more informative,
and something that's gonna be a little bit more transparent
compared to what Legacy's doing.
So it could have been a different program
outside of Jake's that referred to the P3s
as like pink assets.
That's what the program calls them, or pink assets.
What's pink assets?
Biological equipment like cattle, right?
Yeah, that has always stood out to me.
Granted, that is something that has been communicated to me
is that some of the programs refer to them as that.
Doesn't mean Jake thinks that that's the case,
or at least that's how he personally views these people,
because he doesn't view them that way,
but this is what the program treats them like.
Now, corporations out there are no different.
Big corporations treat people like numbers.
Okay, well guess what, this guy died,
so we have another person filling his spot,
and we can forget about it.
The military's the same way, it's just a constant rider
of repeating the trainings and getting people in these roles
and then basically getting them up.
If somebody gets out, they get in, or they get killed,
they get another person to fill the slot.
So it's really no different from that,
but in the same token, because it's so abstract,
that people wanna lynch onto and say, oh, this is evil.
Well, military's doing the same thing.
Is there a way to do this that is above board?
It brings up all these philosophical questions,
because it's like, I'm all for protecting the free world,
and I do, the people who create some false equivalents
between the way people live in domestic China right now,
in the US, as messed up as our country is,
I think I'd much rather live here,
and I'm all for protecting it.
And so there are these game theoretic dynamics
where I'm sure they're doing similar things.
But then the meta-philosophical question is like,
we're talking about aspects of the sacred,
and I don't know what these beings are.
They could be angels, they could be demons,
I don't know what they are.
Well, angels and demons don't need flying saucers
to come here, let's get that straight.
So you think they're extraterrestrials?
100%.
But if they're not bad, you're just baiting them
and zapping them out of the sky.
It's no different than if I was to have an exotic car
driving through a bad neighborhood
and they decided to shoot me and steal my car
because it was-
But that would be messed up for them to do.
That's exactly it.
You want to talk about the ethical conflict here
because that's really what it is.
This is the reason why Jake came forward, right?
Because there's nothing that he was,
there were things going on that he was not a fan of.
Right, because I think Greer has spoken about this,
that when he spoke to Jake,
Jake relayed that craft were being down
and he was deeply-
He was bothered by that, 100%,
especially with the P3 is the way they're treated.
So, and his goal now is to just get them killed peacefully?
Because there might be biologics in the craft.
If that's the case, you are attorney,
possibly living biologics to dead biologics.
Well, and that's what happens when they fall in the sky
because they're subject to our laws of the universe
with inertia and gravity and all that kind of stuff.
If we could peacefully commune with these things,
that would be amazing.
I just-
Well, and I think that's what Dr. Greer's
whole CE5 initiative is all about,
which I've personally attended a few of them.
Who you invited me to because it's more like,
I like to see things firsthand to see whether or not
there's anything credible.
And yeah, Dr. Greer's CE5 is very real.
It's very incredible.
And it's something that I think a lot of people
need to understand that that's not by any means false.
But if you listen to the ancient traditional version
of this stuff, it's always like,
you need to be 35, married, grounded.
Like you shouldn't like try to summon anything.
This is the thing as we're going off of interpretation,
what one person's interpretation is not gonna share
the same as the other person's.
Your interpretations are different than mine.
Mine are different from yours and so on.
It's just whatever you personally experienced,
whatever has been your upbringing,
whatever you believe and value wise
is going to shape your narrative
and what your thought process of a situation is.
So if you're brought up on the more
religious aspect of things, then yes,
you're gonna think aliens are angels or demons.
If you're somebody who's esoteric,
you're gonna say, okay, it's interdimensional
or it's something that could be extra solar, right?
But it depends on what your upbringing is
and what you believe in yourself of what it might be.
But it doesn't mean it's correct.
And so do you think these things come down
and then we're talking about this octagonal,
eight-gon shaped craft that seems to be possibly manmade,
material derived from what lands
or gets zapped out of the sky,
then gets reverse engineered or implemented
in these terrestrial exotic craft that we build?
Is that right?
To my understanding, that's exactly how it happens.
From my understanding, from what's been related to me,
was that every craft that they recover,
they also make reverse engineered versions
of trying to replicate that technology
or that specific craft.
So this, I mean, Jake saw pretty much the same thing,
except much smaller,
that something that was able to be lifted up by a helicopter,
this fucking thing is estimated 300 feet.
I don't think his helicopter could pick something up
that big, you know?
So it'd take probably several helicopters,
but in the same token.
So you think what you saw was a reverse engineered,
manmade version of what he saw?
Could he have locked on to it possibly?
Possibly, because I mean, again,
there's different groups all over the world
that are doing the same thing.
So yes, there's multiple black sites
that probably have P3s that are being used
to lure craft out and then to shoot them down.
That was the most fascinating part of my Jake interview
is he was like, who is we?
And I was like, I don't know,
I assume like the US or like whatever,
you know, space corporations he might be working for.
And then he was like, no.
We don't have shit.
Yeah, he's like, it's all, he's like, it's black money.
It was almost like it was like mafia wars
and international, transnational corporations and interests,
you know, across the world doing this stuff.
And yeah, try to investigate this subject,
particularly with the vehicle you saw
hit so many dead ends.
I mean, it's been talked about publicly by Greer,
but he always says that he knows the craft you saw,
the souped up version of the eight gun that Jake retrieved
is made by the Lockheed Skunk Works in Northrop Grumman.
He says that I myself have pressed into that
with the integral you do art for him
and say, where does he get this?
Well, that's the thing is I think it's speculation.
I mean, because unless you're physically working
for these companies, you're not gonna know what's what.
I mean, he may be connecting the dots
because he's talked to over a thousand other people
that may have been working for these programs
and maybe have articulated something personally to him.
I'm not entirely sure of because I'm not in Greer's head.
What I will say is that this field
offers a lot of speculation
and it offers a lot of confusion.
Because really at the end of the day,
we only know what we experience personally
and what your interpretation of it
and how you tell the story
is going to be different than what you say
because here's the problem.
Every time you retell a story, you're reframing it
based off of memory as much as you can.
So yes, I understand that for myself with this story.
There could be details left out that I don't remember
or there could be a certain thing.
So it's just going off of memory
of what you retell your reframing.
So with Jake's incident,
with him red teaming the event,
I think one of the things that is a little bit hard for me
to accept is the fact that this meeting back-channeled
from somebody in the programs
doesn't happen with anybody.
It didn't happen to Hecker, it didn't happen to DC Long,
it didn't happen to Steven Degna,
it hasn't happened to anybody else I know.
These are all witnesses who came forward with you
and some of them went on Sean Ryan.
I'm the only one that has been corroborated with
or by people.
Why do you think they chose you specifically?
Because they know what I experienced
because of what their personal involvement is
with what they experienced.
And that's kind of the thing of why he offered
when I went out to go see him for the first time personally,
not at the event, but just on a personal basis
to explain what I saw.
And one of the things that was,
because anybody can say that
they're a part of something, right?
But how do we really know?
Well, when Jake took me on a nice little trip
out to the desert, that was something that proved to me
that this guy was legit.
What'd you see?
I'm not gonna tell you.
I can't talk about that.
I'm not gonna burn Jake in the process
because I had given him my word
that it was not going to do that.
He could have easily had me sign an NDA
or originally they wanted to blindfold me
and then just take it off and basically here you are.
But that didn't happen.
But you saw something cool and mind blowing
and confirming of his prior states?
Personally, yes, yes.
Personally, yes.
Are you at least able to say
if this was above or below ground?
I can't tell you.
Gotcha.
I'm not gonna hint to either or because I just, you know,
like I said, I don't wanna burn Jake.
Of course.
He's the reason why I've been included
in certain aspects of this
because for me, he wanted me to have firsthand experience
with a lot of things that are about the subject.
And he didn't have to do any of this for me.
He could have just laid low.
He could have just done his original job
and I would have never seen,
I would have never understood it.
I could have been just labeled one of the crazy psychopaths
that some people think I am and that could have been it.
Have you learned anything more about the fact
that maybe we have reverse engineered working craft
like this eight gun craft in our possession
that we've actually built and we know how to fly
and that sort of thing.
This idea of alien reproduction vehicles,
which check out Gerb's channel, he does amazing work on
and he talks about the Mark McCandlish story.
Have you heard anything confirming of that?
Yes, I have, but it's not something
from Jake's side of the house, for example.
It's more with other people
that I've been in communications with.
Anything you can share?
Well, I mean, I can just say that they exist.
Okay.
And I know where some of them are stored at,
but that's about it.
And do you think that the designs are copied
or we derive material from the UFOs that come down?
Or what's the relationship?
My understanding is that we don't necessarily replicate
the same materials these things are made out of.
What my understanding is we have the same,
they can get them to look the same
using materials we have on earth.
Probably even, of course, who's to say
that they probably replicate the same materials too
in the lab somewhere or they make them
because they know what they're made of now
because they've been doing this ever since the 40s and 50s.
They've been bringing these craft out.
So it's like design inspiration or mimicry or something?
I think it's mimicry for the most part
because if they get them to look, you know,
something that looks extraterrestrial,
but it's manmade and they want people to believe that,
then by all means they're gonna do that.
The other implication is that we have
propulsion modalities in our possession
and we can work this stuff.
Yes, we can.
That transcends chemical combustion
and seems to break Newton's laws of conservation momentum
and that sort of thing and leaves the trees
unperturbed around, you know.
Making no noises, nothing like that.
I mean, I'm a car guy, you know.
So if there is like a fast car,
you implement this kind of technology into,
it'd be pretty incredible.
It'd be very dangerous, but.
Can we get any of this working civil side?
Is that a good aspiration?
Let me ask you something.
Somebody who, let's just say you come up with something
that could be very beneficial, but for you,
you understand it can make you money
or you can control people with it
and it puts you on a playing field
that's above everybody else.
Nobody else has the same stuff you do,
but if you're this person who's greedy
and this person who likes the aspect
of being able to do whatever you want,
except you get to fold it into some people
who make decisions, i.e. lawmakers,
and you pay them a lot of money
or you pay them money to basically steer clear,
donate to their campaigns,
and you basically are above the law,
you can coerce politicians,
you can coerce military officials, generals, you name it,
by just throwing them sacks of cash.
Are you gonna really wanna share with everybody
if you have the stranglehood
in the most powerful country in the entire planet?
I think most people wouldn't,
but I'd like to think I would, but.
I don't know.
I mean, humanity.
Or not necessarily,
but isn't there a midpoint between those two things
where you use it as leverage
to get dictatorships abroad to reform
and you black box it in certain ways
that can't be reverse engineered,
you dole it out in civil infrastructure,
you still make the world a better place,
but you also allow it to confer an advantage.
Fiber optics and night vision and stuff like that, right?
So you've got the Philip Corso narrative.
To an extent.
I think that what's derived from it's real,
but I don't, you know, his theory of how they were,
you know, we have jetliners
that can fly through a lightning storm, no problem,
and very dense thunderstorms that have a lot of lightning
and they get hit by it and nothing happens.
So why is something that's not even from this planet
or from a different civilization
that's more advanced than we are,
why is something gonna be susceptible to a lightning strike?
It's not.
Do you know when we cracked gravity,
if this is using like electro-gravitic propulsion,
do you have any theories around?
Well, just from what's been already disclosed,
which is 1954.
Okay.
We've had the hook on gravity control since then.
And what was 54 specifically?
Well, it's just from what Greer has alleged,
one of his teammates that was in a vault
that saw the documents that talked about
gaining that kind of control.
Interesting.
And this guy has been on the record several times.
I don't know his name specifically,
but he's been mentioned quite a bit.
There was some experiment
where we tied electromagnetism to gravity.
Based off of like even, for example,
when they retrieved the stuff from Nazi Germany
back in the 40s and then sent them over here
with Operation Paperclip.
Now this can get into a whole different conversation.
But they had some disks that they recovered.
The Nazis did.
The Nazis developed the stuff, but it wasn't stable.
So when they brought them over here,
of course you had the best scientists
who were already working on this kind of stuff
that were able to amplify it somehow.
Now that you have the US government backing you,
giving you citizenship,
basically giving you a right to do whatever you want
because you need your help.
Yep.
And this is how NASA was created
because it was a German who created this.
Yeah.
It was also the CIA and the FBI were created
by these people too.
Yeah, everything you're saying now,
I can tell you it was definitively factual.
Right.
It's not conspiracy.
Wernher von Braun, Arthur Rudolph,
basically the NASA Saturn project was a transplantation
of the Nazi space program.
And then you had Richard Mita, Victor Schauberger,
a lot of these guys, Henry Kawanda,
who were working on lenticular aerodyne saucers.
Either they moved over to the US,
or in Mita's case, I believe there's speculation
he worked on the Avrocar project, the Canadian version.
Schauberger, I know the Army Counterintelligence Corps
tricked into giving all of his propulsion,
exotic propulsion stuff to the US.
And that made it actually to Brookhaven National Labs,
which was a Nick Cooke documentary.
That even brings up the question,
did we even really win World War II if that happened?
If we took the brightest minds,
the top military leaders of the Third Reich,
and brought them here,
and they basically got into positions of power
and influenced our government
and created intelligence agencies,
which they wanted to replicate in Nazi Germany,
we are living present day
of what they wanted to accomplish back in the 40s.
I speak fluent German.
I know a lot about German history.
And I know for a fact that...
This is like this Philip K. Dick man
in the high castle narrative,
but like an undercover version or something.
So what, so if they infiltrated our highest ranks,
which they sort of did,
but do you think they sort of maintained Nazi allegiances?
Well, look at what happened with Ukraine.
This is what people don't talk about.
Look at them waving Nazi flags.
A lot of the people that went out of Nazi Germany
went and occupied that area.
There's Nazis here.
I mean, look at some of the prisons and stuff,
like the Aryan gangs,
but yes, there's societies that have Nazi influence in them.
I can tell you for a fact.
So what Hitler wanted to achieve
was a militarized police force.
What do we have now?
A militarized police force.
We have basically healthcare, some free healthcare.
They have some sort of system for education,
which is what they wanted to do.
They wanted to basically put a ban on smoking a whole lot
because they wanted healthier people.
And it was funny because even as a Freemason,
one of the things that Hitler despised was us as Freemasons
because of the secrecy that we have
and the way that we do rituals,
which is nothing spectacular to an extent
because it's just tradition.
But one of the things that he liked
was how we kept things very secret and very word of mouth,
i.e. what we call a pass and a grip.
So a password and then a grip is obviously a handshake,
depending on what degree you are,
that demonstrates what kind of grip you will give.
And then of course,
there's some grips that you give in the public
and there's grips that you give
only behind the doors of a lodge.
No, I mean, yeah, like Werner von Braun,
Rudolf Hess, Himmler,
all these guys were really interested in the occult.
Everybody on that top level was because that's,
so part of this council form relations
was something that helped set up the CIA.
Well, do you think most of these people
that were in the CFR at the time,
they were people who were read into the occult
or participated in themselves in some of these societies?
That's how they learned the secrecy in these programs
was based off of these organizations
that know how to keep things compartmentalized,
that should sound familiar.
So they keep people segmented
and then they basically bring people
onto those segmented parts to basically stay in their lane.
This is how you have different divisions
and different things that people work on
that basically integrate into a bigger picture.
You're almost implying that they're like control systems
that go deeper than just, you know,
NDAs and this is your directive.
Very much so, that is the truth.
And this has happened for thousands of years.
This is no different.
The only difference is, is the people who exist today
are taking the influence from the past
and still implementing it.
So when the next person steps in line,
they get to do the same thing
and basically keep it going the same way.
Then it never changes.
The only thing that changes
is when you have people like Jake, for example,
who come forward and expose
what their personal experiences are
and basically try to not necessarily shatter the secrecy,
but they want certain parts of the secrecy to be out
so that way humanity can benefit.
I don't have a problem with that.
What do you guys think is like,
because Disclosure's in this very interesting place now
where I feel like it's made kind of a quantum leap forward
and then mainstream society.
I mean, a lot of this stuff came out around the inauguration.
And if you look at like what's happening in the White House
and with USAID and like Doge,
like most people are concerned with that
and they don't give a shit about UFOs.
And then you have UFO world where they're like,
we have a guy who came out who said he retrieved
a craft firsthand and it's like they're on an island
like from the rest of society doesn't,
there's some dark matter between them
that's like undetectable.
So where does Disclosure go from here
and is there like an aspirational, you know,
good place for it to go directionally?
Well, let me ask you something.
So everybody understands how the government
is astray these days, right?
Yeah.
So you have all these moving parts
and people don't know what they're doing
or they do know what they're doing,
but there's just so many different things
that are developing within the government right now.
Do you think realistically pulling these technologies
from these black programs and putting them
into the hands of people who don't know
what the fuck they're doing is a smart move?
No, it's not.
Not Willie Neil, not like, you know, yeah.
This is why amnesty and this is why this needs
to get more transparent, at least for a government.
Now, some of the free energy tech we could benefit from,
but as far as the craft or being able to fly,
that can stay top secret and it can just be like,
yeah, we know nuclear weapons exist
or thermonuclear weapons.
We don't know how they work, but we know they exist.
It could be the same way.
Yeah, shouldn't that be the right analogy
where it's like nuclear physics
versus nuclear trade secrets?
Correct.
Where it's like, obviously, yeah,
we shouldn't let trade secret that,
as far as the physics should be open.
I can tell you personally that I don't think
the government would even have any kind of first indication
on how to manage these programs.
They're not gonna know what to do with it.
If they're so, and this is the problem,
to your face, they're gonna tell you
they're all about the right motives
or doing the right thing for this country.
But when push comes to shove
and they don't wanna do a fucking thing about it,
they're gonna put people, oh, it's my political career
I give a shit more about.
Well, Congress has an 11% approval rating.
I've always thought one of the most overrated versions
of disclosure is having congressional oversight over it.
I think a lot of these guys don't know their asses
from their foreheads.
No, they don't.
As far as the public understanding
basic ontological truths and benefiting to the extent
they can from the tech,
that feels like a clear net good.
What you and I have as an expectation for the government
is much different than what they have for themselves.
Their expectations is I get to go home every night,
I get to check my bank account
and make sure I'm getting paid the same funding
I got last year or if not more
and that their reputation still sticks around
as I'm Senator so-and-so
and I'm this cool person because I'm in government.
Yeah, I mean, it's an oligarchy,
it's special interests run the entire thing.
These people are not powerful at all.
This group that has this kind of stuff
is way more powerful than them.
So these guys on Capitol Hill
that think that their shit doesn't stink,
I hate to break it to you guys,
you guys are pawns.
So you think that the UFO legacy programs
are almost like breakaway power fiefdoms
that have leverage over the federal government?
Oh yeah, they have more money than our government.
Are you kidding?
So you think, like with this transition,
do these UFO programs automatically roll up to Trump
or are they their own thing?
They're gonna be their own thing because here's the thing,
Trump's not gonna know what to do with this
because most of the people on Capitol Hill
don't believe in this shit
and some of the ones that do are very far and few between.
But Trump has to know that this stuff is real.
You don't think so?
But his son on his podcast interviewed Ross Coulthart
before Ross Coulthart broke the Jake story
and I'm just reading between the lines and speculating.
Let me break it to you.
I've had meetings with some of these people
in Trump's administration.
I can back it up because I got photographic evidence
and I participate in a lot of meetings in Washington
because of what I'm able to provide them
as far as little bit of advice,
but a little bit more like personal experience, okay?
They will say it, yes, they're interested into it
but when their political careers come up
because now they're gonna be thought of in that cases.
Every single person in this field is thought of that.
It's the stigma until you have somebody like Trump,
for example, he's more fixated on things
that are more short-term that can be a long-term thing
which is great.
I'm not bashing that.
I think his approach of trying to clean up the government
is great because what happens is now they start seeing
funding go in different directions that's not known.
When that's apparent, that is gonna basically say,
where is this money going to?
Then you're gonna have people like Jake knocking
on the door saying, I know exactly where that's going to
and it's going to these programs.
Well, what are these programs centered around?
Well, NHI technology or reverse engineered
and all this kind of stuff.
So it could segue into it.
What's gonna happen with disclosure
is not an overnight thing.
This is gonna be something that has to take
a few generations for people to understand
because this is unfortunately how fast humans learn.
You know a lot about the money flow of like all this stuff.
You wanna just talk about that?
Yeah, I gotta say, I fully agree with you guys
that disclosure probably will come from the Congress.
I mean, look at Kirk McConnell,
the staffer for Senator Gillibrand
on the Senate Armed Services Committee.
Since 2017, he has been pulling witnesses,
talking to witnesses and briefing his Senator.
He's great, he knows a lot.
I know, I talked to him in a skiff.
Okay, so you spoke to him directly first hand.
Yeah, so he's a good guy.
Yeah, because at Seoul, he was asked by a couple individuals
if he had heard of a blue on blue firefight team
with a Lockheed retrieval team
and about transporting humans in reverse engineered craft.
And he said both he had heard.
Yes, so definitely you have talked to him.
So that sounds like maybe the craft is Lockheed.
I agree.
But as far as the money, I mean,
I agree that this is probably like a black programs
or breakaway projects.
I think most of these operate in DOD laboratories
or various MRTFBs, major range test facility bases.
A lot of these have underground locations.
This cashflow is generally moved through FFRDCs,
Federally Funded Research and Development Centers
or UARCs, University Affiliated Research Centers.
And this is so the federal government can,
those who know when the federal government can engage
with legacy programs operations through these FFRDCs
and UARCs to make joint USG and contractor programs,
the block programs as we think of them.
Give us a few big examples of FFRDCs.
MITRE, RAND, Center for Naval Analysis,
the IDA Institute for Defense Analysis.
How much money do these organizations get?
Tons, and there's something called Crystal City.
Do we have a sense of like,
cause it's like, yeah, what's Crystal City?
Crystal City is a location just south of the Pentagon
in Washington, DC.
That is where pretty much all of the biggest
defense contractors are.
It's in Arlington, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you have the Aerospace Corporation,
you have the IDA, you have the CNA,
the Center for Naval Analyses.
And I really think the amount of money that's moved
can't really be tracked because I myself have talked
to witnesses who have seen cash moved,
like physical bales of cash taken to locations.
Most of the transactions are in cash.
And this is something that most, even people I've talked to
have talked about that that's how they do things.
Everything's self-funded in that regard, right?
So if you have a program that you can benefit
off of siphoning funds from the government, right?
Tax dollars that get allocated to that,
but then you don't have to tell people
what you're specifically doing and just say,
yeah, it's going to this program
and we need 60 billion for it, right?
So then when it gets to a point of them actually generating
own revenue by themselves,
they still need that lifeline of government funding
because then it gives them a purpose
because the government gives them
the legal authority to do so.
If the government was like, you know what?
We know what you guys are doing is bullshit.
We're going to go ahead and cut off funding.
Well, they're still making money,
but that's the thing that they'll discover
is how they're making money,
which is not in a legal sense, right?
Because they're still kept from the government.
You're using tax dollars to generate programs,
which then can generate revenue,
which then enrich certain people's lives
or they use it to replicate technologies, if you will.
So essentially, if they figure out
everything they're doing is illegal, then guess what?
They're not going to risk it.
So what are they going to do?
They're going to continue lying to everybody on Capitol Hill.
And because some of these senators and politicians
that are also read into this,
but at least maybe they're getting,
hey, I'll give you a couple of million for your campaign.
Just don't look over here.
Right.
It happens all the time.
Yeah.
Well, you have, you know, Congressman Mike Turner,
who represents the district that right
Wright-Patterson, which is the center of all UFO lore
and reverse engineering, back to Roswell.
And I believe his top three donors are Boeing, Lockheed,
and maybe I'm getting the third one, Raytheon.
You know, some-
It is Raytheon.
And he basically helped NICS, the eminent domain clause,
you know, as part of the-
I'll explain why that happened, all right?
Now everybody thinks, oh shit, that sucked.
We didn't get anything out of that.
Yes, we did.
We understand that it's always gonna be
one step forward, two steps back.
We're gonna figure out what's going on
and who's a part of what.
When that was gutted and who opposed it
was basically saying, hey, we're the ones that oppose it.
Now we know who's a part of it.
So ideally having them NICS, that was a good thing
because they exposed themselves to us.
Now we know what to look for and who to look for.
So it wasn't a bad thing.
It was expected, but it was a good thing
because now we know who's in charge of what.
And Turner's out now, which is cool.
And I think he was out because they figured it out,
what he was doing.
To an extent, not necessarily with UAP,
but just with other programs, right?
Do we have a sense of yearly,
but like if the NDAA, National Defense Authorization Act,
basically our defense budget yearly,
is like 800, 900 billion,
do you have a sense of how much of that is UFO?
Or is UFO off the books
and is it even greater than that?
Probably off the books,
but there's one example of specific monetary value
I can't talk about.
So I covered once a witness, codenamed Ed,
who talked of a joint reverse engineering program
between the Nevada Test and Trade Range
and Edwards Air Force Base,
two highly prolific locations,
done a ton of analysis on there.
But this individual, after his time at the Air Force,
he went on to work for the Pentagon
for the research, development, test, and evaluation
panel chain for the Air Force.
It was here during the span of I think 2012 to 2016,
he spoke of $34 billion and $40 billion
being scrubbed from the books
for non-transfer of authority funds for the Air Force
in respected years.
I'm not sure which year is the 34 and which year is the 40,
but just wiped off the books.
But then simultaneous to all of this,
if we're talking about octagonal shaped crafts
that can use electro-gravitics,
it's like China and Russia are like eating our lunch,
as far as I know, on hypersonics.
And so how do you kind of explain this?
I will say this.
And hypersonics are associated with the same contractors
that are associated with this issue.
Yeah, so it's always this question of
have we actually just stagnated
and this is just some softening of the enemy
sort of narrative or whatever.
I had an interesting meeting on Capitol Hill
and one of the things that was brought up
by a particular gentleman who knows of what's going on,
I'm not gonna say who he is,
but what he was able to figure out
and provide us during that meeting was Russia and China
have their own retrieval teams of non-human intelligence
and they have their own technologies, reverse engineered.
And they're pretty much on par with what we're doing.
And it's to the point to where we,
as in the United States assets that deal with this,
have gentlemen's agreement with both countries
to say if we target and shoot down NHI,
whatever team gets their first gets the prize.
Whatever team gets their second has to wave off.
And this person's a pretty high place in the government.
So the fact that that was established
because that was a theory of mine,
it's like we can't be the only people
that have this in this country.
But it's not even just these countries,
it's this organization which is transnational.
They just happen to exist in other countries
that are doing the same stuff we do here.
Do you think that this could bring us together?
I mean, you have rumors of like Reagan and Gorbachev.
This isn't even a rumor.
Gorbachev, Mikhail Gorbachev says in an interview
with Charlie Rose that he was sitting with Reagan
at some like UN event or something.
And Reagan, you know, whispers over in his ear.
He says, if the United States were attacked
by someone from outer space,
would you help us?
I said, no doubt about it.
He said, we do.
And so like, do you think there's any hope
of this not being this sort of game theory dynamic,
but actually sort of, you know,
creating kind of peace between the nations?
Or is that just totally naive?
I think the only way that we're gonna get full disclosure
is if we are peaceful to each other.
I think if everybody puts their fucking swords down
and understands that we have a bigger problem
to deal with here and it's bigger than ourselves,
this is the only way we're gonna gain ground.
The problem with this field,
if you wanna call UFOs or a community, right,
I don't even consider me a part of it.
I'm just somebody who saw something fucking crazy
and here you go.
So there's so much division.
There's so many factions with this where everybody thinks,
oh, this person's right, this person's wrong,
or this doesn't make sense, or this makes sense.
If everybody was to understand that
we're all trying to do the same thing
and we all group together,
we could get so much further along with this.
But everybody's like, oh, I hate this person because of this,
or I heard this about this person.
So, you know, he doesn't contribute anything.
We have to be uniting together to make this happen.
And that's the problem.
I don't think it will ever happen
unless everybody puts their damn swords down.
The quote unquote UFO community,
which I say, I think it's so cringe-worthy,
but it's like a reality TV show.
It's just this weird, I try to stay out of all of it,
but it's so bizarre.
I don't even pay attention to it because it's just,
you know what, I got more important shit to deal with,
such as either having these meetings
or trying to gain ground on this.
That's more my focus.
I don't give a shit what other people say in this community.
It's just like, you guys,
they can criticize people so easy,
but if they were ever called to go on Capitol Hill
to talk, they would never do it.
None of them would.
Do you feel like people have ever tried to co-opt you,
given your story?
Because, I mean, you signed something,
basically, with this Air Force Lieutenant Colonel,
where it's like your life is under threat
if you say something.
Well, now that they've passed these laws,
I mean, that doesn't apply.
I mean, I have had some blowback.
I've had harassment.
I haven't had direct threats that I'm aware of,
but other people have heard things,
but I can't confirm that.
But one of the instances,
so when I testified to Aero in April of 2023,
after that trip, I started having these helicopters
hover over my house or my dad's residence
for example, or over my business.
What sort of helicopters?
Some of them, most of the time, are Blackhawks.
And then there's one particular CH-47,
which is a dual-rotor helicopter.
It's Army variant that doesn't matter
where I'm at in the city.
If I move to a different area, it pops up there.
Really?
And this has been, and it's weird because you can,
I have Flightradar 24 where I can track these
because I had referenced this to Jake
almost several years ago,
explaining that this is what kind of harassment,
there's other people in the government as well
that were having harassment like that happen to them too.
And partially, I think that's why we can't rely
on government to do disclosure
because once they figure out what they're up against,
they're not gonna do that.
Something that has much more money than them,
has their own private military, has their own assets,
they're more cutting edge than compared to what we've got.
But it's a symbiotic relationship
because we need these contracting companies
to help build stuff for our defense programs,
which the government needs because this is what helps us
keep as a superpower in this country,
but it also curbs terrorism.
It curbs wars that we could have
in any other part of the world.
We need them.
So if we're to gut them from what they do best,
and that basically weakens us as well
because we need these companies to come up with our next
generation seven fighter jet whenever that comes out
or a new tank or new medical systems for military
or whatever it is that they do.
So gutting them would be something that would basically.
So you think they're actually producing a lot of innovation
because like society at large is stagnated
when it comes to tech.
Society has, but look at the military.
It's much more advanced because that's their focus.
That's the war machine.
So if they don't have a war.
But it also goes back and forth.
Like you hear these stories of like nukes
operating off floppy disks,
the story in like 2017 or something.
Yeah, I had talked about that.
It was something that I found out personally
was that they keep it archaic because it's harder to hack.
You can't, if you have a signal that goes up top side.
So that's intentional.
That's intentional.
Nor at operating offline.
So no system for each.
That's why they do it that way.
And some of these black sites work the same way.
So there was, whatever has to understand
is black sites operate independently.
Yes, they get funding from the government
with some research and development programs that they do,
but they operate entirely by themselves.
It's almost like its own country.
They got their own people to manage these things
like these refugees they get from these other countries
that they screen for P3 that don't make the cut.
Well, they have them as janitors, cooks,
people to maintain these facilities.
For every single operator,
you're gonna have 20 personnel
that are gonna basically support that operator
that are in these facilities, if that makes sense.
Such as a medical officer, whatever that is,
an admin people, payroll, if you will.
So there are people essentially missing all over the world.
Are these people willfully signing up to be psionic assets
or in certain cases are they being rounded up
against their will?
They're signing up to my understanding.
This is what I've been told over and over again
is that they volunteer for it.
Well, they get paid well.
And if you're in a country
where you don't get that much money
and you don't get to do anything cutting edge,
but you have a skillset that could be used
in a, it could be in a positive way.
Granted, we're not in these programs,
so we don't understand really what they do.
But if they were to do something that's fun,
that they put their skills to, they're gonna do it.
You know, anybody who's got the skills to do that.
And so you're saying their family
might be taken along to work as logistics
and maintenance and so forth.
Potentially, but I can't confirm that because, you know,
I haven't talked to a P3 refugee from, you know,
that was, oh yeah, my family came with.
No, I've never heard of that.
But then again, I would say it's entirely possible
if they're gonna take the people
that are essentially gonna make them money
or give them technologies, then why not?
Are there gifted and talented education programs in the US
that work as feeders to legacy UFO program?
That I cannot, I don't know that personally.
I have heard it from multiple people.
I know people who claim that they were a part of that,
but I can't personally talk about it
because I have no idea.
Do you know anything about this?
I only know one individual and that is Jordan,
who has talked about, you know, working on programs
and being in gate programs as a kid.
He's the only individual I know.
And it was interesting to see him come forward
with Sky Watchers.
So I always knew him by his previous suited in Martin.
So I'm interested to hear more from him about that.
What do you guys think about Aero generally?
This was the All Domain Anomalies Resolution Office.
I understand it was a front
for basically sifting through information
and plucking people to figure out what they know
and then either trying to shut them up
or just publicly dismiss the person,
you know, like I did with anybody that testified.
You know, they misconstrued all our stories.
What I understand now is that the director there
is really hell bent on getting the right information.
Now granted.
So do you like the, this is John Kozlowski,
who is formerly of the National Security Administration
and, or National Security Agency, sorry.
And before that, you had Kirkpatrick who like,
I don't know, one person in this world who likes,
you know, I think most people think he was sort of.
Anybody who's associated with them, of course,
are gonna like them because I'm pretty sure
they're getting paid the same.
But, you know, that's just what it is.
They're gonna stick up for their own guy.
So most people think, I think Kirkpatrick's
sort of a bad faith actor.
And then Kozlowski, the verdict's still out,
but you think maybe there's hope or.
From what I've heard from people dealing with him
on a personal level that he's for the right issue.
Was yet to be seen, but we will see.
I mean, like I've said, and Jake Stevens said the same thing,
you'll know them by their deeds.
And if they start doing good things,
then that could potentially bring us something to good.
But if they start doing things that we're not approving,
or, you know, that is not gonna help
with what we're trying to do,
then I would say it's definitely somebody
that we need to consider not even involving, you know?
I think the hardest part is figuring out
who's gonna be on the right side of history with this.
Yeah.
What do you, like, how do you position yourself now
to be on the right side of history?
I mean, clearly just by coming out, in my opinion,
I think you're showing courage
and on the right side of history.
But on a go-forward basis,
now that you're kind of implicated in the topic,
how do you position?
I mean, if I had a job around this
where I could contribute and bring the answers
and basically provide to the public that this is real,
I would enjoy that.
It's much more interesting.
Business-wise, it's always interesting,
but it ebbs and flows.
And the fact is this, you know,
when I have these meetings in D.C.
and with important people, it kind of like,
it always fuels my fire because I get to contribute
in a sense to actually help people understand
what they should be looking for.
And so when I get invited to partake in those meetings,
and I was like, okay, this is cool.
I get to meet very interesting people.
I get to meet people I never think I'd ever meet
because most people see these people on TV,
and it's like, oh yeah, there's this person here.
You know, he's part of the administration
or he's doing this.
So I think if I can contribute in a sense that's positive,
I think that that's what I can die leaving this earth
knowing that I tried to help get us somewhere better.
Because all I want from this is just for us to be better,
for us to have these technologies
that we could live a lot longer,
we can live happier, we can be healthier,
and we can be more knowledgeable
and can be at a higher consciousness.
Do you think that these technologies will ever come out?
And you know, we'll get-
Some of them are.
There's some rumors and speculation
from some reputable people.
I know that that's what they're trying to do.
And it's more medical-based technologies.
Like what?
So it's scalar technologies, right?
So this device, essentially all they do
is if you're not there presently,
they use a photo of you.
It could just be like a symmetrical photo of your face.
And they did this with my dog, for example,
because he, like I said,
he was diagnosed with some sort of bladder mass
that they thought was cancerous.
And then this scan,
it hits the body with around 886,000 different frequencies
to up to 1.2 million frequencies.
And then what it does
is when one of those frequencies registers or pings,
that specific ping tells you
that you have this specific element.
With this specific element,
it also talks about specific frequencies
that can terminate that specific cell.
And it can do this remotely via a photo.
Correct.
Now the caveat to this is that they could kill people
the same way by manifesting harmful cells
like fast-testing cancers.
Does that sound familiar?
Have you ever heard whistleblowers
or people trying to come forward
that got hit with this kind of shit
to get them to shut up or it kills them pretty quick?
You might know better than me.
James Allen, the documentarian of Mark McCandlish
and the Flexliner story.
He was diagnosed and dead
of an aggressive form of cancer in about three weeks.
Do you think that that was caused
by some sort of remote scalar weapon?
I'm more interested in the fact
his autopsy said he was poisoned with heavy metals.
So that almost sounds more prosaic,
like more like, you know, conventional or something.
But have you, so you've heard it,
you know specifics of people having hit,
been hit with cancer.
Yeah, but I can't talk about
the people I'm associated with on that
because I don't wanna-
Okay, that's scary.
It is scary.
The problem is that bullets and stuff like that are archaic.
They don't need that shit.
These weapon systems that they have
that they can turn into weapon systems with scalar
manifesting growths and cancers into your,
or they can fuck with your eyesight.
They could fuck with your brain.
You know, that's very real stuff.
So when they are able to use this technology
in a good sense,
there's always gonna be somebody who's bad
who wants to use the same technology in a harmful way,
which is why it's not public.
And, you know, it's not like these people that use it
that I know that have used it on me are like greedy people,
but they cure a lot of people.
And sometimes they cure, I've seen-
So you think that technology is gonna be
these scalar wave healing technologies
might be exfiltrated?
Well, yeah, there's always a flip side to everything.
In order to have good, you have to have bad.
This is what people don't understand.
Nothing's always ever good
and nothing's always ever selling bad.
All tech is dual use.
Correct.
It's AI.
We'll carve, right?
We'll go to the store and do this.
Some guy looks at it,
he's like, you know what, I'm gonna go run over 30 people.
Yeah, nuclear-free energy or nuclear bomb or, you know.
It's the same thing with this technology, you know.
It just depends on what the person wants to utilize it with.
A knife that can cut food for you
so you don't choke to death
or is the same person who's gonna go think ill of it
and go stab a bunch of people.
It is interesting when you say like the remote,
there's this guy, Joe Dispenza,
that does like, you know, self-actualization work.
And it's always like, you know,
you have these like remote healings
and like people concentrate on a photo and stuff.
And, you know, I don't know what to make of it.
I don't know what to make it of either,
but I know this device was pretty crazy, but it's great.
And, you know, so the type of frequencies,
so here's the thing that's cool about it.
So the frequencies that it pings,
and then it suggests, you know,
because it goes down to your DNA,
but then it goes all the way to the atoms
and molecules that make up your body.
And then it can also detect things
that haven't manifested yet, and it can curb that.
So for me, for example,
I didn't tell them my medical history,
but when they did the scan on me,
they found out everything about me
that I never told them.
Really?
And I didn't even know this about myself.
My dad's, you know, I was born with very thick blood.
And so I needed a transfusion when I was born.
My dad's like, yeah, you've had thick blood ever since.
So that showed up on the scanner.
You showed it too.
Because the reason why it showed up
because the way that my arteries and veins
are working harder because of having to pump the thick blood.
And then you talked about it with your dad.
You didn't even know.
I didn't even know.
He told me, he's like, yeah, well, you know,
I told him, I said, well, they said that I had thick blood.
And he says, yeah, you've had thick blood since you were a baby.
You had to get a transfusion.
And that's the reason why my arteries
and veins and capillaries.
They're definitely like quacky versions of this
that exist commercially right now.
There is, and it's called energy enhancement systems,
which are, you know, so you stand by these screens
or sit by these screens and the frequencies they hit you with
are supposed to be of healing frequencies.
I have yet to do that.
I can't say if it's legitimate.
It may be there's people I know that have had that done.
But with this particular device,
it's something that I really hope to God that this comes out.
Because you're saying there is a plan to exfiltrate it
for commercial use.
Yes, there is.
But then you're getting into something
that's like alternative medicine is what this will fall under
because Western medicine is so heavily involved with FDA
and having to do things regarding that with what they said.
Wouldn't this theoretically take out Big Pharma?
That's why they don't want to help.
Can you live forever on this thing?
Are there people in the UFO program
who are going to live to 300?
I mean, the person that one of the people that exists today,
and I don't know who they are,
they're probably on the first already part of living forever
in our world right now because of what the technology is.
That is a possibility.
Well, I would love to understand this stuff better
because it seems so prima facie absurd.
But I'm interested in this stuff.
And you can turn molecular mass into frequency.
That's not at all woo-woo to say in physics or biology.
And if you did take almost like a bank
of like this organ should be operating
at whatever optimum frequency, you could probably tune it.
There's a field called cymatics where with vibrations,
you can create sand structures
in like these vibrational plates.
And so you could theoretically,
and we know that cellular communication occurs
via voltage gated ion channels.
And so you can, the field,
there is a bioelectric field to everybody.
These are all sort of facts.
And so theoretically with acoustics
and electromagnetic fields,
you could affect bodily functions.
How you do that in a precise way to heal people,
that feels very hard for me to understand.
Well, it's hard for me to understand
because again, like I said, I was not exposed to this.
So the first scan took 12, 12 and a half hours.
I was in this chair and they were sitting there working
like literally overnight.
And you're sure this isn't really good counterintel
like the subway order?
No, this is not a good counterintel.
This was something that was used on me
in a sense to one, build trust with this particular person,
but also to understand that this is something that is real
and it's something that can benefit humanity.
I'm more interested in that.
I don't, yeah, the UFO stuff's cool because they fly.
The medical shit, the stuff that we could also do
with this technology is gonna be far more advanced.
Even with consciousness, I mean, that's more mind blowing
than just watching a craft fly.
I'm sorry, but people are so enamored with those.
But it's like, that's the boring part of it.
Jake's even said the same thing.
Yeah, totally, yeah.
So the first treatment was 12 hours of hook to this.
So I fell asleep.
They gave me a stem cells in the same process
and exosomes, which was good.
They also took my blood because it was thick.
So they put it under a microscope to see how thick it is.
It's pretty thick, but being on hormone replacement therapy
and having to do blood dumps and stuff like that
is what I keep up with it.
Plus they told me to take baby aspirin, 81 milligrams
or micrograms, if you wanna call it that,
daily to help with it.
So I didn't even know that.
Instead I had osteoporosis.
Well, I don't drink milk.
I hate milk, milk.
I mean, I like stuff that has milk like cheese and ice cream,
but it hates me.
Yeah, some days it's worth it, some days it's not.
So it knew that about me.
There's a bunch of other things that it said
that it was able to detect.
And you've never seen the machine?
I have never seen the machine.
This was last year, late February, early March.
But you felt that it healed your dog
and it healed something with you, too?
It healed something with me.
I had parasites.
I didn't even know because I started getting
very bad heartburn.
My stomach, my appetite was shit.
I couldn't eat. Really?
I was wondering what it was.
I was like, okay, well, I need to take this medication
and it didn't make it any better.
Then when I got the scan and it got rid of the parasites
because it listed three different types.
And you felt better immediately?
I felt like I was like 20 years old again.
Whoa.
And this was happened over a week.
So part of it, so 12 hours was the first one,
roughly six hours, the second one,
and then the destruction sequence that they do
using these frequencies to target the parasites
and to kill off the bad cells took about four and a half hours.
What they also do on this device is they program
purified water because water in itself,
if you look through ancient history,
also is a conductor for the body,
just like anything else in our life.
So they program this water and then basically
you ingest it twice a day, morning and evening.
There's no medications.
They didn't have to cut me open.
They didn't have to do any of that.
And everything that they scanned me of was resolved.
Can I speak to these people?
I can get you in touch with these people, yes.
It's only word of mouth, so don't put their information out
if they decree to it, but they'll ask you questions
and they will basically, you know,
they want to know who you are first,
which if you're Jesse Michaels,
everybody knows who you are in this,
and I'm sure they do too.
So with my dog, like I said, my dad took him to the vet
because I gave him to my dad when I was competing
because I had a full-time job
and then having to train for a show
which took about four to five hours a day
on top of a 12, 13 hour job was not fair to my dog.
So I gave him to my dad.
So my dad took him to the vet
and they said that he had a bladder mass
and it was looking like cancer.
So they're like, yeah, you got to go to an oncologist
to figure out what it is.
He didn't want to do that.
So I told my dad, I said, hey,
this isn't gonna sound fucking nuts, but hear me out.
So I explained a little bit to him,
at least what he understands.
And so I got in touch with these people and said,
hey, dog's not looking too good.
Can you guys do anything with animals?
And they said, yes, they can do cats and dogs right now
and humans.
They're trying to do other, like bovine, for example,
or horses is something they may be able to do
at some point, cause they're always refining.
And I don't know how they do this.
So they told me to take a,
so my dad sent me a picture of his face
as a very recent photo.
So I did that.
My dad had told me within a matter of weeks
because I started giving him this other stuff
that they have, which is like a blue,
is like a nano blue, for example.
So what this blue stuff does is that you ingest it
and it starts to basically kill all the bacteria
and viruses inside your body.
So it makes it easier for this treatment
to take effect as well.
So I told my dad, I said,
okay, give him one ML in the morning every day
and then they're gonna do the treatments.
So they did about four or five treatments on him.
Said he wasn't looking too good,
but then they started doing the more treatments
and with this blue.
And he was, when he would urinate,
it was very small because his bladder was taken out.
Now he'll sit there forever
just trying to get everything out.
There was no surgery involved.
Like I said, he had cloudy eyes because he's getting old.
They got rid of all that.
He's like a puppy again.
And his appetite is still the same.
You know, he was, some days he wasn't feeling too good
where he was, didn't wanna move.
I mean, cause he's 13, 14 years old almost.
Now it's a different story.
And knowing that this exists,
my grandma was basically like my mom to me.
And she raised me.
She ended up dying from pancreatic cancer.
That was the stage where when they found it.
If I could, if I would have known about this,
then somebody like her, I could have had helped
and they could have done something about it.
Now granted, talking about curing cancer is very iffy
and it also depends on obviously
what side of the fence you sit on.
I know from my experience with what it did for me
and what it did for my dog, completely cured us.
I do not doubt that this would be something
that could help people that are literally losing
their lives over illnesses.
And the reason for not putting this out super publicly,
like right now is the dual use implication?
Dual use, but also the FDA.
This technology exists with these people.
It could really be profound and change this,
but you have big pharma that's more interested
in getting this money.
And that's the thing that upset me with COVID
because obviously per diagnosis,
these doctors are getting somewhere
from 16 to 30 grand per fucking diagnosis.
It's like, yeah, so of course there's incentive
for you guys to literally mark everything as COVID.
So anybody in the medical industry,
if you're gonna do the right thing,
start thinking on an ethics.
This is the problem with this world today.
It's because of greed, it's because of the incentives
that people get and it's because people wanna
be selfish about it.
And the overlap in financial interests
between big pharma and big food is extremely high.
That's why I want RFK to do what he's doing.
I have the same.
Well, I think the FDA governs both food and drugs.
And on the food side, it's extremely laissez-faire and loose.
And so you have all these chemicals that are allowed
in our food, things like glyphosate,
which are probably autoimmune or cancer-causing.
They're like, glyphosate is very close to Agent Orange.
It's just horrible for you.
And we have all these things that are allowed in the US
that are banned in Europe.
And so on that side, on the food side,
we're very laissez-faire.
And then on the drug side, once people get extremely sick
and the big pharma companies are profiting
off of these biochemical solutions
for whatever their ailments are,
it's extremely hard to get new drug innovation
or anything passed through the FDA.
So this side is then super strict.
When you should be throwing the Hail Mary
because you're already really sick,
the restrictions should be very wide.
It should actually be like, let's try.
Let's try everything.
Electromagnetic, whatever, because sound healing, whatever.
But then, so you can't pass anything by the FDA here.
And then here, everything goes to make you sick.
So it's just completely perverse.
Well, and that's the thing.
So if they're working hand-in-hand
trying to make more patients, because guess what?
A patient cured is a patient lost.
Yeah, totally.
They lose money off that.
So of course, we're gonna keep people sick.
Do you guys think more whistleblowers will come out
and the consensus will shift on this topic?
It feels like even shows like podcasts like Joe Rogan's,
which traditionally have covered this stuff,
I think when it was less activity was involved
and it was easier to make sense of
because there were a few kind of hot button stories
that you either had an opinion on
for, again, those like Bob Lazar or whatever.
And now they're, I think, extremely confused.
They feel like the zone is being flooded.
And my basic understanding,
based on the way he speaks on his podcast,
he's kind of suspicious of the whole thing.
Well, he should be.
I'm not saying every whistleblower's gotta be trusted.
I mean, there's people out there trying to get rich.
I get it.
They're trying to find a livelihood.
If so be it, you're gonna be found out.
But at the same time, yes, be skeptical.
The thing with it too is that
these people really need to put egos aside.
This is part of the reason why we have this problem.
Everybody on Capitol Hill thinks they know
what the fuck's going on because they're senators
or so-and-so or they're the president
or they're secretary of defense or all this.
You guys are removable pawns
that are gonna have an expiration of your terms
and they're gonna go living your normal life
and some other person's gonna step into your point.
They're gonna do the same thing you're doing.
So it's really just interchangeable people.
This is a reason why secrecy exists
because they would rather have people
who are permanently involved stay at that level
instead of just having somebody interchanged, right?
Two or three terms, you're out.
Or as a president, you're not gonna know much
because you're gonna literally just go out
and do whatever you're gonna do
after becoming the president.
If there's this sort of shadow government
vis-a-vis these UFO programs, who's the president of that?
Or is it-
Somebody that nobody knows.
And it's somebody that has a hell of a bankroll
that nobody could ever understand or imagine.
And they probably more than likely
do not live in this country
because if they were smart, they'd be somewhere else.
Do you have any-
Yeah, we hypothesize somebody like Dick Cheney.
Yeah, but he would be-
Top of the pyramid, not-
Yeah, but Dick Cheney would be the representative
of something else.
It's gonna be somebody that nobody knows,
that's never, nobody knows their face,
nobody knows they even exist.
It won't be a politician.
I would wager that maybe 10 to 20 total people
in the world have the full picture
of the UAP legacy program.
And they got more funding than everybody
that they could ever imagine.
I also understand the Joe Rogan orientation towards it
because it's so, the whole, the UAP thing is so weird.
You have on the one hand, like, you know,
this sort of like Tim Taylor, NASA,
like all this sort of like strange, you know,
summoning stuff around, you know, UFO,
or sorry, around rocketry, like in the history of rocketry.
And then you have this other stuff of like, you know,
aerospace, black aerospace and like saucers and hangers
and like nuts and bolts, propulsion updates,
that sort of thing.
And then you have like, what are the NHI themselves
and like the ontology there
and kind of the metaphysical dimension
of like Jacques Vallee and Diana Pasulka
and like what we're dealing with and is it spiritual?
And it's just extremely confusing.
Well, and I mean, it could be intentionally
provided that it's confused, you know,
or to bring confusion.
So, I mean, that's kind of where we have to kind of
be very careful to navigate that.
You only know what you're exposed to.
And then again, whoever is exposed to something
could be fed misinformation to say,
hey, go ahead and say this.
Thank God I didn't have that problem, you know.
There was suspicion when Jake approached me
that it was like, okay, maybe this might be the case.
But then he's been very transparent about his role,
you know, being a red team asset pretty much
to try to bump whistleblowers
and figure out who's got what.
And you're sure, you know,
I've got pretty good impression from him in my interview,
but you're sure he's not still, you know, red teaming?
Like, there was this moment in my interview
where I was like, how do we know
you're not red teaming us right now?
Well, you don't, you don't know that.
You really don't.
That was an honest answer.
Yeah, you don't know that.
And so I, and all I can do,
I expect to get asked that a lot.
It's like, you know, I'll paraphrase a book
from Matthew, I think it is.
Like, you will know me by my fruits.
Well, there's, what does he really have
to benefit from red teaming if he's public?
He's out there.
I mean, and not only that, but he...
Well, if I'm playing devil's advocate,
it could be, you know, controlled opposition or, you know.
For what, though?
I don't, for the program.
Because he's trying to prove the exit.
For the program.
Because he's trying to prove this is real.
That's his whole thing.
And he's helping, he's trying to get government
and institutions to help with that.
Somebody's not gonna be in a disinformation campaign
just to have government involved.
And then just to, you know,
everybody's trying to prove it's real.
So is Jake, which we all know it's real.
But in the consensus of the planet,
I think if everybody understood that it was real,
then they'd actually be the first role they can get over.
What do you guys think?
And, you know, I think that's a very noble aim.
What do you guys think is, like, the disclosure moment?
Like, because you think, you would think that a guy saying,
I retrieved a UFO would be the disclosure moment.
But that, you know, I think a lot of people,
like, my video on this guy only has like a half million views
and there are like 350 million people in this country.
And so, you know.
Again, it depends on what side of the fence you sit on.
Some people need disclosure to be something
that they have to witness firsthand.
Nothing wrong with that.
There's some people that, yes, they can take tidbit
information that I've provided to say, OK, yeah,
reverse engineered or something.
For me, that was disclosure.
Yeah, if I saw that thing, hum it.
That was disclosure.
That'd be it, yeah, yeah.
I would have trouble keeping a day job.
Like, you have a couple of businesses.
Like, I'd be like, I'd turn into a fiend,
like, trying to figure out exactly what that is.
Sometimes business gets fucking boring
and then you're like, man, I wonder what's going on over here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Start trying to research into stuff.
I'd spend the rest of my life trying
to take a ride on that thing.
I mean, if that ever happens, I'd be like,
Jesse, don't say anything, but meet me at this point.
I mean, you know, it's up in the air what our future holds.
It's up to us to create the future.
That's really what it is.
Do we want to continue living on the past,
going the same kind of habits and rituals that people do?
Or do we actually want to evolve and actually
be a better person at the end of the day
and help change the world?
Disclosure is going to help change the world.
And hopefully for the better, and that's
something that's going to be taken astray
and weaponized somehow like it already has been.
Yep, yep.
Is there something about, so it's
the people with psionic assets, when Jake even said this
on my show, where it's like, you know, their diets,
their sense of community, they're being tapped into sort
of, you know, they don't live in this kind of materialist,
reductionist framework where like this stuff is actually
more kind of second nature to them.
Is there something about the land itself?
Like you think about places like, you know,
Skinwalker Ranch to come to Washington, Sedona.
People just report like weird stuff.
Well, some of the first CE5 stuff I've seen
was in Sedona with Greer's team.
We were with Demi Lovato and her...
That's an absurd sentence.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it.
We were with Demi Lovato and Steven Greer.
She was cool to me, you know, she was cool to me,
but you know, she's had her troubles just like we all have.
So you can't really hold her accountable for that.
That's her own thing.
But, you know, it was cool to talk to her
and see what she believes on this subject, you know,
and this reaches everybody, you know what I mean?
So it's all walks of life coming up to a certain point
to understand that we're acknowledging something
greater than ourselves.
You know, so seeing the stuff that happened out there
was pretty wild.
What did happen out there with...
With Salt Orbs?
Steven Greer.
So we went to this, I'm not going to name it
because, you know, just in case she ever goes back here
when people trying to like, you know,
from what I understand, she comes here routinely.
But it was a cool place in Sedona.
And so we ended up setting up a circle in two different parts.
One was off grid, one was at this place.
And so the first night we were there in this off grid place,
just off of a trail road,
nobody knew we were the fuck out there.
And there was like two o'clock in the fucking morning, right?
So I'm sitting there fucking falling asleep, you know,
and I'm having to, you know, drive everybody.
And at least, you know, unless Greer was doing that,
but most of the time I was driving us.
So we're sitting there and the way that we are seated
is everybody has a part of the sky that they're looking at
or the surrounding area.
So where I'm facing, I see Greer.
Demi's friend is over here.
Demi's like right here.
Paula, she's somebody in the UFO field
or something, she's some author, I can't remember her name.
Paula Harris.
Yeah, Paula Harris, she wrote the Trinity book
with Jacques Vallee, Italian.
She was there too, she's a good lady.
She actually lives kind of close to where we live.
Cool.
She was there, Demi's fiance was there,
and then Demi's good friend was there.
And then Demi's mom was there,
who's very sweet and very cool.
She's very short, but she's a good lady.
Both of, you know, so we're sitting there,
we're seeing orbs, we're seeing, you know,
disc-shaped craft appear in and out.
Really?
Gold color.
Wow.
And then I don't know what the hell this was.
So I was sitting there and then, you know,
obviously we're way apart from each other.
Yeah.
Something just fucking slaps me
on the side of the, on my side very hard.
It wasn't a fucking animal.
It wasn't any of them because I'm like observing everything
and they're saying shit's happening behind me.
And I'm like, okay, well, I can't see,
but then I'm trying to stay over here
to see if there's anything coming on over here.
And something hit me really hard on the side.
And you don't know what it was?
I don't know what the fuck it was.
And was it, does it correlate with a UFO sighting?
I don't, yeah.
They were saying that there was stuff was behind me and shit,
but then all of a sudden it's sometimes just like hard.
They were saying stuff was behind you,
like what was behind you?
Orbs, shapes, blue, white color, stuff like that.
And you just felt something knock into you?
I just felt something literally just like this,
like harder than that on my side.
And it fucking jumped.
I'm like, what the fuck was that?
So I don't know what it was.
What do you say to the people that say Greer is like,
I don't know, holographically like displaying stuff?
Oh, if that's the case,
sign the fuck up and pay the money because this guy,
I mean, he, this is what he dedicates his life to.
He gave up his medical career to do this kind of stuff.
So yes, does he need to provide a living?
I'm pretty sure everybody watching this show,
if they're interested in UFOs,
they're not gonna do it for free
when they got bills to pay and the families to pay.
But is he faking any of these?
He is not faking this shit.
There's people who say, oh,
you know how many op-eds are against Greer publicly
to say that this stuff isn't real
that are a part of these programs trying to say it's not?
Interesting.
With any other final things or what you wanna add?
Well, you know, and it's just, you know,
I want people to keep an open mind,
but I don't want people to understand that,
you know, whatever side of the field you're gonna be on,
just understand that we're trying to get something done here
and it's gonna happen with or without everybody.
If they wanna help and support, great.
If not, stay the fuck out of our way.
We'll handle it ourselves, like we've been doing.
Anything?
I don't think so.
Okay, Michael, this is an honor, man.
I appreciate you taking the time.
This is a blast.