Over the last 48 hours, I read your entire book, The Extra Tempestrial Model, blew my
mind.
Awesome.
I think it is, it makes so much sense and you do such a good job of laying out probably
the most reasonable explanation I've ever heard to these alien abduction accounts and
these UFO experiences that people have with beings.
Can you sort of just like lay out how you got into this whole thing and how you got
interested in this?
Yeah, no, it's kind of a long and winding road to say the least.
This started similar to a lot of people's experience with the cover of Whitley Strieber's
book.
Right, right back there.
As you have displayed on your shelf, it was sitting out just like that on, in the house
I grew up in, it was sitting on a living room shelf, faced out just like that, maybe as
a conversational piece, I don't know, because my biological father saw a UFO late at night
with another individual.
He was a veterinarian in rural Ohio, kind of northeast Amish country, and he described
it as this ball of light.
It wasn't emitting rays, like you look at a street light and it's kind of got the rays
coming out, but he said him and this colleague crested a hill, they could see it off in the
distance, not too far, maybe five, six hundred meters or so, and then all of a sudden it
shot toward their truck, hovered there above them for a little bit, shot back across the
horizon, maybe another five or six seconds and straight up into the sky at tremendous
speed.
And I overheard him telling this story to some friends at our house, I was kind of sneaking
downstairs late at night because there was stuff going on and I was like an eight year
old kid, so I was curious what was happening, it was right around that time that Whitley's
book came out, he got it, it was on the living room shelf, and there were a number of things
about that, just hearing the account to start with, like A, it's Amish country, there's
no lights, Amish don't use lights, B, it's not moving like any conventional craft, C,
he's talking about UFOs, never heard of that, that piqued my interest, but even beyond that,
when I walked into the living room and saw that book on the shelf, it sort of triggered
this image in my head, and I described this in both my first two books, because it was
the origin point for this little rabbit hole that I've spent my entire life going down
pretty much, where I imagined or saw in my mind's eye an early hominin form, like a chimpanzee,
in the middle was this modern human form, I put it on a koozie too, and then on the
right was this quintessential alien, like on the cover of Whitley's book, and obviously
that's kind of a cheeky character of what I saw, but it gets the point across, and it
got the point across to me, that's all it took, and I had this sort of awareness or
this thought, what if we're all related, what if we look like we do because we came from
this early primitive form, and what if we go on to look like them in our future, and
it sort of shaped the rest of my life from that point, I chose the majors I did in college
to look into this further, I did the research that I did as part of my graduate work and
even after graduate school in my normal anthropological career, looking at craniofacial anatomy, human
evolution, how the eye interacts with the brain and the face in a functional sense,
in a biomedical sense, but also just how all of these things change together, and what
if we project that forward, these same dominant trends that characterize the last six to eight
million years, project those forward, are we going to look like them, and then it obviously
went a lot further into other fields, but that was sort of the impetus for it, that's
what got me started.
So how long did you study biological anthropo- I don't know how to say it.
Yeah, biological anthropology, it used to be called physical anthropology, which was
way easier to pronounce.
Anthropology.
Yeah, it's anthropology.
Biological anthropology, easy for you to say.
Yeah, well, physical was easier, but actually it was just about four or five years ago that
we changed from the APAA to the ABAA, the American Biological, yeah, it doesn't really
matter, but I don't know why we did that, honestly, because there's been physical anthropology
for a century, and all of a sudden we're the American Association of Biological Anthropologists,
so I screwed that up.
And how long did you study it for, what kind of degree do you have in there?
I got a PhD, I started out in physics and astronomy because I was interested in the
are these time machines question, and I was going to pursue that.
And then my sophomore year, I remember it vividly, I was standing behind Morton Hall,
which is the physics and astronomy lecture hall, the actual department was located elsewhere,
and yeah, I was just standing back there by myself, and all of a sudden it was like, you
know, this kind of drive to switch, like what if we looked at the biological side, what
if we looked at the beans instead of the craft?
And from that point on, I switched my major, and yeah, it's been great, I've gotten to
travel the world, work at archaeological sites, three and a half million year old site in
Makhpansgarh, South Africa, for two seasons, a Neanderthal site in Shapenoa, Jeansak, in
the Bordeaux region of southern France, and yeah, go all over the world and study skulls,
and it's been fun, even outside of this underlying question of could they be us?
Where are we going morphologically?
But it's just, it's a really interesting field in general, I find it fascinating.
To you, what is the most compelling evidence that these typical alien beings that we see,
like for instance, on the cover of Whitley's book, are us?
Well, I mean, perhaps I'm biased in the sense that this is what I've been looking at since
I was eight or nine, like I wasn't going and digging up bones and measuring them or anything
back then, but I had sort of been thinking about this, and obviously switched my major
to study this, and it was more about, it's hard because we're at a place now where we
say, well, we have cockpit videos of the craft, we've acknowledged those, there's still debates
about what they might be, you know, is it lens flare or some other, seagulls, swamp
gas has been a common one throughout history, but the question of who's inside is still
kind of on the fringe, but to me, I don't see it that way.
I think at least as far as what I've been looking at, that's the best evidence of future
humans, the craft themselves, and we could talk about this as well if you want, do seem
to have a form consistent with the function of manipulating space-time and creating closed
timeline curves, so there's a technological continuity aspect too, but for me and my research,
it's the extremely ubiquitous description of a humanoid form, and I've said a million
times if what got out of these craft was, you know, an eight-legged squid-spider type
of creature, never would have got into this, but they're so consistently described in very
hominid terms, bilateral symmetry, two gut openings, eyes, nose, mouth in the same location,
pentadactyly having five digits at the end of each limb, four limbs in general, tetrapods
going back 400 million years, and then characteristics indicative of the continuation of long-standing
trends on this planet, going back six to eight million years ago since we stood upright,
bigger heads, larger eyes, smaller faces, less hair, thin bodies, less pigmentation
to their skin, just this incredible suite of characteristics that seem to indicate that
they're not just related to us phylogenetically, but they are part of the hominin clade and
specifically toward the future of where we are now.
With that said, there is obviously variation. There's a lot of variation in what people
describe.
Yeah, some people describe four fingers, right? Like, Willie, I think, said that.
Yeah, and that could be very much an atrophy of our fifth digit. The fifth phalanges just
maybe shrinks down. I don't know. It's pretty small, and also maybe I have especially small
pink hair.
My pinky toe is, like, almost not there. It's so tiny. It's, like...
You're the future, man. You got to get out there and reproduce. You're at least going
to get us into there.
Yeah, I'm saying I could be, like, maybe a hybrid or something.
I wouldn't doubt it. Some look into it, for sure. And, you know, there are... There's
variation not just in the physical form, like we're talking about, in us, but there's variation
in what's described, what people see. So I don't think this theory explains all of it,
but I do think it explains the humanoid forms with the extenuation of traits indicative
of our hominid past. And I also point out, I wasn't aware of this when I published my
first book, unfortunately, but the Dr. Edgar Mitchell free study at the time surveyed something
like 3,200 contactees and abductees as well, so individuals who have been on the ships.
And they asked them specifically if they had observed non-human intelligence, and they
used that term, NHI, non-human intelligence, which biases the question. So they should
have used a different one, something more... Something less leading, I guess you should
say. And it's hard with surveys, you know, because you're trying to get people to think
about, well, what was it, and put in those terms, and that's the common term. But much
like extraterrestrial, we should kind of pull back from that and use terminology that is
less leading. I'm with Whitley. I use visitor, traveler, things like that more recently to
advocate for that as well. So anyway, what they found is individuals who are taken on
these ships, the majority saw humans. They described them as human, even though the question
specifically asked non-human intelligence. So just like us. After that, the next most
common was the short grays, and then the tall grays, and then hybrids rounded it out. About
5% were non-hominin forms, something like apparitions or these mantis-type beans. And
I always point out, too, that with the mantids, if they have four limbs, they're still more
in the hominin clade than they would be in an insect, which has six limbs. So that's
an important distinction, too. But my point is that based on the definition of a hominin,
an upright walking primate, we're in the primate order. We stand up on two limbs. We're not
only the only primate that does that. We're the only mammal on this planet that habitually
walks on two limbs. We're the only biped. I think there's a compelling point in your
book. You mentioned that there's two million catalogued species on Earth, and 20 of them
are hominids, and one of those 20 are upright walking hominids. And it was like .001% are
the upright walking hominids. And then we are the ones who generated the technology
that could get off the planet. Yeah, and even ask these questions. So just looking at how
rare, or how we don't know, it could be non-existent, life is in the universe apart from us, just
how rare we are on this planet that is so packed with life. How would we know that life
would be anything resembling what we are anywhere else in the world? Especially if a lot of
the other worlds that are out there in Goldilocks zones that are habitable for life are mostly
water worlds. What would animals look like in water worlds? Not like us.
That's a great point. And there's so many other variables to the distance from their sun. Are
they in a singular binary star system? Are they nitrogen-based or carbon-based like we are? Do
they have anything even closer resembling DNA? What are the chances they would get AGCT in the
same nucleotide linkages that we have that structures all life on this planet? Some viruses
have RNA, but they're not living because they need something else to replicate in a host,
but every other living organism on this planet, I'll get in trouble for that because some people
think viruses are alive and I get a lot of hate mail. Do they really? Yeah. That and free
will. If I say viruses aren't alive, or they're not living organisms, and I say some about free
will, I get a lot of hate mail, but I'm used to it at this point. Anyway, it's not just all of
these other variables, whether they be celestial, do they have a moon? Do they have a large planet
like Jupiter that sucks up all of the asteroids that would hit them otherwise like we do? We're
so fortunate here in our solar system, but even outside of that, I did a study in 2016 looking at
all of the planets that have been found as part of the Kepler mission, and based on the stats of
planetary size, their mass, only 2.2% of them were the same size or smaller than Earth. I redid it
in 2022 with new data, we're up to over 5,000, but we're pretty close to six or seven now,
based on the planetary habitability study from the University of Puerto Rico,
Arecibo, one of the big dish that collapsed a couple years ago. Right, right. Yeah, what was
the story with that Arecibo? It was a signal that we sent out? Yeah, we sent, I think it was in the
70s, maybe it was our first big broadcast. There was some debate, like, should we be broadcasting
our existence here? Because we could, you know, bring in all of these evil extraterrestrials that
want to treat us like we treated people and we discovered other civilizations on this planet.
I think Hawkein was one of the big proponents of that. But the point of doing the study was
to show, in concert with what Dr. Latimer, who used to be the director of the Cleveland Museum
of Natural History, called the perils of being bipedal. We suffer from all kinds of problems with
our necks, our backs, difficulty in childbirth, blown out knees, hernias, varicose veins, hemorrhoids,
all of these problems we suffer from are the direct result of standing upright. But the benefits
that we get from standing upright outweigh the costs that come with bipedalism. But it is rare
here, like you said, we're the only ones that do it habitually. And if it's rare here, based on the
fact that between two and four and a half percent of all other planets that we've identified so far,
which is a decent sample, are much, much larger than Earth. And it's hard to do here on a very
small planet, relatively speaking, with only 9.8 meters per second squared of gravity, the acceleration
pulling down on us. It's going to be very, very unlikely on any other planet based on the limited
sample that we have. But if we can extrapolate that out, it's not likely that you're going to
get bipedalism on other planets. So even in addition to all these other factors that you've
mentioned, and I threw in some on top of just the fact that they're bipedal, they're reported as
being bipedal in almost every case, I think is an indication that we have a phylogenetic relationship.
When I'm down on all fours, it's only because I've dropped my Mando in the shower. Otherwise, Danny's
a bipedal walking scent machine that dusts each room with bourbon leather in such volume that suggests
he applies it more often than a teenage jock who just discovered that girls don't wink at the stink.
You've heard me talk about Mando before. And when I was stranded on an island for 13 days with no
water, a bearded man walked up to me and scrubbed my whole body with this mysterious bar and said,
thou shall be taken care of for 72 hours. It's clinically proven. Yeah, I couldn't believe it
either. But it turns out it's aluminum free, baking soda free, cruelty free and vegan. And it's
developed by a doctor who saw that people were misdiagnosed with BO. And he said, I shall save
thou pits and packages. There he is. That's him. That's the island bearded Mando man. Mando comes
in four manly flavors, bourbon leather, clover woods, Mount Fuji and pro sport. What is that
you got there, Danny? I got the Mando bourbon leather right here. This is what I scrub my bum
with every day. If you like Danny, Danny likes me and I like you, then that's just a coincidental
bonus to what it's like to have Mando radiating from the happy moist cracks of your body. The
other day I was doing some jujitsu in this hot fort of heat and I got this really big guy in a
leg lock. Then he complimented my butt for smelling so pretty. In fact, I smelled so pleasant. It gave
him the strength to leg lock me. He didn't have any deodorant on at all. It was like being strangled
by a boiled onion. I love sniffing Mando in the morning. Others do too, which is why our listeners
can sniff their very own package wherever you are right now with our special discount. Mando starter
pack is perfect for new customers. It comes with a solid stick deodorant, cream tube deodorant,
two free products of your choice, like mini body wash and deodorant wipes and free shipping. And
luckily I have a discount code to help you get hooked on my favorite smelling whole body deodorant
on the market. New customers get $5 off the starter pack with our exclusive code that equates to over
40% off your starter pack. Use code Danny at shopmando.com. That's code D-A-N-N-Y at S-H-O-P-M-A-N-D-O.com.
Grab your package with us and we'll make Mando our clean little secret. It's linked below. Now back
to the show. Is the idea that gravity would be way stronger on those planets that are larger?
Yeah, it's all about mass. Many of them are super earths. They're many thousands of times larger
than earth. Some are close, but even a little bit of mass increase, even going to one point. And I
did in doing this study, I went up to 1.5 the mass of earth just to have a little cushion there,
saying, well, what if we went up 0.15 the size of earth more, which is a little generous, I think,
because bipedalism is almost non-existent here. But I did allow for that and it was still in
between 2 and 4%. So you think that, I mean, obviously you've studied the evolution of our
species extensively. And you seem to think, you believe that if you go way back millions of years
ago to our early ancestors and where we are now, you can project out what we're going to look like
in a million years and a couple hundred thousand years. And you think that that would be
what these aliens look like with huge eyes, big heads, no muscles, skinny, small bodies.
And what makes you think that we would look like that? And what would be the
environmental conditions that would make us evolve that way?
Right. Well, yeah, there's a couple of things to unpack there. I don't want to get too technical,
or maybe I can and people can just fast forward to this part. But it's good to have it out there,
I guess, if people want the information. But so in looking at the specifics of our evolution,
Kim, a lot of people would write to me and be like, yeah, this makes sense. You know,
we'll blow up this planet, we'll have to live in space or go underground. So that's why our
eyes would get bigger because we have to see in the dark or whatever. Maybe, I don't know.
But that's speculation. And I tried to avoid speculating in these books and instead focus on
long term trends that are understandable in the context of the length of those trends and what
happens. And we might be able to extrapolate those a little bit. And I do that. But extrapolation
isn't necessarily the same thing as speculation, because we have data that can back up that trend
and then see how that would move forward in the future. So a couple of important ones are
obviously brain size. Going back to the time of Australopithecus africanus right between when we
stood up right and where we are now, their brains are bigger, right? Much, much smaller.
Oh, really? They were bigger. 3.5 million years ago, they were third the size of ours,
they're about 420 cubic centimeters. On average, the modern human brains between 1400 and 1600
cubic centimeters. So about the third the size of our own about the same size as chimpanzee,
little bit bigger than a child. It wasn't until we get beyond the Australopithecines homo habilis,
you see a little jump. And then with homo erectus throughout the time of homo erectus,
we start to see an accelerating curve, where it gets bigger and bigger by the time you get
to Heidelbergensis, Rudolfensis, Bodensis, all of those. It's getting to the point where
they look more modern. Their postcranial skeleton is almost the same as ours. It's a little more
robust based on where they live and what they did. But their cranial facial anatomy is still
pretty primitive. They have a prognathic face, a low sloping forehead, big brow ridges, simply
because their forehead hasn't, their brain hasn't grown out over top the eyes yet. And in addition
to us being the only biped, we're also the only mammal with a brain that sits right on top of the
eyes. And it's interesting. Yeah, it's something that I took this study of craniofacial evolution
and applied it in a biomedical context to see if that the two main changes throughout hominid
evolution are an increase in brain size, it moves forward and expands medial laterally.
And one of the characteristics that defines anatomically modern homo sapiens is we have
neurocranial globularity, our brains expanded to the extent that we have like bobbleheads basically,
and our faces are shrunk back. So we have this trade off between the brain and the face. Brain
grows out, expands, face gets smaller, teeth get smaller, and we have a chin. As that happens,
we have what's called a mental eminence, where our teeth and our masticatory muscles retract
and recess so much that we have a little chin that sticks out. Right. And this has a lot to do,
I'm from what I understand, this has a lot to do with the way we ate in our diets back then,
like chewing meat all the time. Yeah, and tool use too. We started to be able to cut our meat,
we could cook our meat, which was a big one. Going back 1.8 million years ago, we started using fire.
And we can also process our food, we can cut into smaller strips, we can cook it, we can pound up
fibrous plant materials. There was an offshoot here, if you pull out on that.
Where are they? I guess they didn't include them on there. Oh, they're there. Boisei,
Garhi, and Robustus, those ones in the middle there. Those are all called robust australopithecines,
because they- Can you punch in on that, Steve?
They did the opposite. What they have, and you can even see on the australopithecus boisei,
this little ridge running from around the top, that's called a sagittal crest. You see that in
gorillas too. And gorillas are vegetarians. They mostly feed on nettle, and they have these big
bellies because they have to break down that fibrous plant material. They have to spend a
lot of time chewing it. And these guys went that route. They went the vegetarian route, like gorillas.
We went the omnivore route, started eating meat, and that helped our brains get bigger,
and likely we killed them off, maybe even ate them. The meat made our brains get bigger?
It's called the expensive tissue hypothesis, where because of the way we can break down
the proteins in meat and turn it into the sugars that we need for our brain, we see not just a
decrease in our gastrointestinal system around this time, but also that's when our brains started to
get bigger. So Lesley Aiello in South Africa proposed that, I think back in the 90s, called
it the expensive tissue hypothesis. But you can see it here. They were a dead end. They have no
living descendants. Who? Which ones? The robusta australopithecine. Boisei, robustus,
and garhi, up just to the top right of that. I'm getting off track a little bit. I told
you there's a lot of moving parts. I love this stuff. So what was the explanation for that
thing across the top of their head, that gray part? Chewing. Yeah. So they have these big massive
faces, and you can see it just looking between robustus there and africanus to the right.
Robustus was a dead end. They went veggie. Their faces got huge, but their brain couldn't get any
bigger because it was all face. We went the opposite direction. Africanus, afarensis,
all of the Homo that came after that. We were able to shrink our faces back, especially with
Homo erectus. That's why we see this accelerating trend, what we call biocultural evolution,
because we started using tools. We started using fire that allowed our face to get out of the way
of our brain, because the brain grows first and it leaves less time and space for the face to grow
out. It's just an aspect of the modularity, the way the different parts of our craniofacial anatomy
grow. But when we needed a face, when we were constantly chewing on fibrous plant material,
the face had to be there. There was selection for that. Once we relaxed that selective pressure,
teeth get smaller, masticatory muscles get smaller. Our temporalis muscles are the ones
that would come up and attach to that sagittal crest and the robustus or lopithecines. Right.
Now they attach right here. They're all the way down here. We have very thin skulls. Our brain
can grow out over our eyes. Like I started to say earlier, one of the things I look at in a
biomedical sense is how that impacts vision. If juvenile onset myopia, stigmatism, which what you
see with a highly myopic eye is it's elongated. Myopic meaning short-term distance. Yeah, we call
it farsighted, but you can't see things at a distance. Nearsighted, it's sort of weird how
they phrased it. We say nearsighted, but you can't see things at a distance. I'm very nearsighted,
like negative five diopters. But what happens is the eye is expanded or medial or not medial
laterally, but from front to back. And what it does is it changes the focal length where the image
focuses in front of the retina instead of on the retina. And what I proposed in a paper, I think in
2012, is that that may just be a function of our massive brains growing out over top of the eyes
and our face is shrinking back underneath them and the eye becomes sandwiched in between. And
the only place for it to go is out. It can't go up because the brain's there. It can't go down
because the face is there. So it's being squeezed almost like a tennis ball. If you squeeze it from
top to bottom, it has the same shape as a myopic eye. So I proposed that in 2012 and it's gotten
some traction. In any case, sorry, I went down a little rabbit hole there. So where does that go,
though, if you extrapolate out into the future? Right. And that's why it's extrapolation and not
speculation, because this is a six to potentially eight million year old trend. This has been
happening regardless of where we lived on this planet, what our political system, group size,
economic system was like. This has just happened. Right. So if you project that into the future,
and it is an acceleration, and this doesn't even take into account how they might be manipulating
us in some way, we could get into the hybrid program if you want to. This is just strictly
what's been happening over the course of the entirety of hominid evolution. To add another
little side angle here, I also, and there's some images in that second book where I show,
based on some geometric morphometric analyses I did, how the shape of our skulls is likely to
change with another dominant trend called craniofacial feminization, which is where
we're basically, our skull shape is turning more female. And what happens there, this is largely
as a result of self-domestication. We've been domesticating ourselves for about the last 30,000
years. Can you explain that? What does that mean, domesticating ourselves? Well, in the same way
that we see morphological changes in cows and sheep, and foxes was one of the first studies
See, it's called craniofacial feminization. Craniofacial. So in the same way that
when we domesticate foxes, very quickly they go from having pointy ears to saggy ears,
and from a tail that comes up to a tail that comes down as a little curve, they start barking. They
do all these things that we see in domesticated dogs. Similar things happen to us. There's this
suite of characteristics that change in us simply because we've been domesticating ourselves
With agriculture, about 12,000 years ago, that ramped up tremendously. We started to
be more domesticated, and a lot of the reason for it is because we're selecting for what are called
pro-social behaviors. When we were hunter-gatherers, if somebody pissed us off, we would just leave and
go somewhere else. We'd take our clan and we'd move to a different area. As space fills up,
it gets harder to do that. One of the main reasons space fills up is because of agriculture.
People just don't have the ability to move, and why would you? If you spent all of this time
tending to the soil and weeding and removing bugs from your fields, you're going to stay there.
You're going to reap what you sow. So we stay in the same place. We're forced to get along with
people, and what that does is it creates for more pro-social behaviors. We get along, and that
exacerbates these trends toward craniofacial feminization. So what I did, and again,
sorry if this is getting too technical, but I did a geometric morphometric analysis,
which factors out size. So we can just look at the shape of a male and female skull,
and so I projected what the extreme female shape would be. So if this trend continued,
if this craniofacial feminization trend continued, what would the male,
what would all of our skulls look like? And what was really interesting about it is it looked just
like one of these gray aliens. You had a forehead that was higher, you had a more forward brain,
and you had even more medial lateral expansion of the parietal lobes in the back. And if you look at
these classic images or even like Skinny Bob or any of these videos where they depict these things,
they have that big round area back here, and the parietal lobes are actually what has been expanding
the most throughout the last 200, 300,000 years. So it doesn't say this is what is going to
happen, but it shows if this trend continues. So wait, if my parietal lobe is expanding,
does that explain why I get so excited for public rec? Smart humans can't resist the allure of
public rec fabrics. It's comfort wear disguises casual clothing, like if aliens were disguised
as humans from the future. If I were a time traveler, I'd wear this. My favorite are the
daymaker pants. It's the comfort of sweatpants, except nobody knows it. Imagine going to work
and looking at all your coworkers and smiling every day. I can't do that without my public rec
pants. And they're perfect for golfing, flexible enough to give me a few more yards off the tee
box. When Danny's out golfing, I have to jump into the bushes and collect his balls.
Now I know why he laughs while I struggle and sweat in my primitive jeans. It's because his
daymaker pants are so comfy that he doesn't have to go without pants anymore. Public rec has finally
allowed me to enjoy pants in my life. It's soft and stretchy, and I use them for jogging, traveling,
and podcasting. The stretch on these pants are elite. When Danny wrestles people on the street
who don't like the show, he does so knowing that all that twisting and squeezing won't crush his
family jewels. It's almost like they came from the future to speed up our evolution by changing our
flexibility. Maybe it's so we can run away from the invaders faster. Or maybe they realize that
pants should just fit you, no matter if you gain or lose a little around the waist. The best pants
ever made are at publicrec.com. Not only do they sponsor this show, but our listeners can save 20%
off when they use the code Danny at checkout. Just go to publicrec.com and use the code d-a-n-n-y
at checkout to save 20% off your order. After their purchase, they'll ask who sent you. Tell them Danny
Jones made the magic happen. Publicrec.com and use the code d-a-n-n-y at checkout to save 20%
off your order. Say goodbye to pants that put up a fight. It's linked below. Now back to the show.
We would have more of these characteristics consistent with that of these gray aliens.
Another interesting thing too, and I show this in a video at lectures sometimes,
because I did a video of how we go from extreme male to extreme female, is that the orbits go up
and around. And that's what people so often describe in these cases of close contact,
that the eyes are bigger. And that would likely be another rabbit hole, this very technical,
that I'll give you maybe a brief example of. But the eyes are described as being larger
and wraparound, that they come up and around. And you can see that in this animation from this
geometric morphometric analysis going from extreme male to extreme female. Is this something we can
find online? No, I could send it to you if you want to edit it in later. Let's pull out the picture
of Whitley's alien on the communion. That's a great example of the wraparound eyes, I think.
Yeah, and it's classic. Every single person describes it. And they're these haunting eyes,
like you see the windows are the eyes to the soul. And it's like they're mesmerized by the soul
of these highly intelligent, highly conscious, empathetic creatures. And it just sucks people
in. Some people can't even look at them because it's too intense. Have you ever gotten your eyes
dilated, the eye doctor? Yeah. Sometimes I don't even need them to, I just want them to do it.
I'll go home and just like stare at my children and they can't look at me because it just freaks
them out too much, you know? Really? Yeah. And they don't know. So I'll have sunglasses on.
Start screaming. Because yeah, it's freaky. You know, even someone on acid. Or Adderall.
I've seen people come in, like I've talked to people like I'm jacked on Adderall. And those
are just normal sized eyes. Those are modern human eyes. We're talking about, you know,
these gray aliens with these massive pupils already, even bigger. People really struggle
to look in those. It's crazy. So, okay, you explained earlier though, like how the brain
would grow, like forward and take up all this space and like crush the eyes. But then how do
you explain the eyes getting huge and wrapping around like that? Yeah, no, it's a great question.
The main thing, and I pointed this out in that 2012 medical hypothesis paper too,
one of the main reasons why the eye would grow larger is because our brains have grown larger
throughout hominid evolution. And the eye is part of the brain. The eye is part of the brain. Yeah.
So it grows out of the telencephalon of the brain, the forebrain, basically, during early fetal
ontogeny. So it is part of the brain. It grows out from the brain. And more importantly, they appear
to be linked because of something called pleiotropy, where you can have the same gene or set of genes
controlling seemingly different anatomical parts. So we see the eye and brain as being different,
but because it grows out of the brain and it's governed by the same genes,
it is essentially the same thing. So as the brain gets larger, we would also expect the eye to get
larger. And then, yeah, couple that with the, and again, this isn't necessarily going to happen.
It's just a model based on this dominant trend of craniofacial feminization over the last 30,000
years. But couple that with the fact that we do see this expansion and posterior rotation of the
upper part of the eye orbits, I find to be really interesting. Yeah, it makes so much sense. What,
um, there's another, there's a, there's a bunch of other compelling reasons for these creatures
to be time travelers. But to me, another interesting thing was how there's the SETI researchers who say
there's no evidence of like traffic or super highways of any kind of ships or any kind of
crafts coming in and out of our atmosphere. There's nothing going on in space. It's super quiet,
but there's all these electromagnetic anomalies that are happening around the world. And especially
in the places where a lot of these experiences or a lot of these sightings of UFOs have happened.
What, how do you explain the electromagnetic anomalies?
Yeah. Um, before we get into that, I, I forgot one key bit of evidence related to the morphological
thing. So for the people fast forwarding through this, just, but you know, hit for,
I promise you, you might miss an ad, you might miss an ad, so stay with us.
But, but I did just want to bookend this with one other thing that I think is pretty compelling,
which is also technical. So I want to just squish them together before we move on.
And that's called pedomorphosis, which is an aspect of neoteny. It's a very common thing
in evolutionary biology where as an adult, you have characteristics more indicative of
the juveniles of your ancestors. So let me say that another way that
when you have the descendants of say group A, when they're, when they've reached full maturity,
when they've finished ontogeny, as we call it, life history cycle, they look more like the kids
of their ancestors. So that is interesting to me because it's yet another, I would argue,
line of evidence to suggest that they are us, because that's a trend that also characterizes
hominin evolution, that we look more like the kids of our ancestors.
And that is also described in a number of cases of close encounters. You have Terry Lovelace
turn into his friend Toby saying, what are those kids doing out there in the field under this craft?
I mentioned Travis Walton often too, where he described them as overgrown fetuses. That's
exactly what we'd expect to see because of this other evolutionary trend. So there's just so many
little things characteristic of our morphological evolution, pedomorphosis being another one of
those. You can see it really well with dogs. I make the comparison in my first book with dogs.
Is there an example in nature we can think of of pedomorphosis?
Yeah, if you pulled up, that's actually in my book, the one with the two chimps there.
On the bottom right?
Bottom right. Yeah. So if you look at the baby chimp, it has a larger, more projecting forehead,
a smaller, more recessed and retracted mid and lower facial anatomy. But as an adult,
once it reaches full maturity, its face is all the way shrunk down. It's got a low sloping forehead
and the brow ridge. So that's just another example over a long period since we split with them,
since the bifurcation of the chimp line and the modern human line.
We look much more like baby chimps.
Yeah. They look like, I think I said in my book, they look like somebody's Harry grandma or
something. But that's another important one, too. And honestly, in Steven Spielberg's
Close Encounters of the Third Kind, he sort of threw a little bone to people when these
childlike beings come out of the craft and it lands on the top of Devil's Tower.
There's the World War II pilots who hadn't aged at all.
They don't age, right?
They don't age. That's a little shout out to time travel right there.
But they're very kidlike. They're small. They're very, you know, petite, childlike.
And we do this, Spielberg and his genius did this intentionally. That's what he did with E.T.
to make an alien that was cute and cuddly that Drew Barrymore would want to give Reese's pieces
to and, you know, hide in her closet with their other stuffed animals that we also make to be
more pedomorphic and lovable. It's something called Kind and Schema. This guy, Lorentz,
I think he was Austrian, first wrote about, and I believe the 40s and 50s,
it's what Walt Disney used to launch his franchise. Mickey Mouse used to just be a little
mouse. After this study, he realized if I make Mickey Mouse look cute and pedomorphic,
people are going to like him more. They did this with all their Disney characters.
And it's a big part of why Disney was so successful. Gave them the big ears,
oversized hands and feet, big eyes. It's why you'll see cheetahs raising gazelles
because they see this little baby. They chase off the mom. They don't want to eat it because
it's cute and they end up raising it as their own. And it's this drive that we have to take
care of cute things. It's just innate within us and all mammals, apparently. We all do it
because it's cute. You just want to take care of it. I had a little baby fawn come into my yard
about a month and a half ago. It was all cut up. Coyote got it. And, you know, I'm patching it up,
wiping off its wounds and stuff. And it's just, they're adorable. You can't not take care of them,
you know? It's just this intuitive, sort of ingrained aspect of our physiology,
but it's all related to that pedomorphosis. We want to have cute babies. So when they're crying
and they're pissing us off, we don't just throw them out the window. Right. Exactly. Yes. Yeah.
That makes a lot of sense. Okay. So let me see if I got this right. My takeaway from this whole
thing, and I think the way you summed it up towards the end of the book, is that we have tons of
evidence of UFOs around schools showing themselves to children and then around like military bases,
activating and deactivating nukes. These children have, they get these telepathic
communications about saving the planet, about nuclear destruction. You had the one lady who
was brought to like a hilltop where they showed a bunch of like rockets and stuff like that. And
they said, we're not going to make you forget this or make sure you don't forget this.
It seems like whatever this phenomena that's happening that people are experiencing is,
there's a very unique correlation between all of them where it's like,
save, keep the planet safe from destruction and don't kill, don't annihilate the planet,
right? And save, don't kill other species even in some, like some of them talk about like even like,
I forget who it is. I think Chris Bledsoe was in here saying that they had an experience where
they were like, don't kill other animals or anything like that. But it's like preservation
of the planet and the species, it seems like. And if this was an extraterrestrial race coming
to our planet, it wouldn't make a lot of sense that they would care. Why would they care that
we preserve ourselves? But if it was a future human race, you would see how they would be very
invested in preaching that message to us to protect the planet. And I've talked about this
at Nausium, but I had a lady on here recently, Annie Jacobson wrote a book called Nuclear War,
and she talks about after the nuclear war, after the nuclear winter, you know, 90, you know,
89% of the human race will be wiped out and the people who do live will have to live underground
because there will be, it'll be blacked out. It'll be just plague infesting the earth. And then when
the atmosphere or when the clouds, the nuclear ash finally clears, there will be no atmosphere
and exposure to the ultraviolet radiation from the sun for even like five minutes will just kill you.
That combined with like the rotting corpses that have been outside for a decade for seven,
I think she said like seven to 14 years before it clears up. Those frozen corpses will now be like
getting baked by the sun causing even more plague and disease and like nasty, nasty shit. So no one
would want to be outside. You'd want to be living underground and you would, people would be forced
to breed with each other and it would be incest. So we would lose the genetic diversity that we
have now on earth. And if that happened far in the future, it would make sense that we would
want to travel back in time and diversify our species by breeding with them. That's basically,
I mean, that seems like it makes a lot of sense. Yeah, yet another compelling little morsel to chew
on. Maybe actually not a delicious morsel. That sounds horrible. All of that sounds nightmarish,
but yeah. And you couple that with how commonly, yeah, like you said, experiencers
speak of something coming, you know, some sort of cataclysm, something transformational earth
shattering, whether that be a shift in consciousness, a sort of mass awakening or something that
really has to spur that into existence or the dark night of the soul in a novel where you hit
rock bottom and everything's bad, but then you emerge from it with this new insight and this new
way of perceiving not just what's happening now, but who you were before. Maybe we look back on
humanity and say, well, yeah, that was dumb. What were we doing? You know, in so many capacities,
war, just overuse of fossil fuels, over consumption. There's so many things, but yeah,
in a biological sense, what would that do to our genome? What would that do to our genetic diversity?
And in my first book, I mentioned the case of Jim Penniston, who completely independently,
and in fact, I only learned of his account or his interaction at Randall Shum, maybe a month or two
before my first book came out, but he specifically remembers being told that they were having
problems with reproduction in the future and they're coming back to get genetic material
to help diversify their gene pool. I had already written a whole section about that in my first
book, just based on past trends and how previously we used to have gene flow between isolated
populations, interbreeding groups, and you do have incest on islands and all kinds of weird stuff
happens. But if you interject new genes into that population, you can get around that problem. So
what we do with panda bears and gorillas at zoos, we're constantly switching them around and switching
up, adding new genetic variation to help diversify those gene pools. So I argued that maybe that's
what they're doing too, even outside of any sort of cataclysm or bottleneck, as we call it in
genetics. But in addition to that, in my second book, I also listed a number of other things
that could help account for why it's so ubiquitous that they do come back and get genetic material,
sperm from males, eggs from females. Many cases, that woman, Terry, that John Mack
interviewed as one of his patients, who was the one talking about being shown the missiles and
war scenarios. She was also subjected to a number of pregnancies, fetuses being implanted, extracted,
implanted, extracted. Linda Jones was another one also in that book. So what are they doing? Why are
they doing this? It's one of the most common features of these abductions. So even outside
of this potential homogenization of our gene pool or interbreeding incest that happens after
a bottleneck. What does homogenization mean again? Just all the same. And that's where the incest
comes from, because all your genes start to have what we call alleles identical by descent. They're
not similar, they're the same, because you got the same ancestors. So even outside of that, we see
problems with the reduction in sperm count, for instance, in males. 50% in, I think it's actually
60% in the Western world, 50% globally, reduction in sperm counts. Women are having a harder time
giving birth. In vitro fertilization, which is great for helping individuals, also helps their
genes, which weren't ideal for reproduction on their own, to get into future populations.
So you're taking genes that would otherwise be selected against and allowing them to propagate
through the future. There's also the risk that we run if we start to manipulate our own DNA. And I
listed a number of cases in my second book where we've already run into problems. Because if you
start modifying even somatic cells, you're trying to help with some congenital disease, so someone's
not affected. But if those modifications get into our heritable genome, to our gametes, not
just our somatic cells, you can cut off your arm, go make a baby, your baby's going to come out with
two arms. Because that's your somatic cells. But if you stand in front of a microwave or dip your
testicles in toxic sludge every day for years, that's going to affect your babies. So seemingly,
if we do things to try to help alleviate problems, genetic conditions, and that modifies
our heritable traits, who knows what's going to happen? So that could contribute to different
problems. Designer babies would be a big one, because we are actually changing the way those
genes are expressed. Are we doing, people are having designer babies? Not yet. No, I believe
it's still illegal. But it seems like it'll start with trying to cure disease. Even that could cause
these same problems. It's a good idea. It may have negative latent outcomes that we can't account
for. I'm just saying there's a lot of things that we can do now that go outside of just the fact that
we live in one island of Earth, an incestuous island of Earth, that we are homogenizing our genome
because of our culture, which we've always used to help our biology. It could actually hurt.
Anyway, there's just a lot of reasons why they might want to come back and get our genes.
So yeah, what's going on with that? If we start looking at the hybridization program,
if we take that seriously, that adds a number of other questions. You have people like Whitley
Strieber, Terry Lovelace, who described seeing these different forms all working together on the
same ship, some of whom are in modern military uniforms. Are we already working with them? Are
we aware of what they're doing? Was there some sort of contract that was made that Grush pointed
out and a number of others have as well? How many abduction cases have you read through
personally? I don't know. Thousands?
Well, we know John Mack did what? How many? It was probably about 20.
Well, he wrote about probably 15 or 20 in abduction, but he references others.
I think he interviewed over a thousand, right? I can't tell you the exact number, but it was a lot.
What percentage of them say they're future humans and what percentage of them tell the people that
they're aliens from another galaxy? That's a great question. Honestly, I would feel a little
disingenuous giving an answer because I haven't really sat down and crunched those numbers. But
this is split. There is a split. Yeah. Oh yeah. A lot of them are told they're future humans.
Absolutely. And why do you think that some of them would say they're from like Zeta Reticuli or some
other star system? Well, this would actually be a great study for a graduate student, especially with
all of the supercomputing capabilities we have. And if we can enter all of these cases into a
database that's searchable, you could easily answer that question. And it would also be
interesting, and this would be a hypothesis that you could test, is there a temporal relationship
there? Are there more that are told they're from outer space farther into the past because we
didn't think about time, you know? And it's probably easier for them with some farmer from
South Dakota to say, oh, we're from that star. Which star? Oh, that one up there. Don't worry
about it. Well, Barney Hill, Betty and Barney Bill was in the seventies, early seventies.
And we have, there's accounts of them telling abductees that they're future humans. Oh,
in the sixties, early sixties. Okay. I'm not exactly sure, but I know it was the sixties. I
think it was early sixties. Yeah. A database of all these things with like all, like a breakdown
of all the communication and all the experience would be great. I had this dude, Sam, I'll text
this to you, Steve. Oh, well, that's weird. He just texted me. Pull this up. TheUFOTimeline.com.
So Sam put together this incredible database with like amazing graphics and visuals
of every UFO sighting. And I think it's like any UFO encounter in history,
but it like includes abductions. I don't know how DP goes into the details of the abductions.
Interactive map. Yeah, there you go. No, no, go to the timeline. Timeline. There you go.
So this hypothesis I'm proposing. Interactive map on the right.
Interactive map. One more. That's his timeline. Oh shit.
No, that's not it. Click on early access. Oh, son of a bitch. He sent it to me. Whatever. Go to the
Twitter link I sent you. It'll show you a little demonstration of it and what it looks like.
Wow, that is so awesome. Yeah, that's it. So yeah, so you can like scroll through,
that's the timeline on the top. It shows you like the year that everything happens.
Shows you like, look at, he has like breakdown of craft type, shape, entity type.
Yeah, this is exactly what we need. This is, this is insane. He's been working on this for years.
If you could have the details of each of these cases, the hypothesis I'm proposing is that in
more recent time, we have more of them saying we're from your future. Whereas farther back,
they say, or like Betty Hill, where she was supposedly shown the star map. This woman,
I think Fisher was her last name, tried to even reconstruct it. Carl Sagan and other astrophysicists
look at it, eventually rejected it because it didn't fit. And it's data mining. Of course,
if you throw, you know, five or six stars up there, you're going to find something that matches it.
It's like monkeys on typewriters are eventually going to type out Shakespeare's works.
Yeah. So she tried to, she claimed that they showed her some sort of 3d star map that had like
12 stars in it. And they like tried to put her in a trance and put her in a flow state to figure out
what it looked like. And exactly. And what's interesting is this guy, Michael Swords, who
wrote this critique against this time travel theory back in the eighties and nineties actually
made more of a case for it than he did against it. And I talk about him a lot in my second book as
well, but he was like, you can't argue that the time travel theory is real without also accounting
for Betty Hill and her star map. Cause that proves that they're from outer space. I'm like,
bro, that's one data point, you know, much respect for this guy, tons of respect,
but that's one data point. You also can't base all of your arguments against a theory
on one singular data point that eventually was gone on to be shown. It wasn't true.
And even more interestingly, the video I just sent you to send Steve shows Betty Hill holding
this 3d model of the beam that she interacted with that she took to biological anthropologists
who told her, oh, that's what we're going to look like in your future. Betty Hill's team time travel.
A lot of people don't realize that they get off at the star map and they're like, oh,
she must think that they're extraterrestrial. They told her they were, she's team time travel now.
Really? Yeah. I mean, I think she's dead, but toward the end of her life,
she was squarely on the side because she saw in this form that that's exactly what we're going
to look like. And she was told that by experts in the field. Steve, you get that video I just sent
you? The YouTube video? It just popped up. I think that higher evolution can only come from
factor meals. You don't have to count calories or avoid foods that make you groggy. You just
trust factor. I just tell factor my diet for the month and they send me my food so I can spend my
time focusing on important things like Mike and space aliens, crush your wellness goals with me
this month and get 50% off. Thanks to our sponsor factor. Factor meals are designed to be great food
that's effective for your body. You don't know how poor your food choices are for your body
until you've had a factor meal prepared for you. If you're like me and you're too busy,
can't cook, but just want a tasty meal that's not frozen or full of preservatives, then your
food Jesus has arrived. So what's so special? You can target your health with specific plans like
keto calories or protein rich meals and factor meals are never frozen. So the cell structure
isn't destroyed by a freezing process resulting in mushy food. It's like your future self slapping
your diet in the face and saying, you're not going to do this to me. When I close my eyes,
I can taste my future. Choose from 35 meals, 60 add-ons, breakfast, even dessert.
So there's always something different for you to try out. Shrimp, filet mignon, which I suck at
making by the way, delivered right to your door, mouth ready in two minutes. So like what do you
want for your body? Flavored noodles or a meal you didn't have to plan? Make today the day you
kickstart your new healthy routine with me. Head to factor meals.com slash Danny Jones 50 and use
the code Danny Jones 50 to get 50% off your first box plus 20% off your next month. That's code Danny
Jones 50 at factor meals.com slash Danny Jones 50 to get 50% off your first box plus 20% off
your next month while your subscription is active. Head on down to the link below. Now back to the
show. Small orifice for a mouth and actually instead of whites actually have yellow eyes and
the iris is a pupil. We put yellow in to emphasize him. I was going to say he needs
byzine or he looks like he has malaria. Okay now, Junior has been evaluated by, I don't know how
many physical anthropologists, but what he looks like now, if we continue along the path of evolution,
this is what we're going to look like in 25,000 years. And would we be mammalian, reptilian or
insectoid or a combination of the three? I mean because if you look at the way we're on our way
with the nuclear, there was a nuclear exposure in Japan for instance and radiation causes mutation
and if you look along the lines of evolution we lost our appendix for instance people say we'll
lose our little toe because we don't need it. The brain capacity gets larger, you become more
spindly because we don't need muscles because it's mind over matter, correct? Is that the...
No. We're going to be like we are now except I mean look at mankind it's been around for
what 2.6 million years? Depends on who you talk to I guess, so subjective.
So that's basically what the astronaut looked like. Can I ask you something, when they put that needle
back on board the craft, they put the needle into your navel, some have speculated that perhaps they
were taking eggs or ovay or... No. No you don't think so? No. Because some have projected that,
isn't it interesting if you correlate that with test tube babies years on? Yeah well because you
know at the time this happened doctors said oh it's absolutely impossible to put a needle in
someone's navel, it would probably kill them but they get infections and then I think the process
was developed in a hospital down in Houston, Texas. Shortly afterwards. Yep. Did they do a
performance... Steve, see when this video was published? Hit escape, you'll see it. 99. Oh 99,
wow. This is what's dated here. Interesting. Isn't that cool though? That's super interesting.
Because yeah we got stuck on the... Lost 108 minute interview. Yeah we got stuck on the star map,
you know it dominated the conversation but... But she thinks they're future humans. Yeah.
And she doesn't think that they were trying to extract her eggs though.
No I think originally she thought that was a pregnancy test or something, it's been pointed
out to me by a gynecologist since that that's a dumb way to take a pregnancy test, that's probably
not what they were doing. So I don't know why they were doing what they were doing there
but it and so much of what they do is mysterious to us because we don't have the technology,
we don't have the knowledge of human anatomy that they have, diseases, parasites, there's just so
much so who knows. Have you noticed any biological correlation between all the people that have gone
through these experiments or been a part of these breeding programs? Like what do they have
anything in common? Me personally no but I mean there's the the cod 8 putamen study that Gary
Nolan did where they seemingly have more connections between the cod 8 and putamen in their brain.
Which can be an effect of trauma right? Yeah and and you know there there may be some relationship
with disassociation, with intuition, empathy, just sensing other people and if that's the case
you know then and this has been argued too that there's the case to be made that maybe it's an
antenna you know that we're ramping up those connections to be more connected to this thing
and and in my first book I look at this question what's with the telepathy basically? Is it a
brain-to-brain communication with some third-party medium with some technology or is it direct
brain-to-brain communication through consciousness? And I came out on the side of consciousness
that there seems to be the capacity to do this in people who have a first-time experience nothing's
been put in their brain it's just our minds connecting so to speak. So yeah I don't know and
maybe maybe there's some biophysical marker that would indicate that maybe it is the cod 8 putamen
or something else that we haven't yet identified but we're just scratching the surface we haven't
been allowed to talk about this stuff yet we haven't been able and we still can't get grants
to study this stuff and it's going to take money to get everybody an MRIs to do all these blood
tests genetic tests of markers and do you think it's true any of these stories that the government
has captured beings? I don't know. Like Roswell or anything like that. I'm on the fence about that because yeah you have
these videos and those can be faked. The alien autopsy like that one was faked but it was
allegedly based on real footage they just recreated it. You have people like Dan Burrish who claims to
have been a part of these he was I guess sampling this j-rod individual from some and who claimed
to have been future human from some 45 or 55 000 years in our future I forget which specifically.
So yeah you look at all of this even going back 10 years that would sound like nonsense. Right. Now
with Grush and his testimony and everything else you kind of have to start putting all of these
pieces together and looking at them holistically like maybe there's something to this. Are you familiar
with James James Fox's Varginia documentary? A lot of the aliens that were captured. I watched it with them in a
screening at the International UFO Congress in Phoenix 2022 maybe. So I think I think that case
happened that crash in Varginia Brazil was like 1992 I believe. I could be off by a couple years
92 or 96 maybe maybe maybe I'm getting that cut them conflated between that one and Ruiz. I think
it was the 90s. It was early 90s yeah and one of the beings was captured brought to a hospital
they said it reeked of of sulfur or ammonia or something it was sulfur they said they said the
hospital smelled like sulfur for weeks afterwards. He interviewed their x-ray technician and he said
the things had cloven feet and red eyes. Weird. And then they apparently the US Air Force came in
and took the thing and left and there was like tons of military activity so they think somebody
if this story is real which it seems like there is because he interviewed so many witnesses around
the town and the doctors. And those the girls who saw it initially I think they found footprints in that
yard they were right where they encountered it. Yeah I know that's a fascinating case. Can you pull the picture
of the Varginia Brazil? There you go he got her. Fuck Steve's talking on it today.
Like that's a new one right there that's yeah I haven't seen that one but that's close that's
close to what he explained the red eyes the brown oily skin and the fingers were different
and the thing yeah I think it had three fingers maybe yeah find a different one like this one
seems a little off yeah it seems a little off from from the this doesn't seem to fit the abduction
encounters no but it's a data point so we got to take it into account we can't throw anything out
at this point right he said there was three horns on the head too like that one on the top left kind
of shows those three horns that one looks like three like bubbles or something one thing I often
wonder too is if the contacts that are so commonly seen on these are some sort of like
night vision or protective shield or maybe even technology of some sort that allows like the six
million dollar man he can like focus in or you know change the amount of light right and then
another thing you talk about in your book too so if we were if we were us yeah those are the
witnesses a million years from now or let's even say a hundred thousand years from now we got we
can travel backwards in time are we going to send ourselves backwards in time are we going to
send like some ai robots back in time I think both and there's evidence for both too I think
I think what an interesting case is the pascagoula
Calvin Parker Charles Hickson and that was also in the 70s I think I'm really bad at dates that's
why I'm not a historian but but they they were taken by a robot straight up no doubt about a
robot how do they describe it um elephant like skin hovering club feet antennas three antennas
not like that but like antennas and made beep boop bop type of sounds um picked them up carry
them into the ship where they saw fully modern looking humans and that's interesting for a couple
reasons one the humans you know looked like nerdy scientists and you're not going to go out there
and pick up two big dudes that are fishing who are scared shitless of what's happening to them
you're going to send a big burly robot you know the one that came into Whitley's room initially
had like a shield on it he describes being small but like he he mentioned them as being like the
transporters or kind of the muscle of the operation but the woman he interacted with a little like
ogre looking bees yeah yeah whose job may be just that like little abduction droids I think I called
them in my book but but then there was also the small grays and then the woman the tall gray
woman who seemingly have traits indicative of a more distant point in our future a more evolved
consciousness and the ability to control these other forms it's almost like they're using their
mind to control what's happening to orchestrate this thing and to keep people calm to the best of
their abilities in these moments so I absolutely think they're not just going to use robots like
in the past gagula case but that we would eventually bioengineer robots we get past moving
parts and things that can break down and need oiled but we will yeah we could 3d print a biological
being right yeah or even just hybridize using genetic manipulation the same way we went from
teosinte a corn of cob used to be about three inches tall to the big delicious ear of corn we
have now simply through the manipulation of genetics and selective hybridization selective
breeding so we might be able to do that to create kind of a robot like thing yeah you know the ones
without genitals maybe they don't need genitals because we're just making them maybe it helps
explain that aspect right because we can just create them they're not reproducing themselves
but they serve some specific function with regard to the abduction itself or they're carrying out
they're the the worker bees essentially of these these future humans right yeah those are those are
the things that he describes is that what they are is that what was in the movie where he said
the little beings that moved him around that these i think this is a joke yeah it is a joke
but it's probably like it it looks like the ones from the movie i think yeah so okay so so
yeah the the ones like the varginia alien is super strange because it it seems to
echo like biblical depictions of demons in ancient text in like biblical text they there's
recollections of demons smelling like sulfur and having cloven feet yeah and you know what's to
say if these things can they can travel back in time they could probably travel back to biblical
times oh absolutely and i wouldn't be surprised if much of our religious lore and in various
folkways and mores throughout history are the direct result of contact i mean why wouldn't they
be you know these seemingly magical beings come down from the sky they have the ability to
levitate they know the future like you think of the archangel gabriel who told mary that this
is going to happen you're going to have this one he knew the future he warned her about what's
going to happen it started with a dream and then you know clearly she was impregnated if you know
this situation i'm plain devil's advocate here um if that situation played out the way it was
described there's a lot of overlap with abduction encounters where there'll be dreams about this
it sort of normalizes it to some extent and then you're brought into this very strange world
jesus had paranormal powers he could heal the sick he could levitate he could make fish rain
down from the sky you could easily pull off all of those tricks with the technology that
is on display in these cases of close contact and it's a big a big uh yeah part of the storyline
in that book too which is let's talk about this for a minute your book revelation
with a beautiful beautiful artistry yeah depiction of jesus and dan i had that commissioned
and jesus christ is being sucked up into an spaceship a flying saucer throwing us the double
bird double bird yeah that is correct that's gorgeous and there's actually it's really really
funny how that happened because one of the artists i commissioned to do that piece i just did a sketch
of jesus doing this underneath the ufo like your classic little peace sign or whatever it was he
did he thought he was flipping the bird and then went even bigger and did the double bird
i was talking to him at this conference in new york city like man i totally respect that you
just took that and ran with it because they gave me that as the final proof yeah not even like hey
do you mind if we had jesus thrown up a middle finger let alone two of them and i was like i
can't believe you guys did they he's like didn't you draw that in the sketch i was like no but
there's actually a scene in the book where after jesus i don't want to give away too much but after
jesus is brought back to life there after the crucifixion that there's this scene where he's
shouting tupac lyrics you know going around jerusalem flipping everybody off you know like
it gets a little weird um so the fact that they just took that and ran with it
mistaking a sketch i had done and then there's actually a scene in the book where jesus is doing
that i was like well we got to keep that it'll probably piss people off but it's kind of funny
yeah that's funny yeah no if i had a time machine i would go back there's two points i'd go back to
i would want to see where the how the pyramids were built i want to see what jesus was doing
totally there was um actually in curt vonnegut slaughterhouse five that was one of the the
things they did too to go back and see if jesus actually died during the crucifixion or if it was
sort of uh just a dramatic thing to help spur i mean that's one of the main parts of the faith
you see the crosses jesus on it everywhere it's kind of the main main element of of that faith
is the crucifixion sacrificing yourself for humanity and whatnot yeah yeah i mean it's a
huge mystery right people want to believe it but the truth is about the gospels is that they were
written most of them hundreds of years later and they were written not by people who witnessed
stuff but they were basically the people who wrote them were writing them based on testimony
of people who told them that things happened and it was hundreds of years later so you know
and there's so many books that were taken out too that tell a very interesting story that maybe adds
a lot of depth and breadth to what happened because these things many of them were historical
events but they were just left out so most people have a very slimmed down version i saw you had jeff
crapple on your show not too long ago and he's written extensively about many of these other
texts gnostic texts and yeah and kind of what we can learn from those and many religious scholars
have as well but i really like his approach because he also focuses on many of the things
we're not supposed to talk about or that we'd like to pretend weren't characteristics of jesus
life and him lying with you know prostitutes and hanging out with the children the women of the
night children right yeah and a lot of that stuff was more common back then but we you don't want
christians don't want to think about jesus in that way so we paint this picture of what this was and
a big part of this book too is calling out the hypocrisy in that a lot of people have a mouthful
of scripture but a heart full of hate and that's not the teachings of jesus it was about love and
empathy and kindness and taking care of the poor and the weak and the sick so this book kind of
bolsters those ideas while calling out the rampant hypocrisy that's grown up around it
yeah there's a lot there's a lot to talk about there you know one of the things that's really
interesting to me about that whole era of human history is that you have like the bible that's
based on the gospels of those guys mark uh john forget the rest of them anyways there's but there's
so much more text and history in that area that is not included and it's purposely ignored there's
there's comedians that existed from 100 bc to 100 ad there's physicians and doctors that existed
these and poets that existed and all these people wrote extensively about what was going on that
gives you a lot of context to what was happening in those times and when you talk to like classicists
or linguists that's how they figure out what words mean so there's like this thing called
semantic drift like if you take the timeline of history one word can mean something totally
different in 1500 bc than what it means in 1500 ad right so that's how that's why they take every
single bit of writing and art or whatever it is that they can find drawings on temple ceilings
to figure out what things meant to figure out the context what was really happening
in that part of that part of history yeah i've never heard that term before but it makes a lot
of a lot of sense yeah semantic drift semantic drift yeah that's cool yeah similar to genetic
drift so yeah one of the examples that guy almond hillman brought up on the show is uh the word
laystace is an ancient greek word that's that's it's experienced a lot of semantic drift over time
and in the bible it's used to describe when jesus was arrested in the park he says i'm not a
laystace biblical scholars like to say that laystace means a revolutionary yeah but
caesar was captured by child traffickers and when he was captured by them and when he eventually
uh got set free well i think they had to like they paid a bounty to for the captors the pirates or
the traffickers that caught him and he eventually got set free he crucified them and he called them
he literally this is like documented he called them laystace so they were child kidnappers
traffickers and he crucified them and that's this guy saying that caesar used the word laystace as
a child trafficker and jesus said he was not a laystace when he was arrested in the park this
is less than a hundred years apart as he's as a child running away and he has barely any clothes
on exactly the naked kid running away yeah so take for that that's interesting context an important
context that's left out of the narrative because it doesn't not only left out but biblical scholars
go out of their way to basically change the meaning of shit right yeah i know it's uh there's some
muddy waters even i tweeted recently um about i don't want this to get political because i'm
largely apolitical i've given up on all that shit because it's hopeless um but but in the first the
the other two that you were talking about matthew and luke i think were the other ones but in the
first book matthew the very first section of it there's all this stuff about sex and adultery
and violence and yeah and it's like well this is the text this is what you're reading growing up
is being into my head as a kid i was raised in a fundamentalist christian household and you know
i'm being taught that women belong in the kitchen and all of these things about
racial superiority and stuff i'm like that that can't be in this book you know is this really what
we're being taught i started to reflect on as i got older jesus christ a lot of that is in the book
yeah but there's also crazy shit about prostitutes and oh yeah children and slaughtering children
like literally going going in and slaughtering women and keeping like i've been reading the
bible on and off like the last few months because i've really been getting into it recently from the
gas that i've had in and there's a part that i just listened to i'm listening to audio bible
that talks about how they would go in kill all the women and children and boys but they would
keep like the pre-pubescent girls that were virgins because they could breed with them and
that's dar four that's what happened in the genocide in dar four and many other conflicts
throughout the world it's yeah it's weird you know and i'm not it's also full of contradictions too
like there's tons of of timeline contradictions especially when it comes to noah and and some of
the things that happen yeah and and you know i'm not i'm not here to bash the bible or any religion
per se i only bring it up because there is something to be said for the original teachings
of this one individual this historical figure jesus you know and i and i i i did hold on to
those parts i'm i'm yeah it's more a religious than i am apolitical these days but i do remember
those parts framework and i think there's something to that and especially in the context of where
we're going as a species and maybe it was the intent was to introduce those ideas of empathy
and love for others and taking care of others and into this time 2000 plus years ago and that was
supposed to take off and resonate failed experiment if that was the case because everybody just took
out swords and started fighting each other over these different prophets and ideas and you know
who's a prophet who's not a prophet right but but what if you know that is the future of humanity
what if they sent back this highly evolved highly conscious highly empathetic individual
to carry out this mission that would help move us in that direction to become more like them
to evolve our consciousness even more did it work no but you could see how that might be something
they would try to do but then it gets into questions like are we just in some kind of
simulation are we an experiment are they just throwing things in here and there can we even
change the past did they already know what was going to happen if we're in a block universe
model there's that i'm not saying that's the case it's just a fun thought experiment and it's a big
part of what this book was is to sort of think about a lot of religious lore in the context of
real contact with future humans and what the intention behind that might have been and what
the ramifications of those interjections might have been as well right and there's also a point in
the the the extra-tempestrial model book where the two brothers they basically came across a
flying saucer that was just had these these two dudes who didn't look like great aliens they
looked like humans like exercising outside the ship and they brought it like they came back a
bunch of times like weeks weeks apart and they eventually brought them in and showed them stuff
answered all their questions gave them a tour except one except one question they asked them
about jesus right and that was the one question they could not answer i find that fascinating
jeff crapo actually i was at a conference with him at the eslin institute in 2022 and he had a
little powerpoint introducing every like the the main things we're going to talk about in this
group of phd's at this really iconic uh place in the cliff sides outside of big sir and he brought
that up in his little slide he brought up uh astin walt and i forget his name but the guy who
interviewed uh leo dorshak about about this interaction but he brought that up specifically
like this was the one question they answered all his questions about electromagnetism language
travel through space and time but they wouldn't talk about jesus and jeff was like we all need
to think about that what does that mean whether they're extraterrestrial time travelers whatever
what does that mean he pulled out the importance of that too and i'm glad you did because i think
i think it is really telling and ties into what i was just talking about like how do these things
relate if they are future humans and they are coming back they must be aware they've they've
yeah if they can go back from from hundreds of thousands of years in the future to now
they could certainly go back to and they must be aware that it's influencing our cultures
tremendously cranial cranial uh morphine the cranial boarding intentional cranial modification
is the technical term for it we see this across the world and through time and almost every major
civilization throughout the world and a lot of small ones even the enderthals might have done it
but why why are they why are they forcing their children's head which must have been tremendously
painful yeah why are they doing this unless there's some huge reason for it and even there was a
study in 1995 where they interviewed people why are you doing this because our ancestors were
instructed by the gods to do it is what they said who are these gods the gods if they're future
humans if they're aliens whether they're future human or not have big round heads how do you get
that shape you squish your head from front to back so yeah there's so many things the cave paintings
with the there's just there's so many and and if they're doing that and it's influencing these
cultures if it's influencing and creating the major religions of the world how do they see that
how do they see what they're doing that ain't your star trek non-interference prime directive
type shit they're clearly influencing the past and present and potentially their own future in ways
but there's so many questions i i don't have an answer i just it's something i've been thinking
about lately and it kind of makes my brain hurt so if they asked him i don't know what they asked
is jesus real or is religion is all the stuff real i mean i guess that would be the i forget
the exact phrase you know something like that though yeah if it was real and they knew it was
real why would they not answer however if it was not real and they told the kids it was not real
you would seem that would have to that would be that would affect us more i played the fifth they
just played the fifth and moved on yeah right no that's a good point they break it down even
more like yeah how does that aversion factor in in both cases real or not real yeah i had eric
wargo in here and he was explaining to me yeah yeah he's great he has the whole time loops
theory which is amazing um there's he was explaining to me and i don't remember it
perfectly but there's like a time travel paradox basically or a paradox too if we go back in time
and we affect ourselves it's going to basically affect them in the future so they can't exist
and that's that that all ties into the block universe versus multi the multiverse yeah eric
is his big time team block universe for sure and and i am too for the most part only because
it is the dominant paradigm to explain time and time travel and can you for people for the
limit can you explain the basic differences between the block universe right right sure
so in the block universe model and i always i always recommend an article i think her name
is dr christy miller at the university of adelaide maybe it's in austria but she wrote this great
concise article very layman's terms helps explain if people want to look that up i'll do a short
one here the block universe is basically the idea that all moments from the very beginning of the
big bang to the very last bit of matter leaving this universe and likely going back to start the
big bang because i think it's cyclic um all of those moments are structured as sort of static
stationary and a four-dimensional block so if you move between those you're not changing anything
you're just connecting different parts of that block it's also called landscape time occasionally
because it's easier for us to factor out one dimension so think of all of time and all of
the moments throughout history past present future is being on the static sheet you can jump to
another part within that but it's not going to affect anything about where you came from what
you're doing if you go into the past is basically just interacting in the way you always had and
there's not going to be a change because when you get back you find that you had just done what you
are always going to do so there's no paradox in the block universe because there's no change
you're interjecting yourself you're doing the things i think in her article yeah she's talking
about you're walking around you're petting donkeys and you know eating lunch and interacting with
people but you're not changing anything you're just doing what you'd always done in that period
it just took you to go back to do it another thing that helps people sometimes is to think
about meeting yourself so if you go back say you're 40 years old you go back to when you were 10
you get out of this disc-shaped time machine and you go up and say hey i'm you from the future oh
cool nice to meet you got any advice don't date rose she was bad for you okay dale don't don't
race today dale don't race today what was that for i'd go back and tell dale on heart not to get
oh yeah right right yeah but see that's the thing is you can't change anything in the block universe
and and one of the saddest things for me when i started doing this and writing about it and
talking publicly in 2018 and 19 i never thought in my life i would have people writing me
asking me how to save their their dead child or their lost father relative or something it was
tremendously sad like that was not on my radar at all i thought i'd lose my job and people would
hate me for other things related to this but i never thought i would have to like try to help
people who are suffering tremendous loss from something they wanted to change unfortunately
in the block universe you can't change those things those moments are structured that way
so everything's predetermined essentially yeah here's a good way of looking at here
i don't want to don't want to say that but that is one of the because i hate mail man they come
after me they come after me hard when i just delete it you don't have to read it yeah there's
there's that's one of the implications of this some people see that as an issue i don't i actually
kind of like it i call it i call it feel will because it feels like we have free will who cares
if we do or we don't right and there's all these studies like the limit study showing we don't even
know what we're doing until after we do it we don't we don't have conscious awareness of our
actions until milliseconds after it actually happens another thing this is the big hang up
for people and i think this helps folks are out there head around the block universe is that if
you look to the past you can see all these things that might have happened in your life but there's
just one timeline there's one world line for you and everybody else we look to the future and we
say oh there's all these infinite possibilities anything could happen but if you're looking back
from 100 years in that future but they see the one line they see the only one thing actually
happened all of those possibilities converged into one world line for the universe and that's
essentially what this is it's looking back at the end of the universe and seeing that one line that
played out in this universe there was one history you can move around within it it's not changing
anything it's not like you come back and it rains donuts and and cats are dogs and dogs are cats
it's that everything is still the same you just went and did what you're gonna do
versus the multiverse many worlds interpretation of quantum mechanics is one of the the more
dominant models here where if you go back into the past it creates this quantum decoherence and now
you have two different timelines it bifurcates the timeline and there's issues with the law of
conservation of mass how can you just double this huge universe and all of the mass within it into
two different things there's other issues too but that's one of the big ones so in that model you
could have different timelines and i've often said that i think the interdimensional theory
and the intertemporal theory this extra tempestual are essentially one in the same
but basically this interdimensional one of the versions focuses more on jumping timelines
whereas this extra tempestual model because it is the most dominant paradigm that we understand
in philosophy and physics looks at it in the context of the navikov self-consistency principle
that all things remain the same there is no change you're just interacting with the block universe
in all of these different ways it's not creating new timelines it's not creating change there is
no paradox so i mostly focused on that because it's what we know is it wrong we'll find out in
the future i don't know but i can only base the things i write about on our current knowledge
of physics and philosophy right yeah that was um super compelling piece of your book when you talk
about um interstellar travel so like the time dilation that occurs when you travel at the
speed of light so like if we eventually figure out light speed travel and i think you made the
case in your book that it takes like 22 years to travel from like the edge of the universe to the
center of the universe or something like that in rocket time rocket time 11 years to the center
from the edge 22 22 from edge to edge of the universe yeah or to the center and back from
is that traveling at like light speed or what what speed is that yeah like 99.99999 percent
um but yeah so that's 100 000 years on earth time right or something like there are no from like
edge to edge it was like two million years right no it was 100 000 yeah so an 11 22 year round
trip and this is based on god i'm spacing his name um but yeah a well-known physicist
did these calculations i i don't have the capacity to do that math but yeah he said that um 11
22 year round trip in your ship you know very doable you could survive that um would be
100 000 years on earth based on the basic time dilation einstein's 1905 paper i think it was
called the electrodynamics of moving bodies or something like that yeah which is it's it's it's
displayed nicely in interstellar how you know he goes off and he comes back and his daughter is
like 90 years old exactly yeah and the argument i made is that if we're going to do interstellar
travel we're also everybody yeah we're going to need to also conquer backward time travel right
because you don't want to just get back to your planet and have everybody be dead you want to
get back to your time too it's hilarious how you explained that if we if we sent a crew of
astronauts out to explore the edge of the galaxy and they were 25 years into their trip yeah and
then all of a sudden like a set of astronauts pulled up next to them in like 10 minutes with
their belly full of breakfast that wasn't that wasn't mine i pulled that a guy was writing about
my book yeah on um medium and he those were his words yeah i was quoting him and i can't remember
his name trevor or something that's hilarious because he put that so well i loved that they're
in a 25 year trip to the edge of the galaxy but that's really like a hundred thousand years on
earth which we can easily develop technology that's so much more advanced by then and they
could travel probably 10 times and it was a great point one that i hadn't even thought of
yeah as soon as i read that i was like damn that's a really good point you know because
yeah if if things are speeding up on earth what's the point of even trying to send somebody out
because they're gonna get all this way in this very fancy technology and then you just catch
right up to them right because everything's going so fast back on earth and i had never even thought
about that but trevor mahoney i think was his name um but he he phrases it really well too and
and like you have implications of that it would be pointless people catch up like shit seriously
doing this my whole is my life's work and they're just whizzing by me yeah that's such a paradox
because it would be it's it would render it pointless yeah right because you spend your
whole life traveling and then earth just catches up and you're here like in this primitive spaceship
what's the point yeah but at what point do you do it with that in mind you know like where do you
draw the line because at some point you're going to want to do it right right well it would make
sense that we would want to figure out time travel first we could go back and get back true true
yeah that's back to that time in our life yeah because then you already know you can go forward
yeah and and actually a friend of mine uh san ali agrama he's a professor of anthropology as
well at the university of chicago but he made a little cameo in that book he's the guy that
i had in there proposing the the super technological singularity like people talk
about a singularity in ai yeah but he's saying like if these are future humans at some point
if we know who they are and we have access to all of the knowledge of the future we instantly
become part of that like it's the singularity where all of the information all the technology
is available to us and we could solve so many problems we could cure all these diseases we
would be them instantly it's pretty wild to think about but i think he makes a solid point
that is pretty wild to think about are there people that think that when i think a lot of
people speculate that the singularity is going to happen in like the 2030s 2040s
do people ever talk about when we might be able to figure out time travel or actually experiment
with time travel well what's interesting is that if time travel exists we have time travel at all
points in the past that that can reach so there really is no point where time travel becomes
new essentially because think about it like we say we don't have time travel yet but it exists
100 years in our future someone from 100 years in our future can come back and pick us up now
and take us to whatever point in the past they want to we didn't have it now but because it's
accessible to the people in the future that do it's also accessible to us it's kind of the same thing
is that super technological singularity where all of these things and these capabilities become
available to us at whatever point they decide to let us know and that may be a part of what this
disclosure movement is too is shifting us toward that because finally we're not
the the humans trying to have a conversation with ants we're the humans trying to have a
conversation with more advanced humans so do you think the like the these government programs
where they have these crashed vehicles or these reverse engineering programs these are time
machines that they have and yeah and i think about it too like um if they are say say this
time machine crashed in roswell let's just use the roswell example okay it's people see this
as a paradox too even though it's also not paradoxical in a block universe but if you go
back in time and crash this thing outside the desert of roswell 1947 those people didn't create
that thing it crashed into there but they're reverse engineering it they're figuring out how
to use it and how to make it and how to fly it and how it manipulates space time and eventually
you develop that same machine that goes back and crashes in 1947 starts it over goes back it's
this infinite time loop of self-consistent events that are connected across two different points
in the block universe but where the paradox comes from it's called the bootstrap paradox
is because people think there has to be an origin point there has to be a creator they say who
created it must be a paradox doesn't matter that thing's always existed in those bookended
connected points in space time the people in the past didn't create it because it crashed into
their time people in the future didn't create it because it took the reverse engineering of
the people who added initially to create that thing so it's like i always say it's like looking
for a corner on a rounded ball there is no corner because it's not a block it's a ball
it doesn't matter it's just always existed but it violates our fragile sensibilities about linear
time and cause and effect one of the first things we do in kindergarten is we're given
little things we got to cut out the paper and then put them in order we're taught from a very
young age brainwashed almost that linear time is all there is not the case when you have backward
time travel capabilities and why do you think these things technically and physically
can work as time machines because i mean there's been the cases made in the book from the guys who
are given there was one guy who saw the thing hovering above a lake or a river or something
like that and he basically showed him the schematics and how the thing operated and you
claim that that's how a time machine would work who do artena yeah well what they told him is
that they were extracting hydrogen from the water in order to power it i guess i don't know or had
something to do with their power system again these were human human looking things entirely
human entirely humans they spoke to him verbally they said they spoke 500 languages i make an
interesting correlation in that book because the case study right before it was mike and leo
dorshak in south dakota the one with udore ortena was in um outside of helena montana not far from
where i live and they both claimed to have spoken 500 languages came out of ships that looked very
similar had very similar appearances in clothing i wonder if maybe they were the same if there was
the same group they just happened to come across these two different groups of individuals but that
makes sense you could use the oxygen to breathe and you could use the hydrogen for power i kind
of feel that maybe they're using something more like they've cracked the case on zero point energy
cold fusion perhaps because they're going to need a lot of energy to do this in any case um
yeah so so it seems that the craft themselves as i mentioned earlier the we have this
expression in biology that form follows function and you can use this with anything you can look
at the form of a fork and think well that probably stabs something to eat you know you can watch
people use it obviously and get more information but the form of these crafts seem to indicate the
function of backward time travel so what i did because i don't understand how to backward time
travel i'm an anthropologist nobody understands how to do that what i did is i started with
einstein's 1915 paper on general relativity his first one in 1905 was on special relativity we
just talked about the twin paradox also not a paradox but uh how time and space are relative
that was the point of the electrodynamics a moving body's paper in 1915 he talked about how there's
a curvature of space time which was largely developed in association with his mentor minkowski
minkowski space time it's our four-dimensional the the same understanding that we have today
um so it's relative when you travel at a high rate of speed like we were talking about right
before we started back up everything's compressed you're going away from the earth and it looks
like everything stops you look back and everything's just frozen because you're moving at the same speed
as the light that left earth at that same time as you turn around and come back you're now blasting
through all of those moments that you had missed as you were traveling and then a whole bunch more
because you compress space and time so by the time you get back everybody's much older as we
just talked about so with the curvature of space time his 1915 paper very soon after he published
that there were solutions to the field equations he published that showed with the rotation of a
highly massive and or energetic at first it was a universe or the earth initially just any sort of
massive spinning body lens in theory and i think in 1918 demonstrated and it's pretty common if
you put like a bowling ball in oil or molasses and spin it the oil and molasses start spinning with
it so it's that rotational energy that can create what's called closed time like curves it can bend
over light cones and a good way of thinking of light cones is if you turn on a flashlight
okay you just flip it on real fast turn it off the light can only move out in this direction
nothing can move faster than light so anything within that light cone is moving with it
so it's always going from past to future however with this rotational energy which
lenz and thuring showed 1918 then godel showed with a rotating universe essentially that that
creates the same tipping over of light cones so when you tip over the light cones and they go far
enough now the past is also at play like you're still moving forward you're still obeying the
laws of physics but you're able to move into the past carry that forward van stockem in the
1970s 1950s i think and then importantly frank tipler in the 1970s showed that if you shrink down
this galaxy of essentially but an infinite galaxy is what van stockem and godel had argued that you
need this infinite mass tipler showed if you shrink that down to a ring sphere or importantly a disc
of finite size you can create that same warpage of space time and the same bending over of light
cones in order to travel into the past and this is why i say that form follows function because
that's essentially what a ufo looks like the cylindrical disc shaped ufos it's this rapidly
spinning disc that seemingly can manipulate space time so even beyond that in my second book i tie
in a number of cases where space and time is manipulated you have corporal armando valdez in
1977 he walks in the proximity of this craft he's gone for 15 minutes based on what his men see this
are the different reference frames when he emerges he's weak he's got a beard and his watch reads
five days in the future so for him he was gone five days to his men he was gone 15 minutes
and there's case after case like that and i try to highlight a number of them in the extra
tempestual model because it it demonstrates that what is happening these things might be time
machines themselves that they're able to manipulate space time if things like that are happening and
they're in control of it what's keeping them from going back into the past and you know based on
the fermi paradox he famously said if there's all these aliens where are they this potentially helps
explain it that we are seeing future humans that if they are going into the past why don't we see
them i think we are and i think they're inside the ufos whoa so the people so the people that
go on board these crafts they can somehow who's ever manipulating them they can somehow
make time stand still or they can some or no they don't make time stand still but they're
i don't i don't understand why time would move faster like where are they going
i think what's happening is that inside the craft everything is extremely normal everything feels
normal right time moves as you would experience now at the speed of life you could say but there's
this what what jim penniston called a sphere of influence around it when he went and approached
the craft in the rendlesham forest in 1980 all of a sudden he described as walking through water
like everything was different he felt like his movements were more labored and time was moving
differently it's seemingly what's happening is that there is this sphere of influence and
corporal amando valdez crossed it he walked into that sphere of influence time he disappeared
because if you um i think in my now that's my first book sorry i think um once he crossed that
you would expect him to disappear in the same way that these ufos pop in and out of existence they
appear and disappear and to go back to something that i accidentally skipped over earlier when we
were talking about the super highway how nasa says it's incredibly quiet in space yeah steve
mera uh ufo researcher in the uk pointed out why is that you know what does that mean we would
expect to see the super highway they're constantly coming and going from outer space if they're from
outer space but what we actually see is them popping in and out of our four-dimensional
frame of reference which is exactly what we'd expect to see of a time machine it would appear
and disappear as it moves into the future or past and that's the same thing that seems to be
happening here and as it was pointed out to me after i published my first book by someone who
claimed to be an intelligence agent who was really concerned that i understand what he was saying he
wrote me the first time i was like oh that's cool and he could tell i didn't understand what the hell
he was talking about wrote me again like no i really think you need to hear what i'm saying
but what he pointed out which seemed very obvious once he said it is that when we see these craft
doing these right angle turns at tens of thousands of miles an hour
the g forces would be five to ten thousand g's nothing could survive that right but what he
pointed out to me is that the way in which they're manipulating space time just creates the illusion
of them moving that fast and that they use this speed to mask themselves they slow everything down
speed up their frame of reference as we perceive it in order to do these things so that 90 degree
turn may be one g to them but because of the manipulation of space time and these different
reference frames inside that sphere of influence for them versus outside of it for us we see this
is some incredible maneuver that would squash anything inside when in fact that's just a
perception differential it's a difference in the way we perceive what's happening versus how they
perceive it because they manipulate space time in and around these craft okay that's not my
information that was given to me by someone who claims to be an ex uh intelligence officer
somebody that just emailed you out of the blue yeah but it makes a lot of damn sense it makes
perfect sense and if we slow there's so many cases where something will zip across the sky
you slow it down and you can see the craft doing this and they might use it they might use it to
protect themselves too if we start shooting at them these bullets which seemingly are going you
know 700 miles an hour a thousand miles an hour to us they're like we should probably move over
here because they're shooting at us again um so it just it makes a lot of sense yeah you know
that's also it was described i think with uh fravor right he said that like the thing went
showed up at his cat point yeah or whatever they knew the future yeah
yeah that's an interesting one too is it kind of like that one
quick silver scene and x-men i've never seen that i haven't seen that either
i'm more of a marvel let's watch it and get this uh episode copywritten
just don't show it on the screen yeah is it the same with video if you show less than 15 seconds
and you don't have to get the rights i don't know usually if you show anything yeah exactly
or like the matrix too you know when he's dodging the bullets he just slows time down and
yeah yeah that's a perfect that's a perfect metaphor steve exactly that's okay so that's
what he's that's what he's claiming and as soon as he said that i was like jesus yeah that makes so
much sense and i included that in my second book because i thought it was highly relevant to this
conversation
and if they're time travelers they absolutely have the ability to do this
you know and in whatever capacity they want and i list the case of linda jones where she's running
and the grass is growing at like four six feet all around her as she's running um you have a study
that was done where travis walton was abducted and the trees in the vicinity of where he was taken
grew 20 times faster than the trees just outside of that circle so again inside the craft once you
cross over that threshold i think everything is how they perceive time but there's this
disconnect between their reference frame in our room
and travis walton also when he came when he finally got found out when he when he came back it was
like a couple days later he had like a beard grown out and uh his watch that one could be that he
was just gone that long it was also about five days i think on earth yeah earth time yeah because
he he was in a bad state like he he sees it as an ambulance call basically like they zapped him good
unintentionally and interestingly the case with um mike and leo dorshak in south dakota north dakota
i forget which um they specifically said we need to ground the ship before you touch it because
they're little boys they want to be like what's this can i touch it and they were like all right
but yeah we need to ground it first really yeah and then travis just ran up on it he's like cool
ufo so he ran up on it got zapped by this electromagnetic discharge and when he woke up
there are these two little grays around him and he's had all this medical equipment on him so
seemingly he had sort of an emergency room visit based on what happened it would take time to heal
so i don't know if that was a manipulation space time i think it was just gone that long
but one of the last cases in the book which you'll probably remember if you just read it
was the one of amy rylance in uh i think gondia australia oh yeah where she was gone for what she
claims was a week seven days in the presence of this man she doesn't call him an alien she calls
him a man and there was a witness to this one though there was a witness her friend petra
came out because there was a storm it woke her up she sees amy being taken out through the window
into this large cylindrical disc-shaped craft and disappears freaks out husband wakes up freaks out
starts running around where'd she go abducted by aliens whatever not the case eventually is like
seriously where'd she go and um yeah they call the cops and this is an interesting one for a
couple reasons uh i'll finish the story and then i'll try to backtrack into why i find it fascinating
but she ended up about 790 kilometers away in mckay an hour and a half after she was taken
so what that indicates to me is that and they told her we're going to drop you off somewhere
different we're going to put you somewhere else because we can't go back to the original place
we took you there's cops everywhere right but they did drop her off closer to the time at which she
was taken and i think because her husband and friend were freaking out like it almost seems
like an empathetic nice thing to do you know if she was gone for seven days they have the ability
to travel back in time they didn't drop her off seven days after they were done hanging out with
her doing whatever they were doing they took her back to an hour and a half after she was taken
to drop her off closer to that moment in time
yeah that's wild man this uh it seems like the most compelling
the most compelling explanation for for what these things are and you know the other weird thing is
like why i asked uh witley this too but like it seems like this stuff stopped happening after
the 90s like nobody else like the stuff people stop reporting these encounters the hybrid stuff
for sure and i think he even says that it's part of their their sort of gene harvesting program
and maybe that's part of some contract i i used to think it sounded crazy and then after grush
came out and you know people talking about the eisenhower meetings and all this stuff if you
get enough of these in your brain you can't not think about them or try to put the pieces together
try to find patterns yes and essentially with that one you know and hearing witley talk about it too
there seems to have been some sort of agreement i and i understand this sounds insane but there
seems to have been some sort of agreement where they needed our genetic material maybe because
of the things we talked about earlier who knows but there was a period of time in which they did
it seemingly from like the 70s to the early 90s maybe even to the early 2000s yeah that's what
willy says okay he thinks it ended i mean who knows right but he thinks it ended in the the early
the early 80s but one has to also wonder if you take that little bit of evidence if we
can count it as that obviously the standards of evidence don't apply to anything that we're
talking about but if we can take that data point let's say and look at it in the context of what
people also feel is an impending cataclysm or some sort of massive shift that will affect all of
humanity are they trying to get as much genetic material as they can while it still exists
before that bottleneck occurs that scares the shit out of me to tell you the truth
because why focus on that period what is it about our genes now and a lot of native americans too
a ton of native americans have these sorts of interactions and they have more wild type genes
than you know a lot of people from other parts of the world have been sailing around and are
breeding with other groups yeah they're like wolves compared to us and australian aborigines
too if you look at a lateral radiograph of an australian aborigines what's a lateral
radiograph a side view of an x-ray okay if you look at their skulls from the side in an x-ray
they're very very similar to homo erectus which makes sense genetic isolation on that island
they didn't go on to interbreed with a lot of other groups and places that were developing
derived characteristics is why we have egg laying mammals in on that side of the the wallace zone
yeah and it's interesting because those genes would naturally be more important in the context
of diversity because they're untouched they're more pure i guess in the sense that if you're
coming back through time to get genetic material to help diversify your gene pool in the future
solve genetic problems those indigenous populations all throughout the americas and
other places sub-saharan africa australia new zealand those may be of even greater import and
you do find story after story in the cultural lore of these various groups yes and how do we also not
know that they're they continue to do this in the future too like just because they stopped in the
2000s maybe they took like a 20-year break and then started doing it again in like the 2030s
maybe i mean you definitely don't hear about it as much anymore you definitely don't hear about it
and that's all we have i mean it's not like someone's out there with a video camera recording these so
all we really have is people's accounts and i honestly yeah it does seem like it fell off
in in the zeros the whole narrative in the ufo community or the government or whatever it is it
seems to be like a very big push to people want to conflate these things with angels and demons and
the bible sure i like i seem to agree with what georgiani said about that is that if we were to
make this whatever it is publicly known society or whoever in charge of society the united states
government would want to put something in place that would bolster christianity or sort of reinforced
christianity um in the case that if some sort of crazy technological thing would become known to
the world that it could have the potential to destroy religion yeah well maybe not destroy it
so much as reshape it or allow people different avenues which they can use to think about it i
mean that that again was probably the biggest theme in this most recent book i wrote and the
reason i did it as a science fiction novel satirical one at that um is to explore some
of these things you just can't talk about in a grounded scientific publication but i feel
like that's going to be the next big issue is religion it shapes so much of the day-to-day
life of so many people it structures life it structures their behaviors activities on a
regular basis the way they see themselves in this world interacting with others where you
come from where you go and you die all these big questions are answered by that if you have
something come out that indicates that much of what you believe grew out of these very tangible
things that existed in the past and potentially came from the future how is that going to force
you to reshape your conceptualization of reality for a lot of people won't matter because religion
is a belief that's all it is right doesn't matter you can say yeah your your religion everything
you believe in jesus was a time traveler he was paranormal because he had the ability to do these
things technologically and consciously and spiritually well it won't matter because faith
is faith it'll bend but it won't break however with a lot of people especially the younger
generations that have more open minds to science and different explanations for things it it may
eliminate a lot of those world views that over time will eliminate the entire religion
simply because those that ardently adhere to it die out and we we see this all the time it's a
very normal process but it might be a line in the sand that helps reshape the way we have
historically looked at our place in the universe in a spiritual capacity yeah did they did any of the
guys who experienced these things ever see any like crosses on the spaceships or inside the
spaceships or any like pictures of jesus not that i'm aware of no um that would be interesting
though if there were different factions do you think the ones that created jesus yeah were like
real big into like their their achievements and what they did do you think that the human timeline
has been linear as far as evolution goes or do you think it's potential potential that there was a
more advanced human civilization that got wiped out by a cataclysm no there's there's no evidence
for that um and it just it wouldn't make sense in the fossil record it wouldn't make sense with the
process of evolutionary change you go back six million years into the past to our earliest
ancestors they were just starting to stand up right they didn't have any of the same traits we
had and wouldn't for another four million years just nothing really happened in that period what
we were mostly doing was adapting to becoming bipedal we stood upright around the time of
lucy three and a half million years ago australopithecus afarensis we see her pelvic morphology
looks pretty modern the head still looks like a chimpanzee and it would be like that all the way
up until about 800 000 years ago when really our brains started taking off our faces started
shrinking back the fire the biocultural evolution the tools like i was talking about earlier
so if there was any sort of chance that that could happen it would have to be within that window
800 000 years to present but it's still one line you know and people talk about well what if there
was like the salarian hypothesis what if there was some advanced civilization they were wiped out
where would they have come from we were the only ones that can even talk about this stuff we're
the only ones that would have done that and we didn't even have the capacity to until the last
100 or 200 years it's happening a lot faster but it's all very recent there's no physiological
evidence in the hominin lineage and more importantly there's no archaeological evidence
that anything ever existed that would suggest a civilization had that capability and look at
what we do look at how successful we are we exist on every part of this planet we erect these massive
structures skyscrapers these monuments once you have civilization you get those you get public
works projects you get these features as we call them those would appear and be highly prolific
throughout the world with any advanced civilization because we don't see those there's no indication
that they ever existed or there's a population that could ever leave earth in our hominin past
up until the 1860s what about the evidence that has been i think i've had a few people talking
about this recently on the podcast but there's been there was newspaper articles that were coming
out in like the i want to say it was like the late 1800s early 1900s of giants that were discovered
that were dug up in like new mexico area and there is actually i think this wasn't like the new york
times steve can you pull up the newspaper articles of giant skeletons the stuff that
peregrine was talking about yeah like click on any one of these like giant skeletons 10 to 12
feet tall found in mexican caves mexico city june does say the year this was there is a better one
indians are rising out of the ledge strange skeletons found and that's so zoom in on that
it says it says new york times and it says like the april 5th what what's the date punch in punch
in punch in uh god son of a bitch what does that say uh 1886 1886 okay seven foot eight eight's
pretty big they declared they have found bones of giant 32 feet bones of giant 32 feet high in
mexico city mexico city yeah i mean there's just like like we don't we according to this there are
evidence of like giants that you know maybe could explain building the pyramids but were they were
they intelligent enough and like like how would people four or five thousand years ago be able to
create some of the things like that we do have evidence for like these i don't know if you've
ever seen these but these there's these dynastic egyptian vases these are made of like this is a
3d print of one but i had a guy who come in who brought in like 40 of them and they're made of
granite and they brought them into a um an aerospace the aerospace division of rolls
royce i believe where they have these light scanner scanning machines where they can essentially
like measure them down to like the one one millionth of a centimeter and they found out
that they are perfectly symmetrical within one uh like the variation of the width of a human hair
and they're made out of the one of the hardest stones on earth and these hands like not only
that but these handles are built into them and today if we wanted to recreate that it would have
to be created on like a cnc machine like a very advanced computer uh modeling machine
and the hundreds of and thousands of these have been found and there's no explanation like it's
absolutely impossible for this to be done with um chisels you know copper chisels and pounding
stones is there a date associated with them what is the date i think it was 2000 2400 bc
yeah it's hard like i i went on ancient aliens a few times reluctantly at first did you really yeah
yeah i've been on five different episodes maybe three different shoots but it was i was reluctant
because they're sort of your your quintessential aliens built everything and and we really pull
back from that as anthropologists because it's also innately racist because it's never european
sites that we say that about we assume the europeans at that time could build those things but well the
these browner people must have had help in egypt or you know central america or wherever but even
beyond that we do have a good sense of how they would make these things and once you relieve
people of the burdens of agriculture because the agricultural surplus allows people to do things
that doesn't mean they have to toil in the field all day then they have the ability to spend their
day doing whatever it is if you're enslaving thousands of people because your agricultural
society was able to take over theirs and force them into slavery you can use those people to do
the manual labor to build these things so right we can understand how they did it we don't need to
alien the gaps the same way we got the gaps with everything else et in the gaps we don't have to
do that because we can see how they did it and understand these massive public works projects
as being a latent effect of agriculture that's what i'm saying like it like wouldn't it be
possible that instead of dating the creation of these and the pyramids to 4000 bc wouldn't it be
more reasonable than claiming it aliens saying that maybe it was like advanced humans before
some sort of cataclysm that maybe like wiped him wiped him out and and had to force us to reset
no that that's something i can get on board with in fact i made that argument
at a lecture i gave in phoenix last may uh may and a half it's a weird way of saying that the
the may before this one the previous may i don't know what i'm giving you seven different versions
of which may this was that makes no uh it's not relevant maybe we could edit that part out too
too in any case i i i looked at this in the context of kind of what we're talking about the
solarian hypothesis that there are out of place artifacts that seemingly indicate that this thing
was produced by a more advanced species than was alive at that time not that they built the
pyramids or anything but what i argued is that you could have the same line of evolution in our
technology from simple to complex where it goes on into the future and we start making things
that if found in our past would confuse the hell out of us but that would only happen with backward
time travel technology so it's the same process of descent with modification we in culture we
talk about how it's cumulative it's always built on what came before even our languages that we
speak like that semantic uh drift thing yeah it's built on the evolution of language and we can look
at what came before and how it changed same thing with technology we go from simple to complex and
this evolution of compounding cultural complexity but with a backward time machine if you jump over
now you take that more advanced technology and the artifacts that you produce and they exist in the
past and even things like atlantis if you can imagine that we do nuke this planet or there's
just it's inhospitable but we go on to exist in the future we have the ability to go back in the
past and set up shop at a time that predates not not just that we could hide underwater we could
hide in mountains or we could hide in plain sight if it's before 70 000 years ago because humans
didn't invent boats until 70 000 years ago you could have this island all to yourself and know
nobody's going to find it because they don't have the technology to do so so i think that could even
help explain like these ideas of atlantis these lost civilizations it wasn't some offshoot
but it was potentially humans from the future and this is a reoccurring theme in the revelation book
too humans from the future that have the option to live in whatever pristine garden of eden they
would like on this planet yes in a place prior to humans having the ability to discover it at that
time right like right now they could live in an ark if they wanted to yeah i mean we're there we
check it out occasionally but there's so much left and yeah maybe they're doing it in our time and
and maybe these usos the underwater bases yeah these crypto terrestrials that we've explored
more of the moon than we have of our own oceans so they could our side of the moon would be a good
opportunity too up until the 1960s when we started going there so it's kind of the same thing as i
was saying 70 000 years ago before boats moon would have been a perfect option up until the
late 1960s and even then it's really weird what happened with the moon like us and the russians
are working together which is weird unto itself during the cold war no back in the 60s like they
had their missions we had our missions and there were these ideas about populating it we're going
to go there and make these bases and all of a sudden we're like no we don't want to go there
anymore why is that you know what what's happening on the moon and the far side of the moon especially
that could be such a great place to build a base if you were extraterrestrial you know the future
humans whatever nobody's going to find you there and even if they do it's a select group of
individuals who you could convince to just pr campaign the hell out of that so nobody wants
to talk about anymore because that's exactly what happened all of a sudden they reversed
the direction and nobody's talking about these moon bases anymore populating the moon it was
like do you think we really went to the moon yeah i do yeah yeah we definitely went to the moon it's
just what did they find up there yes that's what that's what piques my interest and then you look
at ingo swan his penetration book he remote viewed it case after case of other abductees i read one
called like abducted in the latin quarter by this woman that just sent me this book about her
abduction experience she was standing on in this base crater in the moon with this woman who was
telepathically communicating with her looking down at this base terry lovelace claims to have seen
this this guy named jerry wills was taken up to this moon base and shown it and then brought back
he's like what's the point of that i just want to show you that there is a you see enough of these
you start to ask questions there was a guy who i had on the show who said that he was contacted
and visited by a guy who worked for nasa for like decades and he claimed to be like the expert in
mapping the moon for the moon missions the guy was really old i think i forget his name
i can't think of his name right now but he he wrote a couple books about the moon
but his job essentially was to basically like map out where they were going to go
during those missions during the apollo missions and like how to navigate it seems important you
don't want to crash into a rock somewhere crater right and he allegedly told this guy chris bledsoe
was on my podcast that there was ancient structures on the moon like like mushroom shaped structures
that were ancient and he's claimed to know like i think there's so many weird interesting theories
about the moon you know it's crazy apparently like the moon our moon is like the one moon
that is perfectly placed perfectly shaped to keep us in like the perfect gravitational balance to
maintain life and apparently that's the only moon that exists that we know of that's that perfect
yeah what it does for our tides itself and and taking a lot of the the brunt of the asteroid
yeah and it's i've heard it's cheese also yeah delicious cheese well i have heard that it's
honeycombed on the inside too um there's the hollow moon theory well yeah hollow moon honeycomb
honeycomb it could be the same but there was actually like a nasa thing that came out recently
which i think i've talked about in like fucking 10 podcasts already in the last month
that said that they found uh deep caves on the man for that yeah i heard that too and there's
water we're always told there's no atmosphere there's no water as a a fleeting atmosphere
that will form and deform and yeah i was watching on on stephen colbert one night the the group of
people i forget what they're calling the mission but they're they're gonna go to the moon and
they're gonna use this jumping off point to go to the mars and they're getting water and it's like
well they told us for so long there's no water on the moon there's no atmosphere it's just this dead
nothingness right i don't know like i'm not big into conspiracy theories but other than the cheese
moon thing uh i'm i'm kind of starting to ask some questions but there's a what so is that a
real photo right there no i know the one in the middle is definitely not real but the one on the
right and the left or is that a real lava tube on the moon says lunar lava tube wikipedia lunar
lava tube um apparently that's what it is click on the actual link so we can see the wikipedia
lunar lunar lava tubes are lava tubes on the moon formed during the eruption of uh basaltic lava
flows when the surface of a lava flow cools oh so there was lava on the moon yeah it's interesting
something that small could have tectonic activity and a hundred meters deep lava a hundred meters
deep that's what this one is a hundred meters jesus christ
yeah i don't know a lot of questions i did bet some kid at a party one time
that within we bet 20 bucks had some uh some people notarize it who are watching our insane
conversation um a normie you know not into the ufo stuff at all but i i bet him 20 bucks that
within 10 years we would have we would know as a society that there is and has been a moon on the
base that's how convinced i am a base on the moon far side far side of the moon yeah yeah i think
that's likely i think so too uh i also added an addendum for another 20 dollars that it's the
air force they're involved somehow yeah it has to be air sport or air force or um space force
nr o what's that one um the national reconnaissance office there's like we think of like the three
letter agents funny like anna jameson pointed this out there's like 18 or 20 three letter agencies
intelligence agencies that we don't even fucking know about speaking of shit that scared the the
hell out of you that interview scared the hell out of me which one with uh jacobson annie yeah
yeah oh yeah that was intense yeah especially in the context of all the stuff we've been talking
about with the warnings that experiencers have with like yeah no it's all about i took some
preventative action uh after listening to that one for sure it's uh did you buy a bunker no i
didn't buy a bunker i can't afford a bunker look at me weird cheap clothes um no billionaires
dressed just like you what are you talking about i don't know about that although the hoodie was
in fashion for a while i've been rocking that one my whole life so it was cool to see the billionaires
wearing um no just yeah you know like i live i live in a place that's already pretty well
suited yes yes you do i feel very fortunate about that um natural spring and the yard animals
everywhere yes no just just you live in a great place for an apocalypse bring it on and a civil
war you actually look at living a great place for a civil war too yeah no i but i don't want that
for anyone it's it it scares me not necessarily for myself but just what we would all have to
suffer through and and honestly as as destructive as this life is and you multiply it out over the
billions of people on this planet it's relatively comfortable for most people you know you don't
have to worry about walking outside and getting shot by a sniper up on a hill who's hoping to
get whatever little rations you have we we want our children to grow up with the same luxuries
and amenities that we had and grew accustomed to and we don't want people to die like if people
started dying by the millions i think it would just do a lot to our collective psyche as humans
especially empathetic people it would just it would be horrible you know and if if there is
something coming and if we do emerge on the other side better a more benevolent empathetic highly
conscious species great but it would still suck to live through that you know yeah
yeah it totally would um do you think if these things were future time travelers do you think
they would if there was like a a nuclear war about to happen or if like kim jong-un was about to
launch a nuke they would come stop it yeah so where they let it happen we kind of danced around
this earlier um when you were like why would they care you know if they're extraterrestrials why
would they care yes just leave them alone yes you know dance around with their nukes and blow
each other up um and and actually you know jalen heinick's one of jalen heinick's son paul heinick
um i heard him say this a few times like what how would they find us and why would they care
those are two big questions we have to ask if they're extraterrestrial how would they find us
i talk about that a lot in my first book just the difficulties of not just finding us locating
us but then communicating with us too it'd be much easier to learn the languages of the past
than it would have a planet that exists elsewhere and you're relying on radio transmissions which
are governed by the speed of light would take you know potentially light years to reach you
how would they find us why would they care but if they are stakeholders in the future
to your point earlier why would they care um it's their planet of course they would care because
they have to live on i mean my editor made me take this out of my second book but i think it's
an apt analogy where it's like you're at a four day music festival it's day four they're not
keeping up with the porta potties and you're the last guy in line that's them looking at us right
now we are all the drunk people who have been eating bean burritos the entire festival drinking
bush light and about to destroy that bathroom you know and they see themselves at the end of
that line looking at us like oh it's gonna be a mess in there you know i might as well just go
off into the woods or kill them all and then take the bathroom before they destroy it or let them
kill themselves and then take the bathroom after they destroy it or some other solution that does
involve everybody dying i don't know i also don't know if they can save us if we did do that they
certainly can't change the past if we're in a block universe i i got into this in chapter 13
or case study 13 of my second book maybe you remember kind of going back and forth between
tempestrials the second book yeah okay going back and forth between the black universe
and the many worlds interpretation in the context of this very question the nukes getting launched
what they did at malmstrom i was on a conference call with a number of people but robert sallis
was one of them talking to our senator john testers aides about the importance of this ufo
question particularly because of what they did at malmstrom and robert sallis was there he was
is that where they had like an icbm or something like that 10 of them okay go offline and started
with one that's near you right where yeah yeah yeah i gave a talk at lewiston just outside of
malmstrom and it was like there's so many people there and they're so interested because they were
directly affected by they've they've been touched by the phenomenon so they they know it's real
more than a lot of people but what they did is they shut down they took offline one of these icbms
deactivated it while this i think he said it was red like a red glowing sphere is outside all of
a sudden boom boom boom the other nine go offline yeah so they clearly were doing that for a reason
was it to send a message to us was it to demonstrate that they could either for us or them so it might
the only way i could see this playing out where they would the scenario specifically is if they
were to stop something is if they did it as a preventative thing i think if it happens it
happens they can't come back and change it but if they saw us getting ready to launch
they might be able to intervene and they've demonstrated at malmstrom and we have changed
our protocols another friend of mine um im butte he worked at malmstrom to make everything analog
because they thought if this happened again and nothing was digital then they wouldn't be able
to do it which i think is interesting because they're nothing was digital yeah so his job was
to rewire everything oh they wouldn't be able to control it yeah so that they couldn't do what
whatever it was that they did um at malmstrom initially so i don't know i think and if you
think about that in a time a linear uh time travel like cause and effect if they would do it that
would cause us to make everything analog so we could launch a new yeah like again in the block
universe and would they know that would they not know that i don't know there's so many questions
that arise and i didn't give an answer in that case study where i just here's what this would look
like in the block universe here's what it would look like in the multiverse with branching
timelines both are fundamentally different this last book revelation i also do that again um but
in the context of this story that's a i call it peri-apocalyptic it's not pre-apocalyptic it's
not post it's both but it's happening mostly at this time where they've got to decide are they
intervening are they not intervening and what does that mean for both us and them since they are set
to inherit that earth that we may or may not destroy and i can't say what happens because it's
kind of yeah the big plot twist yeah i mean one of the things that annie describes in her nuclear
war book which i don't think anybody knows unless they've read the book was how fragile
that the nuclear protocol is yeah that was surprising wasn't it yeah because we have all
those nr o satellites and and all the planes and submarines that are all that are tracking
everything around the whole entire world like three minutes or something like if one goes up
there's three minutes to decide what you're gonna do yep and i think it's six minutes until the
thing will hit if it launched in north korea i think it's like six minutes until it actually
hit or no it was like 12 minutes until it hits us yeah but it's like three minutes to actually
make the decision on what to do that was the scary part yeah and it's like i mean even the concept of
mutual annihilation is just like really yeah the problem to worry about the problem is though if a
if a rocket if an icbm launches they we have to immediately empty our nuclear silos the icbm
silos that we have in the midwest because we have to assume that they're going to target those which
are going to basically castrate us from having a return attack so those have to go up and then
they have to fly over russia and all these other countries that don't know we can't get on the
phone quick enough so it's almost like an inevitable apocalypse if even one rocket launches yeah it
feels very fragile considering what we're dealing with it's yeah that's the scariest part um you
described that you were at some conference and something happened to you you had some sort of
like crazy experience yeah it's been a lot of crazy experiences lately because when you started
writing about this you had never had any kind of like never even seen a ufo no not at all actually
well other than when i walked into my living room at age eight or nine and saw um that book actually
it's funny you know when the communion book yeah when you and eric were talking eric wargo
you described you guys were talking about uh precognition how a lot of people create things
or do things because they feel compelled to do it but a lot of that might be their information
coming from the future right and you described a situation that was almost exactly my life
where it's like well so you know you might do something and then there's that information's
traveling back and so as a child like you're compelled to do these things and that that's
what i feel happened to me when i was eight or nine years old and i walked in because it wasn't just
those images that popped in my head it came with something that i've since experienced about three
or four times that was sort of like a a light you know and like a i hate the word download but
i don't know what else to use there was information that came with that that in retrospect i
i i framed it as precognition i eventually had to explain because i've had i've had dream
precognition my entire life and i had to find a way to figure out what that was because it was weird
i knew people before i met them i knew what was going to happen in certain situations i knew my
wife and my children before i met them the first time i saw my wife i was like wait who's that
i knew her already we would go on to spend our lives together and make children together and buy
houses together and and and that that's been a very common thing in my life but i've also had
five moments of conscious precognition where and one of them ironically was about a week before i
was going down to be on a panel with eric wargo at the opening the archives of the impossible
conference at rice university where my my wife was taking the kids the bus stop big snow storm
missed the bus had to follow him to the next bus stop she goes to turn around in what looks like
a flat area but it was all drifted over by snow sinks the car straight down this massive ditch
i didn't know any of this i pick up my phone i was like oh it's weird my wife hasn't called
to pull me out of the ditch yet instantly the phone rings she's never gotten stuck in the snow
she's never gotten stuck anywhere that i had to pull her out of but i knew before she called she
was calling me to do that i had to go to work too normally i probably would have been a little
pissed like well i gotta go you know we spent like an hour trying to dig that thing out and pull it
out with my truck but i was just like oh she hasn't called yet to go and then the phone rings telling
me the thing that i just thought it's weird she hasn't called me to do um and that's happened
four or five other times the thing as a kid i feel was a pre-cognitive moment it shaped my
whole life to go on to do the things that we're talking about right now would that have happened
without that probably not so there's these connected moments in life the one uh behind
morton hall when i decided to switch from physics to biological anthropology it seems like there's
these things and there's there's actually this cool study uh being done i encourage any of your
listeners to reach out um i forget what's called like the destiny project or something like that
it's it's sharon uh hewitt raulette who wrote she was one of the runners up for the bigelow prize
oh if you were aware of the million dollars that was allocated to
to give the best evidence i had a guy in here i think who won that jeffrey mishlove he's the
one that won it no it was a different guy he said he won it there were there were there were three
no probably not there were three winners okay he was a near-death experience yeah yeah yeah a lot
of it was a lot of it was based on ndes yeah um but yeah jeffrey mishlove won i think he got 500k
and then there were other prizes too she's one of the people that wrote this i just had about an
hour and a half long conversation with her last week because she's doing this project
looking at people who have seemingly had experiences in their life that shape their life or maybe
lead them in one direction over another where they feel it wasn't necessarily
their ego or their individual choice in doing those things and i've had a ton of those throughout
my life so i saw she was doing this i know her from she was actually at that um esalen conference
in 2022 i just referenced so i got to know her there spent a lot of time on the phone we're
hashing out all this insane shit that's been happening to me recently that has forced me to
look back into my life and see other things that had also been weird that i didn't pay much
attention to until i had the the 2020 hindsight vision where things started to make sense the
dots were connected so to speak but it's only once a lot of this other weird stuff has been
happening but yeah i was at the international ufo congress in 2022 just gave my talk um took like a
two and a half hour nap missed the vip party where we're supposed to go and schmooze with people that
want to meet the speakers show up a half hour late groggy i'd like you know sorry never take naps i
don't know why i just slept so long and then yeah um things just sort of snowballed from there um
it took me about a year to be able to talk about it at all and then um finally got up the courage
to do so but um yeah i mean it's it's way too long to go into from start to finish but the
the cliff notes version is that i was taken up into that same room where these um
where i was late because of the the inopportune nap and i was taken there i wasn't allowed to
leave these two people came in what room again uh it was that vip room that the the organizers
oh booked that for as like a common space and that's where people met you know they had some
beers and stuff and people would go back there afterwards and you know like travis walt brings
his guitar people jam out i was looking forward to do all of that didn't get to um but they uh took
me up there started by telling me something that i had only thought and never told anybody else
who is that well i know who it is now i didn't have any idea who it was at the time was a total
stranger uh but his name is eric mitchell and he he's also experienced some crazy stuff like ufo
stuff and just a lot of sort of um classic experiencer things modifications to his his
psyche his world view uh he's an experiencer you know we all kind of walk home yeah but at the time
i had no idea who he was he was a random stranger that came in pulled up his chair to wear his knees
in my crotch like a very imposing sort of body position races right here and he tells me something
that i had never told anyone a thought in my head which was very effective because i was like wait
what is happening why was i kept here so long who is this guy it wasn't him as it turns out in the
strict sense of who an individual is with their own sense of ego the best i can explain it is
um something called deep trans mediumship where he was him in his body but there was also um
something else some other consciousness that had sort of pushed his to the side and was speaking
through him initially vocally most of the conversation i'd say it was probably over
a half hour period started out with verbal speech between him and the woman that brought me up there
that was keeping me there and then over the course of the next 10 minutes it moved to entirely
telepathic speech where it almost felt like it was happening above my head like the three of us are
communicating oddly in our same voices same voices without coming through the vocal cords i can hear
heidi and eric's voice in my head i can hear my own voice when i speak without moving our mouths
none of us were moving our mouths it's still to this day one of the weirdest things about that
um and yeah it's just that and then a number of other things they they told me they asked me
i was allowed to ask them questions about things and then they got to the main point the main point
was to ask me not to stop doing what i was doing because i was getting really sick of it
and it is taxing you know the travel and just talking to people constantly about these things
that fortunately i love talking about you know i say i've always been easily bored by the banality
of reality and that is very true like these conversations we're having are my favorite to
have i get really sick talking about boring shit with that said ufo fatigue is real yeah big time
big time you know i'm experiencing it too yeah and and it's yeah it was hard it was an especially
hard period and i was just done i wanted to quit and and i didn't tell anybody that they asked me
not to quit how could you know that that's insane and then there were a number of other things that
happened throughout this question answer session people are starting to come into the room
people see us out there and are worried about me as i found out later uh some of them knew me
and at one point three women came out and this individual eric in a vocal speech at this point
we were speaking telepathically which is probably why they came out like why are these three people
just sitting there without moving their mouths i couldn't even move my head by this point but he
said something like can you close the door behind you out loud and it kind of broke from the
telepathic thing that was happening so it jumped out at me kind of like and then all three of them
turned walked back inside and closed the door behind them and that was all that was said nobody
came out the rest of the time by the time they released me there's probably 20 people inside
i would guess i'd walk through a crowd of people to get out of there but what happened between them
is that they said they had to put three things in my brain that would be important for some future
time or times uh they told me what would happen my eyes would go black even though they'd be
wide open and the information would come in i wouldn't have access to it they told me i wouldn't
know what it was but very politely asked if that's okay they asked for my permission for this to
happen after everything else that had occurred it was clear to me that that they were um i don't
know what they are i don't know who they are i don't know what they are a highly advanced
non-local consciousness is the best i can do but i did get the sense that they were familiar
that i had known them my entire life and then it sort of made me start to think more recently
was that thing that happened when i was eight or nine with witley's book cover and the download
for lack of a better word was that my precognition or was it them they were putting things in my
brain at that moment could they have also done that when i was eight or nine years old you know
and then other moments too and a lot of these came up when i was talking to sharon for this
destiny project i apologize if i'm getting that name wrong because there's i started to think
back like wait now that i have this lived experience this sense of what happened and
sorry i'm jumping all over the place but it's hard to describe all of this as one straightforward
narrative but what they eventually did is exactly what they said my eyes went black i'm still
staring right at this individual's faces right here and all this information comes streaming
into my brain at tremendous speed i was able to see it temporarily in that moment because heidi
who's standing to my right with her hand now on my shoulder would say did you get that did
you get that i would just kind of mumble uh-huh uh-huh so i i could clearly see it briefly as
it crossed the threshold but then it completely disappeared it went into my brain i have no idea
what it was no no access to it well how can they be memories if it's a future memory that i will
have you know it clearly time and memories don't work the way we consider them because i have had
dream precognition my entire life as i mentioned but those future events are in my brain for some
thing that i guess is going to happen but i have no idea what it is or when it's going to happen
or what specifically are the events associated with it but they politely asked me if they could
put it in i agreed but it did force me to look back over other things that have occurred in my life
with a new conceptualization of what those things might have been
and how they might be tied into all of this other shit
but i don't know i don't know what the hell it is it really sure did you ever have a conversation
with eric yeah yeah heidi after this yeah so heidi i did know before because i met her in 2019 at
that same conference she was running audio video and we kind of chatted and gave her daughter a
sticker so so she was able to get me up there because i knew her eric was a complete stranger
in fact eric and heidi prior to this had never been in the same room they kind of knew each other
but they'd never met face to face they were both brought here for this thing they were brought to
the balcony of that room for this thing her mind i think was probably taken over before his like
when we were downstairs and she took me up i think they saw an opportunity and brought me up there i
was actually pissed i was like we went up there just to get beers to take down to some of our
friends because she had access to this room and the organizers don't care and um yeah she was
she brought me up there and then wouldn't let me leave i've got beers in my pockets we're ready to
go back down you know our friends are waiting for us and she's like oh we can't leave i'm like why
eric's coming he wants to talk to you i'm like who the hell is eric oh he's a friend of mine don't
worry about it she must have said that 10 12 times and i'm just getting irritated you know
so i knew heidi but i was so scared about what happened even a year after that i didn't i didn't
want to talk to her because i didn't know what she was or what we were or what reality is anymore
so i i spent a year trying to avoid all of this eventually i got the sense that i was supposed to
talk to it and that's one of the things they told me in this conversation i was allowed to ask
questions like my third question was can i talk about this and i said we want you to talk about
this so between that and feeling like a goddamn hypocrite because i dedicated my second book that
you just read to all of the brave people that are willing to talk about their experiences recognizing
i wasn't one of those brave people you know i should be talking about this they asked me to
but i was scared i was really scared to talk about something that a i don't understand how
do you talk about something you don't know about b because i don't know what they put in my brain
and that's obviously what people want to know more than anything else is what's in there i don't know
and c because i had no sense of like what reality was anymore like the things that happened in that
moment really kind of forced me to reconceptualize physical reality and consciousness and
just spirit souls energy like all of these things i'd always been a strict materialist
and now i i've kind of been flipped as cripple says you know i had to flip and start thinking
about these things that were never on my radar um but to your question yeah so i i talked about
jesse michaels first and and kind of had a little breakdown the day before i was flying down to la
to speak with him because i knew he would want to talk about it he was one of the first people i
told because i was down in la with him in december which was only about a month and a half after it
happened and it kind of came up because it was i was still losing my shit over it and really jacked
me up for about a month recently after that it was very recent after it happened and we wrapped on
this shoot and then it kind of just came up organically and the floodgates opened the guy
just i hadn't really talked to anybody about it other than my wife and my kids who had overheard
us talking about it but i knew he knew and would want to talk about it as i was preparing to go
down to finish you know the shoot we did in two different segments and i just didn't know if i
could and then recognized i was being a hypocrite by thanking other people for their bravery and me
being just a little wuss and um so i reached out to heidi like hey do you remember when they said
we want you to talk about this did you get any sense of the time frame and she this made it
even more confusing she was there she remembered being there and all of the weird things that
happened but she wasn't allowed to remember the specific things that were said i eventually
learned eric so so basically with deep trans mediumship the deep one your consciousness
is completely pushed aside so you look at people like um you know the bashar guy or like
uh what's her name norah roberts um mediums essentially people that can channel
there's different levels of that so hers was completely pushed aside she was there she was
participating as a physical form but her mind was completely taken over essentially eric on the other
hand had some awareness of what was being said through him not all of it but he has memories of
certain things that were spoken i didn't know that i just assumed she was some kind of crazy
creature of some sort that could do this shit on her own you know i didn't know
but i was afraid to ask until then because i was going down to potentially talk about this for the
first time and she's like i i don't know i don't i don't remember anything that was said or the
conversation that was had and i was but she remembered being there oh yeah not why she was
there yeah yeah exactly and in the next day she was like eric's an interesting guy huh and i
couldn't even deal like i was losing my mind i was like uh-huh uh-huh yeah pretty pretty strange i'm
packing up all my stuff to get out of there and she's she's one i realize now she was wanting to
know more about what happened and thought i would know and i did because i was conscious throughout
90 of it but i didn't know that's why she was asking i thought she was just kind of like yeah
weird stuff last night and i i wasn't ready to deal at that point it took me a year before i was
even ready to reach out like hey i might have to talk about this did you get a sense of when
we're supposed to do that so jesse's doco comes out and then i get a message from eric i think
it was on thanksgiving and his face pops up and i didn't know he's a real person i didn't know who
he was suddenly there's just this individual in front of me that knows my thoughts that have never
told anybody else they know everything about my past they know about my future they know about
all of our future and can put things in my brain for that future all of a sudden his face is on
my phone and i just i like crumbled as a human how long after it was um well that was october
it was a year later it's november so a year and a month okay but it still brought back everything
even after that amount of time and i've since gotten to know eric um and and we chat from time
to time i've learned a lot about his experiences and the things that you know have happened to him
and the way it's changed him physiologic physiologically his brain his antenna is
cranked up really high um but yeah i know it really challenged a lot of my preconceived notions of
not just reality but who i am like ego and and living a life that may have not
necessarily always been based on decisions i felt i was making for me by myself
um yeah i still struggle with a lot of that stuff but i i think it's i don't know i think
we should all be asking questions and i'm not alone you know as as i started talking about
this publicly reluctantly there's been so many folks who have reached out to me with similar
experiences it's it's not unique um i think it's just unique that i'm talking about it based on
what i've sort of structured my career around because it's risky i'm not supposed to be people
thank me for talking about it um but but i feel like we should how are we going to learn you know
if we don't talk about all of the crazy things that exist around us how are we ever going to
learn about just how crazy this world is that we live in what was eric's specific memory of that
of that moment so for him he what he told me is that he knew he was coming up to meet heidi
he didn't know what was happening so heidi was i hate using the word taken over you know but i
don't know what else to use it's not like a body snatchers thing it's just her consciousness was
sort of moved to the side a little and they got in her head down at this halloween party that was
happening and of course people were like oh you're on drugs or no i wasn't i i do enjoy drugs sometimes
legal ones of course um but but i had one beer and i didn't have any money and she was like
vip room there's tons of beers nobody drank at this vip party will go up there so that's
that's when she was co-opted that's a better word than taking over sure but she was texting
eric to bring him there to perform this thing that apparently took both of them
he didn't know why he was coming but he saw me out on the balcony sitting in this chair he saw
her standing behind me and said as soon as he walked in and saw heidi that's when he was switched
over and from that point on he was them he was used as this conduit through which they were
doing this thing but i wasn't talking to eric at all i was talking through eric to whatever this
advanced non-local consciousness is and he was being used for them to talk to me as well
hmm god
if the time traveling shit wasn't advanced enough they got to be able to take over our
consciousness and communicate through beings that are on our timeline at the time in our time frame
at the time i just assumed he was something else you know uh i had no idea he was a real person
that almost made it weirder once i found out that he's just like everybody else but has had
experiences ufo encounters and changes and things but it was easier when i just didn't know
who he was or what he was it almost conjured up more questions once i learned that he's a person
that's wild shit man yeah no it's been weird there's been other things too that have happened a very
similar thing to that and again once i experienced that i know what it is and what it feels like
um but they did that to me again about three months later i got the sense that there was
something above my house i can't prove it um and actually a lot of the things that have happened
uh you know can be taken with a grain of salt because i don't have proof this one that they
did in phoenix i feel like they did intentionally and made sure there were other people involved
and there were people watching whether they manipulated them too it seemed that they did
there was one individual inside that remembers feeling concerned and seeing what was happening
out there but not a sense of like who was there he can't put faces on the other people which seems
to indicate they were sort of being altered as well or the three people that came out and turned
in unison and walked back inside like that even out of my periphery i was like that's weird um
so so yeah i don't know um i don't i don't know exactly how deep
or how far those threads expand outside of what was happening on that balcony but there were other
people that can corroborate this um that's important the other ones you could write off
is just schizophrenia or yeah just me experiencing something i don't understand which is fine i i
don't it you know it's hard when people talk about these things it's hard to find the right
words it's hard to convey it to people who haven't experienced the same types of things and it also
just sounds insane i'll be the first to admit that all i can do is tell people honestly and
with sincerity what happened and allow them to take other data points and form their own opinion
about what it is and what it might mean you know and i'm not lying it would be really difficult
to lie i've never been a liar because it seems impossible to like keep a lie going you know you
have to remember everything you said before so gotta remember the lies yeah i could never do
that would stress me the hell out so i'm just saying what happened but one thing that did occur
that there weren't other witnesses too i told my wife about it the next morning is um i was in bed
i got the sense there was something above my house and i woke up and i was like oh shit that's the
same thing that happened in phoenix like i i felt the information saw like the colored lights coming
into my brain the same way i did when they blacked out my eyes and put the information of my brain on
that balcony in phoenix and i sat up i was like oh that's weird it's happening again but there's
there's no eric right here there's no heidi right here you know what's going on and so i lay back
down instantly asleep and that never happens to me i'm always up i'm always like ruminating on
everything that could ever happen to anybody i know and love and it's you know anxiety i never
just lay down and go back to sleep half hour later on the dot sit up same thing like oh shit you know
there's the lights and the information again lay back down instantly asleep this happens six
different times every half hour on the mark but it's slower when they did this to me in phoenix
there was this stream of information coming in at a tremendous speed and when i got up and i
was allowed to leave i walked through this room of people a woman put her hand on my arm and said
are you okay and i couldn't even lift my head like my head felt like it was 50 pounds and i
kind of tried to look my eyes i always said uh-huh uh-huh like i was in a such a mesmerized zombie
like state i just walked through walked down about four doors laid down on the bed with my feet still
on the floor passed out for like 13 hours woke up same position feet still on the floor i also
never do that i cannot sleep like that i gotta be laying down but but there were elements to this
that was happening to me at night where they woke me up every half hour that were just like that the
only thing that was different is the speed at which it was happening is coming in slowly and
i can't help but wonder if that's because i was asleep if there's like a subconscious element to
where it's easier to do that whereas at that time on the balcony we were running out of time
people were coming in this is where the after party was gonna be so people were coming in i
got the sense of urgency in what they were doing not just putting it in there for some future thing
that seemed urgent in itself but some urgency because of the way people were coming in they
were like we gotta do this fast and they just shot that shit into my brain and it it hurt you know
like it my head felt heavy and and there was a physiological response i like cried the whole
next day or at least until they showed up again and took it from me eric just showed up in the
hallway they apparently realized i wasn't dealing very well with what they just did to me he shows
up in this empty hallway puts his hand on my shoulder and says are you okay i was cool uh-huh
yeah like just seeing him again freaked me out to start with and then them knowing where i would be
knowing i was struggling but they helped you know some kind of reiki thing i don't know what word
to put with it helped alleviate some of that trauma for lack of a better word and i was able
to finish the conference and then got home and it all just came flooding back but there there was
clearly a physiological response to whatever they did and putting that information in my brain that
was much less taxing when they did it while i was asleep hmm yeah that's very interesting you know
the crazy thing about this whole thing is everyone who has these experiences they seem to be like
not all of them clearly but a vast majority of the ones that i've heard and spoken to they seem to
be like super traumatic and like in some cases destroys them yeah i've met those people too
yeah and then some people what's interesting is some people have reached out saying it was too
much for them they asked it to stop and it did really yeah and it did and then later once they
were able to process things they were like oh i'd like that back and they were asking me like how do
i get that back i don't take some mushrooms or something you know reek rebuild the bridge i don't
know um but i've i've heard that from a lot of people that was just too much it was too much for
me honestly yeah like i i was i was a mess for a solid three weeks and then lingeringly on and off
and then i had sort of um uh another spell about six months after where i was just
i i i really wanted to know what physical reality is what is this existence because when they when
this happened to me and other things since i i really got the sense that this isn't the primary
reality that we're a part of not base reality not base reality not source like we're in some sort
of a simulation or something kind of but i don't know i don't know i don't know i don't know maybe
but but more just like you know the the whole thing big low is trying to do um with best evidence for
whether the the the we survive bodily death you know and it gets it gets into where do we come
from where do we go and we die all of those questions i feel like there's some sort of um
base reality rooted in consciousness and energy and we are manifested forms of that in this
physical plane given different bodies and a different mode of perception in order to feel
individual variations in this physical experience in this plane of existence that maybe contributes
in some way to what is happening in this more transcendental fundamental plane of source
consciousness if that made any sense at all but i struggle and i don't know i still don't know i
didn't answer the damn question but i was pissed about it for a while like i was really angry like
what what is what are dreams how does it connect to this and i was just really jacked up for a
while about that too and since it's gotten better um but yeah they're on and off for a period of
six months to a year and so yeah i definitely empathize with people that that it did mess up
more long term i've kind of come to grips with it and formed a baseline of understanding i don't
i still don't know what it is or how it relates to any of this but it um it's at least become
somewhat normalized yeah i mean the the main feeling you get from reading your book from
the people that have these experiences whether they be sort of you know non-effective on the
rest of their lives or if they actually negatively affect the rest of their lives is that what was
going on in that time frame from the 70s to the 2000s um was it needed to be done like it doesn't
seem like it was good or bad but it was something that was just necessary for the survival of us
or something bigger than than all of us yeah i think jerry even says that specifically that she
came to grips with it because she recognized that she was a part of something much bigger and more
important than she was and it's kind of you know sacrifice the individual for the greater good
yeah i think that's the the sense that she got after a while and then became more okay with
even though arguably horrific things happened to her her entire life since she was a small child
and then if it was like so if we were to figure out backwards time travel would would that be
the same as forwards time travel or is that technologically different or is it is it more
difficult or do you know anything about this yeah yeah forward time travel is easy that that's
happening all the time uh you have what mark and scott kelly went into space mark was already the
older brother um but i think scott kelly was the one the two astronaut twins yeah yeah scott kelly
was the one i think that was in space for like just over a year right and so mark kelly as the
older brother uh aged another like five milliseconds compared to his younger brother scott because of
time dilation because of slowing down time yeah so that's time travel into the future essentially
mark kelly time traveled into the future of his twin brother scott um but yeah time dilation the
twin paradox that's that's future time travel all you have to do to travel into the future is go
really fast relative to the speed of light um the physics of backward time travel and the philosophy
of it and how we understand it is different it comes with a different set of conundrums
but um i i cited a paper about earman at all two separate papers and i think the extra tempestual
model where they looked at every criticism of backward time travel they could find in the
literature this massive literature review yeah and the the title of the paper was uh is back
is time travel to the past prohibited and they said their conclusion was no there's nothing in
the laws of physics that would prevent backward time travel and if that's the case given human
ingenuity and our ability to solve so many different problems our ability to advance
technology if there's nothing that prohibits backward time travel i think it's only a matter
of time until we do it we'll figure it out we don't know how to do it now we don't even know
what time is speaking of like this physical reality versus some conscious reality that may
exist outside of it and these two may be related we don't know what time is we know it's emergent
it's called an emergent phenomenon that means it comes from something more fundamental that
we haven't yet discovered it's one of few things that physicists will actually agree on
so until we know what that fundamental thing is we can't know what time is because we can't see
the whole picture there's a big part of this puzzle that's missing yeah there's a huge part
of the the picture that's just pixelated and outside of our ability to focus on it
but that doesn't mean it's impossible you know and if it's not impossible then we're going to
figure it out eventually and i think we already have and i think what we're seeing in the form
of these craft and the beans that pilot them is is exactly that it's it's an indication that we
do figure it out in the future and use it to go back to whatever point in the past they can reach
has anyone ever talked to you or reached out to you that could corroborate
the fact that the government has these crafts and they are in fact time machines that they're
trying to figure out how to work whether they be depending on how credible they are maybe
they're credible maybe they're not has anyone ever claimed it yeah uh quite a few people actually
really yeah um i i'm not gonna you know pick and choose because i don't know whose names i could
use and who's i couldn't we don't we don't have to say their names yeah some some are people other
people would know um but yeah it's been mentioned to me many times yeah because you might like if
if we had the technology and we were able to go back to the past like you would have to be
very careful and there would have to be i would imagine you'd have to put regulations in place
yeah for sure to and rules on a who could go and b like what are the rules how much are you
allowed to interact non-interference yeah right and you know honestly i think that bolsters the
case for this theory because an argument could be made if these extraterrestrials are traveling
you know light years to get here millions of miles why wouldn't they introduce themselves
upon a rifle or kill us and take all of our stuff yes slave us you know um but right exactly if they
are coming from the future you don't want to back to the future too scenario where biff gets rich
off of sports betting and just starts an empire you know um or maybe you would right yeah you'd
imagine sports betters would be making a killing off yeah no that yeah or like how you talk about
is the um the tourist idea of like yeah time tourists let's get fucked up and go check out
these crazy apes you know in las vegas yeah absolutely i mean or to go back and you know
see jesus crucifixion or how they built the pyramids and all these different landmarks and
i mentioned too in that same section of the book that the most visited sites are these ancient
historic and prehistoric sites that's where tourists want to go so we go there and we imagine what it
would look like if you could actually go to the time that was like the period that they were making
these things you could see how they lived and interact with each other and understand there
were poets and writers at the time of jesus and see what what people are doing in their day-to-day
lives you'd pay a ton of money for that opportunity so yeah outside of us inventing backward time
travel to mitigate the the twin paradox effect where you want to go home not just to your planet
but to your time to see when your family's still alive right you would probably uh also invent it
there would be a motivation to invent it to fill that demand side economic aspect of going back
in time one other thing related this just this conversation just made me think of it is another
line of evidence too is based on what we would do in a longitudinal study of an individual
is very similar to what those individuals who are lifelong abductees describe in these cases
where they're picked up as a small child throughout their teens 20s 30s whenever
as an aged adult they know these people they've been interacting with them their entire life
but case after case they say they don't age and that's exactly what you expect if they're using
time travel in order to do that you could do a whole longitudinal study on that one individual
that for them the the abductee would be a lifetime but for the researchers
researchers might be one or two days yeah um they just pop in and out and get them when they want
Whitley said the being that he asked that he thought was a female he asked how old she was
and she said ancient yeah answer she's probably right ancient and wise i would add that too
another pattern that emerged from this book is oftentimes these lifelong abductees they're the
opposite gender of the person that's taken yeah that's so like i don't know why it's just a
pattern that emerged in case after case willy had sex with his too i know it's pretty wild
wild account and um so david huggins yeah that's another thing like they're so advanced why can't
they just reproduce or like like figure out how to cross breed us with them in a better way than
like primitive i mean have you ever had sex it's super fun yeah i guess i mean yeah no i guess
primitive is even more fun yeah sometimes it depends on your mood and you know yeah if you're
somebody if you're some you know if you're some billionaire living in you know a million years
from now like would you want to go back and and have sex with a primitive ape or a primitive human
yes i don't know yes you would yeah actually so i mean i wouldn't want to go back and
australia pithecus i i i think well i'm a horny guy so i'm sorry i just gotta put that out there
but sick fuck my part of my sick fuckingness uh needs to be acknowledged right now because this
this book we've touched on a number of interesting um aspects of the storyline but the main character
it's a female protagonist in this book the main character is an intertemporal sex researcher
that's her job she goes back which book are we talking about this one this one right here
okay revelation the future human past she is an anthropologist from the future whose job is to
go back and fuck everybody from these different times to learn about sex because they don't have
sex in the future i sort of took that atrophy genitals thing and ran with it they stopped
having sex her job is to go back and study it in order to learn about it so she can teach
people of the future about the the primitive keen as you said it's a very it's a very important
theme actually a buddy of mine he's a he as soon as this came out he was like sex drugs and ufos
baby because that's what this book is it's like um sort of an exploration of basic human drives
and instincts in the context of war violence religion but also very much sex
it's a it's a wild ride wow man well we just did a little bit over three hours seriously
yeah jesus christ i had no idea that was fun yeah that was great um what is in your future
as far as work books is there anything else new you're looking at that you're going to talk about
soon or um yeah i've kind of had to pull back a little bit um not quitting in case anybody's
listening uh that's what got me in trouble in phoenix yeah don't fucking tell them to portal
through me i don't want none of that no i i recently became chair of our department
at the university where i teach and i had no idea what kind of time suck that was going to be until
recently um so i've kind of had to pull back a little bit i started writing a new book in um may
after spring semester let out which was gonna it doesn't matter i don't even know if i'll be
able to write it anymore but then um some things happened we had a crypto terrestrial paper come
out and i sort of had to do a lot of uh public relations with that and then some other things
and so so yeah long story short uh i'm basically trying to focus on getting my legs beneath me
being the chair of our department and focus on university jobs family just being home more um
being present in my children's lives but still obviously engaged in this topic i can't not be
you know like i said it's one of few things that i could talk about endlessly for three hours and
feeling like it was 20 minutes i had no idea three hours had gone by um but i don't have any
big projects right now well with that said some of the researchers that uh have been i've been
collaborating with some researchers at various institutions on some academic papers we had one
come out in june about the crypto terrestrial theory and it got a lot of attention globally
what is that theory it's the idea that there's an advanced um civilization sequestering themselves
in earth's environs whether it be far side of the moon under the water a lot of things we talked
about honestly right we published a pretty vast paper i think was something like 35 000 words
and it kind of went viral um i had to do a ton of interviews with pretty respectable news outlets
it was kind of mainstream media in some cases we always criticized them for not getting involved
in this but and they took it seriously it was it was amazing it was so cool to see i had something
similar happen in 2019 it's also that which is crazy into itself under itself as well um so yeah
it's been kind of fun doing that but there's only so many hours in the day but we are continuing to
publish a couple papers we're working on one right now uh that's likely to come out in december that
kind of also touches on a lot of things we've been discussing in the context of um you know the ufo
phenomenon but also the angels and demons thing um different perceptions but also maybe some
literal translations of various events that have occurred and how we might understand them in the
context of this phenomenon so we're still putting papers out one's actually kind of interesting that
looks at um a way we might be able to statistically model the the relevance and validity of different
cases so applying a standard uh means with which to take a new case and apply this method to it
and then it graphs in physical space uh different important elements to it so a lot like what jalen
heineck did and the ufo experience i think is what it was called um his like um reliability
metric and um what were they called like oddness and reliability or something right right right
i think a lot of your like cataloging everything and trying to find like yeah with the timeline
with the ufo timeline kind of but it applies a matrix to it okay it's like a matrix that that
plots out these things and then also what we want to do is give it to different subgroups so like
give it to skeptics and see where that same case would plot based on that that demographic group
give it to believers skeptics scientists um people in congress you know and and have visual
representation that we can make open source where we can get a big sample size and then tease apart
that data there's a number of studies that could come from that into itself but we want to have
this standardized measure so i'm working with these other phds at institutions in the uk us
brazil as well to try to um yeah add more legitimacy to this by publishing peer-reviewed
academic papers um that's funny i just said i'm not doing anything to focus on my uni job and
forgot about all this other stuff but it's a juggling act i mean you know it's easy to
get ufo burnout um but it's important you know i feel like it is important because it might be
one of the biggest questions of our time so i appreciate you doing this and the show this
beautiful space and yeah i think the more we can just keep talking the more we're gonna hopefully
chip away at the reality of this and maybe even eventually figure out what it is i agree man and
like i said that book is probably one of the most compelling cases i've ever i've ever witnessed to
this thing i think it makes a ton of sense um tell people where they can find your work follow you
do you have social media all that stuff yeah yeah for better or worse i'm on all the socials uh the
twitter the facebook the instagram um i've got a website too which actually has links to all of
those and to the books and um some upcoming events i'll be in denver uh next month at their move on
colorado move on i guess they're one of the biggest move on groups oh really colorado
yeah colorado and um phoenix i think those are the two biggest ones so this will be the
kind of a fun talk um i believe it's in centennial to south of denver september 14th or something
other than that i don't i don't do a lot of talks anymore um it's just that's a lot of work but i do
love these conversations so i appreciate you yeah man fight me down for this was very fun been a ton
of fun thank you for coming down steve do we have any patreon stuff yes we do okay all right um we're
gonna go do these patreon questions talk more to the patrons thanks for watching folks good night