It's not enough for anyone to understand the world and how the world works, it just is.
It's October of 1962, the heart of the Cold War. Images from an American U-2 revealed that the
Soviet Union had secretly begun building missile bases in Cuba, just 90 miles off the coast of
Florida. Strategic Air Command was placed in DEFCON 2, the only time that's ever happened in the history
of the United States. Khrushchev and Kennedy both had top military strategists pushing them to draw
first blood. We are asking tonight that an emergency meeting of the Security Council be
convoked without delay. Curtis LeMay, head of the Strategic Air Command of the Air Force, wanted to
deal a death blow to the Soviets. Amidst this tense backdrop, Secretary of Defense Robert
McNamara called one of his top aides, a 27-year-old whiz kid named Harold Malmgren,
into the Situation Room. Don't tell them what you think should happen. Ask them a lot of questions.
Your job is to slow them down, reduce the heat in the room, and give us time to work something out.
Miraculously, the Hail Mary worked. Harold, the youngest man in the Situation Room, ran circles
around one of the most aggressive four-star generals in American history. And if I remember
correctly, you kind of rhetorically back them into a corner where you say, what would be your prime
target first? Yeah, I said, it's madness. If you hit Moscow, there's no one to talk to. And then
at that point, LeMay storms out. Yeah, he literally got up and slammed his papers down. I'm not going,
I refuse to run with this. Malmgren went on to become a top presidential advisor for JFK,
LBJ, Nixon, and Ford. And the fact that he neutralized LeMay and saved the world is the
least interesting thing I'll be discussing with him. You've been dropping bombs on the internet,
saying some amazing things. JFK fully knew all about UFOs long before he became president.
Harold had been tweeting things that have taken it all seriously alongside his credentials and
background would wholesale overturn your worldview. No, instead of handling them, these are things
that have come down. So you're looking at like material, anomalous material. Yeah. Debris. Yeah.
This interview changed my life forever and will hopefully do the same for you. In it,
Harold admits to directly handling UFO material that fell out of the plume of a
Marshall Islands nuclear test. This is world history. It's the first time anybody of this
caliber has ever admitted to handling UFO material directly. What did it feel like?
It felt weird because it didn't feel anything like that.
He discusses getting briefed on other world technologies by deputy director of plans for
the CIA and chief architect of Area 51, Richard Bissell. Malmgren tells me that Bissell confirmed
to him the existence of the magenta UFO crash of 1933 in Italy recently reported on by UFO whistleblower
David Grush. He did. Richard Bissell mentioned the 1933 magenta crash. That's amazing. If that's not
enough, Malmgren also implies that he was being tracked by the majestic 12 from a young age.
The majestic 12 is an elite group of military science and government advisors
governing the UFO issue that were described in document leaks in the 80s and 90s. But this
is the first time anybody of this caliber has ever mentioned that name. You have uncovered
collaboration between Nikola Tesla and Thomas Townsend Brown. What source did you get it from?
Intelligence. We get into the Chinese science fiction novel, The Three Body Problem, which
Harold believes may be the best model we have for the UFO story. It's not just the atomic connection.
They're generically attracted to the tip of the spear as far as tech development. That's at the
heart of it. Yeah. Harold's daughter Pippa would know that. She was special assistant to President
Bush and on his national economic council. It's now public knowledge through how put off that
George W. Bush contemplated UFO disclosure with his national security advisor, Stephen Hadley.
As Pippa relayed to me, a lot of these high level disclosure discussions revolved around one
particular book, a Chinese science fiction novel called The Three Body Problem, which became
mandatory reading among many high level national security advisors in the United States. And to
fast forward spending time with my own father and discovering that he's been involved with this from
the earliest days. Finally, we discuss secret science going on at sensitive department of
energy sites across the country. Alan Dulles, the director of the CIA, the Italian mob,
secret societies, the JFK assassination, and how all of these might relate to UFOs.
The relationship needs to be uncovered between Angleton's father, Angleton, and the Knights of
Walter. Wow. Do you think that UFOs played any sort of part in JFK's death? Do I think so? Yes.
I think it was probably the number one issue.
In many ways, Malmgren was sort of a forest gump of global elite politics.
Pippa called, looked for me, found me in the crowd, brought me over, and he introduced me to
Putin. Now I knew enough to realize that that was not an accidental meeting. It became clear to me
in the midst of this interview that Harold was part of a much deeper intelligence network that
we barely scratched the surface on. You are now part of a network of people. It will be known
that you've been blessed. If I had a choice, I would have spent weeks with Harold going deep
on his vast knowledge of UFOs, deep politics, and global power structures.
Unfortunately, a day after our interview, we had to rush him to the hospital.
That hospital visit ended up lasting a few weeks, culminating in his tragic passing.
But when I was back in Austin, Harold insisted on speaking to me on the phone to follow up.
His vitals on the cusp of failure, just three days before his death, he revealed even more to me,
things that will make you further question your reality.
In this final courageous interview, Harold Malmgren transcends his earthly oaths and adheres
to a higher godly principle in one final act of service to humanity, one that may end up being
just as consequential as saving the earth from nuclear catastrophe with the help of the
world's most powerful nuclear weapons. In this final, courageous interview,
end up being just as consequential as saving the earth from nuclear catastrophe.
Without further ado, please welcome this week's American Alchemist, may he rest in peace,
presidential advisor and international peacekeeper, the honorable Harold Malmgren.
Hello? Harold, it's Jesse. Oh, hi Jesse, how are you?
Good, man. How are you is the more important question. You scared me last week.
I'm having to explain step by step who I am, how I happen to be here,
and each person says, oh, I didn't know that.
Well, I'm flanked by greatness and just honored to be here. I'm here with Dr. Harold Malmgren,
who was a presidential advisor to four different presidents, JFK, LBJ, Nixon, and Ford, among
various other amazing accolades. You helped stop a couple of global crises, if we're going to get
into that. But I think for the purposes of this conversation, you've been dropping bombs on the
internet and really saying some amazing things that deal with the nature of reality, non-human
intelligence, UFOs, or as they're commonly referred to now, UAPs, and informal briefs that
you've gotten on the subject. And so I couldn't be more excited to be speaking with you now about
all of this. And we also have Dr. Pippa Malmgren, who is equally amazing. And she was a special
assistant to George W. Bush on his national economic council. She's written a few great books. I
recommend you all check them out. And she's going to be joining us for this conversation as well.
So I'm honored to be here with both of you guys. Thank you so much for having us. Absolutely.
Well, I'm honored because I've watched your work with several people. And you've done an amazing
job. The most stuck in my mind is your interview with Matthew Pines. Well, that means so much.
Matthew Pines makes it easy. He's one of the smartest people I've met and has a really
interdisciplinary understanding. He can go from physics. I'm not a practicing physicist. It's not
my job. But I'm trying to familiarize myself with Garrett Lisey's stuff, with Sabina's stuff,
Wolfram and Jonathan Garrard. But he can also understand the minutiae of Washington and how
it works. Yeah, that's why I like him. He's unusual. He is very unusual. So you ended up
known as one of Robert McNamara's whiz kids, quote unquote. And just this kind of child prodigy,
but you grew up on the other side of the tracks. And so I'd love to hear just a little bit about
your childhood. Well, I was born in the middle of the Great Depression. And my mother and father
were immigrants from Sweden. We lived right by Narragansett Bay, just off the Atlantic.
When I was just turning seven, my mother said, well, this is the day you have to start working.
So when you come home from school, I'm going to take you down to the water and bring home dinner.
Because we were on rationing at that time, meat rationing. So I learned to use a boat,
learned to fish, learned to get crab traps, even had lobster traps,
dig up shellfish. So every day I brought home something. It became second nation. Sometimes
I had to stop and pick up a big piece of ice because we didn't have refrigerators. It was
really heavy. I was still little. Anyway, when I was 13 going on 14, just before my 14th birthday,
my father had found work as a restoration specialist. We restored old mansions
in Newport, around Boston, particularly near Cambridge. We were working on this big house.
He said, can you help me? It's the summer. And so I was working with steel wool and some kind of
and some kind of solution to clear walnut panels. And this big gentleman came in the room and said,
hello young man, what are you doing? I'm helping my dad. He said sit down and talk to me.
And that was a little bit unusual. Why does he want to talk to me? Anyway, we talked.
And he said, I want to take this boy out of your school. I want him to come in September
and matriculate at MIT. And we'll give him a full scholarship. I'm not sure he needs the full four
years. We'll give him all the years he needs. We'll give him an internship. You don't have to worry
about summers. And if all goes well, we'll take him all the way to the right of his school.
And I said, well bring him in. I'm not ready to leave home. And he said, listen to me. I'm really
offering a whole new life. He said, yeah, but I like my life. But he said he was president of MIT.
And I didn't know then the whole history of the large role he played in the Second World War.
I think he was in charge of the War Production Board at some point.
So this was Carl Compton, who was the sitting president of MIT, which allowed him,
he had the power to offer you a full ride. He had the power to do that.
We ended up friendly. But he said, you've talked about things that are very frontier of things.
At 13 or 14. Yeah, he said, you stunned me because you brought up what is a photon.
Why don't we understand it? Why don't we have a picture of it? We have a picture of everything
else. No proton. I said I thought about it and thought about it. I didn't know Einstein's
dilemma. So I said it's something that operates in interaction with something else, probably another
proton. And probably it's in pulses. And probably there doesn't matter how far apart. It's just that
interaction. But you can't get a picture of it because those pulses are so too fast.
And besides, it's two different things. Probably it's more than two. Probably it's many.
And that's the problem, that you're trying to get at something specific when it's not specific.
And he said, no, it's not that thing. So you don't understand. You have an invented mind.
You see beyond. But the biggest minds, I said yes, but I'm not ready to go home and leave home.
Malmgren displayed knowledge of physics concepts with Compton that he wasn't supposed to.
Not only because he was too young to know these concepts, but because they hadn't even been proven
experimentally yet. Entangled photons are considered a single system in quantum mechanics,
meaning that even when separated by large distances, they instantly affect each other's states,
essentially acting as a single unit. They also conserve quantum properties with respect to one
another. This is now commonplace knowledge, but Malmgren was saying this at the age of 14 in 1950.
And while entanglement as a concept was predicted by Einstein and his colleagues in 1935,
the treatment of entangled photons as a system was only made explicit in the 60s and 70s,
with Bell's Inequality Theorem and with the measurements of physicist John Clauser.
So how did young Malmgren understand this concept at 14 as a poor painter's son?
There's a bit of a back story, and part of my job in the interview is just to pull out some of this
background that led to my father's extraordinary career. But the key was before you met Carl
Compton, you'd written to the Atomic Energy Agency asking for background on nuclear physics.
So you'd at that age already read an immense amount.
At that age already read an immense amount.
Can we show some of that correspondence?
This is amazing. This here, the control of atomic energy. So this is what they sent back to you.
Genetic effects of atomic bombs in Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
See, that's really interesting. They were really interested in the genetic stuff. And you have
Detlev Brank is written about here. Detlev Brank was the president of the Rockefeller Foundation,
but he was also president of Johns Hopkins, who's rumored to be on this quote unquote majestic 12th
and do autopsies on non-human intelligence bodies. And so, and then you had all these studies going
on at the time, like the Cambridge labs, where you had the Polaroid founder, and a bunch of
these guys studying human genetics with respect to radiation. And Annie Jacobson has uncovered a lot
about Area 51, where they were doing a lot of, you know, human genetic experimentation
vis-a-vis radiation as well. And again, some of these photographs are quite extraordinary.
And when I came across them in dad's old files, I'm like, what the heck are these?
Wow. And they're from the Atomic Energy Commission and they're photographs of
Hiroshima and Nagasaki. These are Geiger counters? Is that right? You were telling me last night.
This is Hiroshima. Credit, U.S. Air Force. Wow. This is amazing.
So that's why he knew a lot at that age. And Carl Compton starts to register the president of MIT
that he's got this kid who's basically holding the paint bucket for his dad. And he knows a lot
about photons. And so I think that's where this began. He was identified at a very early age.
As someone with a very particular proclivity. And then fast forward, because, you know,
I looked at my dad's career. I look back and I'm like, how the heck did you end up at age 27
being the joint liaison between the Joint Chiefs and the President of the United States National
Security Council under Bob McNamara and JFK, just as the Cuban Missile Crisis at the beginning?
And, you know, dad has an amazing story to tell about what it was like to be in that room
as the decisions were being made. And he played a really critical part in preventing a nuclear
catastrophe. That's so amazing. Which is a story I think you should tell. Yeah, I can't wait to
hear. But clearly you had been tracked at a young age. I mean, this is a letter that you're receiving
from Oak Ridge National Labs, and it's atomic bomb engineering. So it's clear that they are like,
okay, here's this whiz kid. Let's give him a limited information set, see what he can do with it,
and maybe have some sort of initiation path. How you almost, you know, serendipitously and
miraculously wind up at Carl Compton's house holding a paint bucket. I don't quite know. I
don't can't explain that. Who is this Carl Compton? Well, he served as the president of MIT
from 1930 to 1948. During that time, he also served on Franklin Delano Roosevelt's National
Defense Research Council and worked closely with Vannevar Bush on federally funded scientific
research for the promotion of American military supremacy. At MIT, Compton was heavily involved
in the famous Rad Lab and its development of American radar. His top technical aide was John
Trump. If you recognize that name, it's because John Trump is the late uncle of our current sitting
president, Donald Trump. And John Trump was charged with investigating Tesla's files that were
confiscated by the FBI to see if they'd confer any tactical warfare advantages to the United States.
One of Trump's last interviews was also featured in a documentary on Thomas Townsend Brown's
Philadelphia experiment. And I was particularly looking for something which would just be evidence
of a secret weapon, which was a matter of concern to the United States.
But I digress. For the purposes of this conversation with Harold,
Carl Compton pops up in UFO history twice. First, you have Robert Sarbach,
former head of Washington National Labs, also one of America's premier nuclear scientists.
Sarbach is famously on record saying that UFO secrecy is classified at two levels higher than
the hydrogen bomb. But Sarbach also told nuclear engineer and UFO researcher Stanton Friedman
that none other than MIT president Carl Compton was briefed on UFO technology at Wright Airfield
in 1950. But there are more UFO touch points for Compton. Another researcher in California
named William Steinman had been corresponding with Fred Darwin, the former executive director
of the Guided Missile Committee for the DOD's R&D Board from 1949 to 1954. Darwin listed these names
as involved in a special committee on flying saucers at the highest level. Dr. Vannevar Bush,
Dr. Lloyd Berkner, Dr. Robert F. Reinhart, Dr. Eric A. Walker, Dr. John von Neumann, and one,
Dr. Carl T. Compton. Finally, when government transparency researcher John Greenwald used the
Freedom of Information Act to retrieve Compton's records, he received a reply back in April of
2014. Quote-unquote, records which may have been responsive to your request were destroyed
August 30th, 2006.
Why would the FBI destroy a file on an innocent university professor? And why would they have a
file on him in the first place? Those are good questions. And how did little Harold Malmgren
somehow end up holding a paint bucket at Carl Compton's house a couple of years after Harold
had written to the Atomic Energy Commission wanting to learn more about the American nuclear
program? That might be an even better question. Well, and he had gone on to work with Tom Schelling,
who was father of game theory, the application to conflict resolution across many different things,
but nuclear, and working with many Nobel Prize winners, including Sir John Hicks at Oxford.
And so I think when Kennedy came in, he knew some of the Nobel Prize winners and he asked them,
who's your brightest kid? And dad's name just kept showing up on the list.
It's fascinating. So then, okay, what happens? So you're recognized by Carl Compton,
you have this correspondence with the Atomic Energy Commission. How do you end up from that
situation to the Situation Room during the Cuban Missile Crisis as the youngest person in the room?
I'm still finding a reason to trust how that happened. At Yale, I was still a huge athlete
and a really top student. I was ranked first along with another person who later became
Chief Justice of the Arkansas State Supreme Court. I had moved from physics to economics
because I thought, my parents need help and I get older and I need to do something that makes money.
Economics sounds like money. So I got a grant from Yale to go somewhere and I wanted to go to Oxford.
It was a dream. And I went there and really fell in love with it.
I didn't really study anything specifically. I went to everything. And then I met a lady there
who was American and those things happened. I got pretty attached. And I came back from
after my one year grant to Harvard. And after I was partly going through the first term,
Mr. George Bundy, who was then Dean, had me in and he said,
we hear you're taking the leave again to go back to Oxford, but we want to offer you something
special. We'll give you three years, all expenses, including summer, and all you have to do is write
a book. You don't have to attend any classes. If you write the book, we'll almost certainly publish
it and that will be your PhD. And this is at Harvard? Yeah. That's a great deal. He said it's
a great deal. And I said, yeah, but my brain was somewhat flattered by this girl.
But also Oxford offered me, they said, just come here, but we'll take care of you. You can do your
PhD here. And so I did that. Married that girl. My mom. And there's always an element of
frailty in unexpected ways, in particularly my males. But at Oxford, Sir John Hurt decided,
well, he and his wife invited me to dinner. And she explained, she was a public finance expert.
So she decided, explained to me, her husband felt I was an original thinker and that they only
come along once every 25, 30, 40 years. She said, at Yale, you went deep into mathematical
economics. So I told my husband that you got to convince this young man to just dump all that
mathematics in a storage shed and start working more fundamentally at behavioral economics.
I remember the first paper I gave him was really a moment of insight. I gave him this paper, nine
pages roughly, full of math. And he said, this looks very interesting. Come back next week after
I read it. Come back next week. He said, don't sit here in the student reception room. Come into my
inner chambers. Sit down here by the fire. I thought, is this bad or good? And I began to inflate.
He really thinks I'm good. He said, but you know, it took me an entire week to find it out.
How many people of my caliber do you think in your lifetime are going to spend three or four days
of their time trying to understand you? He said, I think this is not the way to make progress.
So he said, it's near the end of term. I want you to go in a hole with a big amount of Gibbon's
Decline and Fall, which is in several volumes, and read everything you can before the vacation
period is over. So I came back and said, what have you learned? I said, I only got to something.
Chapter and whatever. And he said, that's not bad. The reason I want you to read that at a dead run
is because you have to know how it was written. Gibbons didn't do it
brick by brick. He wrote it at a dead run from his mind and said, you got to learn to do that.
You have plenty to say. You know how to say it. So write it that way. Don't stop to see if you can
fit it to some model. And so we had a marvelous experience. And then soon afterwards,
he said, there are people you should meet. So some of the best people at
Cambridge came to see me. Famous names. And then he said,
Hayek, Friedrich von Hayek. I persuaded him to come to Oxford and meet you.
So he came. I spent time with him. For me, I knew who he was. It was very impressive.
And then on another occasion, there had been a big debate in the 1920s, going to the 30s,
between Ludwig von Mises on behalf of the Austrian capitalism economists and the communist central
planet. The opposite was Oscar Langer. Oscar Langer came to Oxford to have dinner with me.
We had a fight. Centralization automatically degrades itself because you restrict everybody
from innovation, adaptation. Once you do that, there's no change.
So you would be more on the Austrian school side?
Yeah, yes.
Okay. I am too. Although I'm far inferior in economics.
I'm still the same. I'm totally convinced that China will collapse because of over-centralization.
Anyway, by the way, in the 1980s, I was in China with some kind of an SRI
meeting.
The Stanford Research Institute?
Yeah. They invited me along. And the senior Chinese, very interesting,
years later, said, can we have dinner with you alone? No. Okay. Why not?
So three of the most senior economic officials, we had a long dinner. We knew about your work on
centralization. Really, how do you know about it? We had your thesis translated, and we talked to
Oscar Langer and some other people. We had an argument. I said, over-centralization would
bring you destruction. It's impossible. It's too big to manage. Anyway, so going back to
Oxford, I finished up there, and there was a bidding war like an NBA or national football,
they're bidding graduates. So MIT and Stanford and Harvard and some others, Princeton, offered me a
post, and Cornell said, we'll trump the others. We'll offer you a new chair just endowed now,
so you can bypass the normal process of seven years from your assistant professor and
associate professor eventually. You can start at the top. So I said, okay, I'll accept.
And I came to Cornell with Pippa's mother. Pippa was born in May of that year, and we were living
in the house of Nabokov, the Russian author. Wow. He was on leave, and I leased from him.
In Ithaca, New York. Wow.
Yeah, it was an adventure, and he was something impressive. All these fortunate developments
happened in my life, anyway. By the way, these also became clues for me later, because I realized
Nabokov was said to be a CIA asset. Really?
And was used to help use literature as a means of propaganda, and there are lots of stories about
the intelligence agencies using Dr. Zhivago as a medium for fomenting opposition within the
Soviet Union. And so I was kind of like, how the heck do we end up in Nabokov's house?
Oh, wow.
And maybe the answer was that there was already at that time an intelligence world that in later
years, because of Dad's work in nuclear negotiations, that again, maybe he'd been
kind of identified early on. But I would love for you, Dad, to just dive into you are in the
situation room. You are down to the last three hours before you all think that you're hitting
the nuclear go button. And can you just describe what was it like in that moment,
and how did you avert the nuclear crisis?
A strict quarantine on all offensive military equipment,
on the shipment to Cuba, is being initiated.
I was appointed liaison between McNamara and McGrode Bundy and JFK. I mean, pretty critical job.
McNamara's secretary of defense at the time.
Yeah. And so, all right, I'm there, and I'm wondering what I'm going to work on. And suddenly
the Cuban Missile Crisis unfolds, and I get a call. And Bob wants you to work directly
with a small group in the war room. I said, what's the war room? It's where the generals meet and
decide, no, no, no, because they have the weapons, but my house doesn't have them.
So this is Bob McNamara. He wants you to meet.
He brought me to be there in that room as his guy. They would know I'm his guy.
And I said, yeah, then that can be easier to hear from this young sport. He said, don't
tell them what you think should happen. Ask them a lot of questions. Your job is to slow them down.
Reduce the heat in the room. Everybody can go calm. And if you just keep asking questions and
make them think, you'll be surprised how far that goes. And it buys us time. It takes the pressure
off from them, because there are some people in that group. I didn't realize it was Curtis LeMay
that worried about who wants to go ahead and punish Russia for even trying. So I get started
in that. And after a few days, I got used to the group. They get used to me. They didn't ask me to
get the coffee. They treated me like, OK, I belong there. And I didn't say anything to them.
I didn't talk down to them. I asked them, how's your wife today? And we got to the
last hours, roughly four hours, when JFK told Khrushchev, we put a quarantine around
Cuba. If one of your ships breaks through the quarantine, that will be an act of war,
and we will take action, being specified. And among the generals, there were arguments. What
should we do? Do we take out the missiles that are in Cuba? Well, we don't know whether some are armed
or not. Do we know that they have the ability to do more than we see? Might they start World War III
in order to get a step ahead? This was a time of mutually assured destruction. It was really
terrifying, in some sense. And so we end that final hour waiting to see if they were going to stop
or not. And there was communication going on. None of us were privy to it between Khrushchev
and JFK. And there was one additional element the history books have omitted, the Russian ambassador.
The Russian ambassador, Dobrygin, he arrived that year in Washington. He was unique. He wasn't a
typical diplomat. He was a member of the Central Committee in Moscow. They sent him to Washington
as the highest ranking politician in Moscow. And in that position, he was able to himself talk
with the top people in the Central Committee. Anyway, in those final hours,
the agitation level was high. We all sat down after somebody had a coffee break.
And one of the senior generals sent a signal that we didn't have cell phones. An aide came in,
said, I want you to call Mary, tell her to load the car, get everything ready to go,
and drive as fast as you can to Maine to our country place. And then he said, let's resume now,
gentlemen. Yeah, it's like literally, Mary, take the kids and get out of here. Like we're about
to be at the end. And this is the bit, dad, where it's so important that it's Curtis LeMay
who wants to drop Anuk. So maybe Dr. Strangelove wasn't so... It was based on him.
Yeah, but let me finish the story. So in the group, I said, gentlemen,
all the thinking of the last... ever since the bombers dropped in Japan,
all the thinking is about mutually assured destruction. If we go, we both get obliterated.
Does this make any sense to any of us in this room? There must be some degree of action less
than that. And they all said, yeah, but we haven't explored that. I said, yeah, we don't have any
calibration, any idea of small steps or ways to convince that we're serious. If we attack Russia,
what are we really ready for then? No. Now, if we attack Cuba and Russia thinks
it's the first step, that they want to get one step ahead of us by being first actor,
well, that would be bad. We can't know what they're thinking, but we have to kind of think
about that. Or we may take some step back and say, well, we don't know what they're thinking.
But we have to kind of think about that. Or we may take some step and they fire a little bit
at us, but a little bit makes us pissed off. And then we decide to unload everything.
First, LeMay is in this group saying, my strategic bombers are ready.
You know, we had all these missiles, but- His nickname is Bombs Away, LeMay.
Bombs Away. No, I had no idea what a miserable, mean, arrogant guy this was. I mean, there was
nothing written a lot about him other than he was super aggressive. Is he chief of staff of the
Air Force at this time? Strategic Air Command.
Strategic Air Command. Okay.
And it's important that you mention how he says, my guys, we keep setting them up to the
point of no return. Yeah, that's what I meant to say.
He said in the room to all these other generals and admirals,
you can't imagine the morale problem I have. Every day I send my boys out there, they reach
the point of no return. If they keep going, they'll run out of fuel. And he said I have to order
them back. He said the morale is really, they're ready. He's playing with millions of people's
lives to make sure that the morale of his units are okay.
Mr. President, I'm not saying we wouldn't get our hair must, but I do say no more than 10 to
20 million kill tops, depending on the breaks. He said that and every man in the room looked
down and laughed. They didn't want to eyeball it. I didn't hear that.
It's like if you have nothing nice to say, say nothing at all. I mean, he's also, for the
context for the audience, he was in charge of the 509th Atomic Bomber Squadron in Roswell,
New Mexico that was responsible for the bombings in Hiroshima and Nagasaki.
And he was in charge of all the firebombing in Germany. His idea of enemy is obliterate them.
Anyway, I didn't know what I was up against, but you know, it might have scared me, but it
didn't. So I said, well, let's, all the rest of us, let's contemplate the options. We slowly
thought. And then it turned out that we got word that the Russians stopped the boats
at the point of quarantine. And I said, can we agree that we should back off?
We should back off. And Hiroshima, they said, no way. We've got to teach them a lesson that
they're messing with us. They have to have something to remember. We need some surgical
strikes on Russia. It doesn't have to be population-oriented, but we need to make it
painful. And I said, but that leads us back into, will they think that this is just the beginning
of Armageddon? We simply haven't had a discussion. We have no communication channel to deal with that.
It doesn't make sense. It seems to me backing off for now and letting the discussions continue.
How do we avoid this being the preference? And all the generals agreed, and the one that had
called his wife, pushed the button, his aide came in and said, call Mary back. Tell her, I know this
for sure. But you also made a suggestion that if you hit Moscow, there wouldn't be anybody to
negotiate with. And further, if you let it leak to the Russians that you wouldn't hit Moscow,
maybe they wouldn't hit Washington. And everybody in the room just loved that.
And if I remember correctly, you kind of rhetorically back them into a corner
where you say, what would be your prime target first? And then they say, Moscow. And then you
say, oh, if it's Moscow, then you can't talk to anybody in Moscow. There's nobody to negotiate
with. That's been through them. I said, it's madness. If you're going to start something and
you need to stop, in that system, there's only one point of decision. If you hit Moscow, there's no
one to talk to. And then that's at that point, right, LeMay storms out and gets all angry,
is that right? He literally got up, slammed his papers down. I refuse to run with this.
That man was really maniac, but I have to tell you, I did not buckle.
No, I know you didn't.
Now, he had, by the way, just before that, raised the voting level to DEF CON 2.
It was not approved by the president.
Really?
He did it.
Unapproved. He raised the warning level of DEF CON 2.
He seemed to have that power. I mean, we were surprised, but anyway, he may have had that power.
Interesting.
Anyway, I mean, when I look back and think, Jesus, I stood in the way of this
historic big Obama. I mean, he could have stood up and tried to beat me up. I mean,
that kind of person. When he stormed out, what a relief to the whole group.
But it was the first in a series of evident clashes between him and JFK.
It was personal. Somehow, it all radiated. This is not about Russians only. Something
was going on in his head. We learned later about some of the other things.
And you had the Bay of Pigs before that as well,
which is this crucial juncture where I think, actually, Eisenhower left his second term
slightly skeptical of Dulles. I think, initially, he was willing to go along with his plans.
JFK didn't quite know what to think. After the Bay of Pigs, it was really this clear
rupture where you had the CIA, quote unquote, deep state. They had their own plans and they
really wanted to oust Castro and Guevara. And then you had JFK, and he felt like this whole
thing was just botched. And they send these Cuban exiles in there to kind of create this
revolution. But it's kind of half done, and the exiles are actually left kind of isolated.
Doesn't quite work out. And then you have this rift where you have people like Curtis LeMay
and Alan Dulles in complete loggerheads with JFK. JFK gets angry. He says, I want to scatter the CIA
to the winds. The president's saying, he's going to bring the CIA into a thousand pieces.
Is that roughly right? Yeah, that's right. So this was the prelude, this Victorian,
to what became a flash over how do we respond when we have an excuse. And Curtis LeMay said,
at least let me send my bombers after some strategic facilities of the Russians.
But how do you sort out, for the Russians' point of view, bombers coming at us? We don't know
their trajectory. We can't study that. It's not like a missile. Once it's fired, you know where
it's going. So high risk. And I said, this doesn't make sense. So everybody agreed except
Curtis LeMay, and he blew up when he thought he was going to dominate. Well, I mean, I didn't know
that this was a moment of history and that somehow my arguments won. But on the other hand, I thought,
this is why McNamara sent me down here. Well, that seems, it's such an act of genius to him
on his part to call you in as a 27-year-old to stagnate these sort of more aggressive,
you know, guys like Curtis LeMay. And you think of the way Robert McNamara is depicted in like,
you know, Errol Morris's Fog of War, just as an example. And he's seen as this sort of warmonger.
And this, you know, cuts completely against that. McNamara, do you mean to say
that instead of killing 100,000, burning 100,000 Japanese civilians in that one night,
we should have burned a lesser number or none? And then had our soldiers across the beaches in
Tokyo and been slaughtered in the tens of thousands? Is that what you're proposing?
Yeah, yeah. No, his instruction. He said, these guys are coming in that room.
There's several of them have sidearms that are fully loaded with the safety off.
Oh, my God.
They're hot to go. He said, your task is to lower the temperature.
Yeah, wow.
And see if you can't stretch it out. Give us time to burn something out.
What foresight on his part.
Johnston Island was the center of launch and experimental activity for the 1962
High Altitude Weapon Effects testing termed Operation Fishbowl.
Running from April to October of 1962, Operation Dominic was a classified American program
conducting 31 nuclear test explosions in the Marshall Islands. These tests were designed
to study the effects of nuclear detonations in high altitudes in space and near space.
One of these tests, Starfish Prime, created an electromagnetic pulse that extended over 1,400
kilometers, knocked out streetlights, triggered burglar alarms, and caused electrical surges in
nearby Hawaii. It also produced an artificial aurora visible from Hawaii to New Zealand,
and it even created a man-made radiation belt similar to the Van Allen belt that destroyed
similar to the Van Allen belt that destroyed multiple satellites.
The last few tests of this series were the Bluegill tests, which involved a unique X-ray-based
missile defense system, and Harold was put in charge of doing all of the cost assessments
for this test. Tell us about the Bluegill Triple Prime test.
Well, I arrived in Washington summer of 62. In 61, there were two high-level
tests, an incoming missile and an interceptor fired up to see if they could stop it.
Those two tests failed. Summer of 62, I arrived, and first I'm in the middle of this
missile crisis, and then before it's barely over,
hell, would you set up a small group that will give you the people to devise
the outlines of an anti-missile system so that we can start anticipating for the future.
I said, yeah, that's something that DARPA should do with a
bastard. They said, no, no, what we want is a concise top and back of the envelope calculation.
What should be the elements of it? What would it cost, and how much would it cost for the enemy to
offset it? I said, okay, I'll take it on, and I got that assignment. I'm thinking, holy cow,
this is huge, and they gave me these people in the Joint Chiefs of Staff
in the Reconciliation Valuation Group. Who am I talking to, these guys?
Missile defense was a major priority for the United States in the heart of the Cuban Missile Crisis.
While American offensive nuclear capabilities were ahead of the Soviets, the U.S. still
didn't have precise ways of defending against a nuclear attack. But there were some novel ideas
in missile defense at the time. In 1961, the RAND Corporation wrote a report called
Some New Considerations Concerning the Nuclear Test Ban, which highlighted the susceptibility
of the U.S. ICBM reentry vehicles to high-energy x-rays. To say this is a piece of steel and it's
in outer space. If you impinge high-energy x-rays on this side, so what that does is
blows chunks off the inside at hypersonic speeds. This novel insight made its way into the Operation
Dominic Marshall Islands tests. Here's where it gets interesting. These x-ray emissions could
also take out surrounding UFOs.
This new project, the same report that went to JFK. Now you can assume JFK, it was read by
McGeorge Bundy at his job. I knew it must have been read by McNamara and John McNaughton,
the general counsel, if they were all interactive. And almost certainly LBJ, because vice president
anybody. Lo and behold, they dashed down. I said, wait a minute, I'm puzzled here.
In the report you've given me, you have videos of taking down this incoming missile with
an especially enhanced x-ray projection system. But when you did that, you noticed that there
had been some object that had appeared on the screen and joined and tagged along following
the incoming missile down.
By the way, can I just interject? Because for me, I kind of got my dad a little up to speed on
the whole, why is Congress pursuing non-human intelligence? Why are they passing whistleblower
legislation? And so when we started talking about this, so he says there's this orb around
the missile. And I'm like, so didn't you think that was weird? And I realized that actually,
I think that the people of that generation were so accustomed to seeing them that they
didn't, they knew it wasn't Russian. They knew it wasn't, in those days, it was never going to be
Chinese. They knew it wasn't a threat. So dad said, yeah, we called it a tag along, a tag along.
Like, didn't you ask what it was? And, and he's sort of replied in such a way that I realized
nobody asked any questions at that time. And they were probably encouraged not to ask any questions.
That's what you would call them tag alongs. Wow. What else? So that it's so casual that you just
call them tag alongs. I think they were so inured to seeing them. They were like tag along.
The UFO nuclear connection was a complete open secret among top military brass in the 50s and
60s. In a 1952 Look Magazine article titled The Hunt for the Flying Saucer, Chief UFO
Investigator for the Air Force Captain Edward J. Ruppelt is quoted saying that many of the sightings
reported had originated at one atomic weapons related site or another all around the country.
In fact, while the Operation Dominic tests were going on in 1962, an Avco Mark IV reentry vehicle
attached to an Atlas 8F missile was being tested at Cape Canaveral in the Atlantic missile range
in September. This is the footage that was taken from that test.
At the 4 minute and 40 second mark in the video, an object appears to phase itself into existence
alongside the reentry vehicle, which is traveling at 20,000 feet per second or Mach 18. The official
U.S. Air Force NASA post flight report even states that the object's quote unquote origin or
identification could not be determined. The object appears to be in the middle of the
The very next month, after this Atlas test at Cape Canaveral, the Atomic Energy Commission
conducted the Bluegill Triple Prime test in October of 1962 in the Marshall Islands.
The point is, this was the backdrop for the Bluegill tests. One in which the military,
scientific, and political elite in America were well aware of the connection between
UFOs and nuclear weapons. Anyway, when the incoming missile
reacted to this blast of x-ray, at that moment the report said this appeared to knock down
the attack alarm. I didn't react with shock. I thought, let's find out what that was.
Was there a recovery? Yes, the Navy had recovered but fell. Tell me about it. Oh, we can't do that.
You have need to know about the incoming missile and the test, but not about the attack alarm.
Why not? Just to be clear, you've got all the cue clearances, right? Not some of them. You've got
all the cue clearances. And they say, no, you don't need to know. Why? Well, I had a blanket
cue clearance. Besides top secret and all that stuff, I had presidential clearance for the highest
level stuff that comes to the president. I mean, I had been given everything, but especially that
they gave me a blanket cue clearance. Cue was for anything nuclear weapons. Why was that separate?
Because that was managed by the Atomic Energy Commission. That was in law separate. But it's
so interesting because you hear that UFO secrecy was sort of bound up in atomic secrecy and the
Atomic Energy Commission. The guys that were involved in Manhattan were overlaying the same
ecosystem of secrecy in some of the same ways to protect stuff that they were protecting our nuclear
secret. And you don't even have access to the UFO stuff with all of your cue clearances.
Two KC-135 aircrafts in proximity of the test were gathering footage. Australian intelligence
analyst Geoffrey Cruikshank, who's done the most in-depth analysis of this test, calls these two
pieces of footage Kettle 1 and Kettle 2. A bright fiery object tumbles out from within
the nuclear fireball. You believe that that is some kind of craft?
Just like the one that was following the Atlas 8F test, but this time it was a real warhead.
You can see clearly from the Kettle 1 footage of the nuclear blast, an unidentified flying object
tumble out of the nuclear fireball. The official report written about this test at the time was
written by the Flight Dynamics Laboratory at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base. The report
tries to explain the presence of this second thermal source in the footage. Quote-unquote,
there is no evidence to indicate that even the closest pod was ever immersed in the fireball,
so it definitely wasn't one of the instrumentation pods on the missile.
If that's not weird enough, these videos were declassified to the public in 1998.
At the declassification review, the Defense Special Weapons Agency,
led by Dr. Byron L. Ristvet, applied a large white triangle to the footage, sanitizing it,
right where you can see the object tumbling out of the plume in the Kettle 1 footage.
There's well-known animosity between Los Alamos and Lawrence Livermore Labs. Lawrence Livermore
ran one aircraft, Los Alamos ran the other. The reason why the Kettle 1 footage was declassified
and Kettle 2 wasn't was simply a personal difference in what should remain classified
and what shouldn't. Then on October 21, 2023, when Jeffrey Cruikshank sent a mandatory
declassification review request to the Department of Energy asking them to declassify this Kettle 2
footage which had been sanitized, the Department of Energy responded saying that they were unable
to locate the footage. They were literally saying they lost the footage of one of their most important
high-altitude nuclear tests. And maybe all you need to know is that Bluegill Triple Prime is the only
one of the Operation Fishbowl nuclear tests where any portion of the released video is still
sanitized and classified to this day. And tellingly, look at what happened when a Freedom
of Information Act request was sent to the National Nuclear Security Administration
generally around these 1962 Operation Dominic tests. The exact request was for all records
that quote-unquote mention or relate to Starfish Prime and any of the following UFO, AP, UAV, AAV,
any acronym used by the Atomic Energy Commission at the time for unidentified flying objects.
The National Nuclear Security Administration responded. The letter back in June of 2022 reads,
it was determined that an additional review of your case by the subject matter expert with
jurisdiction regarding responsive records was required. First of all, who are the subject
matter experts on UFOs? Second of all, this seems like a tacit admission that there are
responsive records that apply to this Freedom of Information Act request that specifically ask for
information on UFOs. Finally, we have an eyewitness of the Bluegill Triple Prime test who is alive
today, a former Navy sailor named David Noble Whitecrow. He's spoken to UFO investigator Richard
and look at what he told Dolan. The witness was a man named David. He was part of what was called
Operation Dominic. He was aboard a ship called the USS Finch 19 miles south southwest of Johnson
Island or Johnson Atoll. The date is October 26, 1962. At 9.59 a.m. they launched this missile.
Suddenly he hears on the loudspeaker the voice of the ship's captain saying,
everyone below deck other than a few essential personnel and they're preparing for damage control.
After 15 minutes, an officer goes down in there and he selects about a dozen of these guys,
including David, and they're ordered to look directly forward toward the horizon
and they were not allowed to have any conversation. So after some time, I don't know how long,
the officer in charge orders them to look 10 degrees off the starboard bow. So at this point,
this is a direct quote from David. I wrote this entire thing down. He said to me, lo and behold,
what appeared in the sky, what I saw was a huge cigar shaped object coming toward us
at 10 degrees and about 15 to 20 degrees off the horizon.
And what about the most senior official present at Operation Bluegill Triple Prime?
If you're a head honcho and you see a UFO tumble out of the sky, surely you can't just engage in
business as usual. Well, the logs of a nearby Navy ship, the USS Summit County on 26 October 1961,
refer to a SOPA or a senior officer present afloat being on board the ship. That officer was General
Alfred Starbird, the Joint Task Force Eight commander of Operation Dominic. He was positioned
around 15 nautical miles from surface zero of Bluegill Triple Prime, which is the closest
allowable distance by the range safety officer. William Ogle, the Los Alamos J Division weapons
design chief was General Starbird's deputy for Operation Dominic. Ogle writes that General Starbird
left Johnston Island at 4 a.m. the night of Operation Bluegill Triple Prime. Starbird went
from the deck of the Summit County ship to taking off on a jet from Johnston Island in under four
hours. There were still very important tests to go, but Starbird apparently needed to leave
immediately, maybe because of this successful UFO tag-along shoot down.
What they said is that your project designation was this, you know, anti-ballistic mishap,
but you, we didn't anticipate this unidentified object, but it's not part of your designation,
so I said that's bullshit. So I said I need to know what you learned. Now I'm sure in different
words that's what came out of the White House to the people running the test who were
under the jurisdiction of the Atomic Energy Commission, under Lawrence Gies, who was in
charge of all this stuff. He was head of the Albuquerque Division of the Atomic Energy
Commission, but he was running everything here beside everything that had to do with Los Alamos
and high-level tests. And he's randomly Jeff Bezos' maternal grandfather through adoption.
Amazing.
It explains a lot. Jeff Bezos talked about in some of his earlier reminiscences
to reporters. He spent all his summers with his grandfather.
Interesting. Really?
Yes.
His grandfather had a farm, so I'm sure he had several summers of space.
And now he's got Blue Origin. It's so fine. It's just another point in the direction that
rocketry is not what it seems.
Right. So two things happened. I pressed hard. You know, you have to let me know what took place.
So they said, well, for that you have to come down to Los Alamos.
You pressed hard with Lawrence Gies, and he said I want to know?
I didn't know him that I was talking to.
Okay, but somebody at the Atomic Energy Commission.
I said, you know, I need to know. I'm going to decide what I need to know.
Just to back up, so you go out to Los Alamos, you get briefed, you meet Lawrence Gies,
and like literally a couple of weeks later, suddenly JFK, LBJ, and their teams are
going to Los Alamos. So I asked the question, Dad, how often does a president of the United States
go to Los Alamos? And the answer is never.
So what was so extraordinary that they all suddenly rush out there?
And this is what you have great insight into.
It was about the tagalong. That's what they wanted to know about.
They weren't all fascinated by the tagalong itself.
So when you came out two weeks before them, what did you find? What did they tell you?
I met Lawrence Gies. He said, I have this letter saying that I can brief you.
I said, thank you, because he said, well, the test details are controlled by naval intelligence.
It was interesting. He said, they don't share everything with the Navy Department.
They are an autonomous entity. They are more secure than any other intelligence agency.
It's the oldest intelligence agency in the U.S., in the 1890s.
Yeah, well, he said, just be aware, the mighty CIA is not on their fully approved list to circulate.
So I can talk about that on another occasion.
But anyway, so I said, well, what am I here to find out?
He said, well, he reached for some stuff sitting on his desk.
These are things that have come down.
So you're looking at like material, anomalous material?
Yeah.
Debris?
But debris or images?
Debris.
Wow, that's amazing.
See what it feels like.
What did it feel like?
What color was it?
The color of something in space.
What's the color of something in space?
Depends on the light in the room or the light in the camera.
Was it heavy?
Yeah, the objects were like, I mean, I picked them up.
They didn't, I didn't put them down.
They went through the heavens.
If you had been there without knowing how it was retrieved, would you think that it was at all
different than like random rocks or something?
You didn't know how it was retrieved.
But he said, no, this is some of, he said, I have it on my desk just as an example.
I mean, he didn't say it for visitors, but whatever reason he had it there.
Was it emitting alpha, beta, gamma radiation, anything like that?
I don't know, I don't know if he, he must have known it was safe.
I mean, had all this instrumentation around.
Anyway, so I, you know, I just, what have we learned?
Because it does pertain to designing a missile system.
What kinds of things can interfere with it?
Or might emulate?
We just need to know more.
Who else is studying this?
We need to know about knowledge in other, in other quarters, China or wherever, Russia.
We feared Russian science more than China at that time.
Anyway, he explained though that this is not the first case of other unidentified
objects or phenomena.
There's a history.
Now he didn't go into the history with me, he just said, do your research.
And I said, so you're telling me anyway, but the Navy says I can't know, yes.
He said yes, but probably you saw the original.
My bet is that that part of the test, the video will have been scrubbed.
Which was, but.
And he repeated, that's Navy intelligence, they're another, they live in their own world.
Sometimes they think they're even more powerful than we are, but.
Do they still live in their own world?
Yes.
That's what everybody says.
There are a few key details of this story that fill in some gaps
that Harold relayed to Pippa before he passed.
Malmgren confirmed that the entire bluegill shootdown was an attempt to down a UFO.
Malmgren explicitly told this to Pippa, his daughter, and Jeffrey Cruikshank.
He also told this to Senate intelligence staffer Kirk McConnell, who I interviewed.
What Malmgren reported that he'd been told directly by Bissell is that we downed a UFO
that was monitoring, closely monitoring that test, and it tumbled into the ocean
and that the Navy picked it up.
So the American military knew they could bait UFOs with nukes
and destabilize their flight paths with EMPs.
See, EMPs disrupt local magnetic fields.
It would even locally disrupt the magnetosphere of the earth.
If you're flying at incredible speeds in a UFO, you probably need to use some form of
quantum sensing.
This would allow you to use the magnetosphere of the earth in order to navigate.
Birds even do this.
They use avian cryptochromes to quantum sense the magnetic field of the earth and navigate home.
This form of precision sensing would be necessary in order to navigate a UFO.
So when you disrupt the local magnetic field, you could cause a UFO to spin out,
lose control, and drop out of the air.
Also, UFO propulsion likely requires megavolt range electricity and extremely strong electric
field strength over long periods of time, which would require a power source that far
surpasses traditional fuel or batteries.
I think UFOs have a nuclear propulsion source.
If the X-ray-induced shockwave from the bluegill payload would disrupt the plutonium pit of an
incoming nuclear warhead, it would also probably disrupt the power source of a UFO.
The second missing detail here is that when Harold was holding the UFO pieces Lawrence
Geiss had given him, they seemed to telepathically communicate with him.
He heard words in his head when he felt the pieces.
This is a very common trope in UFO world when it comes to people handling material firsthand.
Malmgren forgot the exact words, but he felt like they were important and that the material
may have implanted ideas in his subconscious.
He also apparently thought that this was a test that Lawrence Geiss had given him.
He wanted to see if Harold would have this mental reaction to the pieces.
Harold apparently passed.
Once Harold passed Lawrence Geiss' test and realized there was far more to this tag-long
UFO phenomenon than met the eye, Malmgren had clearly graduated from his role as the
missile cost assessment guy.
He needed to get fully read in.
That's when he received a full briefing on otherworldly technologies by Richard Bissell.
Who is Richard Bissell?
Okay, so a few months after this series of episodes, Missile Crisis, Los Alamos,
Richard Bissell called me up and said,
I'd like to spend some time talking to you.
Maybe Friday afternoons after work would be good.
I said, sure.
I knew who he was.
He was Deputy Director of CIA, and he was in the news a lot because he had been
the one who helped Kentworth develop the U-2.
And Area 51 at the time was an atomic testing site,
and he thought it'd be a good idea to test the U-2 basically right next door.
Yeah.
So Bissell, I knew he was at the center of all the scientific technology stuff.
I didn't know at that time.
His ill fortune was that he was in charge of the
Invade Cuba Bay of Pigs operation, too.
Anyway, I knew he was somebody with considerable scope of knowledge
and obviously strong enough to run a big part of the empire of CIA.
So I sat down, brought a bottle of whiskey out and said,
we don't have to drink all of it this year.
He said, I've talked to everyone around you.
You were one of the best kids, but I was told you were the youngest
because you came in a little bit after the others
and also that most of them are four or five years older.
But you were the star in terms of agility and ability to work
with the top level people without friction.
And otherwise you were an obnoxious, you know, smart ass.
So he said, you're almost certainly on a curve
where you continue to be at that level.
So there are things you need to know.
And then he went into quite a bit.
But it was not only about what we still were calling UFOs at that time,
but it was about CIA operations worldwide, the complexity.
Some times when the president and CIA were not working in concert.
But it happens when you have a big system like that.
It develops a life of its own.
What did he say about UFOs and other world technology?
And then what did he say about CIA's global nature of their operation?
Well, it all went down simply to they were opposed to anything
which threatened their control.
And these unidentified UFOs, we didn't have the UAP word yet.
They presented forces that were beyond CIA's knowledge or control.
And they interfered perhaps with what CIA was doing with private industry.
There was a lot of interaction between Lockheed Martin and CIA where...
They would show up around specific atomic testing
or around specific technology development or...
Many types of technology development.
So it's almost like the UFOs are more...
It's not just the atomic connection.
They're generically attracted to the tip of the spear as far as tech development.
That's at the heart of it.
Yeah, which is if you read the three body problem
by this amazing Chinese science fiction trilogy.
I saw the movie.
Yeah, it seems like something like that is almost the case
according to Richard Bissell.
Wow.
Yeah.
And so what does he say?
He briefs you on quote unquote other world technologies.
That to me belies almost human knowledge of these technologies.
Not just like these things are randomly showing up
when we're making advanced technology.
He said, this is real.
We don't know these phenomena.
Also, we don't know what the Russians and Chinese and anyone else knows.
That itself is threatening.
No, at that time China was not as threatening to us as Russia.
We always overrated Russia in my judgment.
And we underrated the Chinese obsession to focus in on something very specific,
which was the technology race.
But anyway, it just bothered me to know that there are all these conflicting
forces of power in play, and that they had influence on leadership in many countries,
not just Washington.
And it tends to run deep into local politics, depending on where the interests were.
Now, he didn't mention Arkansas, but when I reflect back, it probably was on his mind.
Why am I not on the front page of the paper
at Ryan Airport or any other airport with a load of dope, with a load of guns?
Did Richard Bissell know what was going on all along, that the Bluegill test was actually
always intended to be a directed energy-based UFO shoot down?
Well, tellingly, Harold told Pippa on his deathbed and off air that the CIA and Atomic
Energy Commission got the very idea of shooting down UFOs with directed energy
from an extraterrestrial being that survived the Roswell crash in 1947.
This being was apparently the sole survivor of that crash.
Harold even told Pippa that later in his career, he saw the video of this creature being interviewed.
And there's a direct link between the Bluegill Triple Prime tests
and Star Wars or the Strategic Defense Initiative that later took place in the 80s.
You see, the Bluegill Triple Prime tests inspired Edward Teller's X-ray-based Excalibur designs,
which formed the basis of Reagan's Strategic Defense Initiative, popularly known as Star Wars.
Star Wars involved a massive network of directed energy weapons for missile defense.
It also involved satellite tracking, an immaculate constellation, if you will,
for UFO shoot downs and tracking.
This of course begs the question, was Star Wars always dual use and intended for shooting down
and quarantining UAP?
And if these very concepts came from the sole surviving being from the Roswell crash,
it begs the very important question, are we involved in some sort of bizarre
extraterrestrial proxy war?
Ultimately, one can only speculate.
But it is important to note that before he briefed Malmgren,
Richard Bissell had to have known about all of this.
Remember, at the time he was deputy director of plans for the entire CIA,
and he would go on to become deputy director for the entire organization,
it's number two.
So he was likely well aware of this interview of the surviving being at Roswell.
Bissell also founded Area 51 in 1955, and he'd strategically placed it at the Nevada test site
where hundreds of atomic tests were occurring in the early 50s.
So he had to have known about the UFO nuclear connection.
Bissell likely also understood the secret UFO-related intentions of the bluegill tests all along.
But Harold goes deeper.
He implies that Bissell knows about this other layer of reality,
a form of sort of extraterrestrial exopolitics that needed to be managed
by elements of the U.S. government for decades.
Do you think Richard Bissell sort of knew that you were sort of an heir to him
in sort of a more like spiritual sense or something?
Very spiritual, and he was looking for someone who was somehow connected.
Whatever was happening with other worldly forces.
Yeah, I'm reading about them all the time.
Yeah, what else did Richard Bissell tell you?
He said this didn't start last week.
This has been going on.
He mentioned that in 1933 in Magenta.
He did?
Richard Bissell mentioned the 1933 Magenta crash.
That's amazing.
That is such corroboration because that is a highly conflicted account.
1933 was the first recovery in Europe, in Magenta, Italy.
I fully trust David Grush, but that's amazing that there's some corroboration from back then.
He mentioned it.
Wow.
Italian government moved it to a secure air base in Italy
for the rest of kind of the fascist regime until 1944, 1945,
and you know the Pope Pius XII backchanneled that.
So the Vatican was involved.
Yeah, and told the Americans what the Italians had, and we ended up scooping it.
So he said this, yeah, he said this did not begin, and you need to know the background.
How did it end up that Truman transferred that object from Italy?
The steps getting there was arranged by Alan Dulles,
but that went back to what Pippa mentioned.
And he said the steps that Alan Dulles helped with the crash retrieval.
And remember, Alan Dulles and so John Foster Dulles and Alan Dulles are twins,
and John Foster Dulles is running the OSS, the precursor to U.S. intelligence, out of Switzerland.
And then I asked, I said, Dad, why was he running it out of Switzerland?
How does that happen?
And he said, well, everybody knew that he did it deliberately
so that he would be beyond the reach of U.S. law.
Let me explain.
After all of this, all these events a few years back, when I was still an official
in the office of the trade representative, well, I was the principal.
I was invited by, you know, Switzerland doesn't have a president,
the leader revolves around the canton leaders.
But whoever was the leader that year, I visited the government about several matters,
and they served a life to see the office of Alan Dulles when he lived here.
So I said, oh, it would be fun to name a beautiful apartment overlooking the river.
And we got talking, I said, how do you explain why he chose to be here?
He said, oh, that's simple.
He told us when he got permission to maintain a very active office here
that as long as he was in Switzerland, no American law could reach him.
That's just something he did that was illegally moral or otherwise in the United States.
So he said he was here all the time, and it was to allow him a free hand to do the most
terrible things if needed.
Okay, that's understandable.
He was a creepy guy.
Right.
Now, going back to 1933, the relationship needs to be uncovered between
Angleton's father, Angleton, and the Knights of Malta.
Wow.
Because the Knights of Malta said there's long historical connection with the Vatican.
And indeed have this special diplomatic status.
You know, you can be, you can have an international passport for the Knight.
I forget how much it's a something.
It's a sovereign state for a handful of people.
Yes.
But it's all connected with the Vatican.
According to multiple accounts, including UFO whistleblower David Grush, a disc-like object
measuring roughly 10 to 12 meters in diameter came down near Magenta in Lombardy, Italy,
in June of 1933.
1933 was the first recovery in Europe.
Under Benito Mussolini's fascist regime, a total media blackout was imposed throughout the
Stefani news agency.
Telegrams threatened severe penalties for any reporters who deviated from a government-ordered
cover story attributing the event to a meteor.
Despite the censorship, a special investigative body known as Gabinetto, or RS-33, formed to study
the craft, with high-level figures such as Mussolini, Air Marshal Italo Balbo, and Nobel
Laureate and radio pioneer Mark Coney believed to have been involved.
Testimonies suggest that the downed craft and possibly two recovered bodies were taken
to the SIAI Marchetti private aerospace hangars for intensive analysis.
This secret research group reportedly drew up a nine-step protocol to manage the Magenta crash
and any similar future incidents.
The instructions included immediate site containment, arrests of all witnesses,
and thorough disinformation campaigns to quell public attention.
Sounds very similar to what happened in the United States after Roswell.
Mark Coney, long fascinated by extraterrestrial possibilities, clashed with Mussolini's
insistence that the subject must be of terrestrial origin.
Some documents and later family confirmations indicate Mark Coney genuinely believed the craft
could be non-human.
In the late 1930s, Pope Pius XII became aware of the Magenta retrieval, reportedly fearing
that any recovered technology might fall into Nazi hands once Italy allied with Germany.
Through discreet channels, the pope quietly informed the allies about the craft's existence
and storage location.
This backchannel intelligence set the stage for the Office of Strategic Services,
America's premier wartime intelligence gathering program, and the predecessor to the CIA in World
War II, to intervene in northern Italy as the war approached its end.
Working under a secret project called McGregor, OSS operatives targeted advanced access technology,
including the rumored crashed UFO.
By 1945, the Americans had reportedly transferred the Italian UFO to Wright-Patterson Air Force
Base in Ohio for further study.
Many of the top Nazi scientists as a part of Operation Paperclip that the allies had
exfiltrated also made their way to Wright-Patterson to work on the Magenta craft.
Malta, as a sovereign territory with diplomatic immunity,
would be the perfect international guardians of UFO secrecy.
Initially, when Harold said the Knights of Malta were deeply embedded in the UFO story,
I had no idea what to think.
It sounded like a plot line from a Dan Brown or Umberto Eco novel.
Secret society associated with the Vatican and the sovereign state of Malta governs UFO secrecy.
Go figure.
But not only were Hugh Angleton and James Jesus Angleton Knights of Malta, and remember,
James Jesus Angleton seemed to be responsible for a lot of counterintelligence around UFOs
that came out from the 50s to the 80s, but the bizarre Knights of Malta-UFO connection runs even
deeper after further research.
Colonel Philip J. Corso, later famous for his claims regarding reverse engineering alien
materials at the Pentagon in his book The Day After Roswell, served as a high ranking intelligence
officer in Italy during the post-war period.
In fact, he was the personal liaison to the future pope.
He was also a Knight of Malta.
He was also a main figure in Operation Paperclip and helped create the quote-unquote
rat lines, exfiltrating Nazi scientists and technology.
In fact, many Nazi scientists specifically specializing in exotic
propulsion made their way to write Patterson Air Force Base after World War II.
Perhaps the most powerful general at the time, General Douglas MacArthur and his whole
intelligence staff, Knights of Malta.
Many of his staff displayed an unusual interest in the possibility of a quote-unquote
interplanetary war, and they framed alien-related eschatology in the exact same terms Corso did.
During a 1955 speech at West Point, General MacArthur told assembled cadets,
the next war will be an interplanetary war.
The nations of the earth must someday make a common front against attack by people from other planets.
Chief OSS member and another CIA founder, Wild Bill Donovan, who journalist Chris Sharpe notes
was likely not only involved in the Magenta crash retrieval, but in setting up original protocols
for UFO crash retrievals, was also a Knight of Malta.
Atomic energy director turned CIA director John McCone, later CIA director Bill Casey,
Knights of Malta. Remember that FDR was responsible for the communications with
the Vatican about the crashed Magenta craft.
Well, President Roosevelt's Vatican envoy, Myron Taylor, also a Knight of Malta.
Maybe religious studies professor Diana Walsh-Pasulka, who has visited the Vatican
archives and speaks with conviction that the Catholic Church knows more than meets the eye
about UFOs, isn't so crazy after all. Maybe she's spot on.
And look at the group that are supposedly engaging in UFO crash retrievals today,
JSOC or the Joint Special Operations Command. According to journalist Seymour Hersh,
one of the modern heads of JSOC, General Stanley McChrystal,
and many of the members of JSOC themselves are all Knights of Malta.
Does the DEWE currently work with JSOC?
We work with all of the security entities around the federal government.
Do you guys work with JSOC? Yes or no?
Yes, we do.
Okay. There are Templars at the Vatican.
It's the residue of the truth or the myth, whatever, of Knights of the Templars.
But there are rumors that the Knights of Malta have something to do with the UFO story as well.
Well, what I'm saying is, yeah, they did because Angleton was there.
So for context for the audience, James Jesus Angleton was sort of one of the
original founders of the CIA. Dulles was sort of a mentor to him. He was a skull and bones kid
and ends up in Italy. And he's kind of this eccentric, debonair, interesting guy
who was also really just good at conniving and lying.
And so Angleton's father, Hugh Angleton, was involved with the Knights of Malta?
He was a member.
He was a member. And then so he's involved in the Vatican, which makes it more likely
that James Jesus Angleton probably had something to do with the retrieval of that UFO,
the Magenta Crash, which was kept at the Vatican.
You're speculating, but there's so many connections. There's even a guy named John
Warner IV, who is the grandson of Paul Mellon and the son of Senator John Warner.
And he tells the story where he's three martinis into, you know, a dinner or whatever with Paul
Mellon. And Paul Mellon recalls the story. Paul Mellon is one of the founders of the CIA,
and he's with Alan Dulles doing tech retrieval. And specifically, he says,
I'm in Czechoslovakia and I'm standing on top of a saucer with Alan Dulles.
And my grandfather said, look, you know, we were in a facility, a hangar, and we saw, you know,
a German flying disc. And I said, you know, oh, is that the one that was cobbled together
with six BMW jet engines? And he laughed and he said, no.
Basically implying that it was like this anomalous object. And right there in Czechoslovakia and
modern day Poland is this thing called Komlerstab, where Hans Komler, the most ruthless Nazi who was
doing the most kind of black world technology projects, was rumored to be working on flying
saucers. And there's this rumor of this thing called Deglaca. And so you have the Hugh Angleton
connection, but you also have Dulles and Paul Mellon standing on top of this saucer. And when
the magenta object crashed, supposedly there was this partnership where Mussolini went to Hitler
and was like, I don't really know what to do with this. Is this yours? And then he said, no,
it's not ours, but we should work on it together. We should collaborate.
So there's, there is, there are actually a lot of data points around this. You start to build this,
this picture up. So Mussol said that too. That's amazing. And the Italians, even to this day,
are amongst the most innovative in defense technology in the world.
That's so interesting. So maybe that either some inherited technology or something. Let me tell
you one fact point that is not well known in America. When we look at the world, we say the
second most important military force is the UK and their, and especially the RAF, but they have
really dwindled in importance. And I didn't know this until recently, but I'm somewhat
rather actively connected with the military world. I have a book coming up with essays on
geosecurity of the last 25 years that's coming up soon. Laser. And anyway, no UAVs in it, but
one of the people introducing the book was the
chief of the Italian air force. And I said, that's a little bit odd. And the editor said, no,
in Europe today, the most important air force besides the US is the Italian air force.
I have no idea. Really? So maybe they might be more advanced than meets the eye.
They were more advanced than the rest of them in Europe. Interesting. Yeah, this was news to me,
but you know. I think of Italian, I guess the cars as being fast, but unreliable. And then,
but wow, the air force. Well, northern Italy has world-class engineering, German level
engineering, and they have it in many fields. And I always thought it was very interesting that
after the second world war, the Germans were prohibited from going into aircraft because
the Luftwaffe had been such a threat. And as a result, the Germans specialized in drones.
And I got into drone technology about not quite 10 years ago, and the Germans are very strong in
that. And I started to also realize how strong Italian engineering. But I think this episode in
history is, it's not well, as well understood as it could be. And I just wonder, was this part
of what drove the decision to create what we now call the Axis? That because the Italians assumed
that this super high tech thing must be German. And that began their dialogue. And as they aligned,
that became the Axis. Wow. And then again, back to George C. Marshall and the team
that is basically cleaning up after the end of World War II and the recognition
that many people have knowledge of very advanced technologies, they must be brought to the United
States. And that operation paperclip, period. And again, who's already there? It's all these
cast of characters. And where have they been based? Italy. That's amazing. That's so fascinating.
Again, there's no proof in that. But there's an interesting line of inquiry.
But there's so much corroboration. Now we have Richard Bissell to add to the dullest Paul
Mellon story, to add to David Grush's recent testimony. So we are building up this
important corroborative narrative. I'm just mentioning in passing, you know,
this washing stick I have, it's from an old shop. It's an old, it's an old car.
But I was told it was Paul Mellon's washing stick. No way. That's so interesting. What do you,
how did you end up with that? Well, they live in the same part of Virginia. Okay.
I didn't know Paul Mellon, but I knew all the people around him, including his wife.
How? Oh, and his personal, I recall, ran the fox hunt for him and took care of the horses.
And, you know, he had race horses, everything. That guy became a close pal of mine. So I heard
all these stories about Paul Mellon. So I didn't meet Paul Mellon, but I knew more about his life
than you would imagine, including all his girlfriends. Oh gosh.
But I have his washing stick. That's so interesting. That's wild. I kind of,
I feel like we should put it in the shot or something. It was sent to me as part of my
mission, but I still don't know my purpose. Thanks, Pippa. And so what, do you think the
Knights of Malta play some sort of role in UFOs? And what do you think their role is?
Now you're getting to the heart of the residue of that organization that still exists.
What form does it take? I have no idea, but they still have the sovereign state identity.
Do you think it goes back to the original Templars? I don't know.
Okay. But how did they get the sovereign state? The Vatican must have organized it.
They seem to have kind of a lot of top level business leaders and politicians
involved in the Knights of Malta. That's right. So something, yes,
it's a secretive society. I mean, there are all these secret societies. So many things
over the years have been attributed to the Council on Foreign Relations.
Yes. I was a member of the Council for, I don't know, 50 years. I dropped out recently
because they wanted me to keep sending them large amounts of money. I thought, yeah, you know,
I've done my, I paid my dues. But when you get back for the Council on Foreign Relations,
then you dig deeper. Well, wait a minute, it wasn't really them. It was some of them,
select group through Brown Brothers Harriman that set up CIA. You know,
they're different groups, did different things. And some of the great financial figures
were involved with some, but not others.
It's not very different from the WEF in Switzerland, a different group.
But there's a Council on Foreign Relations Knights of Malta connection?
I would say there's some overlapping membership, but no connection. Anyway, the Council on Foreign
Relations has been diluted and changed since the days of the Second World War and the Cold War.
It's now much more diverse and much more
defensive of who's ever in power in the White House. I don't know what they're going to do with
Trump. But they have been, they've been swept along with progressive Democrats.
Right. So this is, you just brought this in, this is Paul Mellon's walking stick that you ended up
with. I can't verify it, but that's what I was told. These are the rumors. Does it represent
anything? It looks very unique. Well, he had a lot of power.
So that was bestowed upon you. What else, what else did Richard Bissell tell you?
Well, I mean, I think I've explained that in essence, there are a multiplicity of powers
in play at any moment. And around presidents,
they have certain powers, but they are constrained by these other powers.
And among them, the intelligence community is very powerful because it has found a way
to fund itself and to multiply itself. So you can't look at the budget and say,
that's what it is. It's, it operates businesses, legitimate and illegitimate.
Right. So it's sort of this gangly octopus. It's impossible to really capture.
And so the Russians do this too. And they even do it in overt ways. They did with the,
this group that the leader was assassinated.
Progosian.
Oh, Wagner. Wagner.
Oh, Wagner group. Yeah. Progosian. Yeah.
I mean, they do, that's overt. They do it not overt. The Chinese are everywhere doing
all kinds of stuff. Even in Manhattan. So when you weigh actions, you have to take into account
what you see and what you don't see, the unseen enemies, the, I should have been aware of that
when I blurted out some of these comments on UAPs and I stumbled into controversy. I had no
intention of, have you gotten any backlash because you've been saying some remarkable
things on Twitter or X rather. Yeah. I usually get it. So the dad dropped something on Twitter
and suddenly my inbox is full, like full. What people say, you know, your dad is breaking the
internet. But that seems positive. It's mostly positive. Yeah. Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She calls
me from some far away place, rakes me up in a room, you know, you see different hours and
dang, you just blew up the internet. I actually, I called up, I said, I leave you alone for five
minutes. Breaking the internet. I love it. I carefully crafted some backing up language
that I was not directly
involved with UAP research. You said read my words carefully. Right. Now if you read them carefully,
I was not, I'm saying it, I was not directed to look at that. It was,
but I didn't say that I wasn't aware of it. Yeah. And I knew that eventually this stuff
would come out and say, yeah, I knew about that. But I used the words to make it look like I was
backing away speculation, but I didn't do that. The words didn't suggest I was speculating.
I think this is an issue sometimes with people who are high up in government who want to disclose
certain things, but don't want to break any sort of relationships they have or oaths they've sworn
or clearances they have where you'll hear David Grush or something spec, he'll say,
this is open source. This is a personal story and he'll have to caveat constantly with that.
And so if you're an average person, you just immediately, your skeptical trigger goes off.
But in fact, he's trying to do you a service and saying, look at this, this is open source.
I just don't want to end up, you know, under the gun here because I don't want to, I don't want to,
you know, end up in jail. You're giving your enemies fodder. The thing to keep in mind,
as in the research I've done too, is what you find is a lot of this cast of characters,
including James Jesus Angleton, who went on to become the key person at the CIA.
They all seem to have been part of General George C. Marshall's team at the end of the
second world war. They're all involved with the Marshall plan somehow or another, including
Kennedy and Forrestal for a period are part of that. And so difficult to prove, but strange that
they all seem to be connected to this subject. Well, Forrestal was supposedly on this majestic
12. Who knows how much of the majestic 12 is true, but this sort of, you know, elite military and
intelligence advisory board for Truman and Eisenhower. And then George Marshall also,
there's this thing called the battle of Los Angeles in 1942, where UFO shows up and like
flies down the coast. And George Marshall was briefed to that. And so they're very interesting.
Okay. So you have, and then the other connections I think that are important to make with the
Marshall plan is that was kind of immediately after these tech retrieval programs in Europe.
So the Nazis had all this advanced technology and you had TICOM and ASOS. One was, you know,
signals intelligence. The other was, you know, atomic intelligence. And it was trying to retrieve
their most exotic technology. And if there was anything, you know, involving UFOs there,
that would sort of be bound up in it. One of my closest friends when I came to Washington
was an attorney named Tom Farmer. And Tom and I played tennis together, you know,
but turned out Tom had been general counsel of CIA.
And he'd been at, again, with the guys during the Marshall plan.
Well, I was going to say, it turned out he was involved in the project called Paperslip,
of picking Germans. And the reason why was he was born in Berlin
of a father who was a U.S. diplomat, but he spoke German fluently. So,
now, it never dawned on me when I thought maybe it was my friend that started asking
you about Paperslip, but I learned later he knew everything. He was one of the people saying yes
for him, no for him, you know. Do you believe that advanced technology has benefited from
retrieved unidentified aerial objects? So, this would be like the Philip Corso,
day after Roswell narrative. The answer I would have to give is yes in two ways.
In one way, we have learned that some types of propulsion, for example,
exists that we never envisage, never conceived. The second way
is that they have revealed a higher level of knowledge than anything we have on Earth,
and we don't control it. Now, we only recently even
confirmed where is it coming from? I mean, you know, we have this new telescope looking up,
where are they? But then we have one revelation by the oceanographer in the last few days who says
they are not China, they are not U.S., they are not extraterrestrial, meaning they're either here
already under the water or subterranean, that's where they are. And then David Grashe talks about
is it interdimensional? And one sort of wonders, is this semantics? If you ask officially,
are there extraterrestrials? The answer is no, because extraterrestrial means off planet,
but it doesn't include if it's interdimensional, if it's ocean-based. Are we actually all talking
across purposes? Well, it's the reason the All Domain Anomalous Research Office, which is headed
up by Kirk Patrick, who has all these sort of, you know, and we should get into the atomic ties
to the UFO question, he has all this whole history in atomic research, he was at Oak Ridge, and he
always rests on we have no hard evidence of extraterrestrial life. But of course, you know,
you have these anomalous things, you haven't done a proper analysis on them, you don't know what they
are, you haven't classified them, and so you just, you use, that's like this straw manning way of,
you know, explaining the thing away, and for an average person who's not really into the topic,
you go, oh, this official is saying that there's no extraterrestrials. Yeah, but it's always
extraterrestrial. So is there anything else that Richard Bissell told you? I hate to, you know,
harp on that one interaction, but it just, it's so fascinating, you have this guy who's number two
at the CIA, he set up Area 51, and he's briefing you on other world technologies. Does he say
anything else? Well, he didn't admit to or talk about bad things that had happened. He didn't
want to get into a discussion about the Bay of Pigs. He didn't raise incidents where we have
overturned governments. Somehow he avoided that stuff. But I think most of it was about if you
work at the leadership level, whether you are a leader or a guide to a leader, you've got to
keep it in play in their minds for conflicting forces, and a lot of these forces are not on any
legal boxes of who has authority over what. You can't do a diagram that is meaningful for the
entire U.S. government because a lot of it is other power networks. Well, there's Michael Turner,
who's been, I mean, he was a linchpin for three companies at least, and, you know, he blocked
everything. Suddenly he's, that's very unusual. Someone with that much power, usually you have to
buy them off. You give them something else more important. You promote them. Yeah, someone asked
me once, what's the most effective way to get rid of a major enemy? I said, you promote them.
Give them something more visible where their ego can be pacified. I did it more than once.
You don't want them licking their wounds. You'd rather have them happy and
not focused on whatever they were focused on. I've never been publicly cognizant,
but there were times, well, I think Pippa had breakfast with one member of the Congress at one
time. She told me, Dad, I had breakfast with him, and I asked him, how is it that Dad has so much
power, but he has no enemies? So many enemies. He said the only thing he would say is,
the rumor is none survived. So whether that's true or not, I cultivated that rumor. I told everybody
that's the rumor. Don't ask me. I think the key here is, it's not so much what Richard Bissell
say directly to Dad, although that has immense value. It's important to capture this for posterity,
but it's also an invitation. You are now part of a network of people. It will be known that you've
been blessed. It will be known not just in our government. It will be known in other governments.
It will be known by the Russians, and that network operates for the whole of your life.
There are different sources of information about how communication between JFK and
First Drops was established. Now, for the average human in the world in which we live, they pick up
the phone. But number one, First Drops represented the Central Committee. If you were really going
to communicate with the Central Committee, you would use Dobrynin, the ambassador who had a
direct line, so he would know. So if he didn't serve, I think he may have served us, but we
don't know. He didn't disclose. But I know Dobrynin. I can tell you about that later. But
I mean, he came to know me. That's how short that was.
But, um, but- And the American ambassador, was that Walter Stossel or who?
I don't know. It didn't matter. The only thing that mattered was Dobrynin was number one
power in communication with Moscow. But that was the official channels.
But there seems that there were also unofficial channels. Well, there had to be. And one of them
was, it seems, Norman Cousins, who was against nuclear weapons and somehow was able to pass
letters back and forth that reached Khrushchev. I'm trying to think back. I haven't talked about
this before. My first encounter with Dobrynin, as I said, he arrived in 62, a phenomenon unusual,
the member of the Central Committee. And I was attending some months after this in 63.
And I went to one of these Washington galas, you know, the White House press corps,
roast of the president, or one of those. We have those events. And when you're invited,
you get a seat with a name card. You don't sit where you want. You sit where your name card is.
So I sat down, this distinguished looking gentleman sat next to me
and said, Hi, I'm Hal Momkin. He said, Yes, I know you. I am Ambassador Dobrynin.
So all my alarms went off. That's not accidental. He chose to sit there, I'm sure. So I'll have to be careful.
And he just chatted in a friendly way. Your name is well known in Russia. Long before you're at these
heavy levels of decision making, I said, Why is that? He said, You're named after your uncle,
whose name is identical to mine. He said he was really famous as a chess player,
especially among all the security people who are nuts about in KGB and others about chess,
who was the chess champion. And he played many Russians. So he said, You were identified
as the progeny of that Harold Momkin, which in our way of thinking is good bloodlines.
And so we chatted about that and how coming to Washington was a surprise for me. He said,
Well, you've landed at the center of everything. I said, Yeah, I'm surprised. He said, Yeah,
I gather you were in there with the generals. I said, How would you know that? He said,
Our system is far more thorough. You should be aware of that than you might imagine.
I said, Yeah, you didn't ask me about what took place except to say you emerged as someone
who was able to talk down the most belligerent
American military official of all time, or about time anyway. And so he said,
made you of interest. How did you do that?
Well, like a chess player, how did you win? And so later, we had these encounters, I don't know,
once a year or something. Unplanned viewers found me. Let's have a chat. And
he did ask, I have never talked about this. He did ask at one time,
Why is everyone so excited about these unidentified flying objects?
Really? He just, innocently, he wasn't quite a pumps intelligence out of me about anything
specific. He was very careful. I said, because it's something we don't control. It's very simple.
Whatever it is, we feel threatened because we only feel safe when we are in total control.
Nations are never in total control. There are always unexpected challenges. I said,
Yeah, but tell that to somebody in Washington. I mean, they are not students of history in
Washington. The emergence of new threats. It's not something we easily absorb. It's not our culture.
We're either triumphant or not. Winning the second world war made us feel really superior.
So he said, there's something there, I remember he said, that is dividing your country,
but maybe could unify our two countries. That's the way he said it.
And this is about the UFO subject.
So extraordinary.
Wow.
I think he was looking for me to say something, but I was not privy to those
letters between JFK and Khrushchev.
And there are rumors that JFK wanted to do a joint space program with the Soviets
around this and use the UFO thing as kind of a unifying rallying cry or something.
Number one reason, that's not being misguided by these events to think it might be us versus them,
that this is not Russia or the US. So we need an early warning system.
Those things that you see are not ours.
That makes sense. How it extended beyond that to the other idea.
Maybe we should work together. Put the swords down and let's come up with a way
to develop our futures without being mortal enemies.
Now, that switch, my understanding was definitely in Kennedy's mind.
And so, did I see any note? No, I didn't. But some people did.
The fact that he expressed verbally to a number of the senior people his desire to share our
knowledge of UFOs with Russia caused alarm among some officials in Washington. Now,
Khrushchev may definitely, but that was one of many things that JFK and he were fighting about.
So, but it seemed to alarm people at CIA, some people, CIA is a big organization.
There is this letter that was foiled, used the Freedom of Information Act to get out of the
government in 2005. And it's of controversial provenance. So we should caveat that to the
audience. But it's a letter from JFK to acting CIA director John McCone after he had fired Dulles.
And he's basically saying, we need to coordinate. I need all of the data on, quote, unquote,
unknowns in sensitive airspace from NASA, because we need to coordinate better with the Russians.
So they don't mistake these unknowns as acts of American aggression. And that he's basically
saying, I need all the UFO data so I can better coordinate with the Russians and we don't end up
in some horrible bomb out scenario due to the UFOs. How do we deconflict? How do we create
a regime for deconfliction so that we don't inadvertently fire and it's not the Russians,
or vice versa? And in the 1971 SALT treaty, it's written into it. It's that sort of same
language is written in there. And so do we think that this letter might be real,
this 2005 FOIA letter? That's amazing. Do you think that UFOs played any sort of part in JFK's death?
This is pure speculation until we see. But do I think so? Yes. I think it was probably
the number one issue. Why do you think that?
Because from what I have read, not what I know, because I don't know anything about the actual
documents sent by JFK to Russia, but what I've read is that he wanted to talk openly about
the UAP phenomenon and the basis for why don't we stop fighting with each other
and join forces with and make peace. And he also wanted to reduce the nuclear arsenal on both sides.
Yes. And that was also a threat and challenge to certain part of the community. And Dulles
specifically hated that vis-a-vis China because it was like if we didn't have nukes, they would
outman us. Yeah, it was really by numbers. So you think maybe in some of that correspondence,
it was, let's work together on the non-human intelligence or alien issue. It's funny. Douglas
Caddy, who is the lawyer of Howard Hunt, Howard Hunt's this known CIA, longtime spook who shows
up in all sorts of, he's like the janitor in Watergate or whatever. It's incredible.
Douglas Caddy says, I kept asking Howard Hunt, what was the JFK murder actually about?
And he kept giving these kind of deflection answers. And then finally he says,
it was about the alien presence. I think it was. That's fascinating. I think JFK fully knew all
about UFOs long before he became president. What gives you conviction in that? Because
he was in naval intelligence for a while. He learned most of it from Forrestal.
He was in intelligence. Forrestal was secretary of the Navy before becoming secretary of defense.
Yeah. And Forrestal fully briefed him and talked about it. And he talked about it. You'll have to
do the history, but he was fully briefed by Forrestal. How do we know Forrestal knew about
UFOs? Because there are tons of rumors. He managed Admiral Byrd, who engaged in Operation High Jump,
bringing probably like 70 or so ships and 33, I think, airplanes and almost 5,000 men down the
coast of Argentina and towards Antarctica. And they reportedly encounter all these flying saucers
that are shooting at them with lasers. But other than that, do we have any real evidence that
Forrestal knew about UFOs? You have to do more research. My research, which tends to be scattered
until recently, I haven't tried to organize it. But I found several references to Forrestal,
for him going to Forrestal with questions and getting answers. Interesting. Well, you know,
JFK was also extremely interested in astrophysics at Harvard and was close with Don Menzel, who was
this famous UFO debunker, but who admitted to JFK that he held some of the deepest, you know,
clearances across the board, CIA, NSA and Navy. And so maybe there's some sort of connection there.
But did you ever speak to JFK about UFOs directly? No, no. My interaction with JFK
and Bobby was very limited. But I was somehow part of the plan because Sarge Schreiber, the
brethren though, was the go-between. He talked to me all the time. Sarge Schreiber proposed me
several different jobs, and I defined each one.
But I was an accepted inner circle person. But Bobby and Teddy, they were consumed
with events that seemed to be coming at them faster and faster. If I look back at top management,
I would have to say they were operating without an adequate buffer system.
So my guess is they were overloaded with stuff and didn't have a way. Neither one of them.
When you're a senator, you have a small staff, but you know, you're operating on your own.
You don't know how to run an apparatus. Someone like LBJ came in. He ran the whole damn Senate.
Some multitude of people at lower levels. But JFK came in with a small limited naval experience,
but seemed to be busy with Forrestal. Do you think Forrestal's death had anything to do with
UFOs? So Forrestal was sort of pushed out of his position as Secretary of Defense,
and he was sort of betting on George Dewey against Truman. And then he ends up in this Navy hospital
in Bethesda, Maryland, and he sort of, you know, gets killed by gravity, quote unquote. So he's
like mid-writing some Sophocles poem. I think his brother, Harry Forrestal, had met with him the
day before, said he was totally of sound mind. Through a window didn't seem to be openable.
That's right. That was the other thing. Yeah, and it was like his bathrobe was like tied to the,
the whole thing made no sense. So do you think that had anything to do with an interest in
UFO subject? Probably. Wow. But I'm not going to speculate. Yeah. And so after JFK and all these
guys, George McBundy, all of his top aides, they go to Los Alamos. They're presumably given the
same sort of briefing that you got. Do you think he then takes an increased interest in UFOs
at all? Yes. And what makes you think that? I think JFK somehow saw this moment to make world
peace. We weren't worried about China at that moment. But why don't we and the Soviets just
stop fighting, join forces, explain what we know together, and deal with this
force that we don't understand. And somehow in that exchange during the crisis itself,
there were communications with Russia. We don't know every word. Maybe some of it is recorded.
And some of it may have been through Dobrin, who may have used his lines.
He had his method of communication that was theoretically, it couldn't impregnate probably.
I've seen him establish a working discussion between two guys. And that's a thread that
recurs occasionally. Actually, Gorbachev was being interviewed by Charlie Rose.
And Charlie is saying, you know, talk to me about your correspondence with Reagan.
And Gorbachev goes in a really weird direction that nobody expects. And he says, well, one time
we're sitting there, you know, Reagan turns to him and he whispers, he says,
if the United States were attacked by someone from outer space,
would you help us? I said, no doubt about it. He said, we do. So that's interesting.
Right now in modern times, we are clearly shooting at these things.
In the week of the Chinese balloon, there were three other unidentified objects that the military
said they shot down. And so here's just a very profound question. If this represents higher
intelligence or even just intelligence, let alone higher intelligence, is shooting at it the right
way to open the conversation? Number one. Number two, generally speaking, you're not supposed to
shoot at stuff if you don't know what it is. And so are we locked into a kind of 1950s
thinking about this thing? Because it's so secret. It's so compartmentalized. It's so dangerous to
national security that no one can even really discuss this. And are we missing
something quite profound because we won't even ask the question, why are we shooting at something
that we don't understand and might represent intelligence of some kind?
Maybe they're sort of waiting. You know, there's one of my favorite quotes, Eden Philpott. It's
like, the world is full of magical things patiently waiting for our wits to get sharper.
And there's something about this bi-directional, you know, if we ascend to a certain level,
maybe we can have communion with these things, but it doesn't really make sense for them to
show themselves to us until then. Again, regardless of whether it is real, since we can't identify it,
what I find, again, interesting to observe is the level of fear that exists. And particularly in that
official circles and amongst the militaries, because of the lack of control, that it must be
dangerous. It must be a threat. And you will often hear the discussion of there's this thing
in our airspace. I'm like, what if we're in its airspace? Yeah, right, right. Just a creative
way of thinking. What's the definition of airspace in a world where we have a James Webb
telescope that is literally millions of miles away? We're probably in a lot of other airspaces
that we can't even identify. So it's just, again, given the level of scientific and technological
advancement that we humanity are capable of, we are sending drones millions of miles away.
Why are we surprised if we have something here as well? And so it's the way you begin the thought
process on this. I fear we're stuck in this mental lockdown that made sense in 1950,
but it doesn't make sense in 2025. It really doesn't. It doesn't even make sense from a
national security standpoint, which shouldn't be the primary lens through which we see this,
but it is an important lens. And it doesn't make sense. Yeah, exactly. If you have this
over-compartmentalization and Cold War secrecy where you have these aerospace prime contractors
that were sent to do this so you couldn't use the Freedom of Information Act or you wouldn't have
civilian oversight or whatever. Plausible deniability. Plausible deniability. And then
you have constant compartmentalization. So the left-hand side talking to the right,
you're not getting the proper coordination on the most advanced and exciting and interesting R&D.
I would go a bit further. And again, Dad and I have talked a lot about this.
There's another layer of this problem, and that is China, Russia, India, they never had what we
would call a Cartesian Revolution. Meaning in the West, the United States and Europe,
after Rene Descartes, the philosopher, basically split apart the scientific from the mystical,
the mysterious, the religious, the belief systems. And we continue to this day to have this split.
And so therefore, you can't study this stuff because if it's not repeatable, it's not subject
to scientific analyses because that's all about repeatability. But the rest of the world didn't
have this split and they still think holistically. And you can have mystical happenings with
scientific findings, and that is not contradictory in China, in Russia, in India, and across Africa.
So the question today is, is China, maybe in collaboration with Russia, making more progress
because they don't have this mental hang-up? If you wanted to study certain kinds of things
related to what's called ESP in the United States, you had to hide it very carefully
because you were crazy and the government didn't want you people to think they're supporting crazy
stuff. But if you wanted to do the work in Russia, go right ahead. Fine, here's your money. Because
they're not caught in the religion that says it's not possible. That's an interesting question.
We can't bring our science to it because we have an inhibition. And if China can,
is it possible that they will announce this first? And that's part of why I think a lot of this
is progressing. There's a fear of what is called catastrophic disclosure.
And then China says, we have the fastest supercomputers and quantum computers. We have
the best artificial intelligence and artificial general intelligence. We got to the moon before
you guys in this round, which looks like it's a real possibility. And we have found something.
And if that is announced, we in the West will go, well, prove it. But the whole rest of the world
in that moment, the danger is all the adulation, admiration of Los Alamos, of NASA, all eyes turn
to Beijing. And then we can say, oh, well, but this is not scientific and you can't prove it.
But the whole rest of the world is still in awe and wonder. And that is another reason why
is not in our control here in the United States. There's a real possibility that our competitors
are racing ahead because they haven't got these mental constraints.
I think that's very well said. Yeah. And I hope policy makers and whoever's listening to this
listens to that and we make real changes accordingly.
We're going to do an Explain That Tweet series with you.
Oh, God. The ones that had me going, Dad, what the heck?
I call Curtis LeMay and I said, General, I know we have a room at Wright-Patterson
where you put all his secret stuff. Can I go in there? I've never heard him get mad,
but he got madder than hell at me, cussed me out, said, don't ever ask me that question.
You said on X that you thought Curtis LeMay had some knowledge of the UAP topic.
Yeah. Why do you think that?
I never heard him say something about that, but the research that he was into included the
nuclear-powered airplane for the better bombers. Project Orion.
The better bombers. I have to think about it. I have a reason somewhere in the back of my head.
Maybe we're going to have a break soon. I'll have to think.
Yeah. He started the RAND Corporation and was interested in Townsend Brown's work as well.
And RAND did right on the subject at the beginning.
They did. And you know who ended up running RAND, was the president of RAND for
over two or three decades. It was Michael Rich, who's Ben Rich's son. Ben Rich is obviously
the successor to Kelly Johnson at Skunk Works, who's responsible for the stealth revolution.
Small group of people that are all interconnected.
Yes, absolutely. You also said on X that you have uncovered collaboration between
Nikola Tesla and Thomas Townsend Brown.
Yeah, but I said to you informally, I did not get that from any U.S. source.
What source did you get it from?
Foreign intelligence.
Do you think it is a good source? Do you think it's real?
No reason. Why would somebody tell me that?
Do you know the nature of that collaboration?
Yeah, because nobody had associated them. Now, as I say, I have a network worldwide.
It's not a network of secrets. It's a network of trusted people. I mean, during a lot of these
recent years, I had friends, the national security chief for the Japanese prime minister, my buddy,
from Europe.
Actually, Dad, we should say that after you served Kennedy, Johnson, Nixon, Ford,
you were also an advisor to many heads of government for many European countries.
You advised every single Japanese prime minister since Takenaka in 1971.
So, I mean, the breadth of the network that he has is exceptional. I've never seen anything like it.
Well, when Nixon went down, Jerry Ford entered the White House.
The first full day, I got summoned. He was there with Bill Seidman. Bill Seidman was,
later years, the head of resolution trust and the FDIC and all that. Bill Seidman was brilliant.
Anyway, he said, Hal, we've got something you want to do. I said, you know, I'm probably going to
leave the government soon. Well, don't hurry. We have a lot of things we want you to do.
But first of all, we want you to arrange with the NSA a new intelligence system where
what is reported of interest to Jerry Ford is what he wants, and not what the CIA thinks he ought to want.
So, I did that. The next morning, at 6 a.m., I'm living in Georgetown at the time,
somebody knocking on my door. I'm sent by the Director of the NSA to give me a morning brief.
Every day, I had, you know, I prefer to get up just a hair later. But anyway,
and I said, well, Jerry Ford doesn't need to know about the new mistress for the French Prime Minister.
It's not really up his alley. What we do need to know is important things like
Russian bookings for ships that might have capacity to move a lot of hours range because
you're worried about inflation. So, I went through a list of such things. Oh, this is wonderful.
A few weeks after that, the head of NSA, you know, some general, I don't remember his name now,
told me, can you have lunch over here? Okay. And he said, you're the best client NSA has ever had.
You're telling us what you need. We have huge resources, but we never know what the client wants.
So, we feed them all kinds of stuff and we give it to CIA and then they decide what might be of
interest to them. And they emphasize the love life of most important people. That sounds like a CIA
thing to do or just go for the compromise or something. You know, it keeps your attention.
But I'm told that your reconfiguration of the intelligence that goes into the presidential
daily briefing remains and that the NSA continues to have that input, which they did not have before
that time. Wow. I can't prove that myself, but that's when I'm dead to believe. After I left
government. Well, real quick, Harold, I do want to stick on the Townsend Brown Tesla collaboration.
So, do you know anything about the nature of that collaboration?
About anti-gravity motion. Wow. And so, Tesla stumbled on this stuff as well because they
were both working with high-voltage electricity. Yeah. I really would like to read
such as workbooks, but they're all in the hands of you can't have access.
You know who was tasked with retrieving Tesla's files? John Trump, who was an MIT professor,
the world's or the country's leading radar expert at the time and Donald Trump's uncle.
Yeah, but he passed them over. Didn't need to enable the intelligence. Isn't that right?
I don't know. That's interesting. And that goes towards your theories around this stuff. And
I'm pretty sure Townsend Brown's stuff was classified by the Navy. Yes. Yeah, it had to
be because he was working on submarines. He was. Yeah. And he was part of the Navy
up until 1942 when Skunk Works started. And then he joined Martin Vega Corporation,
but maybe he was still working for the Navy because he showed up two weeks after
leaving the Navy. And he sort of left, you know, they said that they dismissed him,
but like he had an amazing record. And there's even an FBI file from the time saying he was
the country's leading radar expert. So there's something around that story. That's very
interesting. It is fascinating too, that the public are clamoring for the release of the JFK
file, but still no talk of the Tesla papers. Yeah, nobody talks about it. And so what's in there
that's of such great importance? Well, Tesla's another guy. He said he spoke, he communicated
with aliens in Colorado Springs and people just, I think they assume that's the quacky part of his
work or whatever. They assume that that's ridiculous or whatever, but he said that.
You know, so, and then Townsend Brown would constantly talk about, you know, space brothers
and communication with aliens. He would sleep next to what he called a shortwave radio.
He claimed that that was how he communicated with them.
It's quite possible that there was communication improvised, different ways of, is there a way to
communicate? A shortwave radio would be one not so hard to do, harder is to get in somebody's head
telepathically, especially because we don't grow up thinking that way.
And yet the US government spent a fair amount of time and money on exactly that issue over the
years. Well, to the extent that they learned anything between that and LSB, we'll never know,
but they have some knowledge. Yeah, because this is an interesting kind of question,
because Stargate, this psychic spy program started by Hal Putoff and Russell Targ,
originally most of the guys working on that were part of the technical staff services, the CIA,
and it was people like Sidney Gottlieb and a lot of his comrades who were working on this stuff,
and then post church commission that kind of changed. But yeah, how far do you think we
went when it came to kind of mind control? It's clear that one intelligence modality is being
able to remote view, draw up Russian nuclear bases, find hostages, all sorts of things like that.
Even Jimmy Carter is on record saying the craziest thing of my presidency from 1976 to 1980 was
actually this woman, Rosemary Smith, finding a downed TU-22 Russian cargo plane, and she was
given all of Africa as a target, and she circled three square miles in Zaire, and they found the
plane. And the next time one of our space satellites went over that area, we located the plane where
she said it was. So that's clear, but do you think we've gone farther in their sort of mind
control techniques that we have? Very nicely, but we don't know, do we? Yeah. Personally,
when I think about always being at some critical point, all these interconnectivities for men,
I keep looking for where's the direction coming from. I mean, I don't feel any direct
sensing. On the other hand, when I grew up, my mother was a powerful personality,
brain. I mean, she could read my mind. She said, why did you do that? And I was like, I don't
remember doing that. Yes, you do. Let me see. It was 3rd of January, 1942 or something, you know.
And how did she do that? She could do it, but I couldn't do that with her. But on the other hand,
I sometimes feel that there's this hand over me that's leaning a little left or leaning a little
right. That's as close as I have to it. And now you feel maybe somewhat guided to look into a lot
of this, you know, Townsend Brown and UFOs. I feel guided. And why did I hear about that? Because
I showed a deep interest. I sent a tweet saying, why is it I can't see
Tesla's work? Why? What's so important? To be honest, as a semi-scientist, let's call that,
and I respect the work of Albert Einstein, but his work are conceptual and theoretic,
drawing on math. Tesla was very much hands-on when he's learned about electricity, its application.
In everything, the movement of electrons that far transcends powering lights in your room,
which led him into physical movement, transposition, whatever term you want to use.
But all that is buried, but he was way, way out there. I mean, in my mind,
he was equal to or even stronger than Einstein. I agree with that.
Well, Einstein was never an experimentalist. Tesla was dealing real experiment.
If I say, he was cerebral. It was all mental conceptual.
To me, it's almost like Einstein put a governor on our physical progress in reality.
I agree with that. He made physics go that way, whereas Tesla was trying to pull the physics that
way. Yes, and the experimentalists make the most progress, and often they're poor theoreticians,
and they don't actually have the proper frameworks to really understand what they're doing.
They're operating at the boundaries of human knowledge, and often it's with high-energy
physics or particle accelerators, things like that, where we're doing things in the physical
world that are breaking prior limits. Sometimes it's in microscopy and just getting to lower
levels of granularity, but I think that begets so much more progress than guys with chalkboards,
just like writing equations. This comes up against another issue,
and you and I were talking with Eric Weinstein the other day about this, which is, did we create a
invisible glass or perspex wall? Many technologies, particularly in the nuclear space,
were placed on the other side, and so you could only study them or get involved with them if you
had a classified status and you joined a government lab or an approved academic lab.
But if you tried to do things with nuclear physics in your garage, you were going to be arrested,
and people have been arrested over the years for attempting these things.
Well, that pushed a lot of theoretical physics into the don't touch
arena, and now because of incredible advancements in computational power in
the kind of devices that gather data, basically you can't lock it away the way you used to.
People are able to uncover it, and maybe that is part of also what is causing this UAP issue
to bubble up to the surface, is because it's very hard to keep a lock on it now. You can classify
the Tesla papers, but human beings are still starting to figure out what Tesla figured out,
and today there's been talk of, for example, Andreessen and Horowitz, who are two of the
leading venture capitalists alive today, who have recently been discussing the previous
administration's attitude towards math, because they don't want some teenager coming up with an
artificial intelligence that would have wide-ranging consequences, so they started to think we could
lock that down. You know, one of the things we argued in our meeting with the White House
on AI policy was, you know, look, there are going to be issues that come from AI, but they should
be regulated. The regulation should happen at the application level, not at the technology level.
And he argued with me when I said that.
So Ben basically said, look, it doesn't make sense, because to regulate AI at the technology
level, you're regulating math, and of course, we're not going to do that. That doesn't make
any sense, and you'll recall that what they said was, no, actually.
We can classify math.
We can classify math, and literally, this is verbatim. We classified whole entire areas of
physics in the nuclear era and made them state secrets of the theoretical physics.
Science and physics.
And they're like, wait, what?
They're like, what? Yeah, like, physics is supposed to be open source.
And so you start to wonder, is Eric Weinstein right that physics went down a certain road
because there was a wall?
Yes.
And now the weight of new innovations is crushing that wall.
Well, that brings, you know, another Explain That Tweet series. So we have, Harold, you wrote,
questions appearing regarding successor to AEC. AEC is the Atomic Energy Commission.
Department of Energy now oversees all national labs, including nuke research and security.
National labs also include advanced research on other potential security threats,
such as biotech, all subject to DOE, Department of Energy, R&D classifications.
So are you saying here that our most advanced science is not occurring
in the labs or hallways of MIT, Harvard, Stanford, but in fact, at these DOE research facilities?
Yes.
I guess that's just a Mike Girard moment.
Let me give you an example.
I became really close friends with Howard, Senator Howard Baker.
I mean, he would have made a great president. Anyway,
I worked with him, talked to him a lot. We became friends. He had me and my wife of that time
down at his country house several times. And he said one day,
I wanted to go up to Oak Ridge and spend some time with them. And I said,
oh, I didn't know you were attached with them. I thought you were attached with Tennessee Valley.
He said, yeah, but I live in Tennessee. I'm nearby. You can imagine that we are intimately
interconnected. I would like you to spend a few days talking to them about the technologies
they're working on that might be made commercialized in some way or other,
because they don't have that in their work agenda. They just develop and develop.
But he said, I just have a feeling that a lot of that should be made public.
So I did. And they had really interesting stuff going on, areas that you'd never think of.
The most impressive one was when somebody said, we know more about filters than anybody in the
world. I said filters. I said filters for the water supplies and filters of molecules, filters
of any moving elements of our system. And we don't have a purpose for all of this,
but they're very important in developing refining nuclear weapons. That's why we do it.
I said it's a great value in biotech and in the management of the water supply is only one of
many things. But it should be, well, we don't have a mechanism for generalizing what we're doing.
And it's too much work to say, let's be regular. So we don't want to get tangled up with all that
stuff in Washington. So we just do what we're doing. It stuck in my mind. And why it stuck?
When AT&T was on the eve of being broken up, AT&T hired me as the final witness before
Judge Harold Green. And I got into, the United States is not ready for a total breakup because,
number one, Bell Labs is where all our really advanced science is. How do you know that?
Because I went to Bell Labs. I spent a week there. I'm telling you that's where all the brain power
is. And I said the second reason is our industry, we don't have Panasonic and all these other
companies ready to build all the phones for all the offices. We're not ready.
So if you're going to do this, it should be done in stages. The Department of Justice guy kept
getting up. I object to this testimony. It's not part of the case. And Judge Green shut them down
and said, he's the first man to talk about anything relevant and of interest to me as a human being.
So just let him talk. Do you believe, because we're talking about Bell Labs, that's part of
this narrative of this guy, Philip J. Corso, who was working in the army on what he claims to be
the Foreign Material Exploitation Desk. He says that as part of that role, basically crash materials
from Roswell were given to him to dole out to private industry. And mainly it was given to
Bell Labs. He says that Kevlar, lasers, and transistors were all derivative of this alien
technology. Should be. So you'd say possible, but you don't have any evidence for that? No,
but it should be. Okay. Let me interject. Something that keeps coming up in conversation
about this issue is I hear a lot of, Pippa, look for the technologies where there's no on-ramp.
I go, what do you mean on-ramp? I mean, you can't find the research history
that led to it. Those are the interesting ones to pay attention to. They're not saying it's
definitely from this particular story. They're just saying the ones that come out of nowhere,
those have interesting stories. So fascinating. And Harold, do you believe, because you're
interested in Townsend Brown to begin with, presumably the source gave you this information
on Townsend Brown collaborating with Tesla, which if that's true, that is remarkable
and needs to be known more broadly. Do you think that Townsend Brown discovered anti-gravity?
I don't know, but somebody just posted on the internet the workbooks of Townsend Brown,
and I downloaded the whole thing. It turns out to be 500 pages. I have it on my telephone.
He's very excited about it. That's amazing.
I'm going to go through that. Yeah.
Somewhere in there, I'm going to find something. So I can't answer your question right now.
But I think Tesla anyway was on this track of movement of electrons
and allowed repositioning of just about anything.
What exactly does that mean?
It's the term transmutation.
Interesting. Of elements. So that's so interesting because when I go deep enough on the Townsend
Brown stuff with certain scientists, they'll say that it gets into that, the transmutation of
elements thing, and that's actually why this stuff was shut down because there are more dangerous
implications around that than the anti-gravity stuff.
Well, look at today. Again, I'm a bit involved in the world of artificial intelligence. We already
are able to create what are called programmable materials where you can specify the behavior of
the material and use materials as a data transmission mechanism. So suddenly you're
dealing with things and capabilities that don't fit traditional parameters. Let's add to that that
because of Google's new Sycamore supercomputer and their new Willow chip, they're already
discovering basically the recipes for creating new materials atom by atom by atom, which is a
revolution in human history. Because in the past, you had to start with a tree to make a table out
of wood or a boat, right? But today you can start with what is the requirement? What are the
characteristics that I need? And then build that material atom by atom by atom. So suddenly,
I mean, we have, I think they've said 380,000 new materials and 2 million new crystals
that no one's ever worked with before. And this will only continue now. So these ideas that you
can have materials that do strange things is no longer insane, like we're building them.
What this allows you to do is to devise it in here and make it over there.
Also, yes.
So you can make it anywhere once you have the concept. It's a cookbook.
It's a cookbook.
Okay, so the JFK administration, you're this young whiz kid and you see this kind of rupture
in the administration where JFK says he's going to scout the CIA to the winds. Dulles gets fired.
He's kind of licking his wounds back at the Brown Brothers Harriman, which is this firm that sort of
formed the CIA to begin with. And he is plotting possible revenge against JFK?
Probably.
What do you think happens from there? Do you think Dulles had anything to do with JFK's assassination?
Well, they say they are going to release all those papers now.
That's right.
So we'll see. But what does all those papers mean? I mean, like one version or all the versions?
Have you ever met a guy named Danny Sheehan by any chance?
I've never known him.
So what do you think of, because you tweeted, this was the first time I was so like, I was like,
wow, I'm on Harold's radar. This is amazing. You tweeted, Jesse from American Alchemy just went
over a lot of the history around the JFK assassination with Danny Sheehan. And so I felt
like that was maybe somewhat of an endorsement of the Danny Sheehan narrative of what happened.
Pippen knows him. Pippen knows him even better now. I'm about to know him, it seems.
Nice. So his narrative is that Nixon, who is head of the 5412 committee under Eisenhower,
along with being his VP, he was working with Howard Hughes to create this, quote unquote,
S-Force, which was this kind of elite kind of sleeper cell unit. And they were going to take out
Che Guevara and Castro. And that ends up not happening. The Bay of Pigs occurs and Eisenhower
leaves and JFK comes in and they sort of get rolled into these other special ops programs,
Mongoose and Foxtrot. And then once JFK fires Dulles, Dulles is kind of licking his wounds at
the Brown Brothers' Harriman, and he recommissions this S-Force, which is full of these Cuban exiles
who've been militarized originally to take out Che Guevara and Castro, but in fact this time around
to take out JFK. Do you think that there's any credence to this story? There are quite a few
stories. When I was six years old, my father moved us to
first to Providence, Rhode Island, and then to a community a little further along, Narragansett Bay.
And suddenly I found myself in a community which was totally dominated by the Sicilian Mafia.
In fact, most of Rhode Island was. Interesting. And the dominant mafia figure for Boston was
the overseer was Providence. And I grew up in this environment where in school if one kid,
one male, got to be a bully out of nowhere around near closing time for school, a couple of guys,
a couple of guys, big guys would come in, grab him, take him out, beat the shit out of him.
And then they told us next day, he won't bully you anymore. And so I later on began to ask
the police, how does it work here? I said, no disorganized, no disorganized crime.
No break-ins, no bullying, no wife beating, no disorganized crime. Organized crime definitely
is protection. And all those stories about mafia movies, I mean, I grew up in all that. Yeah,
this is the way it works. And I met a lot of these people, not by culture. I wasn't even
Catholic, the role of Catholics. But I learned a lot about it. Now, let me tell you, it's very
interesting to me. The first time I met the Prime Minister of Italy in 1973, along with Pete Peterson,
who'd been sent over by Nixon to do a kind of tour of the world, I sat down and I said,
I sat down. He said, Mr. Malmgren, I've been looking forward to meeting you. Pete,
you won't understand this. Let me explain. How he knows all about the Sicilian way.
He grew up in it. He understands it. I know what he knows. So let me explain before you start some
lecture on the confusion of state and crime in Italy. We had all these
communist troublemakers, red brigades, all kinds of stuff. The only way the church
and the state could fight, we had to use the mafia. Because they could do things we couldn't do.
Okay.
So, yes, there was a triumvirate that ran Italy for a long time, and it was an alliance of the
Pope, the Vatican, the elected government, and the Sicilian mafia.
We'll let the audience interpret that analogy as an answer to the JFK question.
When I met, Chris Hooter had been governor of Massachusetts before he, he'd been in Congress
and governor of Massachusetts before he became secretary of state. So I asked him one day, I
said, how did you ever do that? I said, you're a straight shooter. Why did you ever take that job
as governor of Massachusetts? He said, what do you mean? I said, you can't run
the state of Massachusetts without running Boston. You can't run Boston without
the mafia. He said, oh, you asked the same question my wife asked me. Why are you
doing this stupid thing? Why do you want to take it on? He said, I puzzled, I thought, I thought,
and decided I'm going to establish a principle, and it worked for me. I said, what was the
principle? I announced that I will not meet with anyone for any reason outside government without
members of the press president. And he said, no one from the mafia could come to talk to me
without me inviting the president. So they had to use indirection. And I could always rave them
off saying, I don't, I'm not going to even say, is that a threat? I'm going to ignore you. He said,
I just insulated myself totally. And he was independently wealthy as well. So he couldn't
be bought. He said, they can't touch me. I'm really wealthy. So I thought they asked me,
how are you going to spare me a little money? But I think it's so interesting. How did the
prime minister of Italy know? And the answer must be that because you grew up in that community,
they knew you, they knew your dad. I never told anybody about it. He knew all about it.
So that's a different network.
Coming from me to see the archbishop. We were over there. Martinkas, former archbishop of Chicago.
Big guy, tall in his black robe, cowboy boots, leaning back, smoking a big fat Cuban cigar.
He saw it up the same way. He read all about you. He wanted to meet you. And Mr. Howell,
I think he said, here, he understands everything. But so bear with me. I will explain to you.
Howell will explain more if you have questions later. And I looked up and he said, we know about
you from your boyhood with a lot of our associates in the mafia. So then he proceeded to
talk about the tripartite way of defending themselves against communism.
I remember coming out of the pizza. How does he know all that? I said, search me. I don't know.
But there was movement between Sicily and people living near where I was. And I met a lot of these
people. They never said, boy, when you grow up, you can be one of us. I wasn't one of them. I wasn't
Catholic. I wasn't something. Anyway, it was interesting.
Well, it sounds like the Italian government and the Vatican were tied into,
they had mob ties in the US. And that connectivity allowed them to understand who you were
to begin with. That's amazing.
Do you think there's like a deeper layer to politics that people are unaware of that,
you know, I mean, even outside of the talks of like a quote unquote deep state or, you know,
unelected bureaucrats running the government? Like, is there something even deeper at play
that's sort of transnational?
You could call Putin right now, this minute.
Really? You have you have a direct line to him right now?
Yep. And they were trying to establish a back channel and Obama shut down the back channel that
Yeah.
We've probably never needed this back channel more than we do today.
Harold understood Putin's psychology. And with tensions between the US, Russia and China running
high, Harold's deep expertise on nuclear game theory, and his former close friendship with
conflict escalation expert Herman Kahn would be eminently useful.
I was identified early as the person whose name they were familiar with, the chess player.
And it builds slowly. In 1982 or something, I was with Kissinger and George Jills and a
couple of other people in Moscow. As an aide, we were invited to watch the ballet and we came
and we were going to be seated in the Tsar's box. And Kissinger, as usual, marched ahead of
everybody and went to the seat of the Tsar. And one of the HGV people said, Henry, not tonight.
Not tonight. That seat is for Dr. Malamudin. And he said, what?
There must be some misunderstanding. He said, no, no, we know him. He is the shadow of his uncle.
You are not one of the world's great chess players. You may think you are. And he may not be
yet, but he comes from that bloodline. And in honor of him, he will sit in that chair tonight.
Now, it was intended humiliation of Kissinger.
Yeah, Kissinger must have not been very happy.
I think he melts it down.
I was already at war with Kissinger on other issues. He really got pissed off.
He tried not to show it, but it was out of proportion. Preposterous.
Anyway, yeah, he didn't forget it. I didn't forget it, but I never rubbed it in.
As the Soviet system was collapsing, the Russian Republic was falling together and Yeltsin became
the first president. At that time, 1992, I was invited to a meeting in St. Petersburg,
Russia, by the mayor of St. Petersburg. At that time, the deputy mayor was Vladimir Putin.
And a number of Americans, from business and diplomats and top Soviet officials,
outgoing, incoming Russian officials, heavily loaded with what they call the
syloviki, the security people, who were looking for new careers.
Gathering, I don't know, 75, maybe up to 100 people in the hall as the meeting opened before
you have drinks and before you sit down and all that. And somebody comes to grab me and I
recognize him, Evgeny Primakov. Primakov, who was he? He was officially a national academic
council or something. He was an official body supervising research in all fields.
And he was in charge of Asia from China to the Middle East. But he had known KGB connections.
In fact, many people thought he was a fee official. Anyway, I had met him in earlier years
and he grabbed me by the elbow and marched me over. Somebody you need to meet.
And he introduced me to Putin. He said, this man is rising. He will soon be very important
you should know him. Now I knew enough to realize that that was not an accidental meeting.
Primakov looked for me, found me in the crowd, brought me over. It was intentional.
Now Putin was standing there talking to Kissinger. He did know Kissinger.
And Primakov says, excuse me Henry, but Vladimir needs to know someone else.
He has no reason. How the hell did you get into that?
Anyway, he drew me away from Kissinger. Kissinger believed he was the only channel
and it was through Primakov. But Dobrin may have done this with more than me, but
I had a channel directly with the Russians at his choice.
But he introduced me to Primakov when I went to Moscow. Primakov wanted to get to know me.
I was treated not as partisan of anything, but as someone who should be trusted to carry an idea,
explore it, and get an answer back. That's something different. I was very mindful of
not getting cross-mised with our intelligence system. Kissinger thought he was the number one
the number one communication channel between Russia and America, in the back channel.
There's a history of why he and I had a conflict, a very elaborate history.
Because of my assignments in his presidential election, it all really related to the
the large role in U.S. trade legislation that had a restriction on opening trade relations with Russia
because of the Russian treatment of emigres of Jews from Russia to either to the U.S. or to
Israel. For a while, I worked with the Senate, and Senator Abe Ribicoff
was the senior Jewish political leader in the American system. As Abe told me,
Jake Jamies is my partner. He's number two, and the chief executive of Seagrams in New York
is the treasurer. It's a structure. We give guidance to AIPAC and other bodies, but we represent
the Jewish community, and I want you to take on the task of negotiating with the Russians
about this issue of Jewish emigres. I said, Abe, I'm not Jewish. He said, I knew that.
I've been looking for someone like you for a long time. I had to be somebody who didn't have Jewish
grandmothers or grandfathers or cousins. I didn't want family quarrels in the middle. I wanted
someone with clean hands. You're the first person I met who's as smart as us Jews.
So I said, well, I think that's enough. We had a laugh about that, and I did
act as the intermediary. In fact, I was sent
to Jerusalem and got briefed by Mossad, by Shin Betz. Fully, I made several days of full-fledged
explanation of what goes on between Israel and the U.S. in the dark world of intelligence.
The Russians startled the CIA. Who the hell was I? But I was operating at the request
of the senior political figure in the Jewish community, so nobody was going to mess with me.
Anyway, but the Russians were impressed by being picked out to do this out of all the different
people like Putin. So all of this was in play in the background. So somehow,
the old Soviet guard working through Yeltsin said, Putin has to meet
Harold. We don't understand Harold, but he always pops up in the important places.
Yeah, you're like Zellig or something.
And then you actually dine with him one-on-one. You converse with him. You talk about
what you learned from that relationship.
You can find... I wrote at the time of the invasion of Ukraine.
I wrote my impressions of Vladimir Putin.
I wrote about the results of the referendum that took place in Crimea.
Relying on the will of the people, I bring up the federal assembly and ask to consider the constitutional
law on the adoption of two new federal subjects as part of Russia. The Republic of Crimea and the city of Sevastopol.
I wrote two essays about Putin.
You should feature them on, just a little link to them, because they're very important.
There's so much.
As I said, I didn't meet Putin by accident. They arranged for me to meet him.
They did not ask me to write, but I did. I wrote what I thought he was up to, what he was reasoning was.
I didn't criticize him, praise him. All I said was, this isn't his state of mind.
He liked the two essays that I wrote.
Really?
How do I know? Because he read them.
I said, I'm now going to push a button and call the Prime Minister of Japan.
And then I thought, well, that's what I said. Watch.
And then the second, the Chief of the National Security Council in Tokyo,
I might know.
Wow.
Answer the book.
So happy to talk with you. Is there something you believe?
I believe our President should do.
And I said, yes.
I've given him counsel to improve his speech in English, and his many beliefs and values.
So I would like to tell him from me to fly to New York, give an address to the General Assembly,
call the Good Morning America and ask for seven or eight minutes
of this interview.
And I said, suddenly, your President will become, mightily,
an entirely new figure in the eyes of Americans.
Because instead of being some main actor into the main genius,
you're leading robots across America.
They'll see him, young people,
other people, journalists, young staff members, and journalists.
They'll all see the face and they'll hear his words.
And sure enough, suddenly, he was everybody's friend.
Hmm.
When I went from DOJ to Lyndon Johnson, I arrived in October 1964.
I get called over by General Counsel.
Well, LBJ wants you to go on a very secret mission to Tokyo.
To me, it's already arranged.
I hadn't known about it, but it's already arranged.
You will meet the Japanese Prime Minister.
He will be accompanied by some Japanese named Miyazawa,
whose English is perfect.
But he's an official in the cabinet.
Miyazawa recently was Prime Minister.
So I said, okay, what do I do?
He said, you will arrange the tickets.
You do not tell anyone in your agency what you're doing.
You just take some days off.
Chris Hooter knows.
He approved it and he said, you're just the right person.
Who knows?
Chris Hooter, because I was in his aid.
But no one else knows.
Don't tell anyone your agency.
Don't visit the American Embassy.
They don't know you there.
Don't tell the State Department.
Don't tell anyone.
You'll find the entry and exit will be handled swiftly.
You deliver this message and then get an answer.
Write it down personally.
When you get back, if you want to type it up, it's helpful.
But don't address it to the President.
Don't say on the envelope, eyes only.
It'll be jaded because then 30 people want to see it.
Because then 30 people want to see it.
I said, how do I get it?
Here's the name of his personal secretary.
She will expect it.
She will tell them to give her the envelope.
If it comes and you deliver it yourself,
they'll let you in the door and hand over the envelope.
That's it.
No return address.
Don't have your name on it, date, anything.
Okay.
Well, the origin of this was the Kennedy people
were all over Johnson the minute he became President.
Are you going to keep all the commitments of John Kennedy?
He said, what can I do?
They put pressure on this.
I said, of course I will.
But he said some of those commitments involved
something I don't agree with.
It was cracking down on imports of foreign nations of textiles.
It's been a delicate subject between ours and our administration.
We already have this elaborate system for import controls.
But I think this is all just to favor a certain group of people.
So I want to guide the dialogue with Japan.
So I want to say I'm not going to argue with you about this.
We're not going to have legislation.
But I really would like your cooperation
to ask the industry to slow the pace of expansion
for at least a year or two so that I don't have to address this.
Well, we had some other issues with Japan at the time.
So I met Sato.
And so he was quite happy and said, yes, of course.
Came back, passed it on.
No one ever knows I made that trip.
This is the beginning of what we now know as voluntary export restraints.
And it was a means of keeping the peace between the US and Japan
on this super politically sensitive issue for LBJ.
And the point is that this is often how presidents do things.
They don't always use the official system.
They have unofficial fact channels.
At the time, I asked the general counsel,
why can't you secure lines of communication?
He said, yeah, well, security corps has no system.
But a lot of people listen to it.
Security corps doesn't deny CIA access.
And then since security corps is part of the army,
most of the military knows whatever goes.
So you can't use that.
Not to mention the Russians and everybody else.
Yeah, well, let's forget about that.
We have all these others.
You say something.
It's just like if you ever send a message to the president saying,
I is only the president, it's an automatic imitation.
Everybody knows.
Before the president sees it, they'll have to see it and write a preparatory comment.
I'll give you an example.
I was given, when Nixon came in,
there was a special commission on the transition,
a bunch of papers from Dean Rusk to Johnson.
Nixon was coming in with Feltation C.
And there was a bunch of papers with letters from George Ball
to the president pleading with,
let's downsize this whole Vietnam thing before it blows up in your face.
Cover notes that size, stapled on from Dean Rusk.
Here's George at it again, trying to get in the way of what we must do.
I mean, Dean Rusk totally dismisses
it of everything.
Now, interesting, I was told later,
I'm coming out, I know this, by his daughter,
Linda Bird, that he really valued George Ball.
He read every memo of George Ball.
He thought he was the only guy in the foreign policy system that his brains.
George Ball was always opposed to heightening the war.
So, I mean, I knew the daughter because I dated a girl who was best friends with Linda Bird,
so I spent evenings with her and her boyfriend playing cards.
So I learned lots of stuff.
My own intelligent system.
I'm telling you.
I'm a human male.
It was sometimes beneficial.
I can say over a lifetime, more not beneficial.
Anyway, but that
kind of process, there was no secure way unless you sent somebody.
You can't do it in the way that's visible.
Well, I love your, in my research, your name always pops up next to Malmgren, Inc.,
which I always found like hilariously nondescript and non-threatening and sort of,
you know, just extremely generic.
Yeah, well, I never advertised anything specific.
You seem to just keep getting, having these interactions with people kind of on the inside.
I mean, now we're getting to trippier territory and who knows if this is correct,
but it's almost like a sort of mental network or a network of serendipity or something,
where you look at your interactions with Carl Compton as young as you were and then Richard
Bissell saying, it's almost like I need to tell you this for some sort of unknown reason.
And so there's something about that that I find fascinating.
Particularly on nuclear.
Nuclear.
I mean, how many Americans have sat down and had dinner with President Putin and understand
what he thinks about nuclear weapons and how they might be used, which I think is a story you
should tell a little bit about.
Because it all goes back to the 13-year-old requesting these documents and somehow ends up.
Now, I've been told, but Dad won't confirm,
that he worked on preventing a nuclear crisis on more than one occasion.
But you only tell me about one.
And people in the intelligence world are like, oh, your dad is good.
What? What's going on?
So I won't make you go there.
But you have met with the leader of Russia on nuclear matters after all of this that we now know.
Wow.
This, I think, is related to the subject and it's important to discuss.
And today, do we have a system for de-conflicting the US and Russia if these things show up?
And what is happening practically as we speak?
We have unidentified objects flying all over the United States.
Yes.
Not just in New Jersey.
No.
Over nuclear facilities, over weapons arsenals, but it's happening globally.
And the speculation on the people deepest on the subject, people like Robert Hastings,
who wrote an amazing book called UFOs and Nukes, and all of his whistleblowers, almost 170,
who work, they have cue clearances at these atomic sites, their intuition.
You could say a whole host of things as far as why these UFOs show up.
You could say they're offensive, which I just don't believe because
they haven't really done too much that's offensive.
They've done really nothing.
Well, we shoot at them, but they don't shoot at us.
They don't shoot at us.
So all of their first intuition as to why these UFOs show up around our most sensitive sites
is because they're trying to show us that our ways are too brutal and we're going to blow
ourselves up and to kind of make us think about higher things.
And so I don't know if you guys think that.
No, I think that's what it's all about.
Plus, if we get too serious with nuclear explosions,
we can do lasting damage to the shell of the earth.
You know, we're plumbing deeper and deeper into the center.
I mean, we don't know what happens if you stop.
Well, there's an optimum of radiation necessary for evolution to occur.
Awesome.
Because you have this kind of intersection between the magnetosphere of the earth,
which actually dictates biological morphology on a pretty fundamental way,
and UV radiation, which creates the genetic mutations
necessary for natural selection, differential selection.
And you are messing with this sort of equilibrium every time there's a nuclear spill.
And the really interesting crazy part is you have a town in Japan
next to the Fukushima Prefecture called Lino, and it's dedicated to UFOs.
Over 50% of the residents all believe in UFOs.
There's a museum dedicated to UFOs.
And there, during the spill, they say the UFOs came down,
they helped clean up the spill, this monk who guards this temple in Japan.
And so it's just fascinating.
It's like they're the stewards of the earth.
There may well be.
It begins with the opening question, as I said.
I felt all the way along these unexpected interrelated events.
There was a message to the madness somewhere.
And my mother telling me, just keep doing what you're doing.
You have a purpose.
And you may not know it until the end.
But I may be approaching the end.
Although my doctors say I will outlast my mother.
She lived to be 100.
Wow, that's, yes.
Yeah, but my doctors say, no, you have no physiological problems.
No troubles with your knees and hips and all that stuff.
I'm at 89, to be clear.
You're already lasting longer than most of my interview subjects.
So
Christian are from our governor of Massachusetts.
So I was, somebody was.
I came to the office, so I said,
Why am I here?
I asked for it.
And I said, well, who had a record?
It said the day that you met Professor MIT, that day,
your name went in all the important books of talent.
That who keeps?
C.I.N.
Wow.
Not only C.I.N., but one of my friends, they all took it out on themselves to protect the world.
So, you were chosen, and when you were brought here, I asked you to come to me, and you worked with me.
So you are on a track.
No.
It's not enough for any of us to understand the world and how the world works.
There's no evidence of it.
These sorts of committees have gone by many names, 5412, the 303 committee, the committee of 40,
and they probably involve subcommittees we'll never know the names of.
On our drive to the hospital, with his oxygen hovering at unsafe levels, Harold maintained the cheeriest of attitudes
and could not stop telling stories about his past.
There was so much he wanted to get off his chest.
We discussed the fact that Putin was trying to set up a diplomatic back channel with Harold in 2009,
but that Obama shut that prospect down.
We talked about Harold helping Shoaib Shalhoub,
set up the Toyota headquarters in Kentucky.
We even talked about the fact that Harold was one of the first people on Earth to break the four-minute mile after Roger Bannister.
Apparently, Harold could repeatedly break the four-minute mile in his 20s.
Right as we got to the hospital, we got into trippier territory.
Harold said he was engaged in deep research around the mid-century anti-gravity inventor,
Thomas Townsend Brown.
We discussed Brown's obsession with time travel because gravity is linked with time in general relativity.
We talked about how Townsend Brown really believed he had found a missing puzzle piece for time travel.
I then asked Harold about the existence of a coordinated group trying to deliberately affect timelines.
A very talkative Harold Malmgren went noticeably silent.
Well, Harold, I want you to take care of yourself, man.
And I know we've been talking for an hour now.
And I wish I could be with you in person.
And I miss you, man.
And I want you to just get better.
You know, yeah, I really hope you rest up.
And you have my number so you can call me at any time.
And I'll see you next time.
You can call me at any time if you ever need help with anything.
I'll let you out of here for a second.
Okay.
And my health is good.
Good.
I can keep people out of my way.
Under the pseudonym Chase Brandon, a CIA agent turned Hollywood liaison wrote a book in 2012.
The book discusses a celestial object that telepathically communicates with its recipients.
The object also relays critical information about future timelines.
A secret committee is brought together by synchronicities in extraterrestrial beings that seem to know about every one of its members.
The committee are an elite group of military and scientific thinkers designated to deal with the issue of non-human intelligence.
The main character of the book is a mathematical whiz kid named Chalmers, who is plucked by the head honchos of the Office of Strategic Services and then this special committee.
He helps the committee navigate the future of humanity and manage complex timelines.
He's also taken in and out of a liminal timeless dominion where he's taught important things by other worldly beings that go to determine his purpose in life.
The common trope in the book is that Chalmers had a purpose.
It was a deeply installed, driven purpose, even if it was subconscious.
The first page of this book quotes Francis Bacon.
Truth is so hard to tell it sometimes needs fiction to make it plausible.
When Harold called me again prior to his passing, I thought I'd bring up time travel one last time.
Harold, do you think your life is connected with time travel in any way?
This last inhibition, I was talking as if I knew something.
I don't know why I knew it. I knew it.
And in fact, what I did say was breaking through.
There was no knowledge at that time.
So, if you ask me, did I have a purpose? Yes.
Now, my mother was the most remarkable person.
She read books like there's no tomorrow.
She read so many books.
And she kept saying to me, you have to understand you cannot decide by yourself.
You are given knowledge. There was a purpose.
You have to pursue your purpose.
There is a purpose.
There is no future.
You