I truly think that one day we must unite the factions
because I think one day we shall have an external enemy.
And by external enemy, I mean very external.
NHI.
Think of the Earth.
We are a very yummy apple.
I think remote action is possible.
Can you imagine stopping at heart just by thinking about it?
Say, from Qatar.
That's some scary shit.
You have spoken publicly with these MH370 videos
and it seemed like the civilian aircraft just disappeared
in the Southeast Asian territory.
The most complex of problems has the simplest of solutions
depending on perspective.
When I saw that thing open up,
I saw the Pais effect in action.
This is the Pais effect, come and go.
So we're talking about artificial singularity.
Different parts of the brain have different activity rules.
But you know that, don't you?
We're the people that you grew up with.
Maybe you should interview me.
So excited to be here.
This has been a long time coming
because I've consumed a lot of your content.
Before we get into our guest today,
I want to present our co-host,
the esteemed pseudonymously named Jack.
He has to go under a pseudonym.
He works in some sensitive areas,
but he is very familiar with some of these
heterodox scientific frameworks.
And so I'll allow my interview with Hal Puthoff
and Eric Weinstein.
Sometimes I get out of my depth scientifically,
and I definitely am with Sal Pais.
And so I'm very excited to have Jack here.
Thank you for joining us.
Yeah, thrilled to be here.
Thank you.
What are you wearing for Sal?
I thought I'd give a little props
to a very successful organization,
eponymously known as Skunk Works.
So thank you for your service.
There you go.
And we have an amazing Navy scientist
who has sent shockwaves in kind of the UFO world.
It's interesting.
In 2017, you had revelations around
the existence of UFO study groups and stuff,
ATIP, ASAP, that sort of thing.
But you also had these patents
that were filed by a guy who was right here
named Sal Pais, which touched on
some very interesting subjects.
One might even say that they seem to dovetail
with how you might build a UFO.
And we have a hat right here,
which he's offered me at the beginning of the show,
which is very nice.
It's an F-35 hat.
So thank you, Sal.
Thank you for being here.
You're very welcome, my friend.
You're very welcome.
And never remember as far as how Puthoff,
as far as Eric Weinstein and Jack here.
Trust me, you are at that level.
You're able to trust me on this.
I've seen many podcasts and you're one of the best.
So absolutely.
Well, we can-
Kudos to you, brother.
Agreed and disagreed.
But I'm happy to be the last mile
of kind of cogent distribution
on deeper people like yourself.
So do you have any kind of disclaimers at the top?
Because you are very sensitive areas as well.
And I want to make sure we don't get any tripwires.
Let me see right off the bat with...
Yes, my name is Salvatore Cesar Pais.
I work for the United States Navy.
I used to work for the United States Space Force.
Let me say at this time that I come on this podcast
as a private citizen.
And my opinion, my statements, everything I say,
I have said is my own.
The Navy and the Space Force are now responsible
for any of these statements whatsoever.
And also I would like to say that I'm not on this program,
on this podcast to be cubed.
In other words, to enlighten and educate the enemy.
So certain things that I think certain subject matter
that we may touch upon,
if it deals with certain frequency...
Jack, you know this well.
We keep numbers out of play and certain things that...
If you, for example, see me slip,
please, Aurelien, guide me accordingly.
Yeah.
Before we dive into today's amazing episode
of American Alchemy, I want to thank Aura
for being the amazing sponsor of this show.
Have you ever Googled yourself or maybe a friend
and been totally freaked out
by how much personal info popped up?
I did it once and saw old addresses, phone numbers,
stuff I didn't even realize was out there.
Honestly, it made me wonder who else could see all of that.
In 2024, there were multiple high-level data breaches,
including a breach of the National Public Database.
The incident compromised over 2.9 billion records
used for background checks,
including critical personal information,
such as full names, addresses, dates of birth,
phone numbers, and most importantly,
social security numbers.
Their data broker opt-out tool
goes after those shady sites that scrape and sell your info.
So you're less of a sitting duck for scammers.
Plus, Aura provides identity theft protection,
monitoring billions of data points,
everything from your social security number
to your bank info, and lets you know fast
if something suspicious shows up.
If the worst happens, each adult on your plan
gets $1 million in identity theft insurance,
up to $5 million total if you have five adults.
Aura also has other great features,
like a VPN and antivirus,
that all come bundled in an easy-to-use app.
I'm not leaving my data out there for anyone to grab,
and you shouldn't either.
The best part is I get all of this in one app
at an affordable price.
I'm not leaving myself and my family
vulnerable to data breaches and brokers.
And if you don't want to either,
you can go to aura.com slash Jesse Michaels,
Michaels with no A, to try two weeks for free.
That should be enough time for Aura to find out
if any of your personal data is exposed
and for you to realize that Aura is a no-brainer.
As Dave Grush said,
we're not here to help the adversary do their job.
Absolutely.
Mr. Grush is 100%.
Correctly.
But, simultaneous to that,
it's actually a national security risk.
It's actually extremely intelligent STEM students
growing up in the wrong frameworks
and not being privy to any of this stuff
and thinking it's all factory,
that seems like actually a matter of national security risk.
Yes.
It's an absolutely broken paradigm, you're right.
And it's something that has wheedled its way
inside the R&D framework
of our national defense infrastructure.
And it's kneecapped us from making critical advances
that have national security implications.
I want to start with the kind of autobiographical,
because it's interesting.
You go on all these podcasts
and you talk about the science
and I want to get into the science
and I think Jack can help kind of
drive some of the conversation later.
But, who are you?
Where are you from?
How did you get into this stuff?
Oh, wow.
Origins?
Yeah.
All right.
My name is Salvatore Cesar Pais.
That's the way you pronounce it in Romanian.
I was born in Romania, in Bucharest, Romania,
as a matter of fact, capital of Romania.
I came here when I was about 13 and a half of age,
going to New York City,
Queen's Boy, as they say,
still seek coffee and other things as well.
Love a New York Reuben.
Oh my God, you know, from Brooklyn, Delhi,
a real Reuben.
Anyway, I'm not going to,
I'm going to keep it nice,
since this is a family show, so it's,
right?
Every now and then I let it slip.
The people that know me know
that almost every other word,
the real Salvatore will use STF words.
So every now or like you would not believe.
I can weave a tapestry of obscenities second to none.
Took that from a Christmas story,
but hey, you know, every now and then
you don't have to be an original.
So, yeah.
So again, I was born in Romania.
I came here as a young kid.
I grew up in the public education system.
I went to Brooklyn.
In Brooklyn,
to one of the well-known high schools there
was Brooklyn Technical High School.
Not as on the same level as Bronx High School of Science
or Stuyvesant in Manhattan,
but from a technical point of view,
it was very well known and very well liked.
And then I went to Case Western Reserve University
in Cleveland, Ohio.
No, it's not a military school.
It's actually very highly accredited.
It usually makes the US News top 50 universities.
Almost every year.
And I love my CWR.
I would never exchange it, for example,
going to MIT or any other school.
It's just, I was brought up there and I stayed there.
I did my graduate studies there.
Then I was extremely fortunate to have,
how should I say, a job at Northrop Grumman.
Well, before then I had a couple of stints in New York
Electronic Systems Associates, CISC and Hennessy.
But I was extremely fortunate to work
for Northrop Grumman Corporation and Advanced Systems,
Advanced Concepts, and one of the other things.
And then I transitioned to the USPTO.
And at the time it was Alexandria, Virginia.
They had moved from Crystal City.
And then I was fortunate enough to come here, now there.
And then certain things occurred.
And I was fortunate to work for strategic systems programs
at the Washington Navy Yard.
And then I went for the Space Force and then came back.
And so in 2017, you're probably most known for these patents.
The title of the patent just says a lot.
Hybrid craft using an inertial mass modification device.
How does one even get into a topic like that?
I was very interested.
I've seen certain things as far as
what has been shown on certain documentaries.
Any documentaries or Denzi Convention?
It was a lot of things that were done by Dr. Stephen Greer.
And a great deal of things.
As a matter of fact, I hold a man in very high esteem.
I feel it's very unfortunate that the UFO field seems to be so divided.
It's almost as divided as the country is at this point in time.
And I wish people were more unified.
I've always been a person that drives toward unification.
Unification of concepts, ideas.
You can always work things out.
You can always reach a compromise.
Always.
And I think everybody benefits as a result.
The alternative is the enemy wins.
When we fight amongst each other,
our strength is divided, is weakened.
The enemy will always take force, take strength from that.
So you're watching close encounters of the Fifth Column or Unacknowledged.
Things like that.
Absolutely.
How do these crafts operate?
How do they work?
How do they word?
And then it works.
So this patent is somewhat you kind of reverse engineering it.
How you think they work based on the observables and these sorts of concepts.
The whole idea is it can't all be Newtonian propulsion.
You basically take something, you throw it out the back and the thing moves forwards.
The whole idea of the Newtonian third law of action-reaction can't all be Newtonian.
What if there's non-Newtonian propulsion?
So in other words, can we do something to the field that we operate in,
the gravitational field, for example, to make objects have diminished inertia?
Since inertial mass and gravitational mass, after all, there is equivalence between them.
So I have a dumb question.
You publish a thing like this and it seems like pretty well synthesized and researched.
Presumably, there are legacy programs.
If you believe David Gresh for reverse engineering this stuff,
why don't they immediately kind of hit you up?
No idea whatsoever.
As a matter of fact, at one point in time, I almost expected to be contacted,
so then the idea almost occurred to me, almost instantaneously,
that they must have this somewhere.
They've already started to use it.
They have figured it out and they're already operating certain devices.
Then I hear these things about the reverse engineering craft and then that thing bothers me
because everything I've done is really based on Oliver Heaviside's
version of Maxwell's equation.
The four equations, four unknowns that electrical engineers have grown up to love and use,
thank God, because the original were an absolute trance, extremely.
An unusual, yeah, unusable mass.
Quaternion, formalism, my goodness.
Again, the genius of Oliver Heaviside.
All you do, couple it with the harmonic oscillator and certain things occur
based again on resonance.
Resonance is extremely important because it talks to energy amplification.
You're implying that you don't believe in the E.T. and the craft hypothesis.
You think this is all sort of inmate?
Or do you think you've just stumbled across the same physics of operation?
I believe that there's man-made tech and there's E.T. tech.
It's possible the E.T. tech was reverse engineered from gifts or craft that were found,
historical items, who knows where and how.
There's another avenue.
There's man-made tech.
Why can we have that kind of acumen, that kind of mind?
You mean only these, they're called non-human?
Non-human intelligence.
Only NHIs can have this kind of intellect.
Why can we?
I mean, we should take pride in who we are as homo sapiens sapiens.
We represent a certain intellect.
And this is an interesting question.
Are there multiple branches, multiple tech trees that could be
filtering their way through the defense intelligence base?
Some of them approachably nuts and bolts-ish from a technology that's a couple of hundred
years more advanced than us.
And then other examples that are far more exotic, that when you open them up, you see
nothing familiar.
You see nothing recognizable.
Absolutely.
So in other words, there's man-made tech and E.T. tech.
And I think you can tell them apart.
The one thing that struck me based on what I came to understand from the idea of the
super force, if you take the gravitational field equations of Einstein, you can readily
deduce that the super force acting on the spatial temporal geometric structure, what
we understand as a quantum vacuum locally, can actually give birth, generate energy density.
Right.
This is the idea of Robert Wheeler, the notion that energy density determines the shape of
space time or the shape of the quantum vacuum.
And the quantum vacuum determines the propagation of that energy.
And the super force equation, which is really a re-rendering of the Einstein gravitational
field equations, talks to this.
And then Bob Lazar mentioned at one point that it seemed to him that the so-called sports
model was grown out of the vacuum itself, absolutely smooth, like a 3D printing out
of the space-time fabric itself.
The super force speaks to that directly.
Are you from the Ken Shoulders work?
Exactly.
Vacuum objects, I've read certain papers as well.
It's very interesting, this idea of the vehicle being 3D printed out of the quantum vacuum,
because we can't seem to quite understand exactly.
Because when you talk about chemical vapor deposition, the manufacturing techniques
associated with making very small nanostructured hetero lattices.
My graduate work, for instance, is in topological material physics.
We do know more than is generally acknowledged about how to manufacture those lattices.
But we don't have a lot of control over where exactly the atoms go.
We just spit them out, and physics takes over.
And it deposits them where it wants to deposit them in the lattice.
So if you need them to be in extremely specific lattice points, and then you need to do layer
after layer after layer to get these really novel behaviors, topological superconducting layers,
topological insulative layers, Josephson junctions, and then one after the other,
we don't know how to do that.
So does that get 3D printed somehow?
Okay, well, I want to get in deep quick.
I want to just, for the mass audience, kind of lay some scaffolding, lay the groundwork.
So you mentioned Heaviside.
Most people now, when it comes to kind of classical electrodynamics,
go off of Oliver Heavisides and simplification of Maxwell's equation.
Absolutely.
So where is conventional classical electrodynamics off where you think you've found
kind of a different branch of Heaviside?
Because most people adhere to him, right?
This is not anything new.
This is not new physics.
This is a new perspective on all physics.
All I've done was taken the Heaviside version of Maxwell's equation,
coupled them with a harmonic oscillator, and shown that you get nonlinearity with respect
to the angular frequency, either vibration and or spin, because, as you well know,
the mathematics is heavily similar, and come up with, under certain conditions,
you get resonance conditions, energy amplification.
Emergent phenomena that are not immediately obvious under normal circumstances.
So let's break it down.
What is a harmonic oscillator?
Harmonic oscillator, if you think of, the best way to describe it is from Hooke's law,
the whole idea of f equal minus k x.
A spring.
Exactly.
A spring oscillator that makes the sinusoid n x, y.
Yes, sir.
And then you just write, as you well know from Newton's second law, an acceleration, or m d
x double prime d t square, the whole idea of n a equal this minus k x.
From that results your harmonic oscillator.
So we're talking about derivatives from differential calculus,
and this is how you go from y equals k x, Hooke's law.
Extremely simple stuff.
For you, combining that concept with Heaviside.
From there, from what happens is from a simple scalar, as a matter of fact,
I send you what we presented to the patent examiner, and you can have that with a podcast.
You can actually, sure, absolutely.
That's been already presented.
It's in the public domain, so it's considered non-governmental.
Unclassified.
Domain.
That's it.
It's public domain.
Since the USPTO primary examiner, a gentleman by the name of Philip Bonzell,
has put it into the public domain.
It was given to him via phone conversation.
So that particular PDF was sent to him, and then we had a phone conversation with
the now there attorney, Mr. Mark Lute, which, by the way, was tremendous.
And every one of the five patent applications, mind you, three of them became patents.
The two that did not become patents are the ones that seem to be most mundane.
The high frequency gravitational wave generator became a patent.
The high energy electromagnetic field generator became a patent.
The most exotic concepts.
Using an inertial mass reduction device became a patent.
After some doing, of course, Mr. Philip Bonzell was extremely in awe of that.
He said, this is not possible.
Neutron stars cannot produce these electric fields and magnetic fields.
We're talking about electric fields on the order of 10 to the 18 volts per meter.
How do we get to that?
If you're combining the harmonic oscillator with the heavy side stuff,
how do you get to that big of electric field size?
Again, it is in that PDF, and you can follow the math.
It's extremely simple.
But the whole idea is that you get, from the scaling analysis,
you get a simple relationship that shows that it must be correct,
because the electric field, that relationship, it gives you a relationship.
The scaling analysis of the heavy side version,
I'm actually giving you a relationship,
a simple relationship for the electric field strength E,
and also one for the magnetic induction,
otherwise known as the magnetic flux density, also known as the B field.
From those two relationships, you can actually see that E max divided by B max equals C,
equals the speed of light, exactly what Maxwell showed, the whole idea.
That must be correct.
When you couple the harmonic oscillator within those two relationships,
you get something for the B field, which is amazing.
It shows variance with respect to angular frequency squared.
That's interesting.
Now I'm tracking, because in your patent,
you use microwaves inside the annular channel.
To vibrate.
Yes, to vibrate the atoms.
You call it a confined photoelectric effect.
That's exactly what it is.
What I found interesting is the high-temperature superconductor patent is necessary for the
high-frequency gravity wave patent.
They speak to each other.
Because there's a high Q factor associated with the high-temperature superconductor.
For some reason, the patent examiner did not even take that into consideration.
Sure.
Exactly what you said, because then just by that simple argument,
from an enablement point of view, he should have passed,
or they should have passed the wrong temperature superconductor.
So what allows that frequency to-
Dr. Victor Lacno, Russian of the Russian Academy of Sciences,
actually shows in his archive published paper.
I've never been able to publish an archive.
So the man must have either known some moderators.
Again, he showed that my room temperature superconductor,
from a mechanism point of view, could work.
And yet, the patent examiner just refused to grant the patent.
So it was an incredible idea.
Because you describe what is a proximity superconductor,
probably also a topological superconductor.
From someone that actually has that knowledge.
Thank you, Jack.
Yeah.
So again, cased in a ceramic.
And so it's the interfacial layer that is superconducting.
That's where the current moves.
And so when you've got these 100 terahertz microwaves
inside the annular channel of your triangle patent,
it's exciting.
And you're setting up that standing wave.
And that's the-
That's what it's all about.
Resonance.
The W squared term is why this blows up.
That amazing square is very important.
And for some reason, people refuse to see
that mathematics speaks to the physics.
Are you worried at all about that huge B field
and the surviving materials surviving it?
Because-
That's something we have to be aware of.
And the ninth Tesla fields, you know.
As you well know, you have to be extremely careful.
Because usually when you go above even about 10 to the second,
maybe even pushing 10 to the third Tesla,
we're talking about tremendous yields on the-
B field is a magnetic field measured in Tesla.
We've never made a magnetic field any larger than 30 Tesla?
40 Tesla?
Usually.
I heard of something up to 120 Tesla.
But that's a rumor.
Yeah.
And the Earth's magnetic field is like a thousandth of a Tesla.
Or 10,000th of a Tesla.
How would you insulate materials from that size of magnetic field?
You wouldn't.
Simple.
You wouldn't insulate it.
You would have to-
You'd use something that-
This would all want to be synergistic.
So you would want to use something that benefits in some way
from exposure to that field rather than trying to fight physics.
I think that's where really brilliant engineering comes in
is that you're not going to put a bunch of things together
that are parasitically affecting each other in negative ways.
And you're trying to finagle your design space to make it work.
You'd put a bunch of things together
that actually help each other work better with their side effects.
Physics is not enough.
The engineering of the physics trumps everything else.
Again, experiment trumps theory every time.
And I believe trumps should become a verb.
Have you worked on this from an engineering perspective at all?
Or is it purely theoretical?
We worked on a high-energy electromagnetic field
generated experiment at NAVAIR.
However, we weren't able to obtain a charge,
an electrical charge of more than 10 to the minus 8 Coulombs.
We need at least one Coulomb to show that the Pais effect is correct.
I call it the Pais effect not out of hubris,
as people would choose to call it,
but because it was something purely original.
And I decided, why not?
Let's call it something that's never been called before.
And there was one other Pais there, Abraham Pais.
The autobiographer of Einstein himself,
a great physicist of his own right, said, okay, let's couple the names.
In the context of all we've talked about,
would you step through your explanation of the Pais effect from a high level?
Absolutely.
Usually, I define it as controlled motion of electrically charged mode.
Of electrically charged objects, usually from solids to plasma
based on accelerated vibration and or accelerated spin,
giving rise to extremely high energy densities.
Hence, electromagnetic energy fluxes.
However, it can also be thought of as the production,
the generation of high energy densities
based on certain vibratory fields of plasmas, cold plasmas.
We're talking about plasmas that have been driven far from equilibrium.
Your xenon gas and the annulus that you kind of move it back and forth
with your 100 terahertz alternating electric field.
The terahertz frequency is an interesting field that should be looked into.
But again, we're not here to educate and enlighten the enemy,
so that's as far as I go.
Well, it is interesting how Padov has talked about these kind of micron layers,
magnesium bismuth, and he says that they microsize waveguides for terahertz.
There's a reason.
Look into the slide presentation that I presented at the 2019 AIAA SciTech.
That presentation, please also post that in your podcast
along with the patent examiner interview, those slides.
It makes a lot of sense, but look very carefully, slides four to slides nine
in that particular presentation, and you'll see why the terahertz frequency is so important.
It speaks something that Dr. Eric W. Davis published
in one of those DIA reports that I sold in Televoltage.
More to do with a certain macro dimension.
A fifth dimension?
A fifth dimension.
Right.
There's a coupling factor between the electric field that you're setting up
to generate high-frequency gravity waves and this oscillatory behavior of the particles,
which potentially polarizes the quantum vacuum and allows you—the analogy that I have used is,
imagine you have a Ziploc bag that's full of water, but it's kind of sloppy,
and you imagine you can push on it on one side and you set up a pressure gradient.
Now you have the quantum vacuum doing work for you
and pushing on you with its own pressure.
It has such a tremendous energy density, like 10 to the 44th
calories per cubic centimeter or something, bananas,
that it does an incredible amount of work.
Literally, this is based on metric.
It's using quantum electrodynamics, even Feynman would say, or whatever,
zero point is full of energy.
Hal Pudoff talks a lot about polarizable bag, that you can electrically polarize,
and so it's using a kind of creating a gradient, basically, to propel an object.
Some of your work has cited Max Born, Paul Dirac.
I talk more to the swing element, breaking the swing element.
Why do I talk about that?
Not just because I want to make black holes, but the whole idea is that
when you put more and more energy into a particular space-time locality,
you can actually unravel what we understand as continuum,
space-time continuum within that quantum vacuum limit.
The swinging limit, really, this whole idea of generational particle,
antiparticle fields, this is exactly what the swinging limit needs.
It's on the order of 10 to the 33 watts per meter square speaking,
corresponding to an energy density on the order of 10 to the 25 joules per meter cubed.
Enormous amounts of energy.
Enormous.
Speaking again to those electric field strength of 10 to the 18 volts per meter,
commensurate to the B field on the order of 10 to the 9 volts per meter again.
What is the swing limit?
The swing limit truly, it represents how much energy density the
quantum vacuum or rather space-time fabric can withstand before it breaks apart.
How does this impact the black hole information limit?
You've talked about this.
I've never looked too much into the information loss paradox.
Summarize what he said.
Sure.
So basically, what you're saying is you're using this
electromagnetic amplification methodology to essentially break the fabric of reality
in a way that uses it as propulsion.
Is that right?
That's 100% correct because once you form this black hole,
I truly believe that every black hole has a white hole.
There's a wormhole that truly forms between whatever that locality that you've broken
the swing limit and somewhere else that it talks to based on the superpulse, and believe it or not.
Quantum entanglement.
Where does spin kind of, what kind of spin involves here?
Spin.
So in other words, you can accelerate either in spin or accelerate in vibration depending
on which is easier from an engineering point of view.
As you well know, when you spin something, even surpassing 10 to the 4 RPM,
it's very hard to do so and keep this thing.
So again, you might choose vibration.
I just chose to put in both spin and vibration because the mathematics is highly similar.
From an engineering point of view, you'd want to go with vibration.
When you say spin, do you mean spin like literally spinning a thing?
Not like electrical?
Around its own axis.
And this is interesting, right?
There's a very common through line in a lot of alternate gravity manipulation approaches
relating to either macroscopic spin vis-a-vis something called the Poeum's theory,
Pope Osborne angular momentum synergy theory, something that Richard Eskridge looked into
at Marshall, and then Alzafon's nucleonic spin approaches that he sort of scrubbed with Feynman
back in the 30s.
Very complex stuff.
Yeah, but then you've got Ming-Li's work with the rotating superconductors, the YBCO.
Also, Eugene Puklatnov used rotating superconductors, and I didn't realize this,
but Nick Cook, who wrote The Hunt for Zero Point, he went up to Puklatnov and for whatever
reason, Nick Cook had this instinct to ask him about Victor Shalbert.
How we actually think.
Yeah.
And Puklatnov goes, yeah, my father was this Soviet agent at the time.
Or he was a Russian agent.
He was a Soviet?
Soviet.
Soviet, yeah.
He said my father was a Soviet agent, and he was actually counter-intell, and he was
tasked with retrieving a lot of Shalbert's files.
Shalbert was one of the first people to talk about rotating.
I think in his case, he had something called an impeller machine.
This was pre kind of superconductivity.
Based on implosion rather than, right?
The whole idea of creation, again, a physics based on creation rather than destruction.
Yeah.
Well, and do you think there's a...
Yeah, but there was a connection between Puklatnov and this.
And then Puklatnov said, well, we just needed more higher RPMs.
But again, from an engineering point of view, you know how detrimental that can be.
It's very hard to do.
It's a very exotic environment.
That's why I chose vibration.
What are you going to put in there?
Yeah, sure.
And not just vibration of an electrically charged object, but plasma.
So you think that lineage doesn't make sense from an engineering standpoint.
Actually, vibration makes more sense.
And you know why.
Yeah, yeah.
I mean, because with plasma...
Let's listen to Jack.
By the way, Jack is brilliant.
Like an idiot.
No, no, far from it.
Jesse, please, please, 100%.
That is totally unfair.
Never, never, ever say that.
No, I mean, you guys are more advanced than me.
Well, there's interesting things you can do when you set up standing waves and plasmas.
I mean, you can generate cold plasmas, as he was talking about.
This is something I did in my graduate research back in the day,
with certain frequencies that will pull electrons off of the atoms.
And then you can start doing interesting things with those electrons.
And you can set up double layer plasmas and things like this.
And if you can control where the charge goes...
I mean, this is the problem with a lot of hot fusion experiments,
is that they can't control where the electrons go,
they can't control where the hot ions go.
And so you get all kinds of breaking radiation,
you get Bremsstrahlung,
and you get all kinds of tremendous losses.
And this approach ameliorates that.
So that's why you need cold plasma for the vibration.
It's ideal, yes.
Interesting.
And how do you produce cold plasma?
Not easy, not easy.
That is e cubed.
Okay, got it.
Absolutely, we will not touch on that.
It's in the academic literature, but perhaps we don't verify it.
You're...
Since after all, this is my so-called first in-person interview.
So I shoot out for something to the audience.
It involves something that has been given the Nobel Prize in Physics,
I believe it was last year.
Non-local reality, guys?
Lasers.
Interesting.
Leave it there.
So okay, so that's a better approach then.
And then what does this have to do with superconductivity, I guess?
Believe it or not, everything is related at the quantum vacuum level.
So I'll throw something out there.
So in superconducting physics,
so we have this baseline theory called BCS theory.
Bardeen-Coopers.
Bardeen-Coopers, yeah.
So Bardeen, brilliant physicist, two Nobel Prizes,
the transistor and superconductivity.
And so most superconductors, their behavior is characterized by BCS theory.
However, these are typically ultra-low temperature superconductors
and extremely high B-field superconductors.
So these are not terribly useful in industrial commercial application
because the environments you have to put them in are very exotic.
So of course, superconductivity is very useful
because it offers lossless power transmission,
very high electric fields, very high magnetic fields.
I've often said that the development and discovery
of a room temperature superconductor would be
as transformative to commerce and industry as antigravity.
Very disruptive.
100%.
Now, so there's been a lot of research last 30 or 40 years
into topological materials, topological insulators,
and then something called topological superconductors.
And the nature of a topological material is,
so typically you have crystal lattice materials.
So metals are crystals, insulators are crystals,
semiconductors are crystals.
Ordinarily, those crystals have the same properties
throughout the bulk of the matrix.
Like no matter which way, frequently they're isotropic,
meaning this way or that way, or they're anisotropic,
meaning it's different this way versus that way.
When you make semiconductor crystals, you get polycrystalline.
So you get grain boundaries and features stop
at these grain boundaries.
And so you start to get anisotropies.
That's significant to manufacturing semiconductor materials
where we're doping these layers with different atoms.
And we've been doping since the 1950s.
This has been around some time.
But the level of precision in semiconductor doping
is three or four orders of magnitude lower
than what we're talking about
with these quantum heterostructure lattices,
where you really need these big chromium and vanadium atoms
that install their ferromagnetic ordering across the lattice.
You need them in very specific lattice locations.
Jack, you're absolutely brilliant and right on.
But let's bring it to a very simplest, again,
Occam's razor, simplicity and minimalism.
One does superconductivity truly represent
a macroscopic quantum phenomenon.
Yes.
And it speaks directly to macroscopic quantum coherence.
Look very carefully at slides four to nine
in the 2019 AIAA SciTech.
A lot of people have gone over those slides as if
there's nothing there.
There's something of incredibly important
How do you maintain coherence at macroscopic scales?
Not easy at all.
Condensates.
Because everything wants to decohere.
Everything wants extremely cold temperatures.
Again, the atoms being in this nice dance.
Because again, because of electron full-arm repulsion,
these things don't want to pair up.
And yet BCS theory says that they should.
And Dr. Victor Lacnoe believes it's not the electrons,
but bipolarons.
The whole idea of a bipolaron mechanism
that occurs at these higher temperatures.
Which is a quasi-particle.
It's a composite quasi-particle of two polarons.
A polaron is itself a quasi-particle.
And the Pais effect speaks directly to what?
To this mechanism of room temperature superconductivity.
How?
It basically says once you form an alternating magnetic field,
once you form this Bose-Eythron condensate
that Victor Lacnoe speaks to,
you can use a pulse current, again,
an alternate current, to move it.
To move it.
To manipulate it.
And yet no one has touched either the Victor Lacnoe paper
or my patent.
Thinking again, it's pseudo-science.
How would you do this?
So the reason, generally, you can't get superconductivity
at high temperatures is because the atoms in the material
have all this thermal motion.
They have all this thermal energy.
And so the nature of superconductivity
is that this thing called a phonon,
which is a vibratory mode of an atom inside of a lattice,
phonons facilitate the transfer of electrons
through the lattice as cooper pairs.
So the Pauli exclusion principle only applies
to spin one half bosons.
I know this is really deep.
But what happens is when you force electrons close together,
they behave as though they're a spin one particle,
meaning Pauli no longer applies.
And so they can both occupy the minimum ground state
so they can move together.
So there's no degeneracy.
There's no energy splitting.
And so they move very efficiently through the lattice.
Problem is, if this lattice is warm
and all these atoms are vibrating randomly,
you can't get this coherent phonon behavior.
In extremely novelty-comprised lattices,
you put atoms in just the right place
such that these internal magnetic fields
set up these roadways, stop signs, highways
for current to flow.
And you can get this behavior.
So it involved you would need to fabricate materials
on an atomic level.
You need to get sub-banks.
But not the Pais effect.
The Pais effect does not speak to anything
depending on chemical composition.
That's why Dr. Victor Lagno, he picked it up
because he realized this is the solution
to an active superconductor, one that's not passive,
one that is not based on chemical composition,
like the type Ia or the type II superconductors.
This is basically, it can be done as long as this thing
at any point in its structure has been superconducting.
For example, that's why I chose lead, zirconate, titanate.
All three components at very low temperatures
are superconducting.
Sure.
And yet, because of the bipolar mechanism
that Dr. Lagno, I believe in his paper,
it's just a three-page paper.
But on the third page, he gives the mechanism
and he speaks to the Pais effect room temperatures
for conduction.
You believe it'll work.
So these materials are superconducting
in their natural state, even at room temperature?
Not at room temperature.
At very low temperature.
He's describing conventional superconductors
like YBCO and from...
Lead, zirconate, titanate, BB, ZR, Ti.
These are the components
of what they call piezoelectric material.
You know, Townsend Brown spent the latter half of his career
looking at these electric material.
They're very important because one talks to, again,
the whole idea that pressure induced what?
The electric field can also induce pressure changes.
In the vacuum.
Well, I discovered something very interesting.
The Townsend Brown ceramic insulator of choice
was very enlightening.
It's on the chalkboard in videos of him
at Acufonsi's class.
This is what changed my mind about Townsend Brown.
They had dismissed his work.
And they have dismissed his work.
And he says, by the way, at the beginning of Townsend Brown's
what they're giving proposal, he says,
Oliver Heavyside had a very adequate theory of gravity
back in the 1890s.
So we would be right to listen to him.
So, you know, that was his opinion as well.
I'm convinced that some well-meaning physicists
just didn't see the application
to exotic condensed matter physics at the time.
You know, because I think these are subtle effects
for which the coupling is small in natural materials.
And, you know, as we started to manufacture semiconductors,
this was the world's first metamaterial in the broad sense.
It's not an optical metamaterial in the strict sense.
But you start to set up these solid state environments
that have fundamentally different environments.
And we're just now getting to the point
where we have the SEM tools to interrogate these things.
And we have the chemical vapor deposition
and the atomic vapor deposition to actually make them.
And then we have the interrogation tools
to know for sure what we really made.
I mean, these experiments take years to set up and execute.
That's why it's...
They're not easy. They're not easy.
What would be the next step for...
I mean, because let's build a UFO.
I mean, if there was ever a time where we were, you know,
geopolitically unstable on a macro level
and need to throw a Hail Mary, it would be right now.
And I don't know what we have built.
You know, maybe we're way more advanced than...
I mean, what do you think?
Do you think we're way more advanced than meets the ERI?
I truly believe we must be.
This democracy must win.
This republic must stand.
We must survive.
So yes, I believe we shall.
Do you think that what you're looking into
has already been discovered and then some
in kind of private quarters?
Or do you think that you're deriving something fund battling?
Absolutely not.
I do not think I'm an original in this at all.
As a matter of fact, the physics that I speak to
was available in the 1890s
and there were great physicists at the time, great brains.
I'm 100% sure that I'm not an original in this.
Not at all.
Many interesting things.
It's just the way that I address the Pais effect,
especially from the room temperature superconductor.
Now, the Pais effect driven room temperature superconductor,
I do believe I'm an original in.
I would believe that.
And Victor Locno attests to that.
He says it could work.
Now, for a man of his capacity,
of his capability, of his mathematical prowess,
and not just mathematical physics or physical mathematics
where the physics drives the mathematics, not vice versa,
this man thinks that this could work.
I believe it should be looked at.
Well, there are these claimed replications
of room temperature.
Okay, 99?
A couple of years ago.
They refer it.
Pretty, yeah, you're the only English-speaking patent
that's in the citations.
The rest are Korean and Chinese.
But everybody thinks this is pseudoscience.
How come?
Well, yeah, so do you think that this has already been done?
You think it's been discovered?
Do you know that that team was so sure of their results
that they published one paper with six authors
and then they published another paper with three authors
because only three people can share a Nobel Prize?
They were that confident.
Whoa.
Then what happened upon the era?
There were people that replicated it.
Reproduction issues, yeah.
There were Chinese teams that replicated the experiment.
It went into the void as if...
So you guys seem to lend a little more credence
than meets the eye to LKNL now?
Maybe, yeah.
I think I had heard there were reproduction issues,
other labs tried to make it,
and I find it hard to believe other labs would cover it up
because, again, it's grants galore waiting to happen.
You have, you know, I've talked to a leader who always
I love, I think he's an American here, a great guy.
When I speak to him, he really has to speak super cryptically
about like, you know, some very destructive...
Save the world, but also destroy the world.
We all have to play nicely together,
like the toy or whatever is this,
or is he talking about room temperature superconductivity?
Who knows?
Aslo.
The man doesn't drink, I believe,
so you might not be able to get any information out of him.
He's also a very...
You can tell the man has seen a lot.
So on that note, you know, on the subject of proliferation,
I find it very fascinating to think about the fact
that Manhattan, we got a little lucky
and that nuclear weapons turn out to be very difficult to make.
And so proliferation was slow.
In terms of the weaponization of UAP physics,
and we've of course mentioned
there could be multiple branches and different tech trees.
Do you have a sense that this technology
will be difficult to replicate, difficult to manufacture?
No.
Or very easy?
However, there's a paper out there,
Plasma Compression Fusion Device.
You and I were talking right before.
Yeah.
It's being cited by some very important research teams in China.
And the latest that's being cited is of this year,
IEEE Journal of Cybernetics.
Can you imagine making a Plasma Compression Fusion Device
something compact?
Now, in what artificial intelligence domain
would cybernetics couple with if you were to use such a device?
Say such a device was operational.
It could be made operational.
In a small footprint, a power source,
something like Iron Man's reactor.
Could you imagine what you would use that in?
Why would the IEEE Journal of Cybernetics be interested
in that particular work?
Think what that would mean.
Terrifying.
I mean, you...
Terrifying with so many ways.
Enormous energy densities are terrifying in every way.
Every...
But imagine an army of those.
What they could mean.
Leave it there, Jesse.
Trust me on that.
Leave it there.
It's freaky.
Yeah, it's very freaky.
Again, the fusion of ideas, cross-domain,
the ability of using information from different disciplines.
That's in the open literature.
That's why OSINT can be so incredibly important
in the right hands in cross-domain technology,
interdisciplinary, across those OSINT controls,
extremely dangerous.
It already has.
And it already is.
The use of AI tools in reverse engineering,
all of these ideas right out of the ether,
right off the internet is very powerful already.
It's helped a lot of us in the disclosure effort
find things that are out there in the public domain
that just maybe we didn't realize
they were already in the public domain.
However, it's also a cubed.
Not a good idea.
Well, okay, so you also have written a lot
about high-frequency gravitational waves.
Yes, sir.
And so how does that play into all of this?
And why don't we actually zoom out real quick
and just explain how, okay,
if you've had a room temperature superconductor
and then you had the Pais effect,
how would this allow you to possibly build a UFO?
Like, how does that play into, you know...
I cannot speak to that.
Okay.
But again, please,
there is no such thing as faster-than-light travel.
Einsteinian physics is never broken.
Einstein was 100%.
Everything Einstein has come up with is 100% real.
And I truly believe that, for example,
even quantum entanglement,
we're not talking about instantaneous communication here.
So you don't believe that, like,
a lot of people in national security disclosure world
talk about alcooliary warp drives,
you know, involving negative mass or negative energy
to allow for faster-than-light travel.
You don't think that's possible.
I do not believe that.
Again, once you break,
once you create this black hole,
Einsteinian physics no longer truly applies.
Think of the paradigm.
It's as if you have broken known physics to begin with.
A whole, again, I choose not to call it new physics,
but truly, that's what it truly is.
Let's get a little,
so as you hit the swinging limit,
break spacetime,
what happens vis-a-vis this fifth dimension?
We'll not.
Okay.
We'll not touch on that.
What's interesting about alcooliary drive, I think,
is this notion of negative energy.
And there have been people who have associated
negative energy with quantum vacuum energy.
That's right.
What's interesting is it could be the case
that the alcoubier approach
and the quantum vacuum approach
in fact arrive at the same result.
They're just different paradigms
for looking at the same thing.
Yeah.
But what's interestingly different is
alcoubier is a strictly Einsteinian notion
in a manner of speaking.
It operates entirely within general relativity.
It doesn't require a TOE.
It doesn't require new physics,
which also is somewhat unhelpful
because it doesn't give us guideposts to new physics.
It's not really informative in any way.
Whereas these kinds of approaches
do require those things.
Absolutely.
Huge news, everyone.
We've been sitting on a ton of unreleased footage
that we will now be releasing weekly in our new WAP.
Our first episode is a completely uncut,
heated discussion between Hal Puthoff
and Eric Weinstein on remote viewing.
Yeah, you heard that right.
I still can't believe I experienced that firsthand
and now I'm happy to share it with you all
as our first exclusive video on WAP.
Head over to WAP.com
American Alchemy Premium
to become a premium member today.
By becoming a member,
you'll gain access to weekly premium videos,
behind the scenes footage,
and monthly group calls
where we discuss the ideas we love most.
Plus, you'll get early access to merchandise drops
and be the first to know
about the upcoming conference
we'll be holding later in 2025.
Our WAP community will serve as a private space
where curious individuals and tech enthusiasts
can come together to challenge the status quo
and explore ideas shaping our future.
If you're passionate about exploring unconventional ideas
and want to dive even deeper into our content,
I invite you to join our WAP today.
Head over to WAP.com
slash American Alchemy Premium
to become a premium member today.
Thank you so much and enjoy the rest of today's episode.
Can you talk about how high frequency gravity waves
might allow for UFO-like activity, or?
I would rather not.
Okay.
I would rather not, not go there.
I found it interesting that...
It could all...
And that's just because it can be weaponized, so...
No, no, let's not go there.
Well, I did find it interesting, just high level, that...
I believe Evgeny Potklednov has hit on something already.
And if it's true that he has made this
impulse gravitational generator...
Wow.
Scary.
Because he's funded by the Russians.
So why do they...
Once upon a time, I was told he was working
for an American contractor.
Is he?
I thought he might be.
Because I...
The latest rumors is that...
I had heard going.
Oh, phantomorph.
Yeah.
I hope...
Yeah, he's a phantomorph.
I'm pretty sure he's repatriated.
Okay, so this is really a very scary setup,
because basically, it's funny, because after this conversation,
I'm neurotic about this conversation,
but I'm so much less neurotic about outing towns in Brown,
who I'm sure is right,
because that is so far down the chain of like...
It's like so not dangerous.
To me, it's absurd from an American national security standpoint
that it would all be controversial to destigmatize him.
He's this side.
He's also a Navy scientist.
He was a great man.
Great man.
He is a great man.
He destigmatized his own work, probably for good reason,
because at the time, I think it was the tip of the sphere.
And it was this Cold War secrecy era.
But just based on this conversation,
it sounds like all nations are pretty far advanced
as far as these heterodox frameworks.
And if you're the US, you need to be getting
as many young people aware of these things
as soon as humanly possible, at least from a high level.
Yeah.
Otherwise, where the hell is the talent going to come from?
Seriously.
Yeah.
And Weinstein has spoken on this, too.
And I think there's missing names.
What's going on?
Who's actually working on it?
Right.
Totally.
Or even just like, what are the proper frameworks?
It's like, finally, it seems like string theory is capitulating
after getting bashed over the head for the last 10 years by polemicists.
They've seemed like not a super self-aware crowd.
Up until maybe the last couple of years,
they're all saying Leonard Susskind just won on theories of everything.
Mm-hmm.
Kurt Jemmell, a great interviewer.
I think we've kind of...
With the cap on straight forward.
Yeah.
But you would expect some sort of coordinated effort on high
when it comes to the American national security state,
when it comes to letting this stuff out.
And I always feel like I'm sort of in an awkward position with it.
For example, with the Townsend Brown stuff,
where clearly that was the right thing to do,
but it's in retrospect every time this sort of conversation.
It's like you never know what the right thing is.
I suspect some of this has to do with the fact
the majority of the program was executed during the Cold War.
And I think perhaps at one time,
we were quite certain that we were the only ones with anything.
And we thought worst case scenario,
we put a big footprint on this.
And just like Manhattan, the adversary infiltrates the program
and steals what we've gotten.
And all of a sudden, there's this proliferation
of next generation weapons of mass destruction,
as I spoke to Dave Grush about.
And maybe they thought for the longest time,
max priority is bury it.
Keep it totally, totally silent.
No one knows it exists.
Distance second priority.
Glean as many technical insights from it as you can every once in a while.
And unfortunately, somehow, eventually, they did get it
either through their own crash retrievals
or infiltrating our program, whatever it might be.
And now there is a race and we are not in first.
That's wild.
What do you think it is at first?
If I had to guess between Russia and China, I'd say China.
They're not distracted with a regional war.
They have a significant amount of resources to put towards it.
They've repatriated a lot of their alumni from this country.
Every year, China graduates more STEM professionals
than exist in the entire United States.
They're brilliant.
How many times they've won the Math Olympiads?
Do you think that's simple?
Sure.
And do you think it's probably, you know,
it's like the three-body problem or whatever.
The PRC, if they want you to work on some highly class-wide stuff,
they just knock on your door.
And here it's just as complicated and bureaucratic.
You know, you have all these corporate thief domes
with local incentives taking shots at one another.
I truly think that one day we must unite the factions
because I think one day we shall have...
One day?
You need now.
What do you mean?
Listen, as soon as possible because I think we have an external enemy.
And by external enemy, I mean...
Very external.
What are you talking about?
NHI?
NHI.
So did the doomer take?
So yeah, what evidence do we have?
Because, you know, when you speak to Lou Elizondo,
you have sort of this like idea that something is imminent.
It could be possibly hostile contact.
Maybe they're prepping the battle space.
I tend to think at least historically looking back.
Think of the earth.
Okay.
People have warred for less than the place of extreme natural resources.
We are a very yummy apple.
Very.
Yeah, but do you have any everybody's eye?
Sure.
But it's like you have thousands of years of history where we haven't had contact.
Or maybe if we have had contact, at least it's ephemeral enough
where our modern historical perspective,
I believe we've had contact with thousands of years.
But in this weakly entangled ephemeral way,
in a way that if you were to talk to a conventional historian,
they would not say that...
They'd say we're alone.
We're at the top of the consciousness food chain.
So do you guys have any information that I dealt
when it comes to something coming down the pike as far as hostile content?
Well, there are people who feel strongly that there have been reset events,
human history reset events.
For instance, 70,000 years ago, we know genomically there was a bottleneck.
There was a human bottleneck event where something like 7,500 members of the population
are our descendants or our ancestors.
And I don't know what to think of that.
I mean, I don't really necessarily see the purpose,
but you do have to speculate.
There's so many degrees of freedom associated with what are their motives?
Are they resource-constructed in some way?
What continues to be interesting in 50,000 years?
Isn't it fairly well-documented that that was Luis and Walter Alvarez,
Luis Walter Alvarez, the father who was in the Manhattan Project.
They had this theory that an asteroid hit the earth,
wiped out the dinosaurs around that period,
and then you get this Cambrian explosion of new life.
So that doesn't feel like non-human intelligence to me.
No, no.
I don't mean extinction level event resets.
I mean, more recent than that, like in human history.
For instance, the Toba event and the Randall Carlson stuff
and the Graham Hancock stuff, the reset 12,000 years ago.
You know what I'm talking about?
But that might have just been a common airburst from the tour.
Absolutely.
Oh, yeah, I fully agree.
So it's not the middle.
OK, but then again, you need more evidence.
If you're going to say that non-human contact that's hostile is coming down the pike.
Well, there's a book out there.
OK, what's the book?
Charles Ford, Book of the Dam.
It starts with very interesting words.
I believe we are property.
Read that book.
It's very interesting.
It's for your audience.
Let them look into this little breadcrumbs.
We're property.
So we're already colonized.
What are we?
Again, the whole idea of are we a civilization with amnesia?
As a certain gentleman?
Well, we Graham Hancock.
Graham Hancock, sure.
Well, we definitely seem to follow this like local incentive, scarcity, gamified thing
that doesn't seem like it's in the best interest of our race
ascending into anything more real.
And that's the thing that attracts me to the whole UFO phenomenon for all its
weird cast of characters and Hall of Mirrors vibes.
It feels like a somewhat transcendent topic where maybe we can descend out of...
I think we will soon, soon enough anyway, face a tremendous threat from without.
I believe, as the great Ronald Reagan once said,
if we do not come together as a unified Earth, we will not withstand what's coming.
Do you think it's already...
You have these rumors of the gray aliens collecting biological samples.
I do not know.
I truly do not know.
Why does it happen in contact?
Because that's a crazy, that's a really big assertion.
Do you ascribe to the battlefield preparation hypothesis
that the vehicles acting aggressively with fighter planes,
that the vehicles overflying the test fields and shutting missiles off?
Of course the testing.
Do you think so?
And that's why we should be very careful on putting all our money into
reverse engineered craft because they already have their own technologies.
They know how to defeat their own thing.
What if there's good factions and bad factions?
Like when I speak to Robert Hastings, I'm praying for that
because otherwise we do not have a chance in hell.
Well, a lot of the nuclear stuff is like shutting down silos.
And then a lot of the messaging that people get seems to be like
you're going to destroy yourselves in some sort of nuclear holocaust
and you need to come together now and focus more on the environment
and that sort of thing.
It's a green PC type things.
I'm not saying that's not some tricksterism.
It's hard to say.
We need to maintain that.
If there are multiple...
Yes, I completely agree.
If there are multiple actors in the space,
it's incredibly hard to attribute what to what.
Yeah.
How does your work, Sal, connect with the great output off?
I read a lot of his papers and he is great indeed.
Don't forget, I believe this man,
if he was not connected with things that are taken as non-scientific
and then pseudoscience like remote viewing would have deserved,
is deserving of a Nobel Prize, truly.
Especially the physical review paper on gravity and that's pure brilliance.
What does he say about gravity?
When he describes gravity as an emergent property of the underlying space-time foam
and it's put off like seminal work of space-time.
So if you can electrically polarize the vacuum,
then you can manipulate gravity like you can manipulate variables in Maxwell's equation.
Yeah, and he's the first to talk about that.
It's funny, he was touching on it in my interview with him and Eric Weinstein
and we didn't quite get into the mechanism because this idea, I think...
Eric couldn't believe that he worked on remote viewing.
I could tell that, again, for Harvard-trained mathematician,
the idea of even remote viewing being possible with such an abnormality.
What do you think of remote viewing?
I think remote action is possible.
So that's even farther than remote viewing.
Can you imagine stopping at hard just by thinking about it?
Say from Qatar.
That's scary.
That's some scary shit.
Anyway, who needs the CIA's hard stopping gun when you can do it with a saw?
There are rumors about the fact that there was other teams of remote viewers being trained by
Pat Price and Joe McGonigal other than...
Yeah, there are rumors that are still going on.
I mean, if you read Skimarkers at the Pentagon, it was definitely still going on in the context
of OSAP, but I don't think it ended in 1995.
I mean, you have Joseph McGonigal won the Legion of Merit for over 200 times,
which he helped to relax intelligence, hostage cases, drawing up nuclear sites,
that sort of thing.
You don't just end a program like that.
Yeah, it just wouldn't make sense.
I also think we're emerging.
We're figuring out more and more possible physical models of consciousness
that might explain remote viewing.
So if the brain is a hybrid quantum classical system,
which Penrose would be one model, and I don't know if microtubules are the right thing,
but they can maintain coherence up until the single point.
They grab it and run it or whatever.
That's important.
If that's the case, then in quantum systems, you have temporal non-motality,
and you can reverse cubic positions in quantum computations.
Then if you get into a working quantum computer,
maybe you can send information on the application like back in time.
Many people building quantum computers say that.
If your brain is a hybrid quantum classical computer,
maybe you are accessing shards of information from the future,
especially if you're given confirmatory feedback.
How does the brain prevent decoherence?
That's the question I should ask.
Probably through non-abelian statistics, just like the Bayes effect.
That must be some meditation technique or something.
No, I'm sorry.
Non-abelian statistics, it's like Fermi-Durac statistics.
That's a type of particle statistic model that emerges from standard model physics.
I know from a mathematical perspective,
but a dog isn't doing vector calculus when he's catching a frisbee.
What protocol should we do to maintain coherence?
Great question.
Sal, what do you think?
What do we do?
Great question.
How do we get to the fifth event?
How do we hit the Schwinger limit?
Be cute.
For example, in these UAP phenomena,
they speak of mind-matter connection.
But there must be a transfer.
There must be an intermittent medium.
What is that intermittent medium?
It has occurred to me that these...
The vacuum itself.
Oh, yeah.
What else can be there?
The medium for which...
How does light transfer?
To photons.
But you're saying where's the medium?
Because every other wave has to move through a medium.
A medium.
The ether?
I don't know.
Something.
A quantum vacuum.
Is it at the superforce level?
Is that at the Planck scale?
The superforce, we're talking about 10 to the 44 Newton.
It has to be in a bit of a dimensional state.
It would have to be...
Which Ken Shoulders talks about,
the dimensional space for exotic vacuum objects.
Yeah.
I suppose it doesn't have to be.
It's not necessarily required
that we have higher dimensional spaces.
I mean, there could always...
So Kaluza-Klein compactified sub-dimensions.
It has problems,
but the general notion of higher dimension...
It solves some problems.
It explains the hierarchy problem.
It explains the gravitational weakness problem.
Why is gravity 31 orders of magnitude weaker
than the strong nuclear force or something?
Remember what Kaluza thinks of electrical charges.
What motion in the fifth dimension?
Really?
How interesting.
Fascinating.
It was interesting.
I was reading Frontiers of Propulsion Science by Aaron Davis.
Great book, by the way.
Eric W. Davis, no matter what he says on my physics,
the man must be congratulated for that book.
Just for that book alone.
I brought my copy.
Him and Mark Millis are amazing,
but you can tell that the real forte
behind the physics is Dr. Davis.
Well, he says...
My hat off to him.
He says something around the Leibniz-Brown effect,
which he believes in the Holst & Neve.
If you take the face value,
that's just a coronal wind or ionic wind,
and it's not actually a tie
between electromagnetic and gravity.
But I think at one point he says
you would need a fifth dimensional space
to connect EM and gravity
if this weren't actually work.
Exactly.
Very interesting.
I think fundamental...
Oh, Dr. Davis is very intelligent.
How does torsion...
Jack, please.
Well, so one of my favorite subjects...
Now we're going into heavy pseudoscience
for everyone out there.
So here's what's funny is that...
This is all fake.
That's right, brother.
If you talk about heavy side
as a more fundamental treatment of Maxwell,
similarly Einstein-Cartin
is a more fundamental treatment of Einstein,
because Einstein felt the torsional tensor
should be treated symmetrically in free space
and therefore zero out.
T21 minus T12 equals zero.
And Eli Cartin came around and said,
no, you can't make that assumption.
There could be exotic environments
where this is a non-zero contributor.
And so basically the two contributions
to gravitational force in a geometric context
are curvature to space-time
and a twist to space-time.
So torsion is the twist.
And what makes that interesting
from a gravity manipulation standpoint
is that contents of the torsional tensor
are the spin density tensor,
which can contain contributions
from electromagnetic spin.
So if you can do really novel things with spin,
either by coupling electron spin to nucleonic spin
or maybe like you're talking about axial spin
to harmonic vibratory modes
that sort of blow up real fast,
you can maybe generate really large contributions
to the spin density tensor
and get these torsional repulsion fields
that act like gravity, look like gravity,
but technically they're not exactly gravity.
No.
Well, however they can couple to it
under certain conditions.
Yes.
So then you could basically,
this gravity can't traditionally manipulate in a lab,
so you might be able to manipulate in a lab.
Again, the whole idea of the graviton itself
being a spin two,
whereas the photon spins one.
Yeah.
Now in the broader context,
torsional physics is not a theory of everything.
It's just going to be a piece
of a more complete theory of gravity
that slots into some broader theory of quantum gravity.
Interesting.
Do you think, oh, so that's fascinating.
But this would be torsional physics
a way to manipulate gravity that binds to gravity
more tightly than traditional
transverse Hertzian electromagnetic waves.
Along the lines of multiple tech trees,
this could be one of those branches
that's important and significant.
That's fascinating.
What do you think of, you know,
you mentioned Greer watching this stuff
and that's sort of inspiring.
Some of the work did Bob Lazar.
Do you think that he was?
I think Lazar is right on the money.
When I, I'll tell you the truth.
When I saw in the super force equation,
C to the fourth divided by big G being the super fourth,
and that talking as the linear operator really
to the spatial temporal geometric structure,
thereby giving rise to energy density.
When I saw that, and I remember his words
that this sports mile is the zip.
It was 3D printed on space time.
That's exactly what that equation says.
So that means that they had the capability
to manipulate the space force at a planckian level.
We'll talk about a physics that we, it's unfathomable.
That's why I'm saying they could, that's, that's.
This is root access.
That's pretty well known.
And so what about his idea of gravity A, gravity B?
I don't know about that.
It's occurred to me.
Maybe it's curvature, gravity, and torsional gravity.
Oh, could be.
Interesting.
I know.
And I don't like encouraging him, but.
Well, now I've, I've come around.
I never, I never fully rule.
Logan says that he believes.
Lazar.
So do I.
I believe Lazar is not.
I'm starting to too.
Well, I think he was pushed out by Intel.
Cause John Lear gave the files to George Knapp.
But, and so maybe it was like at the time
that the majestic 12 was coming out,
I think a lot more about the majestic 12 was correct as well.
And that would maybe go, went by another name
and there are false names in there, whatever.
But that's how kind of passage material works.
That's how, you know, recruiting works where, you know,
you have to give it a quacky veneer or whatever.
So I don't quite, you know, maybe believe the story fully
prima facie, but I think you experience real stuff.
Yeah.
And he was given passage material.
Maybe some of it was authentic.
No matter what he did on the side.
And no matter, don't forget this guy actually knew Teller.
Right.
Teller did not approach anybody.
There was, so we're talking about one of the greatest
physicists of all time.
If it wasn't for his, his staying with Oppenheimer
and how much Oppenheimer was loved by the rest of the
physics community, Edward Teller would be remembered
forever as one of the geniuses of our time.
Remember, this is the man that not only is responsible
for the Teller-Wulham device, but for something called
Project Sundial.
It's unclassified.
Look into it.
Well, if it's unclassified, so what happened?
Imagine creating something instead of 50 megatons,
the Russian Tsar Bomba.
Imagine something billion.
Whoa.
Yeah.
He wanted a hundred gigaton.
Oh, I don't know why.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, man was an absolute genius from everywhere.
Oh, genius.
He had no limits.
No, no, he rightly believed.
No, no earth, no, no world in its right mind.
We're all sane.
Trust me.
We are sane as an earth.
That's why we must come together, unified somehow.
Calm down with that amount of energy.
No, no, no.
He believed that no sane world would ever execute such a weapon.
So just the very existence of such a weapon,
knowing that you have that sword.
This is the sword of Democles.
The man must have been very well versed in the classics.
Sword of Democles, always hanging above your head.
Nobody is crazy enough.
We have enough of a sword of Democles in my opinion.
But what do you think?
Because you've been talking a lot about Heaviside here
and him being kind of an inspiration for you in a way.
Absolutely.
I interviewed a Navy scientist,
another Navy scientist who actually was anonymous
in my Townsend Brown episode.
He talked about this framework of extended electrodynamics.
So he talked about the original 21 Maxwell's equations
and a more faithful adherence to those equations
and a quaternary and you know.
No quaternary.
Yeah.
Being somehow essential to all these new exotic electromagnetic waves
beyond the transverse hurting waves.
So scalar wave, scalar longitudinal waves, things like that.
Do you agree with that model?
I believe there are many roads that lead to Rome.
I understand that view because they believe
that truly what we're seeing, again,
the whole idea of the Aronov-Bohm effect,
the whole idea is that what's true
is the vector and the scalar potentials,
not the electric field per se and the B field.
It's the way you look at it, the way you use.
Again, physics should drive the mathematics,
not the other way around.
I truly believe that.
What's interesting is I read a paper recently
because I've always been skeptical of scalar,
longitudinal scalar wave theory,
but I read it primarily because we don't see them.
So the question is, I'm fundamentally an empiricist.
Yeah, we're already going to see these.
Well, what's interesting is apparently there's a possibility
of mistaking very small subharmonics in AC waveforms
or I'm sorry, mistaking longitudinal scalar waves
for subharmonics.
So the notion was if you expose some kind of a novel matrix,
something like what we were talking about,
that this pulls the waveform apart
in the same manner that a prism pulls apart a light wave
and shows you the different frequencies.
You might see something novel out of that
that you're like, wait a second, that's not normal.
That's perhaps your scalar wave.
So there's a possible experimental approach
to verification or discrediting.
Don't forget the fundamental papers of E.T. Whitaker.
1904, 1905, an English-British mathematician
by the name of E.T. Whitaker writes these two fundamental papers
whereby he actually shows that scalar waves,
non-Hertzian, so non-transverse waves are feasible.
Interesting.
As a matter of fact, wasn't it Colonel Tom Bearden that mentioned?
Yeah, Tom Bearden talks about scalar physics.
There's a guy now named Lee Kiley who publishes papers
about wood science and another guy publishes papers
about extended electrodynamics and these other wave types.
I mean, these things are not expressly forbidden.
Anything that's not forbidden by physics is allowable.
Now, is it engineerable?
Right.
That depends on the genius of some people.
You need to polarize the vacuum again, right?
Because it's all about in the Lorentz equation, right,
having a sort of a gauge where the scalar vector potentials
are automatically kind of negated or equal zero,
but back there might actually be a real scalar vector potentials
that are present even if the magnetic field is not present.
The prosaic explanation for that is electromagnetic four potential,
but a lot of the proponents of extended electrodynamics
say that that actually explains this stuff way better.
This is why I think condensed matter physics
is the most exciting field of physics today
because these things are being interrogated.
And please don't forget Nikola Tesla.
His idea of radiant energy is based on what?
Scalar waves.
Scalar waves, yeah, interesting.
Very interesting.
What was he?
He was totally against Hertz, by the way.
Tesla was very outspoken, known to be here anyway.
Because he thought his own these exotic wave.
Well, he was experimenting.
Don't forget, Einstein thought that Tesla was
the most intelligent man in the world at one point in time.
This is Einstein.
I've never interacted with this.
I've never consumed Einstein's commentary about Tesla.
That's interesting.
It's funny, Tesla and Townsend-Brown were doing the same thing.
Tesla was doing similar stuff to what Townsend-Brown was
at the end of his career at Wardy, Cliff,
and in Colorado Springs.
Extremely high voltages across short distances
where you would expect to get these kind of anomalous effects.
Somebody should ask the president-elect about his uncle.
Well, you want to know the one interview with John Trump
is available in a documentary on the Philadelphia experiment.
Philadelphia experiment is this wacky,
psi-off experiment with Townsend-Brown involved.
There probably was a real thing going on underneath the veneer,
the fake thing that was distributed that Townsend-Brown actually pulled off.
But John Trump gets interviewed in this documentary by Bill Moore.
John Trump was tasked with looking through Tesla's files
when they confiscated him from his apartment in New York.
He was the nationalist.
He was very close with Vannevar Bush.
If there is a legacy UFO program, John Trump had to obey.
He was the top radar expert in the country.
I think he even owned a company called High Voltage LLC or something like that.
I believe Tesla physics, quote-unquote, can bring these things down.
This is our trump card.
I truly believe it's the genius of Nikola Tesla
that will one day help us in the upcoming, let's say,
if there's such a thing as a cosmic war.
Oh, you're saying invasion.
Well, that's what Greer says.
I don't like to talk about that.
I think that's a bad idea.
I think we shouldn't mess with the stuff.
Let them decide.
I think they're way more advanced.
Again, I believe we have properties.
Oh, man.
I think they're factions, and I think they're good initiatory factions,
and then they're bad malevolent, more actively fucking with us faction.
Well, interesting math emerges when you look at the sheer number of galaxies,
the sheer number of stars per galaxy, the age of the universe,
the number of emergent species that can emerge from a given planet.
The numbers blow up very quickly.
So this notion of one, two, three, four species gets really strange.
Like, why aren't there 25,000?
Why aren't there 30,000?
Yeah.
On the nuts and bolts side, I think there are power scaling restrictions in play
that restrict how far you can go with any sort of FTL technology.
But at the same time, I think it informs the political landscape.
Yeah.
Well, we assumed this binary angels and demons or angels for demons.
Right.
But there's no gray cells.
Well, you have a hierarchy of being.
It's likely more of a kangaroo and explosion,
more diversity on the food chain above you, maybe even then below you or whatever,
because you have these, you know, all sorts of path dependencies.
And yeah, so maybe that just gets extremely complex.
As a counterpoint, Peter Thiel gave a very interesting interview where he talked about
how he thinks there's an argument to the fact that there might be selective forces
that lead to one very good and one very bad.
And this could give rise to the binary.
And I ran a space on it and we talked about it and it's very controversial
because there are people that hate this interpretation,
but I think it's very compelling.
Well, it's compelling.
But it's biblical.
It's biblical.
It is.
The war between the children of light and the children of darkness.
That's yeah, if it ever felt apocalyptic, it does now.
I mean, look at what's going on.
You look at where the war is actually taking place.
It's pretty wild.
It feels like we're in the book of Revelation, but also-
Truly end of time.
It's weird.
But like, I think the point he was making was that tech itself is a forcing function.
If you have warp drive tech, if you have faster than light tech,
you never see it coming.
It's hard to have the defense against that.
That was an excellent point.
And so because of that, you either have to inflict towards this totalitarian,
total clamp down, one world government state,
or you need to reflect towards complete altruism and heart centeredness.
And if you have one, maybe you'll be okay with the warp drive tech
and it will be saving up humanity.
And if you have the other, yeah, you just, you need total control.
But you know, that's not, that's a-
I hope we don't slip in that direction.
I believe the physics that will win is the physics that's based on creation and destruction.
So Victor Schauber, how do we, how do we get to it?
Cause a lot of this conversation is, you know, it's fascinating and it's mind opening,
but it's also bleak and scary because it's starting to dawn on me just how we live in
a multipolar world and you have these exotic lineages of physics that
all of these countries are somewhat privy to.
And they're, they're very destructive.
And so how do we get to a more generative,
heart centered, positive version of physics and the global landscape?
Many roads lead to Rome, but there's only one Via Appia.
Only one what?
Via Appia, the one that the aqueduct was built along.
It was the major road that led to Rome.
So there could be many roads that led to Rome, but there was one of choice.
I was usually followed by the legions.
There may be just one way of doing it right.
Can we find it before something tragic happens?
What do you think that way is?
There's that-
Unification.
But it can't just be a physics solution.
Can we re-engineer human nature?
I once asked that of Kurja Mangal.
I think he's still thinking on it.
Can we re-engineer human nature?
That's where the secret of all this lies.
What are we?
Who are we?
What do you think?
I think it's possible.
But again, I think it demands a great effort on our part
to leave our individualistic ways and come together as one collective
who are willing to live in total equality.
See, Marx attempted that.
He did.
And yet, the practice of Marxism resulted in tremendous atrocities, pogroms.
Well, he was diagnostically-
Then you could say that it was the Leninist uprising and the revolution
that led to Nazism, that led to National Socialism.
So in other words, everything came from trying to
put this idea of equality into practice but in the wrong manner
because it formed elitism.
Once you have elitism into the equation, you've destroyed everything.
It's just so anathema to human nature of Marxism.
Maybe it's sort of diagnostically somewhat correct as far as
how capitalism creates these sort of alienation dynamics or whatever.
But prescriptively, it's just so beyond idealistic.
But isn't it a beautiful thought, the equality of man?
I think man, I don't like meritocracy.
I think it's overused and kind of in an annoying way.
But meritocracy is way better than equality.
The idea that we're all equal outcomes or whatever, that's crazy.
Maybe some sort of equal footing or opportunity,
but you end up in these sort of never-ending conversations
of how exactly to engineer that in these sort of technocratic ways
that lend themselves actually to power co-option ultimately
of people that don't even care about those things.
It's sort of a bait and switch.
I don't know.
I think it's a really hard conversation.
If the 20th century was a refutation of anything,
it was a refutation of these technocratic ideologies
where you could engineer society into anything.
You had all these utopian ideologies and none of them weren't.
Nazism, Bolshevism, communism, Trotskyist, Marxism, they all failed.
I think it really was a refutation.
It's the most deadly century we've ever had.
I don't know how we get out of this,
but it feels like it has to be a much more individual kind of thing.
Maybe we need a common enemy from the outside.
No, that doesn't seem really good or carries that at all.
You're saying that there would be an enemy from within,
there would be a fifth column,
that there would be people taking their side?
Well, I think the right thing is to look within.
It's to really, really look at yourself,
think about who you are and fix what's broken there.
And I think that's probably a better path individually.
I think we've seen enough microcosms of the outside enemy
to assert, unfortunately, that there would be fifth columns,
in some manner speaking.
That's what the problem is.
What do you mean?
And again, that would only…
There'd be some disruption to the idea of global unity
by way of an external… because the ideology is that there'd be…
So we must go to the most basic of units,
the re-engineering of human nature itself.
Do we have enough self-awareness to do that?
I don't know if I believe in that in some sort of Psy-op-y way.
Well, yeah, what is an open question?
What do you guys think Reagan meant?
You have rumors, right?
Of like, MacArthur…
Why would he have said it in a plain session of the United Nations?
So this is the story is that Reagan was speaking with Gorbachev.
Gorbachev tells this story.
He says it in an interview, I think with Charlie Rhodes or something.
Reagan whispers to him right before the conversation starts.
He says, you know, hey, if aliens invaded, would you have our back?
Compadre on that and defend the earth together.
And Gorbachev was extremely taken aback.
Yeah, this idea of kind of astral politics or something.
Do you think that in this idea of MacArthur, there are rumors that…
I'm interested though.
What was Gorbachev's… was it then the affirmative?
I think it was.
He said, yes, Mr. President, we would defend you.
He meant it too.
Is that real though?
I mean, is that like Reagan, like kind of asking for it?
Sometimes you have leaders that are meant to be there at the right time,
under the right circumstances.
I believe they're born for that particular purpose,
to make sure that earth is not pushed toward the precipice of perdition.
Maybe we're meant to have a certain balance between
the children of darkness and the children of the light.
What do you mean?
Equilibrium.
And yet everything happens far away from equilibrium.
Everything that's physically important.
How interesting.
Well, we're speaking of a mistake.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
Jack, throw some light on this.
Analogously to the Pius effect, which takes place far from equilibrium,
where you can see these novel behaviors.
In the book, you have average behavior.
You have average outcomes.
And so he's making an analogy to that.
Well, yeah.
I mean, you have like thermodynamic laws around that.
Right.
And then it does seem like all these exotic effects I get into
are like a result of like quote unquote higher energy physics.
Extremely granular manipulation of materials or whatever.
And so it's like you're pushing the boundary.
It's like you have this...
Ken Wilson was a stern physicist.
You have this concept of renormalization.
It's really used to describe phase transitions in materials.
But it's like...
Who was against it?
Someone spoke against that idea saying that it's like
it's like putting infinities under the rug.
It's like sweeping infinities under the rug.
Was it Feynman?
I don't know.
But I'm just using really philosophic.
Right.
Just like pushing systems to their logical boundary.
In your case, the Schrodinger, wasn't it?
Right.
You get kind of weird effects.
Like it is a famous quote from Agnew Bonson.
He was sponsoring the Chapel Hill Conference and kind of creates quantum gravity,
which sends physics down to cul-de-sac and string theory.
Very strange what happened.
Very interesting.
But he's also funding Townsend Brown's work back at the house.
And he says strange phenomena occur.
And you have more incredible names.
You have Bryce and Cecil DeWitt.
Yeah.
You have John Wheeler.
And you have Lewis Whitten.
I wanted to ask you, Bryce DeWitt in 1968 writes a paper
about superconductors and gravitational drag.
Does that connect with your work at all?
No comment.
All right.
Yeah, I know.
It's a lot of odd characters there.
The whole conference that was sponsored by Wright Airfield.
So very, very interesting history.
And Agnew Bonson himself is the patron.
Writes a book about man-made UFOs called The Stars Are Too High.
Actually, it's about this plan to unite the world via this man-made UFO invasion.
But he also says strange things occur at high megavolts across short distances.
And he's describing Townsend Brown's work.
So it's clear that pushing things to the limit, even plasma itself,
is the fourth energy state.
We can't go beyond that, at least conceptually.
You get some greater truths by pushing the boundaries inside.
So it's true.
It's true.
Must always push the boundaries.
Yeah.
But is that this Faustian Promethean thing?
Are you playing with fire when you push the boundaries?
If tech is an apocalyptic forcing function,
are you imitantizing the eschaton when you do that?
And is that a bad thing?
It's most certainly a point of inflection forcing function.
That's a great question.
Gorgeous question.
Thank you, sir.
True.
Jack, you want to attack that one?
It's most certainly a point of inflection forcing function.
Such that when you approach it,
some black swan event is going to take place.
And I think that's where we talk about things
that are way far from equilibrium.
These are founder events.
The world is inflecting.
We're in a weird timeline.
Extremely.
Very strange want and time.
You know, things that there may be.
You know, I've always said this,
and I will hold this to my dying breath.
The whole idea is that I describe matter as condensed,
or rather, how do I say it?
I say it in a certain way.
Contained energy, or rather, energy that's contained,
that's bound within fields and frozen in a quantum of time.
You know who believes in?
Confined in a quantum of time.
That's it, confined.
That came, no joke, out of the quantum vacuum.
I choose not to use the term ether
because Einstein was so much against the idea of loop,
even though he introduces it in 1921 on a paper.
And everyone gets back on it.
He says actually the ether is compatible with.
Our orthodox physicists that already believe me
of pseudoscientists and crackpot and stuff.
I don't want to force.
Do you think that in your lifetime,
on a sort of more mass audience scale,
you get vindicated in your work?
It's a dream, brother.
It's an absolute dream.
Do you know how many tears and sweat and blood
and freaking nightmares and sleepless nights I've had?
It just, that's why the Lacknall paper means so much to me.
That's why I honor that man.
We're supposed to not like the Russians
and not like the Chinese.
We're all people, brother.
We're all people.
And that's why sometimes I pray for this external enemy
because it's the one thing that will create
a forcing function to unify us once and for all.
A united Earth as it should be.
Do you think you should want to know about Russia?
No, please.
But Putov?
Absolutely.
Dr. Putov, that paper is one of the papers
that got me thinking.
He's so early on everything.
He's just implicated.
I'm pretty sure that he's had many a sleepless night, too,
and concerned about what others have thought of him.
Well, he's 88, and he's still completely leeched.
I saw him maybe a month and a half ago or something.
We watched James Stock's documentary together.
He's just sharp as a tack.
He's just an incredible hick.
What a mind that man knows of that guy.
Especially when I met him maybe 2018-ish, 2019,
and I felt really crazy and thinking about it a lot.
All this stuff's now in vogue.
UFO celebrities.
Back then, I felt totally quacky
because I felt a deep resonance with him.
He was the one guy who I felt was somewhat credible.
He's very incredible.
But because the deeper Afghans are so serious,
I realize he is.
Just for context, for the audience,
Magenta was a rumored crash, I believe, in Bologna, Italy.
That ended up in Italy's hands for the next 11, 12 years.
It was actually rumored to be held at the Vatican at some point,
and then it was transferred over to the US.
We do think it maybe went to Germany,
but we don't know when, for sure, or whatever.
But Grush wouldn't speak to when it came here,
it was in Atlanta and all of that.
Some heavy physics there.
It's interesting.
It's possible it was a first one-off vehicle
that we had at some point before Roswell
that was at Wright Field or something like that.
So you think that picture of the...
Because you see pictures of Congress stop,
and Breslau, and Pilsen, and Czechoslovakia, and Poland.
And you see this tester rig that's shaped like...
It looks like an acorn or a bell or something can be fit in there.
You think they were testing?
Maybe.
The Magenta craft?
I've heard it's also radioactive on that side.
Also, I mean, why have that shape at all?
Why that shape in particular?
Yeah.
Given...
And then it was transferred maybe to Wright Pad or something?
Right, like at the end of the war,
when we got in or something like that.
That would be a very interesting piece.
Or if it wasn't...
It's scary as shit, though, if it's true.
It's because the implications of...
But so do you think that was a UFO crash?
You don't know.
But like in 1933,
you don't have some sophisticated bell on that you're building.
It's like native brand.
Again, the Paisa effect, 1890s physics.
So you think people, like maybe Gerloff figured this out?
What I'm worried about is Walter Bosley,
the friend of Dr. Joseph Farrell.
Walter Bosley, the whole idea of Ninja.
Who the fuck were these guys?
The airship, quote, unquote, mystery.
What's going on here?
Because that's around...
Hedi Sassan, Death Speaks with a Bike.
Yeah, but that's a really quick translation
from physics to engineering.
You think the 1890s airships...
There were some engineering geniuses back there.
Look at Nikola Tesla.
But that would just be wild.
That's beyond belief to me.
What if it's all fucking connected?
You think it could all be human stuff from the 1890s on?
All of the records could be gone, you know?
I mean, that's just a crazy cover-up.
And just use the empty craft kind of like a...
Because they never...
Again, I believe their fucking craft
touches on manipulation of the super force.
How the fuck do you do that?
How do you manipulate something at the planned scale?
How do you keep that secret for 140 years?
That seems great.
They also didn't have a lot of the material technology advances yet.
Sometimes survival makes you crazy.
They would need some sort of parapsychological read access to control.
They would need the line stuff in order to do it.
Or possibly a brotherhood of the occult?
Yeah, something like that, like a breakaway civilization.
Like that.
Breakaway civilization, arriving at some insights.
Read up on Dr. Farrell's ideas on a breakaway civilization.
Also Dolan, don't forget Richard Dolan.
But who in the 1890s would have been privy to heavy-sides insights
in a way that allowed them to finance the building of these exotic craft?
No, they were some powerful families back then.
I'm not going to name names.
These are still extremely powerful.
Put it this way, it's much better that we know certain names,
but we don't know the invisible ones.
Because touching, even on the invisible one's existence, is not a good idea.
And in fact, our survival.
And again, none of us here are suicidal.
We love being alive.
Absolute.
Absolute, yeah.
That's right.
No, it's, yeah.
Yeah, let's not go there.
Change the direction of this.
All I was going to say was I was in graduate school during
a pulse-icey fusion work.
When I went to a conference to present,
I was introduced to Eric Davis, Hal Pudoff, John DeLay, and Sonny White.
Oh, Sonny White, right?
Now, you shouldn't mention Sonny White.
During OSAP, it turns out.
Davis was helping write that book at the time for BDP.
What a book.
That book opened my eyes, man.
So you think Sonny White was a NASA engineer?
Eagle works, huh?
And he was trying to implement the Alkabir warp drive.
And I think now he's funded by DARPA.
He's a company called Limitless or something like that.
Do you think there's anything to-
Oh, absolutely.
Dr. White is right on the money.
You think so?
Oh, yeah.
Because NASA's-
Have you noticed he hasn't published anything lately?
Always a sign.
Yeah, right.
Yeah, and I think they said it failed or something.
That should happen right before Ning Li just-
Yeah, interesting.
So this Hampton Langley incursion last year
that we now are understanding happened.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
You have Hampton Air Force Base.
You have a 17-day incursion where it seems like drones
are swarming around the area in our airspace.
We have no defense against this.
It seems like there's maybe a mothership, Chris Mellon said.
There's a mothership.
What do you think about that?
What do you make of it?
Let me ask one crucial question here.
I don't know why people don't ask these questions.
Fine, safety of life.
Very important, yes.
Was anybody killed?
Yes or no?
I don't believe so.
I don't know that they would.
I mean, if it were, it would be highly concealed.
Do you think maybe?
I don't think anybody was killed.
There should be an answer to your question.
I'm not going to go further.
Is it extraterrestrial?
Interesting.
Again, there's ET tech and there's man-made tech.
Many roads lead to Rome, but there's only one via apia.
If it's adversarial, it's awful, congregational.
And if it's some advanced tech, they've got it way away from their shoulders over our territory,
where it could be down and captured by us and assess attribution, do any reverse engineering.
It's the only reason I'm skeptical of an adversarial origin.
But at the same time, there were witness reports that they could hear about,
that they were like lawn mowers.
There was their audible.
I'm not going to tell them what we do with that.
Remember the reverse engineering part.
Lazar speaks to this, why he was there to begin with.
He was there as a replacement for someone that had gotten killed,
trying to what?
Use a blow torch to go through this.
Again, why did they never crack that?
Because they're fucking physics folks to engineering the super force.
I don't think we can do that.
But I think they're man-made tech that can go around.
And again, the most complex of problems has the simplest of solution, depending on perspective.
What if we found another perspective?
John is a same problem.
So you have spoken publicly with a guy named Ashton Forbes, who is a big proponent of these MH370
videos.
And these are these videos where you see these three orbs and they seem to circle around.
The MH370 is this Malaysian aircraft.
It was on CNN for a couple of months.
And it seemed like this civilian aircraft carrying passengers just disappeared in the
Southeast Asian territory.
And this guy, Ashton Forbes, took to Twitter maybe around a year ago saying he thinks this
is man-made tech and that the craft was somehow teleported out of the sky.
What do you think?
Don't forget Dave Rossi's force orb.
That's why Ashton now goes by four orbs.
There must be four orbs.
Remember the whole idea that once you open the black hole, there is a white hole.
But the three orbs would have your three axes, hence your point of origin.
But there must be a destination.
So there must be a fourth orb.
There must be a fourth orb.
So you think this is...
It's not me.
Dave Rossi came up with this idea that there must be a fourth orb.
I think he's one right on the money.
Dave Rossi is a very interesting engineer that should be looked into as well.
He's very smart.
Why would you teleport a commercial airplane?
And where did the airplane end up?
Or is it the plot?
All I'm saying is when I saw that thing open up, I saw the Pais effect in action.
And I told Ashton Forbes, that was his first podcast, Hard Truths podcast.
I told him this is the Pais effect.
Oh my God.
So you think we have room to produce secret weapons and projectism.
Those orbs also speak to AGI, artificial general intelligence.
Autonomy.
AI autonomy.
So we're talking about artificial singularity.
I think.
I don't know.
It's funny.
I just interviewed Matthew Pines and he goes, there's an iron triangle.
He goes, AI, quantum, and the grush stuff.
He was talking to somebody who was deep in the national security world or whatever.
The triangle, the connection between those three things is somehow this
incredible technological scene.
Again, cross-domain disciplines coming together.
Fusion of these ideas resounding into what?
Destructive technology.
Exactly what Jack was talking about.
Very interesting.
I hope one day you give your correct name because you're brilliant.
People should know you as you are.
You're welcome.
Do you think that any of this stuff makes it into our civil infrastructure?
I mean, we're sitting in decaying.
Weaponization.
By God forbid, a third party, not even a country.
I don't think this is hard to engineer.
Trinity.
Leave it there.
So basically the physics stagnation, we have to, our physics has to be stagnated.
Can you imagine some nut, some effing person that hates the world engineering this?
Well, my hope is that these nano-structuring 3D lattices turn out to be really hard to make.
Interestingly, it would be fabs like TSMC, the two nanometer structures,
you would need sub-nanometer.
You need the sub-extremes.
The extrema is 10 to the negative tenth meters,
whereas the nanometer is 10 to the negative ninth
to manufacture the structures.
But what if there's another way?
What if there's a resonance-based way?
Of fabrication.
That's not based on material composition.
That's not based on fabrication method or fabrication protocols, procedures.
It's simple.
Interesting.
You don't want a nut to figure that out.
That would be bad.
That would be a bad day in hell.
Or heaven, either way.
What do you want the world to know?
What sort of message do you have for people out there?
We need to unify, 100%.
Need unification.
We need people to come together.
And if these ideas can bring them together, then so much better for it.
But too many things are dividing us now.
And what we need is a unifying factor.
Do you want to build a UFO to take us over?
What I want to build is something that can defeat an external enemy,
one that's external to Earth.
So let's say somewhere close to Proxima Centauri, as we're speaking right now,
an alien armada is being formed.
I would like for us, us, everyone in this room to come together
everyone in this room to come together and with other people, bring together our minds
to create in what...
One thing about what Dr. Eric Weinstein is saying is that he thinks that the best of the best,
the greatest physicists should be brought together to come up with these ideas.
I think even Joe the plumber can contribute, given common sense and enough knowledge
As a matter of fact, look at Ashlyn Forbes.
I'm completely surprised what he's been able to achieve in almost a year,
studying this physics on his own.
Look into his podcasts.
This guy has come up quite a bit.
He does not have a physics, a physics pedigree.
Again, what if Joe the plumber comes up with the greatest physics idea of the month,
whatever that may be.
But one, again, that helps us come together as an earth.
This interview is coming on the backs of congressional hearings.
No, actually it can be seen around the existence of non-human intelligence
and unidentified anomalous phenomena, but also programs thereof housed in the government around
data collection, quarantining these UFOs, tracking them, that sort of thing.
What did you think of the revelation of immaculate constellation,
this idea of this top secret program around UFOs?
Do you mean immaculate constipation?
Because I believe such little information was excreted from those hearings that one could not
fathom, for example, coming together, unifying these concepts into something that can save
us, Homo sapiens sapiens, from an external enemy.
If we continue on with this trickle by trickle disclosure, this farce, again,
immaculate constipation, we will get nowhere, absolutely nowhere.
Do you think that there are deeper programs than immaculate constellation?
I guarantee that arrow will get nowhere in no time at all.
In other words, nothing will come of it again.
They'll generate another great report that will say absolutely nothing.
There's a Senate hearing this coming week into Arrow's activities and Arrow's recent report.
You should come with it.
That would depend on my higher-ups.
Because of certain personal issues, I'll need a riot.
If my higher-ups decide, I would be of use, gladly.
But again, please let someone drive in there.
I need a drive.
That's all.
Dr. Sal Paisos is an absolute honor.
We appreciate you doing this.
The honor was all mine, sir, and please, you are our intellectual equal.
Trust me, certain things you've said during the interview make me say that.
I would not say that otherwise.
I don't just come up with stuff.
Whatever it is, it is a glimmer of hope, and we need all the hope we can have.
I appreciate that, man.
I appreciate the hat.
Wear that.
Yes, sir, please.
Please do.
Yes.
Looks really good.
Looks good, brother.
All right.
All right, bro.
Ian.