No expert in the world agrees with you.
I know you're eager for Arrow to debunk this.
There's zero evidence of what you're proposing.
None.
This isn't debunking.
What we're seeing here is a curve.
It's basically a mathematical projection.
It's not.
Like, propose one plane that would fly like this.
Well, why don't you propose one type of UFO?
The broader problem with ufology is that it's always been
the battle between hard evidence and cool stories.
There just happened to be a distant jet exactly where the close thing is?
Is that what you're saying?
Behind it somewhere.
Really?
You're very familiar with this theory of mine, right?
I think this is flinging to the crowd here a little.
I've brought all the experts to you.
Bring some experts to the public.
Unfortunately, the stigma that you promote is a big part of why they don't want to come out.
These guys are fighting a stigma.
I encourage them to come forward.
Like, come forward and I won't laugh at you.
Different parts of the brain have different activities.
But you know that, don't you?
I know people that you don't love.
Maybe you should interview me.
I am here with Mick West and Merrick von Rennenkamp.
And this couldn't be better timing for this debate.
We planned this maybe a couple weeks ago.
Both of you are very well known.
Merrick, kind of on the pro side in certain cases where I wouldn't call you dogmatically, you know, pro UFO.
But there are a few videos that you've looked at where you think there's something substantial or worthy of investigation there.
And Mick has done an amazing job.
I think you're doing a service of debunking a lot of UFO videos that just are clearly fake.
And so I'm honored to have you both here because I think you're both the most serious on this sort of, you know, this is a poor way of saying it.
But pro and anti side.
And this couldn't be better timing, right?
It's just insane how many quote unquote drones we're seeing over Air Force bases all over the world right now.
And so, yeah, I'm very excited.
You kind of came on my radar because you publish in The Hill and you're a former DoD employee.
And so you kind of know that world.
And you were publishing really substantive pieces around some of these videos.
And you, Mick, have been doing this for how long?
Like five plus years or?
2016.
Since 2016.
And I think you've always done a pretty good job.
And I've heard things from, you know, UFO junkie friends of mine.
Like, oh, Mick's like a bad faith actor.
But all of our conversations we've had, I find you to be pretty earnest and cool.
So why don't you guys kind of introduce yourselves and tell the audience how you got into this sort of vigilante job of debunking or, you know, confirming UFO videos to begin with?
I'll start with you, Mick.
Well, Jesse, thanks for having us.
And Mick, thanks for being here.
So I will be very honest.
I didn't think about this topic.
I thought it was squarely in tinfoil hat territory.
This is not anything on my radar.
I missed the big 2017 story with Leslie Kane and Ralph Blumenthal.
It's just as a testament to how little I was tracking this.
But I did stumble upon, I think it was late 2019, the interview that Commander Fravor did on Joe Rogan.
And I previously worked at the Pentagon.
I worked with some Navy aviators, naval aviators, more rotary wing guys.
But I knew the type, the bravado, the way they carried themselves.
And as soon as, you know, I watched five minutes of Fravor, and this guy is the real deal, right?
He's a skipper of a storied squadron out on the West Coast, VFA 41, Black Aces.
And he tells a pretty incredible story.
And oh, by the way, it wasn't just him, it was three other aviators that were out there.
And that was my ticket kind of down the rabbit hole.
And then believe it or not, Mick West has a lot to do with my kind of my interests in this topic.
We exchanged a whole lot of emails.
I think we did a few Zoom calls.
Yeah, this is years ago.
And I'll just be transparent.
The deeper I dug into Mick's theories, first of all, I'll just say, who's this Mick West guy who thinks he knows more than the government?
Like, OK.
And there's some pretty deep nuance.
And from my perspective, I found, again, in my opinion, he was wrong about a lot of his theories.
And the deeper we dug, I'm like, my goodness, there's something to this.
And that was that was really kind of the kind of the twin tickets down the rabbit hole dug into the history and started writing articles about it.
Awesome. And before we get to you, Mick, for context for the audience, we're going to be going over kind of the classic historic landmark cases.
So Nimitz FLIR videos or video rather, the Gimbal and GoFast videos, which were taken at the USS Roosevelt 300 miles off the coast of Jacksonville.
Mick, what about you? How did you get into this?
Well, I am a retired video game programmer with a very different background to Merrick.
And I after I retired, I took up writing and I was just doing stuff like writing for Game Develop magazine.
I eventually kind of moved into the skeptical arena, like investigating conspiracy theories, things like that.
One of the first things I did was I was on Wikipedia, just messing around with I used to edit Wikipedia about 18 years ago.
And I saw this article on the chemtrail conspiracy theory, which is this fun theory where the government spraying things behind planes.
And we did some I did some work on that on my blog and that blog kind of evolved into my current site, Metabunk.org.
Metabunk is just a forum where you have lots of people just chatting about various different conspiracy theories.
It's kind of grown now to be more UFO focused.
But we have a lot of older stuff like 9-11 conspiracy theories, false flags and even the Flat Earth stuff.
But with the chemtrail stuff, I got really into doing things like tracking planes and trying to figure out what people were seeing in their videos.
And so after that, it became kind of a natural thing for me to start looking at UFO videos.
I occasionally did a few over the years, but it really kind of took off in I think it was 2016 or perhaps the start of 2017 with this case from Chile, Chilean Navy video.
And this is a video that looks really spectacular.
It was released by Leslie King, who you mentioned, in the Huffington Post in 2016 and 2017.
And she was very effusive about how amazing it was.
And me and a few other people looked into it, and we very quickly determined that she was wrong about that.
It wasn't that amazing.
And it was actually just a distant plane.
And we were able to prove that pretty conclusively.
Not everybody agrees straight away, but I think America would agree that case is pretty much solved.
And that really kind of got me hooked on UFOs.
And that kind of almost coincided with the 2017, December 2017 release of a New York Times article, which came with these other videos.
Gimbal and the FLIR 1 video and GoFast was released a little later.
And when I first looked at them, when I looked at the FLIR 1 video, it seemed very similar to this Chilean video.
And so I thought perhaps it's the same type of thing.
So I started delving into it.
Turned out it wasn't exactly the same type of thing, but there were related aspects.
And I really enjoyed the process of investigating UFO videos because it was so similar to the work I used to do with video games, except kind of in reverse.
But use all the same mathematical techniques, all the analysis techniques.
Debugging and debunking are very similar things because they're both about finding the root cause of something.
And so I got hooked and I've been doing it ever since.
And I've done a whole bunch of different videos.
Merrick and I have agreements on several of these.
And we have disagreements on a few of them.
And I think a lot of the time those disagreements kind of fall in the videos that are somewhat more ambiguous.
And this is a problem in general with UFO videos.
But I'm keeping going.
I want to ask real quick before we get into the actual substance about kind of your priors.
Do you believe in the possibility of UFOs, notwithstanding the fact that you don't sort of agree that any of these videos are legit?
No, definitely.
I mean, I would certainly agree.
People ask me, do you believe aliens might exist?
And yeah, I think obviously in the universe, almost certainly, there's some type of alien life, probably some type of alien civilization.
I just don't see that there's good evidence of them visiting us here.
I wouldn't rule it out, but I just don't think there is good evidence of that happening.
OK, what about you, Merrick?
Previously, before I went down the rabbit hole, I was in McWest camp.
I thought the universe is exceptionally large.
We just cannot conceive how large it is.
And I firmly believe that there was life out there, not that it was here.
Fast forward over the last, I'd say, three, four years, I have done a deep dive into the history of this topic.
And I've read the raw case files, the raw blue book case file.
No analysis, just the straight reports.
And I've come to a very different conclusion.
I'm a big fan of James MacDonald.
I don't know if you guys are familiar with him, but very, very prominent figure in the history of this topic.
He's an atmospheric physicist.
I encourage anybody watching to read anything and everything that he has written.
Start with science in default.
It's a remarkable critique of the Condon committee, which we can get into.
But in his bottom line assessment was that the extraterrestrial hypothesis is the least unsatisfactory hypothesis
for what hundreds and thousands of people have observed at close range over the last 80 years in many cases.
I'd say I'm partial to that because of just the long historical record.
And I've got a ton of cases that I'd like to get into because I think they are related to some of these videos and we can talk about that.
Fellow alchemist, Lucy Breakers are changing the game for nicotine users.
If you're looking for 100% pure nicotine product that's tobacco free, Lucy Breakers are where it's at.
Each pouch has a cool twist.
Inside is a capsule that can pop to release an extra burst of flavor and hydration.
It's a unique experience that makes your nicotine routine more enjoyable and convenient.
As someone who delves into the most heretical thinkers and ideas of our time, I appreciate products that challenge the norm.
Lucy Breakers do just that.
My personal go-to flavor is mint.
Whether I'm deep into a podcast discussion, exploring new frontiers or brainstorming ideas,
throwing in a Lucy is an easy way to keep the day moving.
Plus, the flexibility and strengths lets you choose what suits you best.
Let's level up your nicotine routine with Lucy.
Go to lucy.co slash jesse and use promo code jesse to get 20% off your first order.
Lucy has a 30-day refund policy if you change your mind.
Again, that's lucy.co and use code jesse to get 20% off.
And here comes the fine print.
Lucy products are only for adults of legal age.
Every order is age verified.
Warning, this product contains nicotine.
Nicotine is an addictive chemical.
Thanks so much to Lucy for sponsoring today's episode.
So I think we should just dive into the footage and, you know, yeah.
Not to just interrupt, but I just want to quickly just acknowledge,
and again, I bring a historical kind of government perspective to this.
Can we just acknowledge what has happened over the last five years?
We've gone 80 years and we are literally at the 80-year anniversary of the first reports of foo fighters.
Like that happened November of 1944.
80 years of denial, ridicule, obfuscation to, and I love this quote from Mick,
June 20th, 2020.
This is when Rubio snuck a provision into, you know what we're talking about, right?
Stuck a provision into Senate Intelligence Committee language.
And Mick's quote is, years will pass.
It will recede in memory.
Little will come of it.
I assure you in June of 2020, I probably would have agreed with you.
Now we have Aero.
I think it's about three, four dozen.
We just heard yesterday with this week that they're at full operational capability.
Three, four dozen people working at a UFO office, right?
1600 cases as of last count.
And his director just came out and said, in essence, I'm baffled.
I have an engineering and science degree.
I'm baffled.
I don't know what's going on.
And I don't know anybody else who knows what's going on with some of these cases.
And that's pretty extraordinary.
He was a former NSA director.
He was an NSA scientist.
Scientist?
Yeah.
So it is pretty remarkable.
We had just about every single, we had former CIA directors, former national intelligence
directors, just extraordinary things.
You know, Radcliffe has said, UAP UFOs exhibit technologies that we do not have and cannot
defend against, right?
They appear to.
Right.
I'm just saying, I'm trying to acknowledge where we've come.
It is extraordinary.
It is astounding, right?
I don't think, I suspect, if I had shown you a picture of Dave Grush testifying under oath
with the former Inspector General of the Intelligence Committee sitting right behind him four
years ago when you wrote that tweet, you would probably thought I was crazier than I am.
Well, what I meant there, the nothing will happen was not that nothing would happen.
It was more that nothing would happen in terms of giving us evidence that aliens are visiting,
which is the thing they really want.
I'm actually really happy that we've got all this progress and we've got these investigations
that Arrow is doing a lot of work, even the spending millions of dollars on investigating
it, and hopefully they will release their information.
I don't think we've really got much further along the road in terms of actual evidence
of genuinely anomalous phenomena that didn't exist five years ago.
The stuff that Arrow's released, obviously, like people are disappointed with that.
And their overall assessment is, you know, there's no evidence of alien life.
Right.
We have lots of talk about things going on behind curtains and in skiffs and in secret
and things that people can't talk about.
And that's interesting.
But I think it kind of speaks to the broader problem with ufology is that it's always been
a bit of a battle between hard evidence, hard data, and cool stories.
We have a lot of really amazing eyewitness accounts.
A lot of the Blue Book stuff is eyewitness accounts, and there's very little that you
can actually get to this tangible data.
There's some data that's written down, but there isn't really very much we can actually
analyze.
And that's what we really need to move the conversation forward.
Having people come forward and say, you know, I worked on a program in the 60s that did
crash retrieval, I don't think it's really going to move the needle very much, unless
they can actually produce some evidence of something.
It's just more cool stories, which maybe they're true, maybe they're not.
But we can't actually do very much with them.
And that's always been the problem.
And then there's the intersection of the cool stories with the data, with the videos, which
we'll get into later, where people are talking about.
I'll give you two points that maybe give us a little bit of hope to really address your
point.
And I think Kozlowski has said, and the quote here is...
And Kozlowski is the director of ARRA, the new director.
Dr. Kozlowski is the new director of ARRA, which is the government's UFO analysis office.
And his direct quote is, we're going to need the help of academia and the public to address
some of these cases.
And he's pledged to release them.
Now, I'm skeptical, right?
I know how the government works.
They don't release anything.
They don't have to.
But he said this.
So just to address your point, maybe we'll see some more.
I don't know.
I think that's notable.
And then secondarily, Dr. Kozlowski in his hearing said that at least two multiple firsthand
witnesses have gone to ARRA.
Witnesses of what?
Unreported UAP programs.
That was the question from Gillibrand.
So anyway, we can go down that route a little bit.
I'm just saying the story of UFOs is, OK, there's something coming.
But there is.
We'll see.
But there is some chatter about it.
Mick, how do you, to Marek's point, there has been a lot of momentum if you're just
tracking social consensus, hype around this stuff.
I mean, I run a YouTube channel that really surrounds this topic.
Particularly, I've seen a lot of interesting.
My site is all UFOs now.
Well, there you go.
So how do you explain that?
Do you think it's some sort of coordinated PsyOP?
Do you think it's just this contagion mess, social psychosis thing?
What's going on?
I think it's something that was maybe bubbling beneath the surface.
And it's just been kind of allowed to come out.
The New York Times story basically opened the floodgates.
It was something that gave validity.
It allowed people to talk about it.
It allowed other journalists to talk about it.
And once you get that going, it becomes this kind of feedback loop.
People talk about it in the media.
The general public talks about it.
And then Congress gets involved because it's what people are interested in.
And then you can kind of push these things perhaps without the stigma that you had before.
And if there are things like unacknowledged SAP programs,
which I wouldn't rule out, of course.
It's entirely possible that people were running crash retrieval programs
for things that they thought were UFOs back in the day.
But perhaps some of those were under the radar.
We know the government has done dodgy things before in the past.
So that's the type of thing that should come to light.
There's the Church Commission.
Was it the Church Commission?
Yeah, the Church Commission.
Yeah, something like that where we can actually get these things out.
And I've been really enthusiastic about people like David Grush testifying.
And I wish he would come out and actually say more.
Because I want this to come into the sunlight.
I want to know what's actually going on.
Well, that's your goal.
That's, I think, the goal of everybody here.
And I would love for this to either be falsified forever or corroborated.
That's not going to happen.
It's one of those things that's impossible to falsify,
because there's always the idea that that light over there might be an alien.
Well, what I would say.
You can prove it's true.
I think there's not a lot of daylight probably between us.
We're like, I think whatever is going on is interesting.
If it's mass social psychosis, a coordinated psyop.
I think those are extremely interesting because I think it's the best
psyop maybe of all time.
If it's a psyop or something.
Guys, we can talk about this for hours without even getting.
I will say the commentary, direct commentary, from Rubio, Gallagher,
Kirk McConnell, former Senate staffer, Sask, Sissy, sorry,
Senate Armed Services, and the Senate Intelligence Committees.
They have all stated.
Jill LeBrand, her first question in the hearing.
There are, as she said, there are reports that firsthand witnesses
are reluctant to go to the UFO, the Pentagon's UFO office.
Rubio has stated very clearly over and over,
these are credible people with high clearances and high positions
and they fear for their lives.
He said that on camera.
That's fascinating.
So if it's mass psychosis and people in high positions in government
are saying, yes, I was on a retrieval program,
then we have a major, major problem because they're just
fantasists out there that are in important positions.
And very sensitive areas.
I mean, the other thing I would say is say this is all unacknowledged
deep black programs.
I find that fascinating too.
Absolutely.
Maybe it's a bit of both.
I mean, we do know that there are people in governments who are fantasists.
Not everybody who's in government or in the military is going to be
like on the level.
Well, the thing that I've found because I've met all these people
deep inside the government, you know, post doing this show,
they are often more conspiratorial than people who are civil side.
And that could be one of two things.
That could be like, oh, that like discredits them in some way.
Or it can be like they are somehow privy to a lot crazier stuff.
And that makes them more conspiratorial.
Mick, can I put you on the spot actually?
Sure.
Just curious.
When Grush says under oath, I had the firsthand people go to the
inspector general to submit a complaint.
Luis Elizondo goes under oath.
Yes, we have crash retrieval programs.
Rubio says, not under oath, but he says publicly in a very long interview,
firsthand witnesses, they fear for their lives.
Kirk and Connell has been tracking this and is convinced that there's
something to this.
I talked to a congressional source, told me, I asked point blank,
what's your confidence level in the existence of such programs?
The answer was hovering around 100%.
What am I as an analyst supposed to do with that?
What do you think?
I wouldn't be surprised if there were such programs.
I mean, this is something I've been saying for a while.
Sorry, and then it's NHI and it's non-human intelligence.
No, there's actually NHI there, but there's programs that existed
in the past possibly even now where some people who work on those
programs think that it's NHI.
It's quite clear from people like David Grush that people do actually
believe these things happen.
They believe that we have bodies.
They believe that we have crashed alien craft and they believe that
there are these programs to study them.
Maybe the programs exist, but what were they actually studying?
Why do you think the inspector general didn't just shut this down
immediately?
I have no idea.
I'm not really familiar with what the inspector general does.
But Grush's claims covered a range of things.
There was the whistleblower recriminations and it seems a little
bit mixed up as to what the inspector general was actually
investigating and what they're referring to when they said that.
Rubio is very clear.
He's the vice chairman of the Senate Intelligence.
Rubio said that the unreported, the misuse of funds, that portion
of it, they didn't say anything about the reprisal part.
But the misallocation of funds was deemed credible energy.
Yeah, well, if there are unacknowledged special access programs,
I'd be happy to see them.
It's interesting because that's also unfalsified.
That's like also, and Feynman's not even wrong sort of category.
If they deny it, you can't, you can say they're lying.
If they admitted and show it, then that's one thing.
It's like anything.
You only need one.
You just need one ace to win the game.
But everything that's not an ace doesn't mean there's no aces.
So you think it's going to stay in this sort of liminal category
for a very long time?
I would hope it doesn't.
But I think all we can hope for really is to get more sunlight on it.
And if there is something there, something will eventually pop out.
And if there isn't something there, we will see that all the things
in the dark corners become illuminated and we see that there was nothing there.
And perhaps there's something in one of the dark corners that's really interesting.
That would be great.
How did non-human intelligence get into a bill sponsored by Chuck Schumer
and signed on to by Rubio, Gillibrand, former presidential candidates?
22 times.
And then biological evidence of non-human intelligence.
Oh, you should ask Schumer about that.
Schumer said he was doing it to honor the legacy of his friend, Harry Reid.
So he just randomly puts in aliens into 64 pages just because he's buddy?
I mean, maybe. I don't know.
He didn't do it.
His staffers did it. Some staffer did it.
Well, he put his name next to it, right?
He does that for everything, doesn't he?
But he doesn't write the legislation.
Does Schumer put his name next to Bigfoot legislation, right?
You go down the list.
Well, I think, okay, this is great.
I think we should get into, because this is all dealing with sort of social proof,
which does carry for a lot of people, we should get into first principle.
We should.
That's where I think both of you add really tremendous unique value.
And so why don't we start with the famous Nimitz case of 2004,
this amazing FLIR video, thermal video, caught in November of 2004.
You have eyewitnesses, David Fravor, who you mentioned,
who is really, I think, a source of belief for a lot of people, kind of proxy belief,
because he's a very serious sounding guy.
I mean, you heard him on Rogan, and I think he was tasked with defending LA,
actually, around 9-11.
I don't know if you're familiar with that.
I didn't know that.
Because it was like unclear how many planes were, how big the threat was.
And you can hear him speak, and he seems very sort of matter of fact.
But Mick's done a great sort of debunk on this.
So why don't we watch the video and we'll get both of your assessments.
But before we do that, why don't we do a little rock-paper-scissors to see who will go first?
I'm also happy to take it and just kick it off.
You want Mick to take it?
No, no, he's trying to psych me out.
Look here, let's do a little rock-paper-scissors.
That's right.
All right.
I knew it.
I'm too honest for my own good.
Wait, wait, I don't even see who won that.
So just for the audience, before we went live here, Mick said we agreed to rock-paper-scissors.
Mick said he's going to go with paper, and I went with scissors.
So here we are.
Here we are.
All right.
Well, Merrick, you take the first one.
Yeah, but seriously, please jump in if I misstate anything.
So the background is in November of 2004.
The Nimitz carrier strike group, so it's the Nimitz and other vessels, Navy ships,
are out for pre-deployment workups, pre-deployment training, basically,
to make sure their equipment is working before they deploy and go to combat.
I think they're setting out for Iraq.
So this is early stages of the Iraq War.
Very high operational tempo during their training missions.
The USS Princeton is a guided missile cruiser,
and it is part of this Nimitz strike group.
And it is, over the course of, I think, a week, according to one of the witnesses,
the key witness, Kevin Day.
Maybe 10 days, I think.
10 days, sure.
OK.
They begin tracking anomalous objects at 28,000 feet, heading south at 100 knots.
Very strange tracks.
That's odd.
Occasionally, if I understand right, they're tracking them coming from above 80,000 feet,
zipping down to the surface of the ocean, or they'd hover around 28,000 feet.
Notably, Kevin Day has been very specific about this and consistent.
28,000 feet, 100 knots south.
And Kevin Day oversaw radar operations.
Correct.
Kevin Day's story has actually changed a few times, and he's given different figures.
28,000 feet, 80,000 feet, and 20,000 feet.
He mixes things up, and it's changed in other ways as well.
I've only seen 28,000 feet in all the interviews I've seen.
I think he wrote it down, and he kind of memorialized it in a book.
He wrote a little novella.
I did find this interesting.
They wrote this, like, you would need a novella.
It clearly stuck with a lot of these people, right?
So we digress.
And one day, so Kevin Day is concerned that this is flight safety.
It is, right?
I mean, you have objects.
I mean, you sanitize your airspace, and you want to know what's out there.
So when your air crew are out there, that they're not going to have potential collision risk.
So one day, he vector sends out two F-18 Hornets.
Commander Fravor is flying one of them.
We have not heard from his backseater publicly yet.
The other plane, Fravor's wingman, wingwoman, was Commander Alex.
She's pretty new to the squadron at this point.
She's probably a lieutenant.
Alex Dietrich.
Alex Dietrich, correct.
And her backseat is Jim Slate.
Sorry, Wiseau is the weapon systems officer.
That's the backseater that does kind of a lot of the tactical systems.
And they get out to this.
They call a merge so that they're basically in the same airspace as where one of these tracks is.
Look out and see an object doing basically kind of like a weird ping-ponging, zigzagging pattern apparently right over the ocean.
And there's this roiling water underneath.
Very strange.
And so they have these two jets.
If I understand correctly, Fravor departs.
Dietrich stays up high and starts circling.
And they both start circling.
And Fravor's going lower and lower.
And as he goes down, the jet, according to Fravor, kind of reacts to him coming down.
And it kind of does, Fravor does a boop noise.
I don't know if you guys have seen that.
But somebody did a pretty good compilation of his reenactment.
And then it kind of shoots off at just unbelievable speeds, according to the witnesses.
Anything else?
Well, a couple other interesting things.
So it goes, you know, it's 80,000 feet and then, you know, right above the surface of the water.
And then he says it goes back up 80,000 feet.
And then he goes 80,000 feet is space.
So that was like this interesting line.
He also says when he sees the craft, and this is what I found very interesting.
He was like, it almost seemed like it knew that he saw it.
Yeah, and he recognized him or something.
There was some kind of awareness.
Yeah, that's right.
No, I'm sorry. Good point.
Yeah.
Now that you mentioned it kind of.
So as Fravor's going down the circle, the thing does one of these like kind of a counter circle.
Right.
And I think it's called a two flight.
But it shoots off and apparently ends up at a predesignated rendezvous point.
Let's call it a cap point.
And that is an area known to aircrew.
So that is interesting.
Yeah, this is interesting.
A lot of this information kind of comes second hand by various people.
They were talking about the 80,000 feet.
And you said Fravor said that Fravor didn't see that himself.
And he didn't even get a blip on the radar.
They didn't actually see it on their own plane's radar.
And when they arrived at this location, they didn't at first see anything.
And the jets are hauling along at 600 miles per hour, which means that you're not just hovering over one spot waiting for something to appear.
You end up a few miles down the road very, very quickly.
So Commander Dietrich or Alex Dietrich disputes that very clearly.
She disputed that to you, as you know.
And Fravor has said that that log is third hand.
It's just inaccurate.
They both said that they arrived at 20,000 feet and there was nothing at 20,000 feet.
So they both said that when they heard merge plot, they looked out and they saw it.
You're suggesting that there's no link between the radar.
They dispute that. I'm just trying to be clear.
And she disputed that to you, as you know.
Right.
I think Fravor himself has actually said that when they arrived, they had to look around a little while before they saw it.
I think they was pretty quick.
Dietrich, well, of course, like Dietrich's account.
Let's just leave it at there's a discrepancy.
Well, no, there's a big discrepancy.
If you're saying that Dietrich's account matches Fravor's account, you have to say that also Dietrich says her experience only lasted five, sorry, eight to 10 seconds.
The entire thing from merge plot to the thing flying away.
Right.
And Commander Fravor says it lasted about five minutes.
And he said that all four pilots had eyes on for five minutes.
So using one person's account, we don't really know which one was the more accurate.
I would think probably Fravor because it's a more experienced pilot.
But he himself said that it did take a little while to find the object.
And Dietrich has addressed this and we can go down this rabbit hole.
But she's just said like as a number two, like she's watching him.
She's not watching the target.
She's watching him.
Yeah, but she said from merge plot.
Okay.
On Twitter.
Which she asked very specifically as it was from merge plot to when the thing shot away.
Fair enough.
I'm acknowledging that there's a dispute there and that's fine.
That's all right.
Big discrepancy.
Well, one other thing I think to discuss is just this idea that this was caught by many sensors.
So all we have and all we can go off of on a first principles analysis,
semi distrustful of government in a lot of cases, is this FLIR video.
And we're going to play that in post-production.
We can also watch it here if it's useful to both of you.
But they say that they caught it on phased array radar and then you also have eyewitnesses as well.
And so can we even use that as data or what do you guys think?
Go ahead.
Yeah, I think it's a bit of an issue.
I think some of the stuff like it dropping from 80,000 feet was something that Kevin Day said that someone else told him
the people who work in the kind of the missile defense program on shore told him that they saw it later.
He didn't actually see that at the time.
He says like, you know, it's 28,000 feet, but they went in at 20,000 feet and it wasn't there either.
So there's a lot of in the actual verbal accounts, there's a lot of variation.
I think we can get an overall sense that something happened.
There was something that was showed up on the radar and they did see some object, but there is there is quite a bit of variation.
Was it a seagull, Mick?
Because I've seen a video of you suggesting it might have been a seagull.
I don't think it was a seagull.
OK.
I suggested that when Fravor was looking down, there might have been a variety of things that he might have seen looking down, like white caps and boats and things and seagulls.
I think he said one of the things I said.
I think he said, I hate to say this, but there would have been seagulls out there.
Yeah, there would have been.
Yeah, but a hundred miles offshore?
Yeah.
I actually looked this up.
Seagulls really don't go.
I'm not an ornithologist.
Let's be clear.
They don't venture very far from shore.
The seagull thing is quite entertaining.
I don't think it was a seagull.
You got to go down there.
It's kind of interesting, that little little segue.
We were talking about Heineck earlier.
Yeah.
Heineck was the person who came up with the swamp gas thing.
Correct.
Yeah.
And then later admitted that he was lying and covering things up.
I think he was lying about that particular case.
I think then he actually thought that might have been a reasonable explanation because
there was a marsh in the middle of where they were looking across.
But it was a pretty silly explanation and it was kind of rightly ridiculed by the press.
Then it was seized upon by kind of UFO fans to label any explanation of UFOs as being
like, you know, it's just, they just say it's swamp gas or they just say it's a weather
balloon.
And I think to a degree, the seagull explanation has become like the modern swamp gas.
So I get seagull comments almost every day.
Okay, got it.
Almost every day on Twitter.
So you're saying you would admit that seagull is not your base case?
No.
I mean, what Fravor saw was some kind of tic-tac shaped object.
Yeah.
And it appeared to be moving around.
And if it was a seagull, I don't think he would have made that mistake.
Let's talk about a guilt-free alternative to alcohol that's perfect for your dry January
or any time you want to unwind.
Cornbread's Organic CBD Gummies.
These gummies are an absolute lifesaver for my evening routine.
They're a natural way to relax, celebrate or wind down without the hangover.
I've cut back a lot on my alcohol consumption over the last few years.
For a lot of you trying out dry January or cutting back generally, it's not always easy.
But swapping that glass of wine for cornbread CBD gummies is a total game changer.
It's a simple upgrade to your evening routine that leaves you feeling great the next day
without sacrificing the fun.
Plus, with all natural ingredients, they're the perfect way to stay balanced.
Cornbread hemp isn't just a product.
It's a small way to bring balance into your life.
Whether you're journaling, meditating or simply enjoying some downtime,
these gummies elevate the experience without any of the guilt.
It's like having a moment of calm in your pocket, ready whenever you need it.
Alcohol doesn't have to be the default anymore.
Whether you're cutting back for dry January or just looking for a healthier way to relax,
you've got to try cornbread CBD gummies.
Right now, American Alchemy listeners can save 30% on their first order.
Just head to cornbreadhemp.com slash Jesse and use code Jesse at checkout.
Again, that's cornbreadhemp.com slash Jesse, code Jesse.
Cornbread hemp, this is the good life.
And then how many eyewitnesses do we have?
That's a great, yeah.
We have a few, right?
Can I just quickly back up maybe?
And gosh, I mean, the setup has taken so long.
We're not even going to look at the video.
But there's another, there's a, I believe a squadron commander from a Marine Corps squadron
that was actually flying by.
Kurth, I think is his name.
Kurth, Kurth, Kurth, whatever.
And he, they decided not to vector him out there.
I think because of fuel issues, I'm not sure.
But he saw the roiling whitewater.
He didn't see the tic-tac, but the roiling whitewater.
That's interesting, right?
But to your point, for that first encounter, we're talking about eight eyeballs on this thing.
One of them is squadron commander, the others are pretty well trained.
Right, right.
And what do you think about that?
Yeah, I wish that we'd get more witnesses coming forward.
I think it's difficult now because it's literally 20 years since this happened.
And memory face and Alex Dietrich herself has said that she doesn't really remember the details that well now.
And probably the other people won't either.
But I think once you've got past the initial year or so of people remembering things,
it's very difficult to get that much more good information.
And using accounts from the time, if available, is usually the best way.
But we don't really have those.
Alex does say she has some notes that she made and some diagrams.
How do we get those?
Well, you give her a call.
That's right.
Yeah, reach out.
Well, there are a couple of other interesting things.
I think there were two radar systems, the SPY-1B radar and the APS-145 radar.
And we've seen neither of those.
We just have the FLIR geostorm.
And this is recorded after.
This is like an hour or two after the video, which I think that's when you had the E2 Hawkeye and then the Princeton.
So just to back up, the E2 is like a flying radar, basically, right?
And it apparently had a weak hit on this target, what's in the video.
And the Princeton did as well, which is how.
And Underwood had it on his radar, too, he said.
That's right.
Yeah, he said he got a hit on his radar.
He had three radar systems on whatever that is.
Indeed.
And this is Chad Underwood.
Correct.
Sorry.
Yeah.
So that original aircrew, the four aircrew and those two jets go back to the carrier.
They get out.
Apparently, Fravor tells Underwood, hey, we just saw something weird.
Try to go catch it.
And Underwood's really gung-ho about it, apparently.
And yeah, I'm going to go get it.
And yeah, he's vectored out.
I'm guessing like an hour or two after.
It's not clear.
They don't say.
Okay.
So they cycle through.
People about it.
I think I asked Kevin about it and he didn't want to tell me.
Yeah.
But they cycle through.
Underwood gets out and he gets these hits on the E2.
Was the E2 on the first encounter or was it on the second one?
And I just don't remember.
I'm not sure.
I think there were some eyewitness accounts from the E2.
People said they saw it out the window, but I don't think they'd actually really come
forward to swear on it.
The other possible interesting piece of information, which I'll just speculate on and that we probably
get to the bottom of, is you have this interesting nuclear connection with past UFO sightings.
This seems to be some possibly repeatable thread.
You have a great book called UFOs and Nukes by a guy named Robert Hastings, which I always
tell you.
I was reading it on the way here.
I appreciate that.
Excellent book.
And so what's interesting about the Nimitz carrier strike group is there were likely
tactical nukes on board.
Yeah, just when it comes to ships like that.
I can say with certainty that I think the Nimitz is a nuclear power carrier.
I don't know about the weapons and that's out of my expectations.
It's both nuclear powered and then most of those hold tactical nukes is my understanding.
That's about my pick right there.
You got me there.
My source there is Robert Hastings.
I'm a big Robert Hastings fan.
Well, yeah, you would say that's biased.
You would say that's pretty good.
I think Hastings is a tangent.
We can get into this later.
But I think Hastings is pretty solid.
He is, yeah, go for it.
I'm mixed bag, I was saying, I think.
Listening to his book, he does a pretty good job of doing a lot of research.
He's very detailed.
It does seem very much biased towards trying to prove that point.
And he'll lay out a few things.
Well, it could be this, it could be that.
But I think he's actually aliens.
On the theory side, but on the kind of what happens side, he's like pretty empirically rigorous.
Yeah, he's repeating things.
It's mostly eyewitness accounts.
Well, I got to give him credit.
I mean, he's compiled and I take an intelligence analysis approach to this topic much
more than Mick takes a much more technical approach.
But the documentation that Robert Hastings has secured is unbelievable.
I mean, it's extraordinary.
It's 170 eyewitnesses.
It's incredible.
And also the government documents, right?
That to me is also of interest.
Anyway, that's a whole other recipe.
It's a whole other apple, but I think it's important for establishing some sort of priors on this stuff.
Because just to kind of out myself here, I want to be as much of kind of a non-factor
and just honest judge and let you guys have at it.
But my own kind of way I process this is I usually think these things are prosaic or explainable.
Explainable way, they're air trash or balloons or whatever, or exotic craft.
But I think in the case of nuclear, that might be the exception.
Just because I think you have this repeatable, they say science needs to be repeatable.
And you do have this really interesting repeatable thread where you have all these witnesses
who have cue clearances.
It's hurt their careers to come out there.
Incentives are not to come out.
And if 170 have come out in the form of this book and you have a researcher who's now in his 70s,
how many more are out there?
That would be my question.
Well, to your point, we wouldn't know about these videos if they hadn't been leaked.
Right.
To your point.
This is interesting, too, because let's talk about the provenance of Nimitz.
Because Nimitz, Gimbal, and GoFast were popularized in this New York Times article in 2017.
But Nimitz, I believe, the video itself was kind of floating around on Reddit.
And it was even on a German server or something.
It was on a German server.
And you can still access it via the archive.org, the Waybank machine.
So there's actually a live link to this from, I think, I'm not sure exactly where in 2010.
So what German server?
This is...
It's like a CGI.
People digging into this.
And I quickly just make a point here.
This is when debunking goes wrong.
Because when that came out and it was on Above Top Secret, all these message boards or whatever,
people had decided, oh, that's a hoax.
That's not real.
And then Mick, I love this.
So in December of 2017, I think, To The Stars Academy put out an interview with,
I think it's Commander Alex Dietrich.
And your quote here on Metabunk on December 30th is...
And she kind of described the whole encounter and described everything that we just discussed.
And your quote here is, frankly, it's laughable that anyone is taking this seriously.
Right?
I'd have to save a bit more context about what I'm saying.
No, it's Metabunk post 84, December 30th, 2017.
Post 84?
What do you mean by that?
But on a particular thread, on the FLIR1 thread.
So I just want to be...
Debunking can really go wrong because this is arguably the most perplexing case.
I assume this video was real from the start, as I recall.
I'm not accusing you of...
So I mean, taking it seriously must have been like taking it seriously that this was something
performing amazing maneuvers, which is something I wanted to bring up.
With all these videos, there's really two questions that we better ask.
The first one is, is this object on the screen doing anything amazing?
Is it demonstrating unique physics that we don't understand or advanced technology?
And then after you have answered that question or addressed that question,
the other question is, what actually is it?
What might it be?
Do you have a base case assumption?
Because it doesn't seem to be flying normally.
Well, my base assumption for...
Well, my base determination for these three videos is that they don't demonstrate
anything amazingly anomalous.
And so with FLIR specifically, so like Seagull is not the base case.
Do you have any other sort of explanations or you're just like not anomalous?
As Murray knows, I think it's some kind of distant aircraft that is not moving,
not moving laterally.
When these videos first came out, there were people talking about how amazing they were.
FLIR 1 in particular was deemed to be amazing because the object appears to zip off screen.
And there's parts of the video where it seems to accelerate very rapidly
and then it loses track at the end.
And that's one of the first videos that I analyzed.
And I kind of went through it frame by frame.
And I think I showed fairly conclusively that all those things are just camera movement.
And you really think David Fravor saw just a normal aircraft?
No, I don't think so.
Okay.
No, these are two separate things.
Fravor and Dietrich had an encounter with a little tic-tac of some sort.
And then this video was taken out later.
It may be the same thing, but I think it's probably a different thing.
Despite the fact that these sightings had gone on in this little week-long stretch in November,
you think they're just different?
The sightings, they hadn't.
The radar returns had.
The radar returns, yes.
We had weeks of radar returns.
And then they went out for intercept on November 14.
Yeah.
And then apparently it stopped.
That was it after that.
That's what Kevin Day said after that encounter.
They didn't.
Nothing ever happened afterwards.
But yeah, the video itself, I don't think shows any like a balanced physics or anything
like that.
We don't know exactly what it is.
I think it's some type of distant aircraft that's flying away.
But as Merrick will explain later, there are issues with determining what type of aircraft
it is because of the angles of the image and things like that.
Merrick, if you just had the video and you didn't have the eyewitness accounts, is there
anything that would lead you to believe that this is anomalous?
That's interesting.
Without the eyewitness accounts, I probably would have...
That's a really good question.
Old me would have just dismissed it.
The me who's engaged with Mick, who has studied this topic, would be much more interested
absent the eyewitness accounts.
But maybe with the promise of other sensors that pick this up but that are too sensitive
to release or something.
Yeah.
It is weird.
It's odd, obviously.
Sorry.
In removing the context, it is odd on its face, on its face.
And I'll just to counter Mick or just to maybe respond, I'm very much on the opposite end
of the spectrum.
I'm glad we started with this case because ruling out a plane is probably the easiest
thing we can do today.
It is pretty simple to tool out of.
That's fine.
Yeah.
But so look, I mean, it is fascinating.
I have, based on the analysis that, and it's not just me, but the analysis that some of
my colleagues and one of them, as you know, is a University of California scientist, brings
superb expertise to the table.
And I would say, I'll speak for myself, but I have fairly high confidence that that was
a tic-tac-shaped craft and we can go through the data as we...
And then to kind of flip it on you, Mick, if the video didn't exist and you couldn't
easily straw man it with a debunk and you just had like these super credible pilots,
like eight plus, all saying, you know, we've seen this anomalous thing, would that lend
all of this more credence?
I think the detrick and Fravor encounter sounds by itself as being a really interesting event.
And it's Fravor's account of it that convinces people.
It's what convinced you with this Joe Rogan thing and a lot of people on the Hill have
talked to Fravor and heard his account and they've been convinced by it.
So this video isn't what's convincing people.
It's the eyewitness accounts that do it.
Having this video as well kind of lends some credence to those eyewitness accounts.
It says like, we saw an object and here's a video of an object.
It doesn't really look like the same object, but it's extra evidence that something was there.
And the more witnesses you have, the more likely something is to have actually happened.
So, Mick, can I just quickly say this video is not convincing to folks on its own.
And I think my job here today is to make it convincing and thank you for giving me the
opportunity because I think we have some compelling data to show.
Absolutely, yeah.
Well, the final other thing that I'll say about this case, which I find interesting,
is I think a new Raytheon FLIR system had just been installed before detection.
And Raytheon, I think, came out with a statement because they were like,
what's going on with our FLIR system?
This is kind of crazy.
And Raytheon was like, we're not responsible for what you detect with our system,
which I found very interesting as well.
Yeah, I think they just upgraded the system, upgraded the software perhaps.
OK, OK, software.
I mean, this wasn't known publicly, right?
Nobody knew about this until, I mean, 2007, people didn't know about it.
I think it was 2015 when Fravor started talking on fighter pilot podcasts and stuff.
And it really didn't bubble up until 1516.
The German server thing is fascinating.
Yeah, it's super bizarre because it was like a graphic design shop or something.
I think it was CGI or something like that.
When I hear that, my mind goes to they were trying to see if you could possibly recreate it.
Yeah, I think what happened there was that it was just basically a site where you could upload stuff,
like an open FTP server.
Back in the day, you would use that for uploading stuff.
And they just dropped it there.
Who dropped it there?
The person who leaked it.
So it was just a leak, but on a German, so it was like a place you would leak a video like that?
The US military doesn't have the original.
The one that they released is the same.
It's the one that they got from the German FTP server.
And then they released it.
That's fascinating.
Well, they just re-record over the tapes.
Can they now release the original?
They probably don't have it.
They don't have it.
I strongly doubt it.
There's a wrinkle there.
There are allegations from some of the sailors aboard the Princeton, I think,
that people in suits landed in helicopters and took all the radar data.
I don't know what to make of that.
Who says that?
Is it Voorhees?
Gary Voorhees.
Gary Voorhees?
I think he's mentioned that.
And there are a couple others that have said it.
Okay.
Sean K. Hiller.
I apologize.
I just don't know.
I know Fravor.
P.J. Hughes, I think.
P.J. Hughes.
Yeah.
They're into me both of them.
Fravor's been skeptical of that publicly.
I don't know what to make of that.
So just to the point of data retention, it has a spooky immaculate constellation level.
Yeah.
Because that's what the allegation of immaculate constellation is.
That all this stuff is siphoned off.
Yeah.
I don't know what to make of that.
That's another good example of how the stories vary quite a lot.
You've got all these enlisted men on the boat who have this story about how the Databricks
were stolen and then Fravor just didn't happen.
Exactly.
It's difficult to reconcile.
Correct.
Yeah.
But obviously maybe Fravor didn't know.
Who knows?
Very interesting.
Should we dive into the...
Yeah.
We can watch the video.
I think you guys both see this?
Yeah.
Cool.
We're familiar.
This is the start here.
So it's in infrared mode.
And let's explain.
So thermal imaging, what is this white dot in the middle mean?
Well, it's not actually a white dot.
It's actually kind of a spiky shape at the start, which is interesting.
It's a good valid point.
Then it switches to TV mode.
And TV mode means it's basically a video camera, black and white video camera.
And we see it's black here.
Now, I originally thought it was black.
It looks almost exactly like the Chilean case, but of course it's TV mode.
So this is actually what you would theoretically see with your own eyes.
Then it switches back to infrared.
You can see the object kind of moved around a little bit.
A little spin there.
Now, that's the camera doing a gimbal roll.
The camera has to readjust itself occasionally.
There's another little roll there.
Yeah.
Well, it's going to do some interesting stuff in a second.
That's kind of the one boring part, I guess.
OK.
So it looked there like it zoomed off screen.
And then this is the end thing where it appears to zoom off to the left-hand side.
So yeah, the symbology, we got like a whole bunch of stuff, numbers on the screen.
And then it switches back to TV mode.
And this is how we kind of get to do the analysis.
We have the angles.
We have the top of the screen.
We have the heading, the azimuth.
And then we've got the elevation, which is like six degrees here.
I can't remember.
You mean from right to left?
No, the elevation.
I think it's five up.
It's six up, and then five.
Yeah, it's six, then five.
Yeah, exactly.
So that gives us kind of a line of sight.
So we know that it's somewhere along this line of sight.
And this line of sight moves from right to left fairly levelly.
And so we can kind of correlate that with the other numbers on the screen,
which is the airspeed of the jet, which is expressed in calibrated airspeed.
You have to convert it to true airspeed.
And then the altitude.
We know the altitude of the plane from that.
So you can use all that to kind of set up a model of what we're looking at
and what's actually happening.
That's kind of like almost like the second part of the analysis.
The first part is actually, is it doing anything amazing?
And we saw at the end of the video, it kind of zooms off to the left of the screen.
And there's kind of two parts to that.
There's one where it kind of, well, first of all, it kind of drifts a little bit,
and then it seems to shoot off very rapidly.
And people initially thought that that was it accelerating very rapidly.
But it's actually just changing zoom levels kind of halfway through the movement.
If you kind of undo that zoom back from two times to one time,
it just basically smoothly goes off.
And the analysis I did on there using all the angles and everything
was that the drift that it moved off from left to right
was exactly the same as the drift that the camera was moving at.
So I think what we're actually looking at here is the camera was tracking something like this,
and then the camera lost lock, and the object just kept going at exactly the same speed.
So it gives the same effects of the object zooming off to the side,
but it isn't actually moving.
Mick, are you familiar with Yannick's analysis that it actually drifts off,
it moves off four times faster at the very end than it does during the other losses of lock?
Are you familiar with that?
No, I wouldn't be surprised because it's only a partial loss of lock.
In the other ones, it's still basically kind of tracking it.
I don't think when you see it losing lock, it's not really lost the lock at those points.
Can I just say, we're getting so in the weeds,
and I just want to say maybe for the audience that part of the reason that I'm doing this
is I want to engage more people.
I want more people mathematically, scientifically inclined folks to grapple with this stuff.
That's why I write these articles.
I'm trying to encourage interest, spur interest.
I 100% agree.
We should teach this in colleges because it's a fun analysis exercise that people can get their teeth into.
Sorry for that PSA, but I really just want to convey that.
That's probably the whole problem here between you and I is it's just you and me.
Right. Exactly.
And there's other people.
There's no reason why other people can't analyze these videos.
Exactly.
But it does take a long time, though.
It does.
It is quite a lot of work.
This is years of work that we've put into these videos.
On my side.
So I got to give them credit.
And they would say that the loss of lock just wouldn't account for that sort of zinniah.
It's ambiguous.
Chad Underwood, who's the whizzo, who filmed it, he said,
nope, there's no way the system would have lost it.
I've talked to an active duty whizzo serving now.
And he said, it's a finicky.
I sent you the emails, right?
You remember this?
And I made a point.
But the system can be finicky and can lose a lock.
So it's a wash.
I don't know what to make of that.
Is the FLIR auto-tracking or is there somebody operating that?
That is auto-tracking.
So yeah, that is correct.
It's a pixel, exactly.
Yeah, it's using basically the contrast between pixels.
It's just like image tracking in After Effects.
You just lock onto something and it follows it.
Got it.
It doesn't do a very good job.
It's kind of interesting comparing the technology in 2004 with the later things in Gimbal and GoFast,
which the lock seems a lot more solid.
What I like about this is I feel like both of you are being very reasonable.
And if anything, I'm more confused in a healthy way.
You know, really, I mean, in my mind, the assessment there might be like the net assessment,
quote unquote, would be like, you know, really interesting eyewitness accounts
and then kind of inconclusive on the video front.
We'll just wait until we get to the analysis.
OK, cool.
Yeah, yeah.
That heated discussion between Hal Puthoff and Eric Weinstein on remote viewing.
Yeah, you heard that right.
I still can't believe I experienced that firsthand.
And now I'm happy to share it with you all as our first exclusive video on WAP.
Head over to WAP.com slash American Alchemy Premium to become a premium member today.
By becoming a member, you'll gain access to weekly premium videos,
behind the scenes footage and monthly group calls where we discuss the ideas we love most.
Plus, you'll get early access to merchandise drops and be the first to know
about the upcoming conference we'll be holding later in 2025.
Our WAP community will serve as a private space where curious individuals
and tech enthusiasts can come together to challenge the status quo
and explore ideas shaping our future.
If you're passionate about exploring unconventional ideas
and want to dive even deeper into our content, I invite you to join our WAP today.
Head over to WAP.com slash American Alchemy Premium to become a premium member today.
Thank you so much and enjoy the rest of today's episode.
All right, should we move to GoFast?
Can we go to the slideshow real quick?
Oh, yeah, sure, sure.
I really want to show you what Road and Mick, you know, this is the video that you still have up
and I got a bone to pick with you, right?
This video is still up and it's clearly not an airline.
Let's describe what we're talking about for a second.
So Mick has several videos up looking at the FLIR 1 video and one of them,
he hypothesizes that it's a distant airliner.
I think you said on a podcast that it's probably 50 to 100 miles away.
Yeah, I think this video I made is like, do you remember when it was?
Like 2019 or something like that?
Yeah, I just think it's still up there and I think that's misinformation from my perspective.
I have added the description of the video.
You put one sentence on there, nobody's going to read that one sentence.
I think it's very misleading to have that video still up there.
If you said it's an airliner 100 miles away, that thing's at 66,000 feet.
That's impossible.
Originally I hadn't done this analysis, very much analysis.
It was pretty early on in the discussion thread.
And so I was saying like what it might look like.
And I picked a airliner because that's what I'm kind of used to from this Chilean case.
I was still kind of maybe biased by that Chilean case.
And I kind of did a little side-by-side comparison and they look somewhat similar.
You can kind of see they look somewhat similar, not the same.
Will you remove that video because it's clearly...
No, I think the basic analysis is right and I can maybe change the title of it.
The analysis isn't that this is what it is.
It's that a blurry shape can look like another blurry shape.
You clearly say in the video like, oh, it looks kind of like an airliner going off to the right.
It does kind of look like one, but it isn't.
Yeah, but it can't be.
So why wouldn't you...
Yeah.
The analysis of the video is still valid, but it kind of looks like that.
You know it's not.
Maybe you understand my point, right?
I think it's misleading.
I think it's misleading to keep it up.
I've added that to the description of the video.
Okay, let's move on.
So this is why it's so easy to rule out a plane.
Number one, there's no tail.
Boom, simple.
Number two, if you're looking five degrees up, right?
The perspective is if...
Mick's theory is that it's another plane.
He uses another F-18 in his example.
I'm trying to do this for the camera.
If you're looking five degrees up, the jet will have kind of like a downward slope like this.
Clearly, the object is tilted up this way, and there's no plane.
You can change the plane type.
There's no plane that'll fly like...
What do you have this distant plane going?
Like 250 knots?
300.
No plane is going to fly at like a 13, 15, 20 degree angle of attack at 300 knots.
It's just not reasonable.
There's no tail.
Ruling out a plane is the easiest thing we'll do all day today from my perspective.
Yeah, I think you can though.
I think the problem with this video is that it's a super low resolution video.
But the angle is really...
It's crystal clear.
It's not really.
You will talk later about how the angle of the sun is going to affect the way you're
looking at things, and we don't know exactly what we're looking at here.
We're looking at a dark shape.
Maybe some parts of that are being illuminated by the sun.
Or the tail.
Maybe that's a similar color to the sky.
Lots of planes have different...
No, no, no.
This works by contrast.
Contrast, right?
Contrast in the optical spectrum.
It has a white tail.
Planes cannot have white tails.
This is black against the sky.
You're saying that it's a white tic-tac shape, an actual tic-tac shape.
Yeah, absolutely it is.
And you're saying that it's got this funny weird shape.
Yeah, we addressed that.
Because of the lighting.
So it's not a plane, from my perspective.
It's easily...
If it could be a tic-tac shape that somehow morphed into this bizarre peanut shape because
of the sunlight and these little legs that are supposedly sticking out, then why couldn't
it be a different type of plane?
Perhaps not this FA-18.
There's a whole bunch of different types of planes.
What plane flies at this angle?
I don't think you're just flying at that angle.
So your eyes are just seeing me like it's really not at that angle?
No.
I think what we're looking at isn't representative of the actual shape of the object.
Great.
So anybody who can see...
Okay, it's pretty clear that it's tilted up.
Why wouldn't it be representative?
You mean it's pretty clear that it's tilted up?
You can see with your own eyes.
It's got a pointy bit at one end.
And we'll get to that.
So if it's tilted up, then it's got a pointy bit at one end, that means it's not really
a tic-tac shape, isn't it?
Well, that is an artifact that your software...
And this is why you make...
You've been so helpful.
I've shown you this.
You can recreate that effect with your software with a tic-tac.
You could probably recreate it with a different plane as well.
It's something I haven't done.
You're a big evidence guy.
Try.
Why can't you find me something with no tail?
I feel it's kind of a fool's errand because there is not enough evidence in that video
to determine...
Look at it.
It's this blurry blob.
The video is probably out of focus.
You see the attitude, the tilt.
And if you watch the whole video, you can see that tilt.
It's crystal clear.
You see it turning as well, which is something that goes kind of weird.
It doesn't really work, I think, with the tic-tac model in the simulator.
Do you want to just go to the next image?
Because this is super interesting, and I owe credit to, I think, somebody on...
I think his name was Paul, but he did very simple edits, brilliance and contrast.
And there's no trickery here.
It's very simple.
If you go to the next one, please.
We did a 3D model.
And this is kind of a Rorschach test, right?
The UAP is in the eye of the beholder.
And I need to quickly add that both Commander Fravor and Lieutenant Commander Dietrich have
stated that when they reviewed Underwood's tapes afterwards, they saw these little appendages,
these protrusions.
Which is impossible.
I mean, is it Lonnie Zamora?
That reminds me of a Lonnie Zamora craft, would he describe?
But we know he's completely out of focus, so you wouldn't be able to see this.
Lonnie Zamora is a famous craft that came down in 64 and in New Mexico.
Allegedly had little legs, but anyway.
Allegedly had little legs.
This image here, I think, is very misleading.
I think it's basically being that you've tweaked the amount of brightness to bring in the edges.
If you do that, you're just sliding the middle slider in the levels adjustment.
So we can find a tic-tac shape if you just do basic edits.
You can find the gimbal shape.
What basic edits are we doing?
Brilliance and contrast.
And what exactly?
So contrast, I think, is probably pretty obvious.
Increasing the contrast.
And then brilliance is...
I think he turned it up.
Again, I didn't do this.
Anybody can go, that's the beauty of this, and this is why anybody can do this.
The level slider would do that, I think.
Is brilliance like light saturation or what?
I'm not sure, actually.
I'm not an optical effects guy, so I didn't do this.
No, it's an un-standard term.
It's not like a Photoshop term.
So what I think is really interesting is, and we can really drill down to,
you see that little kind of that sunlit section on the top?
Yes.
That, in fact, we can place this object and we can actually find which direction under what is flying,
and we can see where the sun was at around 330, 320-ish, give or take,
and you can recreate that in a 3D.
This is the first time I'm really presenting this.
We're very excited.
We're going to put this in a paper very soon.
But you can actually recreate that effect and see where the sun is.
And in 3D, you can move the sun around and it gives you that effect.
Interestingly enough...
And that lines up with his position in reality.
Correct.
So let's go to the next one.
Mick, you brought up, oh, it's black.
Well, this is TV mode.
Those F-18s are not black.
They're light gray, right?
That's how the system works.
It's back in the silhouette.
Yeah, so that's why we have a black shape.
It's something you can't say that is the same because it's the same color.
It doesn't mean it's a different color either.
We don't know what color it is.
But you've moved off the plane thesis.
You don't think that?
I don't think we can rule it out.
But you have to provide...
Just give us one option.
Just propose one plane that would fly like this.
Well, why don't you propose one type of UFO that could fly like this?
Right there.
A Tic Tac.
A UFO is just unidentified by nature.
But what about a model of a Tic Tac UFO?
It's a sport model, obviously.
That's impossible for him to answer.
A plane that could flip that profile silhouette with the lysing.
We just don't know...
I have a couple more.
Do you mind?
Sure.
Yeah, sorry.
Run through this.
So you talked about that peanut.
Yeah, so this is...
I used Mix.
This is Mix.
Oh, weird.
Well, just do you know what's going to be?
Just say it.
We'll put it in post-production.
Yeah, so when you actually edit the video to kind of recreate the graininess and the
out-of-focus, you can recreate the Tic Tac shape.
You can recreate it.
I mean, it's not a plane, guys.
It's extraordinary to find a match, like a remarkable match with what eight eyeballs saw
two hours earlier, you can recreate that.
With Mix software.
With my software, yeah.
I wish I did.
No, thank you.
And I did that for you, Merrick.
But isn't that compelling that maybe this is just sensory data, that is?
There's a couple points.
I'll say one thing.
Thank you, Mick.
We owe the U of Hope World owes you a huge debt of gratitude for the amount of work that
you put into it.
I'm glad you're finally getting paid.
I don't know who's paying you, but...
Wait, what is...
Are you going to pay by who?
Someone I can't name.
Okay.
This is incredible.
And it allows us to test out everybody's theories, not yours, not ours, not anybody's.
And so thank you for that.
Just real quick.
The reason this software exists is actually because of you.
I appreciate it.
And we are...
So what are the odds?
It's not just this.
The original gimbal simulator, which is the granddaddy of this, was because Merrick was
getting so annoying with this consistent criticism that I had to finally make a good video and
I had to write all this software to do it.
And then I wrote this nice long video and...
But Mick, you always say like, oh God, you know, these eyewitness accounts are always
so incredible, but there's never any data to back them up.
Here's a Tic Tac with little legs, which is exactly what Fravor and D-Trick were called.
The amount of blur that you had to add there to make them match would mean that they wouldn't
be able to see that as well.
All I'm asking is give me any plane.
SR-71.
Any plane.
YouTube.
I don't care.
Well, how can I make...
I'm mad.
It's a mad.
You made it blurry.
So...
Well, I guess, Mick, what would you say to the fact that you can use some slight edits
with a program that you built that allows you to...
This is just to recreate one frame.
I think what would be interesting...
No, it's a video.
Oh, okay.
Fair enough.
Yeah.
The actual object itself appears to do this kind of weird rotation and get a bit more
pointy at one end, which I kind of interpreted as being like a plane turning, but...
The pointiness is recreated.
It's an artifact of that front appendage.
I've sent you the video.
But we don't have the rotation, the matches.
And your highest percentage likelihood thing is plane still, even though there's some issues.
I don't know.
Like, you know, Marik brings up some good points in Yannick.
So, you know, I think what I would say is you can't 100% rule out a plane.
I feel comfortable doing it.
There's no tail.
And it matches with...
100% ruling out things is a huge mistake that people have historically made.
I think of the Chilean case.
They spent two years ruling things out.
And they were wrong because they ruled out a plane right at the start.
And then there's this...
There's no tail.
You can't see a tail.
Of course you can.
What about the...
Remember the video that Jesse sent us a few days ago of the tic-tac?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
And you said that you agree with me that it was a plane.
Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry.
It has no wings.
And that's a very common thing that people see, like in videos.
So what was that?
It would have been another plane.
I'm sure it was another plane, yeah.
Go to the next slide real quick.
So this is how we were able to place it.
There's a consistent rightward banking.
You can kind of see it here.
And that's how...
There's a strong...
And thank goodness Yannick is a climate scientist.
Sorry, buddy.
I hope I didn't out you.
But he has access to extremely nuanced weather data.
And we can find out, if you go to the next slide there,
we can look at the weather data from that time at that altitude.
And there's an extremely strong northerly wind coming from the north,
about 100, 110 knots.
And in the video, you see this kind of this consistent rightward banking,
which is the autopilot compensating to maintain a straight heading as it goes.
And that allows us to place the heading of that plane and see,
okay, well, now we know where the sun is,
and then we can match the sun with the top of that illuminated section.
The issue with that is that planes don't need to bank to maintain a heading.
Is that true?
Yes.
Okay.
And then we discussed this.
So you said that you thought that they did, but...
So yeah.
You sent me a bunch of chat DQT things.
You're talking about crabbing, right?
No.
No?
Well, I'm talking about the dinner screen, like the true heading,
the ground heading, and the air heading.
Right.
So to maintain a particular ground heading,
you just need to have an air heading that incorporates the wind vector.
So the autopilot, you can see at the bottom, it says HDG.
That's heading.
So that means the nose is going to maintain a heading.
Yes.
Ground track is irrelevant.
It's the same thing.
Ground track's irrelevant.
It only would need to bank if the wind was changing.
No, it needs to stay.
The nose is going to stay at, let's say, 270, right?
Doesn't matter.
So how's it maintaining...
You point it in the direction you want to go,
and you go in that direction.
Or you point the velocity of your plane in the direction you want to go,
which might involve you turning a bit to the side,
but you don't need to bank to do that.
If you bank, you'll keep turning.
But it's consistent, right? It does this.
No, it's just wobbling a little bit.
That was greatly magnified.
That was the thing I sent you years ago.
And it goes in both directions.
It goes a little bit more to one side.
It does go, actually, to the other side a little bit.
It doesn't.
You're fundamentally wrong with the idea that you need to bank
to turn to the side.
It's 100-knot winds coming in.
It doesn't matter. It's completely irrelevant.
It could be 1,000-knot winds.
So if the wind is pushing the aircraft...
Planes fly relative to the air.
That altitude of the air is basically just a constant, homogenous mass,
and there's no real turbulence to speak of in terms of differentials
between the wind directions.
So if the wind is moving like this
and you want to be flying in that direction,
you'll just have to turn a little bit into the wind.
That's called crabbing.
No, that's called changing the heading of your plane.
Crabbing is something where you actually slide the plane a little bit.
You're using rudder, exactly.
We're not talking about that.
No, we're not talking about that.
Your velocity relative to the air is just straight through the air.
Okay, let's move on.
We're going to get in the weeds.
We can cut that out or whatever.
No, leave it in.
But would a plane need to bank in this scenario?
There's a consistent rightward banking,
which our hypothesis is because of the 110-knot winds.
So real quick, last point on this.
You might just go on up one more.
Sure.
Sorry, just one higher.
Sorry, the other way.
Last but not least, we can actually
so Kevin Day said that these objects were at 28,000 feet.
I'd be curious to see if he has said other,
but everything that I've seen is he's said that 28,000 feet heading south at 100 knots,
we can find that in the data.
We can find the Chad Underwood object moving south at 100 knots at 28,000 feet,
descending slowly, but we can find that as a very, very anomalous flight path.
So again, we can find very, very specific descriptions
of what the witnesses recall in the data.
That is critical, and we see that with Gimbal as well.
Do you not find that compelling?
You can find all kinds of things in the data,
depending on what parameters you put into it.
And this is at the distance roughly that Underwood gave.
That's important, right?
You can find basically a straight-line path as well of the object moving away,
consistent with it being a plane or some similar type of aircraft.
And if you change things around, change the way the wind direction is,
then you can find different things.
If you change the distance, you can find different things again.
I don't think this is the only solution here.
No, but it is remarkable to find that in the data.
It doesn't happen by accident.
That of course suggests that what we're looking at is actually a balloon.
That is absolutely a possibility, yes.
And a balloon would explain the radar targets possibly,
because they're moving with the wind.
We have this wind, as you described earlier, moving from north to south.
I think balloon is a far more reasonable explanation than plane.
I wouldn't rule it out.
I think, like I said before, my analysis of these videos is kind of two parts.
Is it doing anything amazing?
And what is it?
And I don't think it's doing anything amazing.
I don't think drifting south at 100 knots is doing something amazing.
It is very weird. At 20, what, 20,000 feet?
What do you know that does that, that is that size?
A balloon?
That's that size?
Why would a balloon be that far off the coast?
I don't know. It could be some kind of military balloon.
Then you're going to have to...
This is 20 years ago now, literally.
What kind of proposal?
You can throw spaghetti right against the wall.
This is a debunking playbook.
But provide some options. What could it be?
I think we should move on.
Let's do it.
This is great. I love it. This is awesome.
I think there are a lot of open questions we just presented that the audience should go out and investigate.
Please, by all means.
I don't rule out these options, but I don't think you should also ride a plane.
Let's get into the GoFast video, which was recorded in January of 2015, 300 miles off the coast of Jacksonville, the USS Roosevelt.
Merrick, you set up the last one.
Why don't you set up this one, Mick?
This is a fun one.
This appears to be something that's moving very fast over the surface of the water.
It's similar to the FLIR 1 video in that it's thermal footage.
This is all thermal. There's no TV mode.
I think they do switch between black hot and white hot, but what we're looking at here is the surface of the ocean.
We see this object, and the object appears to be colder than the surface of the ocean, which is very unusual for a powered craft.
We have a variety of numbers on the screen.
We have the angle down, minus 23 at that point, is it?
29, again, I need my glasses.
And then we have the heading, which is off the top of the screen.
We actually do have that.
And then we have a range value.
Now, unlike in the FLIR 1 video, when they lock onto this object, they actually do get a range number.
There's some dispute as to actually where that number comes from, like how far away is this object?
We don't know if it came from a radar hit or if it was some other way of doing it.
So we're not entirely sure how accurate it is.
But if you assume that that number there is relatively accurate, you can do a reconstruction of this object.
And it turns out to be going a lot slower than initial estimates.
Like initial estimates predict, I think, somewhere in our 600 knots.
Max six point something or other.
And it turns out to be going much, much slower.
So definitely under 100 knots.
Some disputers are exactly how fast it's going.
I've done some reconstructions where it's about 60 knots.
Yannick just pointed out one where he's done where it's more like 90 knots.
And he said that's also consistent with the wind speed.
So my hypothesis about this one is that it's probably just a wind blown object like a balloon.
If we do some analysis as to the size of the object, we can determine it's not particularly big.
It's about three to six feet in diameter.
So something just like a weather balloon seems like a reasonable explanation for me, especially as it doesn't really do anything amazing.
And this one's really interesting because Arrow just came to the All Domain Anomalous Resolution Office.
We're talking about its director.
It came out and they said that this is possibly parallax.
And so they're saying that there are probably certain things in the sky that we can't classify.
But they are kind of coming out against this video in particular.
This video is also interesting because you have audio associated with the video.
And the guy goes, whoa, got it.
We just interviewed Navy fighter pilot Ryan Graves.
He testified before Congress, also under oath.
And he kind of admitted it was a buddy of his who he thinks is kind of beyond the approach.
They're very close friends. I mean, they're super close.
Close friends. So yeah, what's your response to Mick here?
I think we would  I'm very confident that we would not had Arrow come out with this assessment at the recent hearing if they had actually talked to the air crew.
And I have a major bone to pick with Arrow. They didn't talk to the air crew about this.
Why wouldn't they talk to the air crew?
I don't know. And it fits in with the blue book, the debunking playbook of never talk to witnesses.
Just throw something out there.
I don't know if this is part of the old guard, the previous director who I think has rubbed a lot of people the wrong way.
Rubbed me. I had a long discussion with him. Rubbed me the wrong way.
So I think that's a massive oversight.
It is an analytic failure for them not to talk to the air crew because clearly those guys were excited by something.
There's a reason  you don't just lock up some little random object in the middle of 300 miles off the coast of Jacksonville, Florida.
Oh, by the way, this is 10 minutes before the gimbal video.
Oh, by the way, this is amid daily observations or sensor observations of spherical objects off the East Coast that are,
as Ryan told you and has been very public about, were A, a safety of flight concern and B,
were operating in very anomalous ways per their systems.
They're locking them up on FLIR on their training, their infrared training missiles on their radar.
You have multiple three, four sensors. Their eyeballs are seeing them sometimes, occasionally.
So it is a massive analytic oversight.
I have a major bone to pick with Aero about that because Ryan just came out on your show
and in your discussion said that this was part of  and I think you said it previously,
but shocker, this was part of  this was one of four objects that were in a line of breast formation, right?
So they're kind of like cruising along next to each other.
That's not  weather balloons don't do that, obviously.
So I don't think we would be having a very different discussion if Aero had actually done their job.
And this is  it's right above the surface of the water, right?
No, no. I actually  I think
It is or it's not?
No, it's not.
So the aircrew did not name this GOFAST. I don't know who named it.
So I think Ryan has said  Lieutenant Graves has said all the Pentagon did is debunk the name,
which the Pentagon  I think the Pentagon itself gave the video.
So I  look, there's a  I want to just be very clear.
There's a reason  you don't just  this is like a tiny needle in a haystack.
You don't just find something just slurring  slewing your targeting pod around to the ocean.
They had a  there was a radar hit that gave them some kind of an indication that there's something there.
And by the sounds of their voice, what they were seeing visually did not match up with the radar, the data they were getting.
That's really a reach, I think, trying to
Look at it fly. What's it doing, right? Whatever they said. They're very surprised by it.
I think they were surprised that they caught it on their  they're at FLIRT.
What's it look at it fly is the actual word.
Yeah, well, it looks like it's going very fast.
Well, I don't think they're stumped by parallax. They might have been, but the bottom line is
You'd be surprised. I mean, the pilots are stumped by parallax all the time.
Bottom line is  okay.
Can you describe what parallax is to the audience?
Yeah, parallax is just when your viewpoint changes, things that are closer to you appear to move faster.
So if you're looking at the wall over there and you're looking at my thumb and you move your head, my thumb appears to move that way.
And you think that multiple eyewitnesses saw parallax, even though the gimbal video was recorded like minutes after this?
No, the GoFast thing isn't multiple eyewitnesses seeing things.
It's these people, these two guys in a plane, seeing this thing probably just on their screens.
And so all they're seeing is this display.
The field of view here is about  it's less than one degree.
It's tiny.
Which is a really, really powerful zoom lens. It's like the biggest zoom lens you could get.
It's equivalent, I think, of over 2,000 millimeters SLR.
And this is in an F18 Super?
Correct. Correct. Yeah, two seater.
Yeah, I just mean eyewitnesses. They're actively looking. It's not on a screen like the Nimitz thing.
That's what I mean, not eyewitnesses in that they're seeing the object.
People did look at the video afterwards.
Ryan Graves said he was distracted looking at the gimbal video.
At least I'm sure he must have seen this one as well.
It's really interesting that we have all these witnesses coming forward now.
It's a shame that they didn't come forward years ago because this is new information.
Absolutely. And we might be hearing more from, as Ryan said on your show  and sorry, Ryan, if you're watching.
I think he's annoyed at me because he paid me.
When's your buddy coming out? When are they going to come out and talk?
I would love that. More information is great for everyone.
Absolutely, because it's the same guy who recorded the gimbal video, which is the poster child of this whole
Well, that guy needs to come out. I'll do an interview with you.
Guy wherever you are. But again, I cannot stress enough. I'd love to hear him expound or kind of expand, rather, on the formation.
I mean, your point here is that you don't think he's doing anything amazing in this video, but you think there's something amazing about the situation.
If it's flying in formation, absolutely, absolutely.
When this video doesn't show that.
Well, we've got this kind of second-hand 10 years later, a years later thing from Ryan.
Can I just say one thing, to your point? Yes, he might actually be doing something. Yannick, put this in all caps.
Assuming the range is exact, the best visual match  and this is a scientist, folks. Not me.
The best visual match in mixed simulation has the object around 100 knots. Not 60 knots, as Mick claims. End quote.
Yes. That's assuming it's accurate, which is, as we discussed earlier, it's a very dubious thing.
And was it not moving against the wind, or was that just the gamble?
Plus the gamble.
Well, we don't know that. Because if the aviator who recorded it comes out and says, oh, yeah, we were freaked out because it was moving against the wind.
Well, that would be great, but that hasn't happened yet.
I'm just saying that's why we really need to hear from him. But I really want to hear about the formation.
And if there's any way he remembers what direction, maybe that's why they're so surprised.
Wow, that tiny thing is moving against the wind. We don't know. Bottom line is Aero dropped the ball, in my opinion.
Yeah, well, we need more. We need these guys to come out. And they need at least a behind-the-scenes interview.
I'm going to put on my ex-government hat here. Aero kind of put themselves in a really tough spot, because they came out and did this.
Now you're going to have an aircrew come out and contradict you. That's a terrible position for a government agency to be in, potentially.
Well, he already did, right? I mean, through Ryan.
Where do they contradict him? I mean, all they said was that it appears to be going slow.
I'll tell you exactly why. Because it says the Aero conclusion, it does no anomalous maneuver.
All right.
It doesn't do any anomalous maneuvers in this video.
If it's holding formation, that is anomalous maneuver.
Well, no. Four objects blowing in the wind will stay in the same formation for 300 miles off the coast?
Well, then they're in formation at that point.
Balloons are going to stay in a perfect, or we don't know if it's perfect.
We don't know exactly what the formation was. Or was it a perfect straight line?
We've got to hear more, bottom line.
I agree.
Track him down, Jesse.
I'll do my best.
Yeah, I'm going to have Ryan right after this and say we should do something.
And again, the context is so critical. Ten minutes before Gimbal, ten minutes before the most anomalous, or at least strange video that a lot of people have seen.
Was that very kind, the time that it was before?
Yeah, you can see the timestamp on the bottom.
That kind of wraps around, I think. It doesn't show the hour.
I'm pretty confident it was right before.
So it could be an hour.
Yeah, it doesn't really matter that much, but I'm just wondering if there was some verbal confirmation from a witness.
Should we watch it? Anything else on GoFast before we go to Gimbal?
No, I don't think there's much there that we discussed.
Okay. Yeah, we can play it in post.
Guys, Arrow, your job is to investigate UFO videos and data, and this is one of three of the most recognizable videos. How do you not talk to the aircrew?
Arrow should release their analysis.
Do you agree that it's kind of egregious that Arrow did not interview the aircrew?
I don't see why they wouldn't have done. It's a data point.
I mean, they even got the year wrong in the slide. It said January 16.
That's weird.
I mean, I have a major bone to pick with the analytics side of Arrow, because we all know that they have really done a poor job on a lot of their reports, so I don't need to belabor that.
I'm optimistic that the new director will change things around.
I think you and I both know that Arrow have said some things that are incorrect.
Kirk Patrick, basically, it was astounding, and I don't need to get into it.
He's said various things in public as well, which didn't really tie with reality.
Yeah, that's a very diplomatic way of putting it.
At the NASA hearing, he said some speckles on the screen were stars, but they were obviously not stars.
Weird.
I think he phoned it in. I think he was close to retirement. I don't know.
I think he's more there as a person who's standing on the organization rather than being an analyst himself, so he wasn't that familiar with everything.
And to his credit, he did stand up, so I'm grateful for the first time that he talked to me.
And they solved a lot of cases.
Do you guys ever wonder if any of these things are sort of Rorschach tests or initiation paths for your analytical rigor abilities or whatever?
And so some of these videos are halfway truths, and it's like our job to somehow solve it, and then you solve it.
You get in the program or something.
I hope not, because the taxpayers need to get their money back. This is pretty awful.
It's a waste of time in a nuclear multipolar world that's heating up.
It's kind of a, why are you playing puzzle games with the American people?
Yeah, exactly. Right.
Well, they're doing it because of that legislation.
Well, I do want to say it's interesting that just on the TikTok video, so my buddy Chris Ramsey, amazing magician, has a channel called Area52.
But he's actually kind of good when it comes to this stuff, because Area52 is around the UFO thing.
He actually believes in a lot of the UFO stuff. As a magician, he debunks other magicians.
Yeah, that's great.
So he's kind of like a good person to throw at this whole topic.
He was flying a commercial flight over Nellis testing range, and he saw that TikTok that I showed you guys.
You both said probably prosaically explained. I'll play the video.
But why prosaically explained?
Because it is interesting in the context of de-fraversing a TikTok, too.
It's a super common sighting before they would describe them as being cigar shaped.
And what it is, it's just planes.
The fuselage of the plane is eliminated by the sun.
But the wings are either a different color, if you're looking from above, like the gray wings, you're seeing the plane of the gray wings,
or they're not being eliminated by the sun because the sun's above them and you're below them.
So you will see basically just the fuselage of the plane, the bright white thing.
And at that distance, you just can't make out the wings.
And when you take a video of it, it doesn't show up on the video.
And we've seen this numerous times with tracks I've seen myself flying down to LA once.
And you can just get the location and find which of the planes were in the area
and just drop it in to Sitrec by my software and you can see what it actually was.
Gotcha. Well, yeah, no, that's good to hear.
I mean, the way in which that didn't comport at all with the Fravor eyewitness account is it wasn't going right next to the water, shooting off,
exhibiting all these anomalous flight characters just sort of floating.
We never see these amazing maneuvers unambiguously on video.
Either it's this fuzzy dot in the distance.
You certainly do in Gimbal. You see it very anomalous and it's fantastic.
Well, it's dissipatable.
And then how put off, rebuttal to what you just said, Mick, is especially when it comes to optical sensors like just cameras,
you get these kind of blue shift, red shift effects where you're stretching light.
If you're kind of moving away or kind of crunching it, if you're moving close, you get these kind of ultraviolet.
It doesn't make any sense, though.
It's an excuse for why we can't get these things on video.
But people see these things and they have these eyewitness accounts of them.
It's not like your eyes are somehow physically different to a camera.
They're little photoreceptors in the back and there's a lens in the front and it works basically exactly the same way.
It's just a chemical, electrochemical reaction rather than a sensor array.
I mean, that's somewhat of a biochemical reductionist view of the way we see things.
Do you think that consciousness is important?
Well, the way we see things is extraordinarily consistent with the way cameras see things.
If you take your camera and take a picture of this, you're going to see pretty much the same thing.
It's not like we're magically conjuring up things in this room in our brains.
There's a physical reality that we can see and the same physical reality as what camera state pictures are.
And so if UFOs exist in physical reality and we can see them, then we can also take pictures of them.
Yeah, I think that's fair.
I think you'd have to get into kind of trippy philosophical discussions around, you know,
widening the doors of perception or can kind of glitch into like other realities and we don't need to go there.
Basically magic at that point.
Oh, magic or a different theory of mind, which you could get into.
I mean, that a lot of pretty well-respected philosophers and people like Aldous Huxley, William James,
and there's even modern neuroscientists would possibly agree with.
You have Donald Hoffman talking about the brain as sort of an interface.
But anyways, we don't need to get into that.
So let's get into that.
Can I say one more quick thing on GoFast?
Because it does appear spherical, right?
Like if it's a balloon.
It's very hard to say.
It's about six pixels across.
And I already mentioned this.
This is amid daily encounters.
But the sphere is that one morphology, that shape that keeps propping up just over and over in the historical record,
starting with 80 years ago with the Foo Fighters and you have metallic, I'm going to quote, right?
There's a whole bunch of stories.
In 1944, Newsweek ran the silver sphere puzzle on Christmas Day in 1944.
Associated Press, balls of silver seen over the German Reich, intrigue science, right?
So there is a consistency.
If you read Captain Ed Ruppelt, he's the first director of Blue Book, his book,
The Report on Unidentified Flying Objects in 1956 is a remarkable read, and that is just, it is staggering.
And that really got me down the rabbit hole.
He mentions just over and over these sightings of these metallic spheres,
silver spheres, metallic spheres, flying in formation, V-shaped formations.
We'll see that in Gimbal.
We'll talk about that.
It's a shame we don't have more photos of metallic spheres.
It is extremely interesting.
Eisenhower was aware of the Foo Fighters issue from 42 to 45.
You had around or possibly over 200 fighter pilot witnesses when it came to allied fighter pilots seeing these things.
You had some that were kind of prominent.
Ted Stevens, who later became a senator in Alaska and co-sponsored UFO research with Harry Reid through OSAP,
saw a Foo Fighter.
OSAP is why we're having this whole discussion.
There's a chain.
You can draw a direct link.
OSAP to ATIP to Lou Lozano to New York Times.
That's why we're having this conversation.
So it's fascinating.
I'll quickly wrap up.
Kirk Patrick, former director of Aero, said, quote,
we're seeing metallic orbs, direct quote, making very interesting apparent maneuvers all over the world.
That's interesting.
Nobody in the NASA panel, by the way, raised their hand when he said that.
These are scientists.
Why didn't every hand go up?
Excuse me.
Did you clarify a little bit?
Right.
Nobody asked a question.
The chair of the panel was texting on his phone as he was saying that.
It's pretty astounding.
Top gun pilot Jack Stewart came out a couple maybe a year ago.
I think Ryan mentioned this on your discussion.
But he's flying along and notices something whizzed by his canopy.
He kind of thought it was a balloon.
OK.
His wingman saw it, right?
He's flying, I guess, somewhere in a position to see his tail.
And he said, yeah, dude, that thing turned around and followed you.
It goes on.
Donald Trump has said, I've had Air Force pilots, very good guy, better than Tom Cruise,
come out and say, we've had spherical objects, circular objects out fly our F-22s.
That's one of the most advanced aircraft in our arsenal.
This consistency in the Korean War, you see this reporting in these old documents.
There are good reasons for this consistency.
How do you explain that?
I think there's two reasons why you would see spheres a lot.
One is that there's balloons out there.
And the other one is that a lot of people are just seeing very small things that are far away.
And they interpret that as a point of light as a sphere because they're asked what shape it is.
That's one of the kind of almost like a mistake that people make in UFO reporting is that they ask what the shape is
and they give them a list of things to do and they don't say, you know, it's a tiny dot that we couldn't say.
But the balloon thing is interesting.
Like you mentioned the German things.
Weather balloons get a bad rap.
But Germany at that time was actually using metallic silver balloons as sighting balloons,
which was an old fashioned way of determining the wind speed at altitude.
You would release a balloon some distance away and then you'd use a theodolite to measure the angle.
But the Foo Fighters were not really described as looking like balloons.
They would follow vapor trails that seem to lock on to flight or fight paths.
So it's a really interesting government report that I think is the earliest known assessment.
I think it was a 48 and I credit to John Greenwell for putting it on his site.
And I think his project signed one of their first reports.
I think it was late 48.
But it said that the most commonly reported shapes or morphologies are silver disks and spheres and balls of fire.
And then they go on to hypothesize that the balls of fire are viewed at night and the metallic spheres,
which again, there's that through line all the way through, are viewed during the daytime.
Did they all disappear when cameras were invented?
Kirk Patton.
There's the Middle East Orb as a metallic sphere.
The Navy Slime video is a metallic sphere.
Go fast, arguably, is a sphere.
In the public domain, like America is a big country and there's like a billion cameras in America.
We don't really have any good videos of these metallic spheres.
I don't disagree.
Oh, actually, that's not true.
There's a tap.
That's not true.
That's absolutely not true.
The Manchester one?
Sorry?
You're thinking the Manchester one?
No, no, LAX.
Let's keep going.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We can go on and on.
Okay.
So let's go Gimbal.
Gimbal.
Do you think there's anything, there's probably enough unique to say here that we should hit this because we are a little pressed for time?
Yeah, I think we can tap up here.
Absolutely.
No, but I want to get into contemporary stuff too, but do you think this is definitely worth touching on Gimbal?
100%.
Absolutely.
I think this might be the most compelling.
So should I set it up real quick?
Yeah, yeah.
So very, very quickly, this is Ryan Graves Squadron.
I think it's VFA 11, the Red Rippers.
They had just done a fairly complex air-to-air training mission.
They're just like the Tic Tac incident.
They are, I believe this is a pre-deployment workup cycle, so they're doing their training before they ship out to the Middle East.
And they had done a pretty complex air-to-air mission off of Florida, so the carrier is out there.
They're heading back to the ship, and one of Ryan's buddies, the WIZO, the backseater that we were talking about.
The WIZO is Weapons Systems Officer.
Weapons Systems Officer, thank you, the backseater.
They're circling the land, so they all come down at once.
They kind of, they hang out, so they clear the airspace.
And they got hit on their radar and to this object, and they went to go investigate.
And the video kind of picks up as they're kind of trying to sneak in behind it on what they call a stern conversion.
And yeah, the video captures some very interesting maneuvers.
And this is, yeah, so that's why it's called the gimbal, right?
You see it sort of rotating in this interesting way.
Well, look, who named GoFast?
Clearly, the name wasn't correct, right?
The aircrew didn't name it.
Somebody at the Pentagon named it.
So is the name gimbal correct or not?
Because it could be correct because they're calling it that because it's tilting,
or it could be correct because it's the gimbal motion of the camera which is causing the rotation.
I love one of your first thoughts was that it was a training video.
People have told me it was a training video.
Who told you that?
I don't remember now, but I asked Susan Go, and she told me it wasn't a training video.
Who said the last?
Susan Goff.
Oh, Susan Goff.
But didn't Susan Goff like run PsiOp for the DOT or something when it came to rallying support for the Afghani war?
I'm just telling you what she told me.
Don't take that prima facie.
She wrote an academic paper on psychological operation.
So that's why there is suspicion of her.
But then she seems to be kind of tight with Kirkpatrick, or at least in the context of one conference.
I met Kirkpatrick in person, and I was there at that incident, and she was attached at his hip, would not leave.
So that's interesting.
This is the former director of Aero, this office we keep bringing up, the kind of authoritative all-domain anomalous research office.
And you have its former director, Kirkpatrick, speaking at some event, and then Susan Goff is just kind of like trailing him.
Correct.
So this is like November 2023, I think at George Mason University.
So I was there.
I just happened to be in D.C. for other business.
And I went and had a chat with Kirkpatrick afterwards, and Susan was right there.
And that continues if you saw the current director, John Kozlowski, just testified.
And Susan Goff's in the background.
Right in the background.
And so you could probably find millions of Reddit threads that she's the handler.
I mean, there must be a reason why she's there.
So the simplest reason is that she's there so that he doesn't say things that he's not supposed to say.
Not because there's something hidden.
I would like him to say things that he's not supposed to say.
Well, yeah, everybody would.
It's just like the lawyers you see behind people.
They never whispered to her and asked her whether she should say anything, but then she would leap in and stop him if he says something bad.
A lot of senior government we talked about that, like, that is unique.
That is unique.
It does seem a little strange, also, that I would like to hear what the explanation is.
But she said that the Gimbal video is not a training video.
Yeah.
A couple of years ago.
Did she say anything else?
Did she say, I think this video is real?
No, she gives these boilerplate answers for a lot of stuff.
Gun-based.
It's a bit frustrating.
Okay.
This is like, say a lot without saying anything.
It's like ten questions and seven of them come back as, like, we don't discuss that.
In more words.
Gotcha.
It's a little frustrating.
How were you able to get in touch with her?
Just e-mailed her.
Wow.
All right.
She doesn't answer my emails.
Yeah.
I was going to say, I doubt she would answer mine as well.
Okay.
So, yeah, so I guess it's probably, you know, you set this up, right?
So do you have anything to say on the Gimbal?
On Gimbal?
Yeah.
Yeah, Gimbal.
I think, again, we've got two aspects of it.
Is it demonstrating something anomalous and what is it?
And with the anomalous thing that people claim in this video is that it's a saucer-shaped
craft, like a flying saucer, that kind of tilts up on its side, which is aerodynamically
impossible.
It would kind of fall out of the sky if it did that.
And that proves that it's some kind of, you know, advanced technology for possibly aliens.
But the analysis I've done suggests that it might actually be a camera artifact rather
than the actual shape of the object.
So what we're seeing here is a saucer shape.
It could be just the glare.
I know Merrick doesn't like the word glare.
The experts don't like it.
They don't know what I'm talking about when I say it.
Nobody knows what that is.
The problem with that is that we don't actually have in optics the terminology for things
like glare and lens flare often overlaps.
It's called blooming.
It's a well-known artifact.
Sensor bloom is something that people sometimes call glare as well, but we don't know what's
actually going on.
But basically, there's an optical effect here.
And there's a number of indications in the video.
You can see, for example, there are bands of light and dark in the background that rotate
with the object itself when it's rotating, which kind of suggests that it's the camera
that's doing the rotating rather than the object itself.
There's things that look like little diffraction spikes on the top and bottom, left and right,
and even a little bit hint of the 45 degrees on this object, which make it look like it's
some kind of optical effect.
There's instances where the turn rate of the object kind of seems to deviate from the turn
rate of the horizon.
And then perhaps the biggest thing is that the amount that it rotates and the speed and
the time is all exactly the same amount that would be required for the camera to have to
rotate to traverse the forward-looking direction.
Because these cameras, here's going to talk a little bit, it's not mounted like the cameras
you see under helicopters or even like a drone where the camera's like this and it can rotate
around like this.
It doesn't have the ability to rotate around.
So it has to rotate using a kind of a roll plus a tilt, which means the camera rotates.
And then that makes the picture rotate.
So it has to derotate that afterwards inside the camera using a device or using some kind of
software to rotate the image.
And that rotates the image back the right way.
So nothing appears to rotate, but this optical effect within it, because it's tied to the
camera, the optical effect rotates.
There's like a glare that rotates.
Like if you look at, say, this light over here, you can kind of see like around the light,
there's kind of a shade, little spikes and things.
If you turn your head, a better thing if you look at that light, squint a bit like that,
squint with your eyes and then kind of rotate your head left and right, you'll see the rays
that come from it are kind of rotating around.
And that's what's happening, I think, in this video.
There's an optical effect similar to what you saw there.
I've got spots in my eyes now.
And the rotation plus the derotation creates this illusion.
So it's like a camera turning plus lack of focus or something.
Yeah, the lack of focus actually might be something that's actually going on there as well,
which the focus is something that actually changes the shape of these optical effects.
And Mary doesn't like glare, so I'm going to call it an optical effect.
I think there's enough evidence in there that that's actually happening.
Beyond that, we don't actually know for sure what we're looking at.
And my hypothesis is that it's a distant jet.
And the reason I think that is that if you do this analysis with the lines of sight,
you can find a path in the distance that's more or less a straight line.
It's kind of like a slight S-turn about that.
And if you come closer, you get these kind of weird kind of like J-hooks
that have been described by Ryan Graves, I think.
And there's some debate as to whether this straight line of a possible jet engine
powered aircraft or this J-hook powered by some kind of weird anti-gravity thing
is the more plausible of the two explanations.
And a lot of people, you know, UFO fans, would go with this one
because it matches the verbal description and the distance that was given.
I think it started out, they originally said like 8 to 10 miles and changed to 6 to 8.
I think 6 to 8 is the current estimate of the distance, 6 to 8 nautical miles.
And if you do the analysis there, you do get this kind of J-hook,
which does somewhat resemble the verbal description of the pilots or Ryan Graves specifically
when he describes what he saw on the radar page, the SR page.
So that's kind of the debate.
Super simple theory, thanks, Scott.
What do you say, Meric?
Ockham, I say Ockham.
So I put that you've seen this before, but it's quite simple.
On one side, what the aviator, what the aircrew say is a remarkable match with the data and the video.
On the other side, you have these cascading malfunctions in this anomaly,
this artifact that nobody's ever heard of.
And I've looped you in with, I think, several of the top experts in the world on this.
I've not heard of it when we've got videos of it.
Not this video, other videos.
There's zero evidence of what you're proposing.
No.
There's zero empirical evidence of what you're...
How do you have evidence of glare, like in Dave Falch's videos, for example?
That's all blooming.
So the point is, I'm on Team Ockham here, and I'm on all the data lines, the video, the rotation...
You say Ockham, you're referring to Ockham's Razor?
Sorry, yes.
So Ockham's Razor, named after William of Ockham,
the most parsimonious, simplest explanation is usually the right one.
It is.
The assumptions here, the cascading of failures and malfunctions and unseen artifacts
that Mick proposes and requires for his theory is just...
We'd be here all afternoon and probably through the weekend.
There's kind of a lot missing from the left side of that page, though.
You have to kind of...
My side of the page basically gives a complete explanation.
Your side of the page just says, oh, it was some kind of thing that was moving.
Can I bring my analytic kind of perspective to this real quick?
Yeah, yeah.
Why is it Ockham's Razor?
Well, because I don't have to account for an extraordinary amount of malfunctions
and never before seen...
New technology.
So that's even new physics.
So Ockham says nothing about the nature of an assumption.
He's talking purely about volume and the number of assumptions.
He's not talking really about assumptions.
He's talking about entities.
Least number of entities to explain it then.
Correct.
You have to create the right answer.
What a big new entity, which is an entirely new form of proposal.
Ockham is silent on the nature of the entity.
Let me just bring him the analytic perspective.
So what's super interesting...
I don't think he can just count entities and say, like, I have one...
All right, let me respond.
I mean, it's not mine personally, right?
I think Ockham would be rolling in his grave if he were to say...
Well, I think Ockham would be rolling in his grave if it was used in a rationalist framework
because he was a 13th century monk.
And so I think the fact that...
He probably wouldn't mind invoking angels.
What's that?
He wouldn't mind invoking angels.
Oh, he wouldn't.
I'm thinking God because that's the least number of entities to explain any miracle.
So let me just...
Let's just operate off a hypothesis that this was, in fact, a very bright, very anomalous...
Let's just say sauce or shapecraft.
Let's just go with that, just for hypothesis.
At the end of the video, it's on its edge, right?
Slightly over.
OK, fair enough.
But it's on its edge.
Well, it goes past vertical.
OK, fine.
No, I'm just...
No, no, fair enough.
Fiddly with my details.
Yeah, that's fair enough.
And according to the air crew, there's no evidence for this,
but according to the air crew, it wobbles after the video cuts out, right?
Yeah, that's, I think, Brian Graves, did he say that?
Correct.
Yeah.
So maybe if the aviator comes out and he says it wobbled, that's interesting.
So let me just put on my analytic hat real quick and bear with me.
I'll do this as quickly as I can.
You mentioned the Theodolite, the tracking.
In the 1940s, I'm going to list several cases here, and they get very interesting.
April 1947, this is months before Kenneth Arnold's sighting,
which kicked off the flying saucer craze, if you want to call it that.
Four months prior to that, two Weather Bureau employees observed four metallic disks
flat on the bottom, domed on the top.
And the US government assessed, because they occurred previous to Arnold's sighting,
they were not influenced by hysteria, mass media, anything like that.
They reported internally.
They never actually said this publicly.
So that is quite interesting.
Now let's move on.
Portland, 1947, July.
Five police officers see a total of nine disks going different directions.
So five cops, three cops, and one cop see different disks going in different directions,
wobbling or oscillating.
You can see this in the Project Sign raw reporting.
New Mexico, this is in the very famous Life Magazine article of 1947.
One of the Navy's top astronomers observes and takes various precise measurements of a disk,
and he observes it wobbling.
Masala, Japan, 1952, training exercise, a guy's flying, doing intercepts,
and he sees a disk come up to his plane that engages in a slow fluttering motion,
rocks back and forth, and flipped on its edge.
Direct quote, direct quote, flipped on its edge.
Southern California, Lockheed Martin aircrew is in the air.
They see an elliptical object flying over the Channel Islands, kind of a hot spot if you're following this.
Kelly Johnson, who is the skunkworks, basically the most famous,
the most well-known aeronautical engineer in American history, sees the same object from his ranch.
So you have two different perspectives, and they both saw this object.
Pretty credible.
And he actually goes on to say, I'm a believer in flying saucers,
the most kind of credentialed aeronautical engineer that we know of in American history.
Exeter, New Hampshire, 1964, four people, two cops,
see a large disk from 100 feet away and 100 feet altitude engaging in a wobbling motion.
Westall, 1966, Australia, 200 or 300, depending on the accounts,
and a teacher sees a silver disk sort of banked on its side, then took off at a thousand miles per hour.
Beverly, Massachusetts, 1966, nine witnesses, two law enforcement officers see a metallic plate-like object
that hovers 20 feet, according to three women, over their heads.
20 feet.
I see Mick's rolling his eyes.
I'm just reporting what people have said.
Minot Air Force Base, home of nuclear weapons missiles,
a Border Patrol officer sees a metallic disk, direct quote, wobbling on its edge, 30 feet wide, 100 feet away.
Five days later, the Air Force base...
Does your point just say a lot of UFOs wobble?
The Air Force, these are all in government records, right?
Are we noticing a consistency?
I'll finish up, we'll be quick.
Well, yeah, you pick the ones that wobble.
These are the close encounters and probably the best known encounters, and you do see a consistency here, right?
Well, I have to see what the steps are.
If these witnesses are close enough to observe wobbling, I think they can see the shape, right?
Anyway, quickly finish up, Porter's County, law enforcement officers chase a large metallic disk-like object
for 90 minutes going 86 miles.
Michigan, swamp gas, you also see large disk-like objects.
Redlands, California, this is one of the most extraordinary cases that really hasn't got a lot of press.
200 people see silver disk, 40, 50 feet in diameter, 200 feet altitude.
1968, Redlands, California, James McDonald did it.
Fair enough.
Broadhaven, UK, 10 students see a silver disk.
They draw pictures, they're identical.
Ariel, we all know the Ariel case, or a lot of people know the Ariel case.
62 students see a silver disk.
Pictures, identical, this disk is surrounded by-
The pictures are not identical.
There's a huge variety of pictures.
It's all the same kind of shape.
They look vaguely like a variety of children's drawings of flying saucers.
What I'm saying is you have this extraordinary amount of failures,
never before seen artifacts that just happen to you.
I don't agree with all the things that are on that thing.
I think they all have to happen.
What are the failures?
You're missing everything that I've ever hypothesized is that everything has to happen all at the same time, which isn't true.
Of course it has to happen, right?
Because you have a radar malfunction or-
So what's on the radar?
I don't know what's on the radar.
We have to account for it.
Writing a theory, you have to account for it.
Well, it could be a distant plane.
Well, what's on the radar that's six miles away?
I don't know.
It could be like a training exercise site thing, which they said it wasn't,
or it could be a malfunction, or it could be some kind of weather anomaly.
It could be balloons.
We don't know what it is.
Well, they're going west, so it's coming from the east, so it's going against very strong winds.
We could rule out balloons on-
We could just cross that out.
The aircrew saw something on the radar.
Yes, I agree with it.
You don't have to account for what it is.
You didn't account for what the object actually is.
You just said the aircrew saw this object.
You're not telling me what it is.
So it's the same thing.
I'm not following.
But the bottom line is, can we pull up the video?
Because the match between the flight path that we can reconstruct-
Don't mind the F-bombs.
And that's the anomalous thing about this video, is you have 120 miles not wind-
They're going against it.
They're going against the object.
Correct.
Well, it's not like planes can't fly against the wind.
Well, you suggested balloons.
So could we rule out balloons?
No, I don't think this is a balloon.
Well, no, the objects-
The fleet is going against the wind.
Right.
So you just said that those could be balloons.
Are they balloons?
No, I didn't say those could be balloons.
That's a different fleet.
This is a fleet of five objects.
Would a plane be able to rotate like that?
I mean, that doesn't-
The fleet described by Ryan Graves is nothing at all like the GoFast fleet.
We should really dive into the empirical evidence.
Let's get to the evidence, right?
And we have a lot.
If you mind just flipping over to the-
Video is the evidence.
We have empirical evidence of what jets look like with this camera system.
So if you just cruise down, maybe, we don't have time to get through all this.
I mean, we have a ton of that.
Let's just start there.
That's, yeah.
Yep.
Actually, no.
So maybe we can, I don't know if we can play it here, but maybe we can add this in.
Yeah, yeah.
But there's a-
We can reconstruct, and Mick mentioned this kind of this vertical U-turn, this J-hook path
that matches precisely with what the aircrew say that the object that was tracked on radar does.
And when you play that video, you'll see that there's a series of rotations,
and then there's one really kind of pronounced one that is slower than the others,
and that coincides with the apex of that turn.
And if you play it, it is a remarkable match,
and I got a couple other videos there that maybe we can throw in when we edit this.
But using Mick's sim, and again, Mick, thank you for making this possible.
It is remarkable when you watch that thing just ride up the reconstructed flight path.
It is a remarkable match.
You keep saying remarkable.
It is.
I think you used that word a little bit too much, because this isn't remarkable.
What we're seeing here is a curve that's basically a mathematical projection-
It's not.
It's flat.
Of the path of the jet onto a straight line in the distance.
If you take what the actual jet did with the camera did,
which was just basically do a little turn like that,
and then draw a line over here, which is another jet,
and then draw the lines of sight between the two,
you're going to get these J-hooks if you slice a plane through the lines at that point.
And if you move them closer, it gets a bit more curvy, and then it kind of flattens out.
But if you draw it there, it's just a mathematical projection.
It looks the same.
It looks like the same curve.
And this rotation of the object that Marek talks about,
yes, it happens at about the same time as that curve-
It's exactly the same time.
But that's the same time that we're traversing the singularity in the gimbal,
and it has to do these rotations.
So it's doing these big rotations.
And it's not the same.
It doesn't match the curves.
It does.
It happens roughly in the same region.
We can pull up your shim right now.
You want to pull up your shim right now and do it?
There's three other rotations that don't match.
The one big one is kind of roughly at the end, but it doesn't really match.
It's kind of like a bit of a reach.
It's not remarkable.
It's not a remarkable correlation.
I will let the viewers, maybe we can put this in,
but I really want to show people.
And this is directly from McSim.
I think, more importantly, let's just bottom line this.
Well, real quick, though, on just the audio associated with this,
do you think the operators of these systems are confused at what they're seeing?
Because they seem to think it's remarkable.
So their eyes are playing tricks on them or something?
We obviously don't know what they're seeing,
which means either it's just something that they don't recognize.
Yeah, but if you're using the camera's rotation as a way to explain it away,
then presumably that would be very easy to be like,
that was just the camera's rotation.
There's no wow factor at all.
The smoking gun for me was that it rotates in steps in that system.
There's zero empirical evidence.
But we talked to Mr. Snow.
There's no evidence in that system.
You asked him if he had seen that before, and he said yes.
He has seen it.
You don't believe him.
He's the expert.
It's absolutely possible.
Nobody else has seen that and is aware of that.
That's fair enough.
But we did talk to truly the top experts in the world on this.
I won't go on the record, surprisingly enough.
And that is part of the stigma.
I had a Zoom call with one of those individuals.
I sent you...
Can we say who this is?
I can't, unfortunately.
And I had a Zoom call with...
And when you say experts, experts from a military perspective.
So let me just run through.
So we talked to a senior Raytheon engineer who was,
let's say, intimately familiar with the system.
I don't want to give away too much.
We talked to two of the...
I think it's fair to say that the two top academic experts
on this type of technology, not the FLIRT, not the...
So we have the ATFLIRT.
Sensor technology.
Yeah, it's called indium antimonide.
Right.
And they were all truly perplexed by it.
The one that I talked to, and to your point about why
won't they go on the record, he said,
I am intrigued by this.
I sent you an email.
This is very interesting.
We had a long talk.
I don't want to get involved in this.
But highly credentialed.
But just the stigma is still there.
And what did they say?
Did you give them mixed hypothesis?
Yeah, so we had a lengthy...
We had a lengthy...
So basically they debunked mixed glare on the glass.
Would you agree that they debunked your glare on the glass?
The glare on the glass is a pretty old notion of the theory.
No, that's what you've been saying
until we indicated he's expert.
That was your theory.
You did just say old version of the theory as a fear.
The theory is...
Oh, no, glare on the glass was just one possible way
that you could get this shape.
But that's the only thing you've said
for seven years about this thing.
You've never said...
No, it could be something along the internal optical path
of the thing.
Basically, the aperture of the camera
creates this coming in shape.
There's no such thing as glare.
When Mick talks...
I really want to show people what this looks like.
What he says glare is glare is called blooming.
That's when...
I'm not a scientist, but I've read enough.
This is part of why I want people to get engaged.
Gloaming is when there's so much energy
being directed at a pixel
that it overcharges it and it spills over.
There's no way that that could result in that.
We agree that blooming is not...
I disagree.
Sorry?
How could blooming...
Blooming could create a shape.
I don't think it is blooming.
One of the experts right here said,
no blooming in indium antimonide
would not explain this rotation.
That was right after he said Mick might be right,
but for the wrong reasons.
No, this is a different expert.
I'll just leave it at this.
One of the top academic experts
deferred to one of the top government experts
on air-to-air FLIR imagery.
This guy...
You saw this, right?
He specifically refuted your theory.
I'll read it.
The object in the video is definitely maneuvering,
causing the appearance of rotation.
A D-roll axis of the payload
would not make this phenomenon of rotation.
This is specifically to your theory.
This is arguably the top expert in the US government.
I think...
In air-to-air FLIR imagery.
I think really he...
You're interpreting things that he told you.
No, I'm talking about the government expert.
Are you reading verbatim?
Let me quote him.
He said to me,
I would not want my response sent out as I am government,
and it might be seen as an expert official response
rather than an opinion based upon limited real information.
I just wanted to point some things out
that others may have missed.
Well, I'm reading what he said.
We all have limited info.
I guess, specifically, to Merrick's glare point,
you mentioned, okay, that's probably
the earliest version of the argument.
You've updated it.
You're talking about the internal optical system.
What does that mean?
What is your argument now?
Because now that glare's been ruled out, what is it?
Because these guys are saying glare in quotes.
Yeah, but then they don't want to talk about glare.
No, they didn't.
He said there isn't a point spread function.
Then he talks about a point spread function.
He puts glare in quotes, and he says it's all an internal...
And Yannick did a great job.
Yannick said, how do you reconcile this, quote,
glare on the glass, all the self-congratulating discussions
on Metabunk about glare spread for glare...
That's Yannick.
That's not an expert, so is it?
...that grows with the...
You know, right?
How do you...
And this is the best part.
So Mick's big explainer video is based on a cheap,
what is it, 200 bucks, FLIR camera
that this expert said is not a good comparison.
No, no, it's not a good comparison at all.
That was just an example of how you can get a rotation glare.
He literally calls you out.
It's just not a good comparison.
There's no empirical evidence...
A FLIR one, which costs $200 versus an app FLIR,
which costs a million dollars, is not going to be a very good comparison.
So anyway, bottom line is we have a lot,
we have a ton of air-to-air footage,
and there's zero empirical evidence.
And you have experts who don't want to be quoted.
Okay.
Do you want to loop me in?
Because I looped you and all the experts.
Looped you in on what?
Emails.
How was that?
That was email.
I asked him if I could reuse his material.
I'm sorry, I thought you were bringing somebody new to the table.
The other expert, the Raytheon engineer,
he told you not to include him.
He said, I gave you permission to publish, to share any of our discussion.
I now regret any discussion with him.
I'm putting out, I believe that this is more important than the stigma.
These guys are fighting a stigma.
So you think they're debunking me, but they just won't talk,
and they won't go on the record?
The expert in the world agrees with you.
I know you're eager for Aero to debunk this
because you thought they were doing lab experiments
that Kurt Patrick was talking about.
It's been seven, how long has it been since this video came out?
Almost a decade.
Actually, gosh, we're on a decade now.
Well, Aero's only been working on it a couple of years, I guess.
Yeah, you think they're very slow, very slow.
Well, they did Aguadilla.
They're doing a whole, don't you want to show where they debunked?
It's an interesting thing, I see Aguadilla, like when you talk about experts.
No, no, no, let's stay on Gimbal.
Well, just very, very quickly, I think Aguadilla has the SCU,
the Coalition for the Study of...
Yeah.
They did like a 200-page documentary
with a bunch of different experts, people with PhDs.
They think it's some kind of alien work.
But why do you think Aero hasn't, or anybody hasn't...
Why has nobody backed you on your theory?
Well, they backed me on Aguadilla, and they backed me on the triangles.
On Gimbal.
Because they haven't finished their analysis yet.
Okay, I think that's a stretch.
Why is there no academic literature that supports your glare theory?
It's all blooming, defraction, and saturation.
Because it's not a very common thing.
It's not something that happens all the time.
If it was common, we wouldn't be having this discussion.
This is an anomalous event.
This is something that happened that was weird,
and the pilots didn't recognize it,
because it isn't something that happens every day.
There's an active-duty wisdom.
Based on them being a narrow field of Zoom,
I sent this to you years ago,
narrow field of view Zoom, too.
He uses this system daily, and the fidelity of the picture,
they're probably less than 10 miles away.
He uses the system every day.
Life and death, right? They rely on the system.
Yeah, but I don't really see how that can be determined
from what we're seeing on screen.
If you point the camera at the sun,
it doesn't look like it's 10 miles away.
One other fact I just want to introduce
is that possibly this was also
involved in the formation of other...
Correct. That's the fleet.
And Ryan has done it, to his credit,
and we can maybe throw this up,
I put it in the slides, but he's recreated this,
and it's kind of a V-shaped formation.
When the object does this very bizarre
kind of reversal of direction with no radius of turn,
they kind of do a jumbled turn,
and then they proceed and go in the same direction
as that object.
They're all moving together in concert, basically,
is the recollection from the top-down view
from the radar.
His recreation isn't actually that good
because it doesn't incorporate the rotation of the plane.
That's fair.
But what is your theory now?
Now that the glare on the glass has basically been ruled out,
what is your theory?
I think what we see here is some kind of optical effect
that is rotating because of the de-rotation mechanism.
And what evidence do you have for that?
Well, for a start, there's the bands of light and dark
that rotate in the background.
Does the fact that the rotation exactly matches
the needed rotation?
So, no, it doesn't, right?
You don't know what the pitch angle of that jet is.
You picked a random number.
It was not a random number. It was 3.6,
which is exactly what the F-16's...
F-18.
So they were in a matching Durn's profile.
You were in a max range profile.
You're already wrong right there.
Well, if you change that, it doesn't really change it very much.
It just slightly offsets the curve.
Not right now, obviously.
Bottom line is I think
we need to hear from, hopefully,
from the backseat.
You can see by looking at it that there's an optical effect.
If you actually look at this thing
and you see the light and dark rotation
in the background, I know you said you've
thrown some anonymous exposure
that won't go on record.
I sent the email to you.
Yeah, but if it's not going on record, it's kind of useless.
Okay.
So you've brought no experts to me.
I've brought all the experts to you.
That's great, but if you bring some experts to the public,
it's not that useful just bringing them to me.
Unfortunately, the stigma that you promote
is a big part of why they come out.
I encourage them to come forward.
Come forward and I won't laugh at you.
There are lots of scientists who aren't
afraid of doing
proper analysis.
I'll kind of strawman
both the arguments here. Please do.
I think on
Merrick, your side, I think we need
more of these people to come out to
gain confidence on this, both on the expert
side and then the
operators of these FLIR systems
and the pilots themselves.
Then on your side,
Mick, I think
you probably have to take
prima facie
this
operator of this FLIR system, this
pilot who is
saying, whoa, this is crazy.
The idea
that it's an F-18
and that this is happening around
the GOFAST as well
and that it's in this bizarre formation
and if you turn the
camera and you're the person turning the camera,
you're actually operating the system,
there's no reason to freak out. There's no reason
to attach that audio.
It turns automatically.
Sure, but if you're highly aware
of the camera turning.
David Fravor discussed this
hypothesis and he said the camera doesn't turn,
which is just my player on.
From his perspective, the camera appears
not to turn. The camera turns when it tracks
something going underneath the plane.
You're saying David Fravor isn't
familiar with basic
locking and tracking?
He's familiar with using it.
So he knows
what does the press and what
appears on screen and what it actually means in terms of
what's in the air, but he doesn't know what's actually
going on in the optics, what the lenses do,
what the mirrors do, and how it rotates.
So you think it's like,
and then that same guy
who presumably, I mean we have to figure
out who he is, but has like
some history
doing this stuff. Right.
After he sees this, he doesn't
see anything like it.
Nobody's seen anything like this.
That's why we've got this video, it's this once
in a 20 year thing that happened.
When the pilot says
they won the lottery of the
jargon here, and it just happened to
occur right amid all these
encounters, when the pilot
says that is the LNS,
and I'll just explain, the LNS is the launch
and steering, which is the selected radar target,
what does that mean to you?
So let me just explain,
the WISO says, hey, is that
our radar target on our FLIR,
on the camera? And the pilot says, yes,
that is our selected radar target,
which is six to eight miles away.
What do you think the pilot meant when he says
that is, and what do you think he meant
when they briefed Congress
and says we knew it was not a false hit,
we knew that we had a
stable radar lock, a stable
track file on it,
when they mentioned closest
point of intercept.
You know what the Jehemic system is,
right? It places, how does
your theory square with all the technology?
Let me just quickly,
it's basically like an Apple
Vision kind of
thing, the visor that puts
all the data, yeah, it pumps all
the data and you'll get a little box like
where there's a target somewhere. Ryan talked about it
in your... So how do
you square, like, let's just start with the LNS, right?
The pilot says
that is, yes, that's our radar target.
It's actually a bit instinctive to what he actually says, but what we see
on the screen here
is an optical
track. It's actually tracking it using
the contrast
on the screen. So
what you might be referring to is something that's on the SI
page,
which would be like the nearer
radar target. No, the
WIZO asks, hey, is that thing that we're looking on
the FLIR, the selected...
He said, is that...
I'm trying to remember what he said.
Is that LNS, dude?
And the other guy said, yeah, that is LNS.
We don't know what he's referring to,
it could be like... The selected radar target.
That's what the LNS is.
Well, yes, but like, is that that?
Or is that a different target?
Because they also saw this fleet of things.
So there just happened to be a distant jet
exactly where
the close thing is? Is that what you're saying?
Behind us somewhere. Really?
So it just happened... Like, this is the odds of this?
So you're saying that they're referring to another...
You're very familiar with this theory of mine, Mark.
I think this is... Wait, so
let me just... Playing this with the crowd here a little.
Hold on, hold on. So you... They have
this radar target, right? It's six miles away.
And directly behind it,
is some other jet
in doing...
Like, showing
its heat
engine in a way that's
never been seen before in a malfunctioning
pod in a... What else
we have? A malfunctioning of all
the electronic identification systems.
It's just cascading
failures. I can't wrap my head... I hope I'm
getting through to people, but it's just...
It is pretty wild to me.
Yeah, it seems unlikely, right?
It's perfectly lined up.
You would just say, what, like, law of large numbers?
And we've never... The AT
flare does not rotate in steps. If it's malfunctioning, maybe
I don't... I just find that hard to believe.
By the way, the patent, literally
the patent, which you looked up,
the patent... There's a sentence in there that explicitly
we can pull it up, explicitly
disproves your theory.
Why is the patent explicitly...
Well, we can go... I know we have to wrap up.
No, no, we're good. We have until four now.
Oh, wow. Geez. Okay. I don't know
if I can...
You tell me where the patent is.
There's a lot of things at the very end.
It says, for example,
that it will avoid using
the roll in a fashion. So this is super
jargony. Mick knows what I mean.
This, on its face,
disproves your theory.
Spacely saying that it avoids
rotation. What are the
three words before that paragraph?
In some embodiments. That is,
any patent expert will know that is in
every single patent, that language.
That is not unique.
For example,
these patents are very broad.
Like in some...
We have to describe to the audience
what the patent is.
So this explicitly... So Mick says,
this is so... It hurts
for you. It's so complex.
He says that...
So normally the pod will just do a nice
slow rotation like this to find out.
We'll put the video up. We modeled it out.
And it's just like this super chill...
It doesn't do this for rotation.
Because you can remember in the Gimbal video
it does one, two, three, four.
Normally, the patent
says it would just do a very simple,
very gradual, nothing aggressive.
It doesn't say that. Absolutely.
So it says in some
embodiments it only uses the two axes
which would give that smooth rotation.
Correct. But it doesn't say that the app
that was used that day is that particular
embodiment.
And also this was a patent
from, I believe, 2006.
And we're talking about the Gimbal video
which was filmed several years later. And as you know
from talking to Mr. Snow,
these systems change quite a lot
over time. But when they get smoother, not
less. Correct. Not more. Mechanically
it makes no sense to do this crazy
stopping though. The image is what you want to be smooth.
And if you notice in the Gimbal video, it actually
kind of like loses lock, weirdly,
quite a lot throughout the thing, even though it's not
moving around very much. There's little Gimbal rotations
and it moves off to the side. You don't see
that in the GoFast. But the rotation
wouldn't be more jagged,
right? It wouldn't be more like locked.
There's two things they have to balance. There's the actual mechanics
of the part itself and then what
the pilot sees. And it wants to make the
tracking as accurate as possible first.
Is there a trade-off there? Introducing steps is
the worst part because you're like starting,
stopping, starting, stopping. Well not if you have a very
agile mirror system in there that can
counter those. So we're
purely in that speculation. That's
what we actually have. And that explicitly
disproves your theory. Well, they also have
the description of the mirror systems in there with
plus or minus three degrees of
source, which is about
the same deviation from the way we get with
the steps.
Sorry, I don't
follow. The point is the pattern. We know
that we don't have to point directly or something.
We can use the mirrors to steer, the extra mirrors.
No.
It just doesn't work that way. There's no
evidence of that. You need evidence. There's no evidence
of glare. There's no evidence of rotating
glare. There's no evidence of any
of this. Well, we just gone over all the
evidence on it. You can see it on the screen
that we have an optical effect.
You can't use
the gimbal video to prove your
theory for the gimbal video. That's impossible.
I'm just using it to
show that there's actually some kind of optical effects
going on. I hope we can maybe, if you wanted
to quickly look at some imagery of what
the camera, how it actually
records jet engine exhaust.
So where are we going?
While you're doing that,
I would like to encourage anybody out there
who understands this
to weigh in. Because we need more people
looking into this.
That's a big takeaway.
No, we need more analysis,
more credible eyes, people with rigorous
backgrounds, experts. We need experts to actually
speak on the record. Agreed.
And also people who know, because a lot of this stuff is just
the systems and how they work. We're
debating these obscure
raping on patents. This is absurd.
I know.
We need
something that's 30 miles away.
By the way, to the extent you're not compromising
American national security,
if you are not, I think it's your patriotic
duty to come out.
If you are, then maybe
stay where you are.
Varying distances,
the engine exhaust
gets bigger and bigger. No, it doesn't.
In fact, it gets smaller.
And I have a video. I can show it.
So this is from the same video.
And this is a lot further
away at the end of it. And it gets smaller.
So Raytheon,
I believe it looks like
they have some anti-blooming effects on there.
So that is the opposite
of what you are suggesting.
And if you
go down one more.
So this is the glare to wing size.
I'm sorry.
That's exhaust. Don't use glare.
Glare doesn't exist.
I'm telling you, there's a lot of papers
about blooming. If you go down to that one where your mouse
is right there, compare that
to mixed theory. That's mixed theory right there.
Yes, a point light source
will create a specific
size on the sensor. So it doesn't really matter
how big it is. Your speculator.
What is the light source though?
It's not light.
It's the heat of the engines.
This is a thermal camera. So we're looking at
the camera of this jet.
Essentially, it's a very, very bright,
brilliant light source. And the
camera for some reason has created this
glare, this optical effect.
There's perhaps sensor blooming.
Probably not though.
Look, I'm just a bystander.
I'm open to both of you guys being right. I think
it's kind of
scary from an American national
security perspective, if you're right.
Because that's just so bad.
It's like this heat source. It's fuzzy.
It doesn't happen every day though.
It doesn't happen every day. It's not like
this is going on all the time.
If that's an F-18
at a base that's frequently
flying F-18, it's like that's
pretty bad detection.
Arrow thinks it's a glare.
Arrow thinks it's a glare? That's not true.
Kirkpatrick? No.
Kirkpatrick thought Gimbal was filmed during
the daytime. Yeah, but
what they're actually working on is
the assumption that this is some kind of glare.
An optical effect.
I don't think there's any evidence of that.
Well, we'll see.
You said that right before this hearing.
You're very
excited. Oh, we can't wait to see what Arrow has to say about
this. The hearing came and went.
The game is GoFast and Aguadilla, which was
good. Well, now they're
in a tough spot with GoFast,
as we said, because Aircrew is going to
contradict them.
Yeah, well, then they'll take that new
information into their analysis.
That is just absurd to me based
on the empirical evidence, right?
That shape, if you go up...
That matches the Chilean case.
Almost exactly the same size.
First of all, that's blooming, right?
Can you explain what blooming is?
Yeah, so it's, again, when
a sensor gets hit with
a pixel gets hit with too much energy,
that it'll spill over to
other pixels.
And that's what we see in the Chilean case.
That is an apple to orange.
Can you explain what glare is?
It's relevant to this conversation.
Oh, but you said, like, it doesn't exist.
Sorry, in infrared.
Why not?
I'm going off of the people who
are experts on this.
Why do they talk about a point spread function
if glare doesn't exist in infrared?
I'm pretty sure he was talking about
your FLIR 1 example.
What point spread function?
Point spread function is
a mathematical model of how
light spreads from a point.
So any point on the thing, this is a photo
of the scene here. So in what context are they bringing up
the point spread function?
In the context of glare, essentially.
It was a little
confusing as a paragraph, and it was something I wanted to talk to you
more, but you never responded to my emails.
I emailed them this morning, actually.
The second expert.
If you,
usually the point spread function is kind of like
a curve that goes
like this, a very, very sharp curve
like that. And that's how
light spreads from
any pixel
on the entire
scene, spreads according to
this function.
So for things that are pretty dim,
like most of the stuff in this
room, you get a very, very sharp
pixel, because the stuff that's to the
side is very, very low level.
But around a bright light like
this, everything is kind of boosted up.
So you actually start to get the effects
of the edges of this point spread
function. And you can use this
to basically model optical effects, and
they use it to model glare
in various optical systems.
And you would have a
point spread function for an
infrared thing. There's simply no way of not
having it, because you're going to
get some scatter from imperfections in the mirrors,
possibly in the lenses.
And you can also incorporate that
into the
sensor blooming as well. This is called, I think,
optical transfer
function is the entire thing.
It's point spread plus the
sensor spread as well.
And these are details that I think
experts should be able to weigh in. Absolutely.
I'm a little skeptical, Mick, because you
spent years, you went on CNN with your little
glass, right? That's the glare
on the glass that was disproven, what, two
months ago, three months ago?
We've got you
saying, oh, well, if it's not, I got you here.
Briefly, if the glare effect is indeed
all in the sensor, then you shift here to another.
It's showing that if part of the camera
rotates, or if the camera itself rotates,
then it rotates. That was the easiest way of demonstrating.
Since then, I've been doing it by rotating
a camera, like you can actually
hold two cameras up and rotate them. So basically what you've been saying for seven years
is wrong. No, no.
It's improved. No,
no, no. The glare on the glass
has been disproven, which you've been
viewing on CNN. Well, according to you, it's been
disproven, but I don't think it has been
disproven. How do you reconcile
this with the glare on the glass?
According to Yannick, your co-author
on this paper, he quotes
the expert.
The, quote, glare that Mick mentions
is likely from boost filters,
high-pass filtering, edge shut. That's all internal.
That's not on the glass. Yeah, but
he's assuming that the glass is clean.
Oh, so we're back to the, so
at one point, I think it's necessarily
something on the glass. At one point, Mick thought that
he, some source told him, or somebody apparently
told him that crew chiefs
in the military just wiped
the glass.
I've got video of that happening.
The guy just manhandling one of those
systems with his hands. And I'm sure it was
cleaned after because there's pretty darn good
maintenance on these, on these systems.
As soon as they get up in the air, they're going to throw
a cloud up their face. So your
theory at one point was like
that some crew chief like
wiped a greasy sleeve on it, and that's what
gave us this. I've heard people say that. I mean,
I don't think that's what happened because
the glare on the glass thing would probably give
a less even
shape. I think it's probably more to do with the internal
optics. I've got a camera
that gives a very similar
shaped glare to that. So my little
helmet mounted camera. Maybe you can
recap. So you have a malfunctioning
mechanical malfunction. It has to be.
No, we don't know that for sure because
we don't know if there's an embodiment that doesn't have
smooth steps. There's zero evidence
for that. You have to provide evidence. You don't have
evidence either way, really. Absolutely.
There's tons of footage of
you know this. You once
used Top Gun Maverick as evidence.
I was joking. Oh, my God.
You realize I was joking, right? No, because
you seem very, very serious
at the time. It was on a tweet
for Crying Out Loud. There's tons of
There's tons of
actual video evidence of how
these systems rotate, and it's a nice
gradual, simple
You don't really see it from the outside
rotating. You can see it on the edges
tracking. I have a
two minute long video. Very nice, smooth.
Let's move on, but both of you guys can
follow up. You can follow up with the
smooth rotation. If you want to
follow up with any videos that show the jagged
kind of locking rotation, that's cool too.
I just want to quickly reiterate how
you're saying there's a distant jet right
literally exactly in the line of
sight. Roughly.
Okay. And then we have
a malfunctioning
pod, and then you have
an artifact
that nobody's ever seen before and no expert
know about, and no aviator who's ever
And you're saying that it's like this
new advanced technology, possibly aliens. I'm only
saying it is
there's a spectacular match between
the eyewitness accounts
of that anomalous trajectory,
that direction reversal with no
radius of turn, the rotation we see
in the video, and the flight path we
can reconstruct. I'll leave it at that.
As you say, you know, new advanced
technology or possibly aliens,
Dr. Stephen Greer
is obviously an outspoken person
when it comes to the UFO issue.
Very polarizing figure
on the topic. He
will come out and say things like, oh, the
Nimitz stuff, you know, that's all
Lockheed Martin special access programs.
And we'll
say that they're red teaming our
detection systems or spoofing us
or something. Which people say
doesn't happen. So do you guys
have opinions on that? Do you think that that's at all
possible? That some of these
These guys are training for war. They're not going to do
that to guys that are training for war in a
training airspace. It's all right.
That was when I spoke to Ryan Greer.
That kind of leaves aliens.
My basic point here is that if we're going to
entertain extraordinary
options like aliens or even
advanced technology being used by
the Chinese or the Russians, then we should also
entertain things like maybe
there's a series of coincidences that happen.
Can you really say that
it's less likely?
Entertain all options, but at some point it just borders on
the ridiculous. I'm sorry.
But aliens borders on the ridiculous.
The historical record is pretty
remarkable of
identical performance characteristics,
wobbling on its edge.
Identical eyewitness reports and people are very similar.
They've got similar brains and they report things in the same
way. You picked all the ones that
wobble? Where
are all the videos of wobbling discs?
I picked the ones that are the best
known and they just happen to
wobble. When it comes to
secret American craft,
again, I normally don't
find myself kind of steel manning this position,
but it's
probably more conspiratorial
to say that we don't have
craft that is classified
that exhibits exotic characteristics
than the inverse. So like
80% plus of Lockheed, I
think of Skunk Works projects currently
are classified. And so
yeah, are there things red teaming our
systems? And to steel man, your point
that you just made is I just spoke to Ryan Graves.
We had a great conversation.
And he was like, yeah, maybe
that's happening in spots, but
in his case, he was stationed at Naval
Airspace Oceania in
Virginia. And
he basically, one of
his people in his
squadron, fighter pilots,
the object almost hit
the pilot. And it was this
sphere inside a cube.
And he was like, they're not going to put us in
danger if they're kind of red teaming our system.
So I don't know. Yeah.
You don't do that over international. We have
ranges for that. We have designated airspace
for this kind of stuff.
I think it's possible that the radar hits
were some kind of red teaming
thing because it doesn't really put anybody in danger because
there's no actual targets. But in this case,
it was a pilot almost hitting the object.
Okay, yeah, that's a different thing. But in the gimbal
thing, for example. You think it's radar spoofing or
something? Yeah, some kind of radar interference.
Perhaps there was a distant jet and the
radar got messed up and made it appear
as someone actually told me that as a
possibility. How does it account?
If it's
something like that, how do you get five or six
objects moving in concert like that?
Well, it's the same. It's just one object. You're getting
five echoes of it or something. I don't understand
the details, but someone did actually
mention that to me as a possibility.
Someone who was familiar with radar obviously
doesn't want to speak on the record
because of the stigma that I'm perpetrating.
But yeah, it's
I don't know.
How can we move forward with this?
I think we actually do need more input.
Let's get the wizard out there.
Let's get people who actually
understand the system to speak
on it. That would be really good.
Please. Come out and talk to
us. I've tried to contact
Raytheon, and they said, oh, you should talk to the Navy.
And of course, the Navy doesn't want to talk to anyone.
They clam up. As soon as it's UAP, they clam up.
I see it over
and over and over again.
Arrow will eventually release something, but
I'm skeptical that it's going to be
a comprehensive explanation of what's
going on.
We should move on.
So, USS Omaha.
This is a very
controversial, interesting case.
July of 2019, off
the coast of San Diego. It was released by, I believe,
George Knapp and Jeremy Corvell.
Admiral Gallaudet, who
just testified before Congress,
might have some more interesting
info about this case.
I think it's mixed turned
at TSOF.
I'm not actually that familiar with it, but I'll give you my take on it.
The video we're going to look at
is the sphere descending
into the sea.
It's taken off the screen in
the command center of the ship.
We're looking at thermal video again,
so we're seeing like a heat source,
possibly glare or blooming.
And it
kind of looks like it was moving around at first,
but that's actually just the camera
moving, the camera that's actually
recording the thing,
not the other camera.
There's a cut in the video
where it kind of jumps down to a lower level.
It's actually descending really, really slowly.
There's cuts where it's just
above the horizon.
It's not really moving at all.
It's just kind of slowly, slowly
descending to the ocean.
When it gets to approximately
the horizon, it shrinks
down to a point.
Then it kind of pops up again, expands
and then it shrinks again and disappears.
And I think
at the end of it, they say
splash down,
mark bearing a range.
So they think that it's actually gone into the water.
But if you zoom
in on the video, I think it actually looks more like
it's actually going, it's actually a heat
source that is expounded.
It's either blooming or glaring.
And then it goes behind the horizon.
There's some dispute as to exactly where the
horizon is. If you move the horizon
up or down one pixel, it's in front of it.
If you move it a pixel all the way
it's behind it. There was a guy, I think
Dr. Phil Metzer,
he did some analysis of that.
I published it on Twitter
and said it was very
ambiguous as to where the actual horizon was.
But it's very similar to like
a light going behind a
solid object will actually shrink
if it's a point source as it
goes behind it rather than just
disappearing.
So we don't know what it is.
It appears to be moving,
I think it appears to be moving northly
and the wind is coming from that direction.
Pretty strong winds too. It's apparent wind,
apparent motion against the wind. But I think
I don't know what it is but I think
my best guess is that it's a strong
heat source that's actually moving away
and it goes behind
the horizon.
There's various interpretations and there's
more analysis.
Maybe just paint a broader picture. This is part of
five or six
months long incursions over these
naval vessels off the Channel Islands
and off the coast of Southern
California. Multiple ships
and they were reporting
in fact, Jeremy and George
released a video of
basically two red lights
from the Omaha that night.
And we know that the ship
was being, sorry, and they were just hovering there
and I think another one kind of cruises, maybe we can splice
this in, but another one kind of cruises by
it. So clearly there were objects around
the ship. There's no question, right?
There's radar footage from that
same night and the
ship is getting swarmed. I think at one point I counted
ten, twelve.
Fourteen objects were observed simultaneously.
The objects were described as
self-illuminated spheres,
approximately six feet in diameter.
So it kind of comports with your kind of orb
general description. Back to the orb thing
that has been consistent.
So where to begin?
Geez. Number one,
you can see in the indicator that
they did have a radar contact at one point.
A slave of the radar. You saw that R. We know the
symbology. So again, this is like
the gimbal. The system says
tracking a radar target.
The system's saying that.
But it clearly isn't in this one. It's been
done by a joystick. Someone's manually
moving the camera around.
They probably, just like with gimbal, same
thing. They probably had the radar drop it off in
the system. So you're saying the same thing happened again?
Like they missed the actual radar target?
I don't know. Maybe that was the actual
radar target. Okay.
Maybe. Then we have the radar.
It's all within like six miles.
Five, six miles. All those radar contacts.
Well, yeah, but that doesn't mean that's the only contact.
So you think
they're
surrounded by like 14 ob, whatever
it is. There's a lot, right, on that
radar footage. And you think they
decided to focus on the object that's 60
miles away, slowly going
over the horizon? It was something what the video looks like.
It looks like... Come on, you've got to
apply a little common sense here.
Well, it looks like a plane flying away to me. It's very, very
similar to the Chilean
evidence of blooming,
which is your theory, that is
that perfectly spherical?
Perfectly spherical?
Really? Let's go take a look.
Compared to like one of the engines of
the Chilean... Right.
It's all
distorted. It's not
circular, right? We're kind of getting it.
No, no, no. There's zero evidence for
your claim. I've looked at
a lot of Dave Fauci's Flirvid and
Thanks Dave for all your work. There's no
engine that looks like a
perfectly round sphere. They're generally
perfectly round. Really?
Well, if you could show me one, we can go back.
We looked at it. It's all jagged.
It's flickering. You know what I'm
talking about. You know that there's frequently...
The false ones do flicker a little bit more.
But I think this is a much more distant object
and it's zoomed in a lot more. So you have no evidence
that it's blooming.
It seems very similar to other things.
Well, the evidence that it's blooming is that it shrinks
when it goes behind the horizon. Do you mind if we go on the slideshow
real quick? Because we can test that
very... So this is just the shot.
If you look closely,
you can see the horizon line.
And the key here
is
the horizon is above
the center
point of that sphere.
So if you go down... It's about the same as the...
We go down to that one.
That's a line that I drew.
We'll leave it
up. A UAP is in the eye of the beholder.
This is green.
I see quite a bit of sky underneath that horizon.
Do you? I don't. But if you go to the next one...
You see how it's a lot lighter than the rest?
If you go to the next one, we can see the line that you drew
and I see a lot of ocean above your line.
I see an enormous
amount of ocean above. And if you go down to the next one,
I zoomed in on one section,
there's clearly ocean above your line.
There's pixel. There's dark pixel.
This is the problem with this thing.
You can't... And this is what Dr. Phil
was saying, that you can't actually determine exactly where it is.
We know where it looks like. It's almost exactly
at the horizon, maybe pixel above, pixel below.
And it shrinks
in exactly the same way that the line would shrink.
Well,
if you watch SpaceX capsules go down,
it does the same thing. Remember, we pulled
those up and they look exactly the same.
We should dispute that.
Again, you have no empirical
evidence that an engine
actually has that very,
very clear circular...
Do you think this is an actual circle that's
shrinks? It goes in the water.
That is one thing.
Let's talk to the air crew.
Sorry, the air crew.
Let's listen to what they say.
They say, first
thing the guy says, it took off.
It's booking it. Where does that imply?
Play the video.
Do you want to play it? The first
thing he says, it took off. In this one?
It's booking it.
Took off. It's booking it.
It's not when they're looking at the radar.
There's multiple radar targets.
Right there. Yeah, you said.
It's not moving.
What does it imply?
It left the vicinity and it's
moving very fast. But it's not
doing that. It took off. It's booking.
It's booking it. It means it's going very
fast. So, correct.
So the implication, as Tim
mentioned recently, and I think some of the folks
that were on the bridge of the
Omaha at this point, during this
incident, said these things were hovering.
We have video of these
things hovering. Jeremy Corbell,
those two red lights hovering, and
another one kind of cruising by it.
It took off. It's booking it. Implies
to me, it was sitting there
and then it started moving.
It's not moving, though. Yes, it is.
It's clearly moving. Well, it doesn't suddenly
start moving in that video. It doesn't
change. So the
assumption is, it was stationary.
It starts
moving and it records it.
It took off. Is that a fair interpretation?
It took off. It's booking it. It's very
speculative, I think. Really?
You're interpreting what you want to be happening based
on a few words that somebody said in this video.
But we have evidence of these objects hovering
over the deck of the
Omaha. The drones?
Whatever they are. It's something with red lights.
That video is a terrible video,
the Corbell video. It doesn't
really show anything. It could be drones. It could be planes.
You know what I'm talking about, right? The two red
lights with the other one. Yeah, most people think
it's a silly video. And a lot of the eyewitness
stuff. So what were those objects? Were they
just drones flying around? I don't know what they were.
So here's where it gets really interesting.
24 hours later, the U.S.
was Paul Hamilton.
It's foiled. You can find
it. We'll put it up.
Reports the same thing. One of the objects
splashes. You can see it in the deck log or in
the briefing of the event.
If you look at, I don't know if this is diagnostic,
but if you look at the video footage
from the Omaha, two of those contacts
are cruising around. They just disappear off the radar.
Went in the water.
It could be in the water. I'm not saying
that it is. That's not... We're working under the assumption
I think that there were drones in the area
because they reported drones and...
Who knows? The only evidence
we have shows a spherical object. There's no evidence.
There's no empirical evidence that
a... You're taking up
splash just to be the same as that splash when
it was probably... Well, they were getting ready to get a...
They asked three ships around them to get a helicopter
out. Because they thought that there were drones
in the area.
They thought it was close.
There's a lot of issues with the whole drones thing.
The army, the military, the navy
has misinterpreted a lot of things as drones.
I tweeted
earlier today about how they
once put out a photo
of a jet
and said it was a drone. We know
that the Snoopy team,
the trained observers on a navy vehicle,
have
misidentified stars as drones.
And
what does that have to do with the spherical
looking object? Well, we were talking about these
eyewitness accounts of things that happened that go
along with these videos.
Maybe they mistook
something else. Maybe they thought that
Venus was a spherical object because
it looks like a bright light
in the sky, like hundreds of yards
away. Can you provide a
single piece of evidence that
blooming looks like that? Like that very rounds?
I'll give it a go.
I looked at a lot of infrared imagery now
and I haven't seen nothing. That's the natural
shape for blooming there. I think we should
move on. Admiral Gallaudet
says that he has a first-hand witness who
might be coming out soon.
So let's both, on both sides, we should hope.
I think you mentioned there's some video.
That would be great.
I will say, just
quickly, so there was another ship that reported
an object splashing in the water.
This is where it
gets kind of, very from an analytic perspective,
interesting.
That ship, the Paul Hamilton, so this is the day
after the Omaha video.
It's swarmed by a group of
drones, UAP.
They depart, you can actually
track this, they depart
on a heading that goes right towards Guadalupe
Island.
And I bring that up because
there's a series on
I think National Geographic, Unidentified,
Luis Elizondo,
and I think Sean Cahill went down to Guadalupe
Island because there have been reports of
spheres going into the water.
And I spliced the
interviews together. They had five or six fishermen
out there, including one of the world's most
renowned shark experts, a scientist,
said they've seen these objects.
The fishermen all say, yeah, I've seen these
lighted luminous orbs, spheres, going
into the water. That's interesting, right?
So you have one group of UAP,
one splash is recorded as going
in the water, and then this other group goes right
towards the location where, oh, by the way,
witnesses have been recording, reporting
spheres going in the water.
There's a military testing area there, isn't it? Isn't there a
drone base down there where they test military drones?
That's in the islands.
It's Mexican. No, but north of there,
there's an island. So we're talking about, no, we're talking about
well south of those islands. And Danny Sheen
just came out as well as a famous
American lawyer
who represents a lot of UFO whistleblowers.
And he said that he
has coordinates for a
UFO underwater base.
Go check it out.
I said we should all do a
boat trip out there, and we got
some Twitter momentum.
I think that's interesting, right?
Sure, but it's just a lot of eyewitness accounts.
It is, but it just
happens to align with
two splash events.
A splash just means something going
in the water. Correct. Do you think these
guys are genuinely mistaken?
Do you think they have some sort of incentive?
Well, the people in the Navy.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying. So you don't
think they're like Psy-Opping
the American public or
wanting money or fame out of it?
Jay Stratton
took this slide of three stars and
presented it to people in Congress.
He thought that it was
triangular drones.
This kind of types of mistake
goes all the way up the chain. Do you think
that's still happening today at Arrow?
And I'm sure they're making mistakes
still. They couldn't get the date right and they
go fast.
Alright, let's move on to Nellis
Tonopah. Yep.
So this is a restricted airspace
testing range. Nellis
is famous. There's a lot of UFO lore.
You have this object moving
towards the Black Mountains.
Why don't we play this video? It's a little
lesser known.
1994.
There's two
videos actually.
Within this clip you mean? You mean
those two clips here? Within this video?
I don't actually...
There's a different video
following this.
Stabilized.
I'll just throw my
thesis on the table here. I think that's just a
balloon. Or a bunch of balloons
floating in the wind.
The camera is running a lot.
There's no actual movement of the
object itself. We do have a range
indicator which tells you how far away
it is and if you use that we see that
the range indicator isn't very accurate. It kind of
like zips back and forward.
I just think if you're
operating these
machines at a
Nellis testing range you have to be pretty
familiar with probably exotic
stuff. Yeah, but look at it.
What can you see there? It does basically
a 90 degree turn.
It doesn't. Sure does.
A guy made a
metabunk in 1996, sorry,
a sit-rec and he did a good job. Remember?
I sent you the video.
I put this in a sit-rec and you can see that
the range data is like
bullshit basically.
And if you just use the lines of sight
there's a perfectly reasonable
wind-driven path for a balloon.
I'd love to see that because
it's like a triangle shape.
This isn't infrared I think.
No.
I mean you asked me
to do it in sit-rec so I did.
And then you
took my results and you said that it drew
what you'd originally
thought. But I don't think it does.
I think the results show that the range data
is very inaccurate. It looks like it's
morphing in shape.
Like a bunch of balloons kind of rotating in the sky.
It does a little bit of like an Apollo, you know, like
very bizarre.
This is maybe the weirdest video
I've seen. It is bizarre.
Doesn't that look like a bunch of balloons to you?
It kind of pivots. Yeah, but it looks like the balloons
are like malleable and
morphing.
It looks like it rotates
in the wind, which is very bizarre.
I just think if it were balloons and you're
operating these systems at
restricted airspace,
you have to have some protocol for
balloons. You have to know what
you're tracking. Yeah, but you wouldn't
be freaking out. You'd know
those are just balloons. What's interesting is
it's coming from
it's coming from Area 51.
That is very interesting.
Yeah, well that's Nell's testing range.
But it's actually, like if you
could trace where like it's
moving west at first and then it takes
basically a right turn and goes
north. So shouldn't your Ockham's
Razor be, you know, well it depends on
what you think what's going on at Area 51.
Well, it is an interesting
twist. It's a military event.
Why didn't they scramble jets
and go after it?
You were all in shock.
You could hear them like, what is that?
They were too surprised to scramble jets and do anything?
No, they didn't do anything. Nothing happened.
I have no idea.
That's all we know. All we saw. Maybe they
scramble jets as soon as that. Maybe they
realized it was some balloons and didn't scramble jets.
So it's zipping along, right? And it's
going due west and then it basically
does a 90 degree turn. If you
take the range data. No, you can see
it visually. Like you can actually see it visually.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Do you want to play it again or?
We'll have to revisit this then.
Yeah, no, I mean, it's quite clear, right?
It's because it's like, okay, so. The camera moves.
Let me do this for the folks
at home. It's going this way,
right? Going kind of away from you.
And then it does one of these and flies
over the camera.
Yeah, if the range data is correct.
No, no, you can see it visually. You don't even need the range data.
It's moving towards the camera.
So first it's doing this. It's moving
perpendicular. And then it does
this. We shall revisit.
Okay. Okay, next one.
I like it. We're moving.
Okay, Aguadilla.
Aguadilla.
So this is off the coast of
Chile? Puerto Rico. Puerto Rico.
Okay.
And this is 2013. It's on the
coast of Puerto Rico. 2013
on the coast of Puerto Rico, where
there are a lot of
sightings. This is
over the airport.
At Aguadilla,
a big tourist destination. There's a bunch of
hotels up the beach.
It shows an object that appears to
be flying in a circle
around the airport.
And this is something that's been analyzed
by a lot of people.
And the interesting thing about it is
that it flies in a circle, which is
kind of unusual for such a small object
to be doing. And then later
it appears to
go underwater. It looks like it
goes underwater. And then it appears to spit
into two, spit into
two parts.
But a lot
of people have analyzed this. And pretty
much everyone who has analyzed it has realized
that if you take the lines of sight, which
you can get from the camera here,
all the numbers on the screen,
the
lines of sight all intersect over
the airport. Not just at the intersection,
a line over the airport. And that line
represents a vector that's moving more or less at
wind speed, about 18 miles per hour.
And it kind of decreases a little bit as
the balloon or the object sinks
to a lower altitude.
And a theory that was
proposed by the head
of Brazil's
UFO investigation
department, Ruben Lianza,
is that it's actually two
Chinese lanterns, wedding lanterns,
kind of tied together.
And that's why you see early on in the video
you see kind of like two shapes
kind of like moving around each other.
Partway through the video you see
the heat source and then
you see kind of the paper canopy of the
lanterns
behind it. And then when it gets to this
section here, this is where we see it kind of disappear.
Now,
this is thermal footage.
So we're seeing the black is the hot
of the flame and there's some blooming or
glare. And then when it moves,
so that's hidden by the paper, the paper
canopy, it
becomes, you know, it's almost the same
color as the ocean and the
media compression just can't keep up with it so it
disappears. You can more or less see it a lot of
the time. And then it reappears and it
kind of like splits into two
which ties in with the earlier observations
that there appears to be two heat
sources, that there's actually
two wedding lanterns.
And more research was that there are
actually hotels up the beach, upwind
from this location which release
these types of
wedding lanterns. And then this was all
confirmed basically by Arrow
analyzing this and coming to the same
conclusion. What do you think, Merrick?
It'll probably cost me some Twitter
followers. Great, I agree. I don't have any
objections. Okay.
So this is, let's get to here.
So you guys agree on something? Yeah, absolutely.
There are people who won't agree.
SCU, for example. Let me just be clear, I
agree with the vast variety of mixed
work. Sure, yeah.
Because as we know throughout history,
80-90% of these things are
prosaically explained, misidentified.
We've seen this in New Jersey.
People are literally videotaping
or recording aircrafts.
Speaking of which, the world is
going crazy. There are drones in sensitive
air spaces, quote-unquote drones,
and I'm just saying quote-unquote because
nobody has any good,
even you have to admit, Mick,
nobody's coming out and saying anything
clear about these things on either side.
One thing that's very, very clear is that there's a lot
of misidentifications. I believe that.
I'm sure. And there really aren't
any good videos that are unambiguously
of drones or
some kind of beyond-drone-type
things. Sure, but would you admit that there's
a spike globally of
these weird sightings in sensitive
air spaces? Is this because there actually
are more of them or is it because people are
reporting more of them because of this story has kind of
blossomed up from these original
stories of drones over air
bases? I don't have the data, but my
strong bias would be that there are more
sightings going on. All these
false sightings are just people
looking at planes, so there's a huge spike in those.
So why wouldn't it be
all of this from this huge spike?
Push back slightly, Mick, just a little bit.
You're right,
people misidentify things.
But I think you
might be pushing this
narrative a little too far because
really the very
obvious plane videos, there's only like three
or four of them, they're obvious,
that are planes. There's
not that many. There's a lot more
that are resolvable
as planes if we know the actual location.
I got sent one the other day
and tracked down the actual planes, and it just looked like
these little points of light. Let's get to the
weirdest one. It's
gone completely viral on Twitter. It says Manchester
Airport, June 2024
sighting, and you have
an employee, an anonymous pilot and
co-pilot,
see this thing, and
I think the quote is,
I've worked in
aviation for a very long time,
and I know
what a weather balloon looks like.
The report is that this orb comes down,
hits the tarmac, and then shoots up.
But he also said it was the size of a small
car, and that's 24
inches tops.
We did very detailed analysis, 3D
recreation of this thing, from
the exact viewpoints and using all the data
that is at the most 24 inches.
Okay, and Merrick, what do you think?
I got nothing, guys.
I don't know.
So you basically
agree with Merrick? I think it's a balloon and some
artifacts in the image there.
I got nothing.
We have this interesting case of
quote unquote UAP activity near Duke
Energy's nuclear facility in North
Carolina. I personally find
this interesting because my Occam's
Razor belief generally
is that it's prosaically explainable
away. The thing I hold
out interest in
is when the sighting
occurs around a nuclear facility.
I find it very fascinating that
there is a town next
to the Fukushima Prefecture in Japan
called Ino, which is dedicated to
UFOs, and it's where they had
their famous 2011 spill
nuclear,
and then there have been sightings in
Bariloche, Argentina, which has its own civilian
nuclear grid, and then if you look
at Edward J. Ruppelt, the book you sighted,
the vast majority of the sightings
that he takes seriously
occur around sensitive
nuclear facilities in the US.
And then you have Robert Hastings' work,
and so if I had to
again, steal me in the UFO
position, it would be around this nuclear
connection. So this I find interesting because
you have UAP activity around this
nuclear power plant. Should we just watch
the video? And I'll just quickly say, Jesse,
your point that the nuclear
connection is extraordinary.
It is remarkable, and I've written about
it. Sorry, go ahead. No, I mean
it's amazing, and more and more
Roswell itself, the
site of the 509th Atomic Bomber Squadron,
the first bomber squadron in the US,
you have, you know, the
Trinity Test Site possibly, there was a crash
there. Unclear, you have D.D. Johnson
on one side, you have Jacques Fillet on the other side
they're kind of arguing. Well, Lani Zamora
happened a couple miles from there. A couple
miles from there. It would be the reason
that New Mexico is such a hot spot.
It's kind of a
I think there's a lot of
reporting bias. You get
reports on highly sensitive sites
just because people are much more vigilant.
People who
work on these sites are trained to report
things, and people who work at Wal-Mart
are not trained to report things like that. You gotta read
the cable, and this is, again, to
John Greenwald's credit,
you gotta read the cable, like 1975,
do you know anything about those incursions
where you can see in a
literally a cable
to the Pentagon. Is that
nuclear specific? Absolutely.
A hundred percent. And it says
the language is a clear
intent, so there's objects hovering
ten feet above their
nuclear weapon storage facilities, right?
And there are videos of the plume of
various detonations where you see the UFOs
like there's one, Blue
Gill Triple Prime in 1962.
I think they were at the spot of plunge
or something else, but I can't remember what they were exactly,
but that was resolved as I recall.
Was it? We'll look it up.
We should look it up. I'd love to resolve.
Even Virginia in Brazil
where James Fox went down
and investigated for a moment of contact where you have all these
hapless
local citizens who don't seem like liars.
Is there a nuclear power station there?
That was the start of
their nuclear program is what I've heard.
And so, I don't know.
It just keeps popping up with
the nuclear thing. And it does cut
through. Lakenheath, just recently.
Lakenheath, there you go. It's allegedly
according to open source reporting that
it's supposed to host US nuclear
weapons. Lakenheath was one of the
site of one of the most extraordinary
historical accounts. 1956,
James McDonald wrote
quite a bit about this in
folks at home. Just look up Lakenheath
1956, McDonald, you'll
find CIA documents.
You'll find a really
lengthy write up on the Princeton.edu
website that is just absolutely
astounding. Also,
Royal Air Force Bentwaters.
1980, yeah.
You have a bunch of witnesses because
it was joint managed by the US
and the Royal Air Force. You have a bunch
of John Burroughs, Jim
Penniston, Colonel Halt who did
the investigation. And the audio.
I was listening to the book on the way here, UFO
news. Yeah, what do you think about
that? I told you to read that.
I can certainly see how it would seem compelling because there's
account after account after account of
something seemed. And if you meet, I
actually get the sense from you.
I don't think you're a liar at
all. I think you're very, no, I mean it.
I really, I get this
clear attention to detail,
good, earnest
vibe. And that's the same vibe
I get from Robert Hastings. In fact,
the way I connected
with Robert Hastings. I don't think he's lying
in the book. No, I know you're not accusing him of that.
But he's dedicated his life
to this and the amount of granular
detail. I mean, you should meet him if you're
interested. He reached out to me
that this is how I got in touch with him. I made
my peace with David Grush.
And I screwed it up
and I overstated the case. I was like, you know,
UFOs and nukes,
you have, you know, over a hundred
and I go missileers,
ICBM security personnel, like a few.
And it was, it's a hundred
and seventy total witnesses, but it wasn't a
hundred, you know, radar operators or whatever.
And I just dispersed in the moment.
But I love it. He
emailed me, said Jesse,
it was only like twelve to
fifteen. I don't remember the exact number.
But radar operators, the
rest were ICBM security
personnel, you know, missile
technicians, you know, whatever. And
it was, and then that's been
literally like all of my communications
with him have been around that.
And he'll correct you immediately if you're wrong.
And if you're overstating a case.
Hastings is outstanding. Are there actual statistics here?
Like actual statistical
analysis of, you know,
sightings near nukes versus
other ways that are actually invalid?
Well, yeah, it would be Edward J. Ruppelt's
original study where he came in.
That was
done from 1947 to 1952.
And then he wrote a book about it in 1956.
I mean, the Colorado
sightings, right? The 2019, 2020,
those were over those nuclear
missile silos, partially,
partially. And they mirrored 1965,
the same exact, like they're
witnesses talking about up and down movement,
bright flashing lights. Where have we seen that before?
And it's undocumented, right?
140 some witnesses.
And I've met some, I met Robert Salas at
Malmstrom in 1967. You know,
that was his sighting where,
you know, ten of these sites were
disarmed, according to him. And I've
also met Mario Woods, who was stationed at,
you know, South Dakota Ellsworth Air Force Base
in 1978. He claimed
to have boarded a craft and been abducted.
But this guy maintained acute
clearance for 20 years after this. And
all these guys, it's the most sensitive
clearances. They're on what's called the PRP
program where they have to report if they're taking
ibuprofen. So I do find that
compelling. It speaks to the whole, like, issue
with, you know, Marco Rubio.
We were talking about it in the start, like,
you know, either there's some crazy people in power
or, you know, what they're saying is true.
And he leans towards true, right? Just to be clear.
Rubio's very clearly leaning towards
I trust them. But there is evidence that there are
crazy people, but
people with very strange ideas. But who?
Lekatsky, for example. He's like
a rocket scientist. Right.
But I think the more you
go into, like, you know, highly
competent, you know, impressive
circles of people, the more you realize
a lot of these people are weird. But who?
Tim Taylor. Yeah, Tim
Taylor's super weird, but he's also, you know, working
with Elon Musk around, you know, various
launches. How weird. That's interesting.
That just speaks to, like, how much
weirdness you can actually get.
But at what point do you say, at what point
do you say, at what point do you say
reality is weird and that
a proxy for somebody's
credibility is actually how
high functioning they are in society. Or perhaps it's just a big
tolerance for weird within the Pentagon.
How weird do you have, like, you have to be
pretty darn weird to go to the ICIG
specter general
and say, I was part of a
I was part of a
reverse engineering program.
That's right.
Forty people have done.
Allegedly. That would crush test
final growth.
Does that make sense, right? Okay, there's
could be weird people, but there's a different level of
I was on this program.
I worked on this
NHI craft.
That's border, that's delusion.
There's weird and then there's delusion if they're not
We don't know what they said.
Well, enough for
the Senate intel kit, my god.
We should move forward. You should meet Hastings at one point.
Let's watch this Duke video.
Bro. I am.
Oh my god.
What the fuck is going on?
Oh my fucking god.
Oh, I wish.
No, that ain't no brain, yo.
It's always a pleasure to meet you.
It's blast.
Oh, we got a plane.
Bro.
Well, top one looks like the landing lights
of the plane.
It made a fucking triangle.
It's three lights in the sky.
We actually got a fucking.
Oh my god.
Yeah, you can't get much from that.
Oh, that's.
Wait, so one of them, so it's a triangle
and then one seems to kind of mirror off.
Yeah.
Look
left there.
The bottom one there is just sitting on the.
The bottom one is became.
Yo, Hastings is coming towards us now.
And he's zoomed in.
Okay, what are you guys making
this?
Mick? Well the white light at the top you can see
there, it's got two lights, which kind of suggests to me
that it's the landing lights of a distant plane
very far away. We see this quite a lot in these videos. People will see a plane that's
coming directly towards them. It could be like 40, 50, 100 miles away. Not that far.
And it looks like this. It just sits there and it eventually raises up and it will eventually
go over them. The other lights I don't know, they were kind of orange looking. I'm not
sure what they were. It could be helicopters. It could be drones.
If they're landing lights, Mick, can we test this? Right? Because if I were...
What?
Yeah, we could.
I'm just saying like, because we know where this... Do we know what facility this was?
Yeah, Duke's Energy.
But do we have the time and location?
Well, no, no, but landing lights implies that there's an airport and a final approach path
somewhere close by. We can test your hypothesis.
If we have the location.
Yeah, so it's Southport, North Carolina. So we should look into that.
That's not really accurate enough. You need it.
Okay, fair enough.
Down to the street, pretty much.
And then we have some other people commenting. I have seven videos of them from last night,
around 30 minutes of good video. I'm in Asheville, North Carolina. The two mean ones were in
red, were a red and blue one. The blue one was amazing to watch. Pulsate grow 5X larger
than shrink back to size. I don't know.
People post videos of things that are obviously planes and think they're the UFOs. So it's
not surprising people will post videos of lights in the sky and think they're the UFOs.
I'm buddies with Tyler, so I'll get some more.
What I find more compelling maybe than this is, and I'll just be very quick, the Langley
incursions. There's a witness video where the guy zooms out and you can see, I don't
know, 10, 15 flashing light. And you can tell they're very, very far out. That is interesting
in itself, but you see that over the Goldwater training ranges of video. Same thing, just
unbelievable amounts of flashing lights in the sky. Drones and, oh, by the way, Air Force
pilots have been reporting drones up to 36 drones, up to 36,000 feet. There's like 30
or 40 reports over the last couple of years that they, metallic objects, eight or nine,
it's all documented. It's all out there.
Can we all agree that we need to figure out what is going on?
More information would be great. More videos would be great. More analysis from Aero would
be great. More experts should weigh in.
I think that's the takeaway. Please, if you're watching at home.
We have to wrap up in a minute, but do you guys have any opinion on this New Jersey
thing? Should we play this?
Look, I ...
I'll just say quickly, we have the FBI, we have FAA, there's drone restrictions in place.
There's the governors involved, all the elected officials.
It's a flap.
You think it's a flap?
Yeah.
I think it's a flap. I don't think there's very much there.
Do you think Colorado 2019, 2020 was a flap?
I doubt it very much so.
Can I read a couple of emails or do we have to go?
A couple of emails.
Quick.
Thanks to Doug Johnson. I'll make this very quick.
Drone activity. Here we go. Reports from Colorado indicate that drones were not flying as a
group or pack, but as a single unit. Chase County, Nebraska, Sheriff, Deputy, reported
observing 30 to 50 ...
Sheriff.
Hold on.
... 30 to 50 flying independently of each other with a larger, quote, mother ship hovering
for hours.
You're seeing planes flying overhead.
Yeah, this idea of a mother ship and then other crafts coming out of the mother ship.
Chris Mellon, former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Intelligence under both Clinton
and Bush said that there was this mother ship dynamic going on with the Hampton Air Force
base incursion as well, where you have these little saucers flying out of a mother ship.
I don't know.
Here's a ...
Here's a hypothesis for the green meteorites in UFOs and nukes, that there was a mother
ship outside the atmosphere and the green meteorites were ...
UFOs and nukes mentions this as well, yes.
He's a K-9 trooper from ... I'll be very quick ... K-9 trooper from Kansas.
He had these fly right over his head.
He said one of the drones had a really bright light on it, like a spotlight.
That drone stayed relatively stationary at that location.
He then said there were anywhere from 10 to 15 drones that flew all kinds of patterns
around that stationary drone.
At one point, one of those flew directly over his house.
He had night vision with him, so he tried to look at it, made no sound, even though
the wind was calm.
All right.
Eyewitness accounts.
Great.
Video for all we need.
Merrick, Mick, this was awesome.
I appreciate you guys both.
Thanks for doing this, Mick.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
This was great.
You guys were, I felt, mostly pretty civil and cool with each other.
I think both of us, all of us, want just more experts to look at this, more data, and
more witnesses, again, to the extent you're not compromising American national security,
come out and talk about this stuff.
I enjoy this very much.
I enjoy solving cases and investigating them, and if it turns out that I'm wrong about things,
that would be really interesting.
You'll buy me a beer.
Agreed.
And if Kimball's debunked, I'll buy you a beer.
And I have a bet that I guess we never resolved.
We were talking about this before the show.
I bet you $10,000, which is insane because I gave you one-to-one odds, and it should
be million-to-one odds that 80%, we'd get 80% consensus in academia, military, and
civilian sector that non-human intelligence or future humans are occupying these sort
of anomalous crafts, and that people would, this would become the consensus in 10 years,
which is, as you pointed out, kind of hard to verify, ultimately, this 80% consensus,
but you moved that number from 10,000 to 1,000.
I just like more reasonable bets because it avoids legalities.
I think it's an unreasonable bet for me.
It's like a joke for me.
I'm giving you free money.
Let's just bet a beer, then.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Awesome.
Thanks, man.
We appreciate it.
Yeah.
Thank you, guys.
This was great.
Awesome.
All right.
Cool.
So we're back with Mick and Merrick, and we felt compelled to extend our debate somewhat
because so much bombshell footage has been released since our long debate.
Specifically, we're talking about this egg video that has kind of broken the internet
over the last couple of days associated with Ross Coulthart's News Nation story involving
psionic assets, specifically a guy named Jake Barber, who was part of a crash retrieval
team, involving these psionic assets, people psychically calling in exotic material of
which this egg is claimed to be kind of a part of that.
And it's being hooked on to, well, I guess you want to play it, Mick, and we can kind
of analyze it from there.
Sure.
Yeah, let's just play it.
Yeah.
So it looks like it's on the end of a long rope.
It looks like a big egg.
Yeah.
It's kind of swaying around, then it hits the ground.
And you see it kind of roll over, and you see the kind of wrapping around it loose.
And then you see these wires.
And this is from the TV show.
It kind of went in and slowed it down a little bit.
And you can see like, you know, this lighting coming from over here, there's a shadow in
this direction.
There's a little bit of a roll when it hits the ground, which shows it has a little bit
of inertia.
And it's not a super high quality video, but you can see that it is kind of like an egg
shaped object on the end of a rope of some sort.
We don't know whether it's, is this a real video?
Is it something that someone's faked?
I think it was sent anomalously to Ross.
It wasn't actually taken by the Jake Barber guy, was it?
It was sent anomalously.
No, I'm just joking.
It's like an anomaly.
Yeah, it was sent by a third party to News Nation, not by Jake.
And it doesn't show the actual event that he was talking about, which is odd because
that means that there's multiple versions of these eggs being picked up by different
people, which apparently there's all these different eggs that people are picking up.
Maybe it's a very common shape, but it's kind of a new shape to me.
Like the egg, I guess it's one of the ones that crops up, but it's not like a tic tac.
It's not like a flying saucer.
It's an egg.
I did spend a little bit of time trying to replicate it, and I made a little egg in a
little sling, so I've got like the whole caboodle.
It kind of led me to think it's probably not a scale model.
I don't think it's actually an egg-shaped thing.
I think it's probably something larger.
I think it might actually be from a helicopter, and it might be something being moved.
But yeah, like all these videos, the quality really isn't there.
It's just very low resolution and it's very short.
It's very short.
Where do they chop it off?
So not a lot to go by.
Interesting, though.
Oh, and the backstory, of course, is very interesting.
I saw Marik, you were talking to Ross Goldthart and Tim Gallaudet about this, and they were
talking all about all kinds of strange things like psychic powers and stuff like that, which
was kind of an interesting mixture of things.
I think we've got a lot of this UFO serve as just nuts and bolts.
This would be nuts and bolts if it was just like an object being retrieved.
But then we've got the whole psionic aspect of it, which is a bit weird.
Yeah.
Marik, what's your take?
Damn it, it looks like an egg.
That's all we got, really.
What I do find interesting is, and again, I try to bring a bit of an analytic perspective,
but there's a gentleman named Eric Taber who went to Aero.
I don't know if, Jesse, if you're familiar with this, but he's an auditor who did speak
to Aero, and he spoke of an egg-shaped craft being retrieved, and I believe this is at
Area 51.
I don't believe he was a firsthand witness, so take it as you will.
But again, that shape does come up.
I agree with Mick.
It's not your standard saucer.
It's not your orb.
It's not your sphere.
The stuff that you hear a lot, it's not a triangle.
But it seems like there is some precedent for another story of this nature and involving
an anomalous craft that is egg-shaped.
It's just a shame we don't have a better video of it, because it just remains somewhat ambiguous.
Yeah, it definitely felt like this high-resolution footage promise, maybe it's slightly underwhelming.
And then at the same time, in the instance in which this was a real thing, this is actually
very good footage comparable to what we've had in the past.
So it kind of depends on the objective truth, which is this weird epistemic impasse that
we're facing, where if it is true, it's actually a really good video, and then if it's not,
obviously not.
Yeah, I guess that's all.
All these videos are big if true.
All these claims are big if true.
But better than FLIR and Gimbal and GoFast.
These are different sensor modalities.
I'm back to differ, Jesse.
Well, not better from an analytic perspective, the way you're looking at it, Meric, but better
from, again, if we were to get corroborative sensor data, it would be better for the eye.
Yeah, this isn't doing anything, though.
It's just inertly hanging on the end of a rope, and we've got UAPs supposed to have
all these observables, like sudden acceleration, defying gravity, being hard to see.
I think what was it, low observability and transmedium travel.
It's doing none of these things.
So it's hard to kind of classify this even as a UAP.
I guess it's the context of the story that's around it that makes it interesting.
Then we got this Jake Barber, who I believe he was a mechanic on the helicopter, not the pilot.
I'm not sure.
I think we might be learning more about that, Mick.
Okay, that's cool.
But he did some kind of crash retrieval, apparently.
There's an interesting story and all kinds of other aspects of that story.
But it's not doing anything.
Which is what we need.
We need videos of things doing things.
What do you guys make a...
I feel like the UFO world took a bit of a hard left turn away from Cartesian space,
aliens from a distant galaxy and into Psy, parapsychology, almost more in line with occult practices or something.
How do you guys feel about that?
It seems like a lot of that just suddenly cropped up.
It was weird because before it was all nuts and bolts.
And then we suddenly had this drone stuff, which is even more nuts and bolts.
Everybody's getting into drones.
And then it's kind of like a hard swing now to psionic powers and Steven Greer type stuff.
Like Dr. Steven Greer, who does this CE5 stuff.
And then Ross Colfart, who brought this out, says that he went out with these people
and they had these psionic assets who could take control of craft,
which sounds bizarre and frankly ridiculous claim that you could actually cyclically start take over an alien craft.
You think the aliens would be able to stop that type of thing.
But it does seem like a weird shift.
And someone mentioned that they thought things were kind of dying down a bit in the UFO space.
And so perhaps people are reaching for more interesting things.
I don't know. But it was weird, definitely.
What do you think, Merrick?
I agree. It's a shift.
Again, I have focused on the nuts and bolts aspect.
I will say just my own personal progression.
I've been very open about this.
I was deeply skeptical of UFOs.
I missed the 2017 story.
I think I mentioned this in the longer version.
But I've gone through a few of my own mini oncological shocks throughout this journey.
And again, I'm skeptical of everything I see.
Just kind of right off the bat, I would need to see evidence.
I have seen evidence.
Now the gimbal video, Nick knows that we've talked to some experts
and none of them agree with his theory.
And one of the most important ones explicitly disagrees with this theory.
So those are steps on my journey from this is all tinfoil hat,
whack jobbery to, wow, there's something to this.
Then the next step was I had people telling me,
hey, man, there have been crash retrievals.
And I was deeply skeptical of that having been in the government.
I was like, there's no possible way that secret could have been kept for X amount of years.
And now we have people on the road.
We had Chuck Schumer alleging that in congressional legislation.
So it's remarkable.
I've gone through several ontological shocks.
And I might go through another one with a science.
I don't know.
Keeping an open mind.
Right off the bat and keeping an open mind.
And I'll just say last, I'll add that Jake and I think the other special operator,
Fred Baker, who's truly a legend in the community I've found in over the last 24 hours,
they've said openly, don't trust us.
We'll show you.
So, okay.
That's good.
Yeah.
They got a timeline on that.
You know, we're doing it when it's good.
But I think that's great.
That's the right attitude.
Yeah, definitely.
Definitely.
I would definitely appreciate seeing more data and just the stories aren't cutting it.
We need to see actual evidence.
I agree.
I think everybody agrees on that, right?
Yeah.
And Merrick, you had something you wanted to bring up as well.
Real quick.
So I'll just tee this up.
And Jeremy Corbell, there's a video.
Mick, I think you figured out when this was posted first.
But this is the quote unquote Iraq gimbal video.
But I'll just tee it up first.
Jeremy got an interview with the Marine who actually recorded this.
This was in 2008.
And he's in what's called a LAV, LAV 25.
I think it's a lightly armored vehicle.
He's got a thermal site.
And they're out there in the middle of the desert, truly in the middle of nowhere,
close to 100 miles from the Syrian border, doing overwatch and reconnaissance.
So he's looking around to see what's around to make sure nobody,
the bad guys aren't sneaking up on them at night.
So he's got this thermal site and he sees an object rising, in his words,
rising up off of the desert floor.
And he says it goes up about 25 meters,
then it moves to about 30 to 50 meters to his left,
comes back to that center point,
moves about 30 meters to his right,
and then goes back to that center point and then slowly starts climbing.
And then at that point, he's like, this is bizarre.
I'm going to record this.
And he starts recording the screen.
And then we have this video.
I won't bore people with the full video,
but I do want to maybe quickly just point out if I can share my screen.
There are some intriguing similarities.
Is that coming through for you guys?
Yep.
There are some intriguing similarities to Gimbal.
I think we can agree on that.
And if Gimbal is this never-before-seen anomaly,
no expert has ever seen this before.
I mean, Mick, we were on the call with the AT Flir expert.
He says this is, quote, bizarre.
I've never seen anything like this.
No one could be able to see anything like this.
So when you see these matches, that's interesting to me.
Oh, and by the way,
these anomalies just happen to look like the classic saucer.
What are the odds, right?
That's what makes it fun, isn't it?
It makes it more interesting.
I'll just quickly add one more thing.
There's an interesting video.
And Mick, I know you did a semi-debunk of this,
but I do have a few bones to pick, per usual.
Is that coming through for you guys?
Yeah, I see it.
It's kind of stepping.
Yeah, so it does this stepping thing, right?
And then it would slow down at half speed.
So he moves the camera up, and you see it jolt down, right?
So that's moving the cameras, right?
So this system is a thermal system.
You can move it left, right, up, down, and it's a thermal sight.
So the barrel, the gun barrel, there's video of this online.
The gun barrel is actually pointed to where he...
This is how they shoot the weapon without getting out of the vehicle, right?
Yeah, it's a gun sight.
Exactly, it's literally a gun sight.
So you can see him moving, but that up and down,
that kind of that jittery, that jumpy ascent is very interesting to me.
Yeah, it's an interesting little thing.
I think, again, we have the issue of it being very poor quality.
We see here, you see all the compression blocks and everything and the pixels.
I think there's a couple of points I'd like to make.
The first is you did that comparison earlier where you did two frames
that look very similar with the gimbal and this Iraqi gimbal.
One of them is in the gimbal frame that you showed was in black-hot mode,
and this is in white-hot.
And the contrast curves are very different for those two modes.
It's not really... One isn't the inverse of the other.
So you're comparing a black-hot to a white-hot isn't a very good comparison.
And if you were to take the white-hot images,
which are at the start of the gimbal video,
they're actually quite different shape to the rest.
You see a more irregular shape.
It's kind of like... You're familiar with it.
It's kind of like narrower at one end and then wider at the other.
It doesn't really look like that.
So if you were to actually take that...
I saw your comment, and as you know, Mick,
over the course of the gimbal video, the object grows, it gets bigger,
and it does actually become that shape.
So I think you're missing the point.
Anyway, we could talk about this.
Why is it changing shape, though?
Is it magically morphing from one shape into another?
It doesn't really make any sense.
As the jet gets closer, it becomes more defined, right?
Well, I think, obviously, as you know,
I think that the gimbal shape is actually a camera artifact.
I know you don't like the word glare.
You don't like the word glare.
A lot of people agree with me, but...
No, experts in the world agree with you.
Yeah, but then the experts that you found...
We went over this before.
The experts you found, they also thought that it looked like an SR-71,
which it looks absolutely nothing like an SR-71.
So, you know, really all these experts,
really very good at analyzing this particular video,
they took a quick take.
And the guy told you that it was just a quick take
and it wasn't meant to be an assessment.
Let's get to that rule.
What do you think we're looking at right here?
I don't know what we're looking at,
but I think, again,
it's something that doesn't show the observables.
It's far away,
so we can't really see it.
What do you make of this jumping?
Yeah, the motion, I think.
Obviously, we don't see
the really dramatic movements
that he talked about.
He's rising up from the desert,
moving left and right.
We see it moving slowly up.
Now, we see it kind of looking like it's kind of
moving a little bit like this, up and down,
kind of relative to the background.
I think what we're seeing there
is actually the turret
of the vehicle, or perhaps the vehicle itself,
with the engine, just moving a tiny little bit
up and down, which would make the camera move.
He talked about how he was raising
the... I have to be careful not to do a Nazi salute here,
like Elon Musk just did.
Raising up the
camera thing,
so it was always pointing in the sky, and he got
embarrassed that he thought other people might be looking at him,
and so he lowered it down.
But I think doing that is going to make it kind of wobble a little bit,
because we're kind of zoomed in quite a lot here.
So I think we're just seeing camera movement.
It doesn't register exactly
with the clouds, because the clouds
are very low
frequency, in technical terms.
They're very smooth
curves, so they don't move very much because of
the video compression. Now, this video,
I think it was part of a dump
that somebody did.
There's a UFO
site on Twitter, I think it's called
Ray Fios, or something like,
ARIEFOUFOS,
and they uploaded a whole bunch of stuff
to MEGA.CO.NZ,
New Zealand NZ,
and so there might actually
be a better version of this out there, which might
actually help resolve some of these things.
So if someone knows of that better version,
then that would be good to have.
In thermal, you incorrectly thought this
was a night vision, and thought this was flying.
What do you think it is?
Well, I still think the most likely thing
is essentially the landing lights of an
aircraft, which do show up in thermal,
because the halogen lights,
the hot lights,
LED lights
wouldn't show up. How would they be bouncing
up and down like that, if they were LED?
Oh, they're not.
That's the camera bouncing up and down.
So it's like very little jiggles
of the camera light, like here,
would actually make things move around.
And why would the lights
be irregularly shaped? Why wouldn't they
be uniformly distributed?
Because it's bright, it's looking
directly into the
camera. It's like the usual
glare type thing. So I think it would be
bright lights in the middle on the landing gear,
and maybe two lights on the side. I don't know, though.
I mean, it could be that
this is...
Why would there be landing
lights a hundred miles from
the Syrian border in
the middle of the desert in Anbar
province, or wherever this was? Well, maybe because it was
landing somewhere. It's a plane.
It's a military plane. It's not like everything
up there fires black.
You can't see lights in thermal.
You just cannot see... Oh, you can see heat in thermal,
though, and some lights are very hot.
You're telling me that as well.
I don't know.
I'm not ready to rule
this out. Where's the engine exhaust if this is a
plane? The engine exhaust? Well, it would be behind
where you're looking at.
If it's coming at you,
you'd be... Yeah. No, it's
behind something. When something comes at you, you
don't see the things that are behind it. I mean, you can't
see the back of my head, can you?
It's coming at you like this, right?
You can see the plumes going... No,
you really can't. You really can't because
if it's far away,
I've taken lots of video of planes
that are, say, like 50 to 100 miles away
and where they're coming towards you, the angle
between the plane and
you really isn't that much.
That's one big point we're looking at.
This is just so bizarre
to me. It is pretty bizarre, isn't it?
Yeah, but I don't know what it is. I mean, it could be
like a weird drone or something,
but I don't really think it just shows
any kind of... Stumped undone ears.
Well, that's fair enough. It just
happens to look like him. I mean, look
at this video. It's like you can
barely read the timecode at the top
of it. It's a crappy video.
If we had
the original video, maybe we'll be able
to see a little bit more. Maybe we'll be able to prove
that it was one thing or another, but
I really don't think we can rule things out from this
particular video. I mean, I see the plane
thing isn't super
compelling. It's not
compelling at all.
What I think is it doesn't
actually demonstrate any of the observables.
It doesn't demonstrate
extraordinary motion.
It's just something... It just
happens to look like the gimbal in this particular
frame. As I said, you're taking
white heart against black heart,
and if you take all the white heart
frames from gimbal, they don't actually
match.
Because it's not morphed into a
different shape yet. It gets closer to
it. It gets 15% larger as it gets
closer, which is the exact size at the
correct distance. Why is it changing
shape? Getting larger doesn't change
shape. Sure, you pick some frames here that look the same.
So if you're flying in a jet, Mick,
you're a pilot, so you know this, right? If you're flying
at something, it gets larger as you
get closer to it, right? I'm familiar with perspective
in America. Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
So that's what happens in a gimbal. And it just happens
to grow at
the exact same size
at the distance. But it doesn't change
shape. I mean, this egg
isn't changing shape from here
to here. It's just a bigger egg.
One end isn't going to get
thicker, which is what happens in a gimbal.
You realize perspective, right?
And the way they come up
from behind, right? Or they're
maneuvering to come in behind
it, right? So it's not like they're coming directly
at it, Mick. You know that.
So you're saying
the angle of the object changes?
Yes, absolutely.
I look forward to you doing
a 3D model of the gimbal object
that will demonstrate this change
in shape. It's already in your Syrac.
Anyway, we can go on for days.
We could go on for days.
And I go into this
in the
longer interview. But again, the bottom line is
no experts agree with Mick.
And literally, one of the
top air-to-air infrared
experts explicitly disagree with this
theory. Yeah, I came up with another cockamamie
theory, which is completely wrong as well.
So what are you going to do? I think
we've got some crappy videos here,
which are unfortunately the best videos that we have.
And I think that in itself is a huge
clue about ufology. The only videos
that we get are crappy videos.
And the reason that we only get crappy
videos is that the videos were better quality
would be able to tell what the thing was. And then
we'd know it
was a UFO or not. None of the
good videos show UFOs.
All we're left with is these crappy videos.
It's the low information zone.
That's how UFOs work. I don't
think so, Mick. And I hope
we learn more. But the Pentagon has
said that they have, quote,
true anomalies that they're so
stumped by. And this is because the new director
in the Pentagon's UFO office has
said, we have true anomalies that
I, as an engineer and a physicist,
I'm paraphrasing, do not understand.
And I do not know anybody else
who understands. So let's see what those videos are.
That's because they haven't got the information.
But yeah, I'm looking forward to seeing those
true anomalies. They said they're so stumped
that they need the public. So that's me.
That's you, Mick. That's me. That's everybody.
That's everybody that's watching.
They can use my software,
Open Source, SITREC. Anyone can use it.
And hopefully they will. And maybe it'll help
them solve it. I'd be happy to help.
Whatever we're
seeing is definitely at the margins
of reality. And so
I think we wouldn't be having this debate if it was
super clear. The margins
of perception, which
isn't really the margins of reality.
Well, there you go. Now you're talking
like us. I mean,
I think, yeah, the margins of
our, because we, there are doors
of perception, to quote William Blake
or Aldous Huxley, and
the optical range that involves
400 to 700 nanometers.
And if you have
these things traveling
close to the speed of light, they're probably doing
one of two things. They're probably,
if they're moving away
from you, they're stretching light. And so
that's like the bottom
end of the visible band, but probably lower
than what we can actually see. And then
if they're coming towards you, they're crunching
light. And so that's, you know, your microwaves.
And so it's either, you know, it's
going to be infrared or microwave,
and you need these sensor modalities.
Normal civilians don't have those sensor modalities.
And so it kind of makes sense
that you would either get blue
shifted or red shifted optical, or
you would get like other sensors, and
you'd have to debate it endlessly
because it wouldn't really look like
the normal eye.
Have some non-UFO physicists
about that. I mean, Hal Puthoff says
things like that, yes, but I think you
should need to ask some, I hesitate to say
real physicists, but someone who isn't
perhaps so enmeshed in this whole
UAP thing.
What would they say? Yeah, go for it.
Just very quickly, and
Jesse, to build on that, there's
a documented history of
the most important, kind of one of the
most important historical documents in
this whole topic, is what's called the
Twining Memo from 1947.
General Nathan Twining, who I
believe went on to become the chairman of the Joint
Chiefs of Staff, he
wrote a memo that said, it listed
all the characteristics of UFOs,
and I think the one word that was underlying
was that they are invasive. As soon
as they are contacted by... That's how
they work. But you've
had aviators that have seen
metallic disks within a few hundred feet.
And I
lay this out, there's I think
at least 30 cases where multiple
credible witnesses, police officers,
pilots, engineers, have seen these
objects a hundred feet away.
And they all just happen to look like
the gimbal and the Iraq.
They're evasive, but not
when there's no camera available.
They're evasive, but they appear a hundred
feet away, where you would be able to get wonderful
4K video if you had your camera
with you. They're not really evasive.
They're just evading cameras.
This is the flaw in your analytic
approach.
I wish
you took some time to read through
the actual... And I'm happy to send you
the most compelling ones, and
you have to read through the
most compelling reports that are out there.
Multi-witness within several hundred
feet.
Go ahead, that's fine. I'm just telling you
that's my analytic basis, that's what I
go off. Yeah, your analytic basis is
stories from 70, 80 years ago.
It's not really very useful.
I would also say
if we're talking about things that travel
the speed of light, or do any of the things that seem
to break our conventional
physics,
and then you accept any of these stories
around consciousness, they probably
know how to evade
perception on more of a
root level than we're able
to even understand.
And we're getting away from the nuts and bolts
here. This is kind of like
speculative. I wouldn't say
it's getting away from nuts and bolts, it just
goes towards the Arthur C. Clarke quote that
any sufficiently advanced technology appears
to be magic. Can you demonstrate
that is happening though?
Demonstrate what is happening.
Any of what you just said.
They're detecting cameras and avoiding
them.
All good science is the
interplay between experimentation
and theory. And I would bucket in
anomalies with experimentation
where you see these observable things.
You can't just snap them to grid
on present theory of, you know,
this can't exist because of present physical
models. That would have, you know,
stagnated science in all sorts
of cases in the past, whether it's black
body radiation or the orbit of
Mercury, which were both very anomalous.
And so in this case, you're seeing this anomalous thing.
It's actually somewhat repeatable with two things.
Nuclear and
consciousness. And it's kind of on us to
theorize and we could, again, snap it back
to the grid of like general relativity
and say it's impossible. But
usually that loses the snapping
back to the grid and maybe, you know,
the person, you know,
making theories around this thing is
a heretic of the present, but they're often
vindicated in the future as kind of
the hero of the future, scientifically
speaking. So I'd say if you're looking at it
from like a meta-scientific,
you know, Thomas Kuhnian
model of like the structure of scientific
revolutions, you'd probably bet
on the anomaly. You wouldn't bet on the present
physics model. The present physics model
always goes away. You can't just bet
on every single anomaly out there and expect
them all to be true. It's not like, you know, they laugh
at you and you're right. It's
the most things that are weird
and aren't actually real. There are very few
of them that actually turn out to be interesting
things. And those are things that where we do have repeatable
and measurable data like
the orbit of Mercury and things like that.
We don't have that.
You know, we've got an accumulation of anecdotes
and accumulation of stories
and we've got lots and lots of them. It seems
compelling. It seems compelling
because you just
gather together all the ones that seem similar.
Here are all the ones from nuclear power stations.
Here are all the ones that show like shiny
disks. So yes, of course they're
remarkably consistent because you
gather them together. Do some actual
statistical analysis on this and see what
comes out.
Yeah, go for it. Yeah.
Go ahead.
No, you go. You go.
Battelle put out a very, very
deep analysis
of the 1947
and 1952
sightings. And guess what?
Fascinating.
33% of the most
credible sightings were unknown.
And those are ones that had enough data to
be analyzed.
Sure, but we have no idea what they consider to be
enough data. And we don't know any of those cases.
And it was like
80 years ago. It's
useless.
And then Edward J. Ruppelt
also
did a study for
pre-Blue Book, Sine and Grudge. And
it's the same thing. It was like 70%
of these cases show up around nuclear. That's the
reason Battelle was involved in the first place
because they're managing all this nuclear stuff
to begin with. And then you have
again, my editor is
going to kill me because I wanted to keep this kind of targeted.
But
we have 167 guys
with cue clearances
who have no reason, they haven't made
a dime from this. They're
sort of, they've been castigated
and shamed
and often demoted. If they sneeze, they have to report it.
Exactly, they have to report it
if they're on the personal
reliability program.
And that has to be an extremely
depressed number. That 167
has to actually be
10,700
or something. You really have to
multiply that by a ton.
How many people have cue clearance?
And how many of them are in positions where they have
to report things regardless?
And so they end up reporting a whole bunch
more stuff than your regular guy at Walmart
would report. That is a
very high subset of people
with cue clearance. And it's not just people
seeing these things
in distant places in the sky because of
hypervigilance around nuclear assets,
it's them shutting down the power
around these nuclear
sites, disarming the nukes themselves
and in certain cases these guys
claim to board crafts and
have things implanted inside them.
Well, it
seems a bit implausible to me.
You want those guys to control the nuclear button if they're all insane?
They're not all insane,
they're just normal people. They're regular people.
They have normal human failings.
But come on, I mean,
if a guy was guarding
these nuclear assets and claimed
these things and it wasn't repeatable,
like I just interviewed a guy named Mario Woods,
1977 Ellsworth Air Force Base
South Dakota,
boarded a craft or whatever
and woke up nine
miles in Lake
Newell away
from the base and has marks
on his body and
it was just a really crazy
experience. And he had his cue clearance
and retained it and worked at Sandia
and all sorts of other DOE labs,
I think Oak Ridge, for another 20
years. If you're like a higher
up person in
the DOE and you see that
and you have this one
guy claiming this crazy shit,
why would you continue to hire
him for the next 20 years
unless that was actually just this repeatable
thing happening to a lot of people and you were
hyper aware of the phenomena overall.
And you didn't blame the guy and you
realized he was totally lucid and mentally
sound. I wouldn't let that guy near
my nuclear acid. If he was the one guy,
if he was just the one guy.
He's not like he had his finger on
the bottom and he could launch things. He was
someone who worked there, he had a cue clearance
and people were like, David Grush
has a psychotic episode
and was voluntarily hospitalized and he
kept his clearance because people, just
because they have episodes
doesn't mean you automatically lose
your... He didn't have a psychotic episode
at all and he had too much to drink
one night and his buddy next to him was blown
up in war because of that.
PTSD, so it's
arguable.
But I'm just saying you don't lose your
clearance just because
one thing happened to you. If you get
cleared by a doctor later, you go to therapy
whatever, you can carry on working. Obviously
we don't know the details of that,
you know, HIPAA and everything.
I don't know if he volunteered exactly
what happened. Did he just go back
to work the next day and say, I saw aliens?
No, there was a very
clear protocol he underwent
due to
obviously the Air Force
having seen this before. They
checked him for certain things.
I'll just say
in the post
global war on terror era,
their PTS has
been a significant issue and yes
Jesse's correct that military
services have had to deal with
this a lot.
And there are protocols indeed, Jesse's
correct about that, that had
to be followed for Grush to
retain his clearance. But I don't
want to get into personal stuff. Mick, can I just quickly
I will shut up after this.
Mick, can I pin you down? The experts
have spoken, they say glare is
not a thing, they say what we're seeing in those
engines is what's called blooming
which is a well known artifact
in infrared technology and they said
and you know exactly what I'm talking about,
the credentials are impeccable.
Blooming would not have
resulted in that rotation.
What's the theory for the
gimbal video? I think
there's two possibilities, well there's three possibilities.
One is a real craft that's rotating.
One is that what I suggested is correct
then there's some kind of obstacle artifact that happens
before the sensor. And the other one
is like glare.
And the other one
you said you'd shut up Marek.
Then the third one
is that the derotation happens after
the sensor, like it's a digital derotation
which is something that's
in the patent.
So I don't know which one of those it is. I do know
that it looks like it's an optical artifact
that's rotating because of derotation
because of all the various observables that I
list in my video
and one of the experts says
that he thought I was right but for the wrong
reason. Another one said that
it looked like an SR-71, well they both said that actually.
So you know, I think perhaps
we need to talk to these experts in a bit more detail.
Drill down into this.
And for the record
the one who said you were right, he actually did not say
that, let's be clear, and I'll put up those emails
happily after this and we can have
that discussion. You know that's not true.
He said I think Mick is
right but for the wrong reason.
I don't think that's correct and I
put that out there.
Sure, well I'll check him out. I could be wrong too
but that's how I recall it. Please do
because everything he described was
an internal thing. It's not on the glass.
Anyway, bottom
line is the experts have
basically ruled it. Arrow is not
Arrow is not
the patent does the same thing.
You know, those experts
did not give a definite
answer. They gave an opinion
based on limited data. The one
I read the email to you
explicitly ruled it out
He explicitly said this was
an initial impression based on limited
data and that it was not
intended to be something, it wasn't even something
that he wanted to share. He didn't want his emails
to be shared and
he didn't come to an actual conclusion. I did it anonymously
because I think it's important to hear those voices.
He didn't want to share it
anyway. Did you get permission
from him to share those emails? I did not. I put
it out anonymously, anonymized it because
I think it's important for people to see what the
world's leading experts say about this
footage. I asked him for permission
because I wanted to share it myself and he said no
and the other one didn't reply.
I already heard that.
Does it bother you that Aero does
not endorse your theory?
No, I don't think they've got round to it yet.
It's the most recognizable
footage of all time.
They did Aguadilla, which
is just one that existed
before that. I think the
fraction of people who see
Aguadilla come up all
the time. It's a very famous UFO video
and they
know you agree with them on that one.
I do.
I know you've talked to
Kirkpatrick and he told you some ridiculous
interpretation
off the top of his head. Unbelievable.
He said it twice.
It's
disappointing that
we're not getting more information from Aero
but we haven't
got the official word yet
from them. Maybe we can leave it at
let's hope Kozlowski is true to his word and he
can, whatever bureaucratic
classic issues he has
to overcome to get
the really anomalous stuff that
he said he is stumped by, the
quote, true anomalies, maybe we can leave
it here, let's hope.
Let's get that stuff out there.
Let's figure this out.
Why doesn't someone leak something that's really good?
Why are we getting these crappy egg videos and these
bouncy objects?
Leak the 4K stuff, please.
Well, I think we can all, let's end on that
note of collegiality
between us.
We would all like to see better footage.
Indeed.
No matter what our takes are on the existing record
and what we currently have.
Mick, Merrick,
appreciate you guys. We're going to put this out
pretty soon and just
tag it onto our finished video.
Sounds good.
Cool. Thanks again, guys. Appreciate it.
Thank you.
Later.