We have to be comfortable with the fact that maybe when we study the abyss it studies us back.
On this episode of American Alchemy we meet a 26 year old whose name is Deep Prasad
reverse engineering UFOs using quantum computers. Andy's raised 15 million dollars for his startup
quantum generative materials to do just that. There are too many anomalies around the world
for us to ignore. So now you're probably asking yourself how the hell do you reverse engineer
materials that you don't even have access to? Well luckily the pentagon has hundreds of instances
of optical radar and infrared detections of UFOs and from those records the DoD has laid out five
observable properties that are very consistent among the UFO sightings. These are things like
sudden and instantaneous acceleration, hypersonic velocity with no signatures. All of these are
properties that as my colleague Eric Weinstein loves to say exhibit wholly new physics not just
new engineering. If we're taking visitation seriously it almost certainly means that Einstein
isn't the last word gravitational. To me immediately I realized that's not your average
macroscopic interaction. He thinks that the five observables point to UFOs engaging in quantum
macroscopic behavior. So what exactly do I mean by that? Quantum physics generally governs the
properties of the very small things like atoms photons and electrons tiny elementary particles
that do spooky things like entangle at a distance tunnel through physical barriers and sometimes
exhibit wave particle duality. Similarly Deep believes that UFOs could simply be large macroscopic
quantum objects. What's to say that what we're observing now today with UAPs aren't just materials
more advanced materials than we have access to today whose emergent properties we just can't
model with today's physicists and mathematics right? But imagine if you have a computer that's
doing it a quantum computer with a much more powerful brain than any other human on the planet
they may be able to figure out what these materials are. So strap yourself in and grab some salt
because your brain is about to be scrambled by the master quantum chef himself this week's
American Alchemist Deep Prasad.
Why don't academics in Silicon Valley, serious high functioning people, why the
fuck don't they take it more seriously? Yeah there's just so much social pressures basically
deterring people even highly intelligent people from wanting to study this subject.
I'm here with Deep Prasad who is 26 years old he has a quantum computing startup but part of the
mission of this quantum computing startup it's actually reverse engineering UAPs or UFOs based
on their observable properties. In some sense the most interesting starting point is like how does
one get into both quantum computing and UAPs. It completely blew my mind that the technologies
the observables and what was being reported there was no way in my personal opinion that that could
be a derivative of any human science. So you have hypersonic velocities for example right with no
signature. As the waves get created around your craft the waves at the beginning the sound waves
at the top will get bunched up and compressed and that's the sonic boom that you hear. So when an
object can travel at greater than five times the speed of sound like the tic tac which is estimated
to reach at least 31 times the speed of sound and it doesn't disturb the air around you to me
immediately I realized that's not your average macroscopic interaction so the physics that we
use to describe macroscopic bodies no longer applies to these things. Like my colleague Eric
Weinstein likes to say this isn't new engineering it's new physics. Correct. The role of aerospace
companies as holders of potentially basic scientific knowledge not shared with the academic
world seems very wrong to me. Maybe wrong but it's true. It is true you believe it's true.
Yeah I know it's true. You know that there's physics knowledge held by aerospace companies
that is not known. There certainly is materials knowledge which involves topological physics.
Eric and I had a pretty trippy conversation with the guy that briefs all of the presidents on UFOs
a guy named Hal Putoff. For more of that conversation you might have to wait a couple
of weeks but let's get back to deep. Okay so how does this relate to your interest in quantum
computing? You know what let me give you like an actual example and why this might apply to UAPs.
Yeah. So okay so let's rewind to 1911 because we can never ever observe absolute zero we should
never be able to observe exactly zero resistance and in 1911 when Dr. Ohm's discovered the first
superconductor it blew everybody's mind because this was supposed to be thought impossible and
40 years later we finally understood why this was even possible at all and we learned that
it's because of quantum mechanics that quantum mechanical behavior occurs at the macroscopic
scale and that's what we're observing and it only applies to keep in mind low temperature
superconductors we still don't know how high temperature superconductors work we know that
it's some weird quantum phenomenon but we don't have the physics and perhaps mathematics to
describe what's happening there or the computers. So what did we learn in 1911? We learned that
when a material breaks the laws of physics when anything does it's actually probably because it's
an emergent property or an emergent phenomenon right of underlying strange quantum mechanics
that are going on. Okay so you're looking at properties of UAPs things like you know
hypersonic travel with no signatures or you know breaking conservation of momentum
you can't make that work in sort of our classical physics or aerospace you know abilities so you
have that and then you have this interest sort of in quantum field theory how does this relate to
quantum computing and yeah how do you tie it all together? So look when I first started quantum
computing my goal was to be able to simulate any new material and predict it before having
to make it in the lab right I wanted to be able to tell is this new combination of atoms going
to be the next semiconductor will it be the next solar cell the next batteries that's cool so you
wanted like the ultimate modeling software or something you got it like the what Tesla could
do in his brain and you would be able to do that with quantum computing or we will oh absolutely
here's why the classic equation that we'd use to simulate the properties of atoms would be the
Schrodinger's many-body equation if you can solve that many-body Schrodinger equation you will know
everything about that material you will know the speed of sound in that material you will know its
resonance frequency you will know its heat capacity its strength the problem is that in the past we
haven't been able to do this equation for more than about three atoms yeah not much it's not
it's not very useful right in other words the many-body equation has a scaling problem as Paul
Dirac said he literally said everything we want to know about materials hasn't figured out we
just don't have the computational resources interesting to solve this equation deep thinks
that the bottleneck for solving this equation at scale is basically just using classical computers
and with quantum computing we might actually be able to do it and simulate meta materials that
exhibit the five observable properties of ufos
we engineer every technology today and in the sense that we treat quantum effects as a side
effect an artifact a consequence that we have to engineer around quantum computers
decide they take a different approach they say instead of treating quantum effects
as this unwanted thing that we're engineering around right incorporating accounting for
let's actually leverage it let's create quantum systems of our own and manipulate them so that
we can simulate other quantum systems because in order to simulate nature and nature's quantum
mechanical you need a system that is also quantum mechanical the quantum mechanical world is like a
powerful and ethereal anything can happen in it however as soon as somebody on the outside disturbs
you you wake up and all you're left with are memories similarly subatomic particles exist
in a probabilistic state of many possibilities but when they interact with an observer they
collapse into a single state as a result quantum hardware which relies on maintaining two or more
states in quantum superposition will decohere if they're interfered with by anything from the
outside this is the main bottleneck for building fully fledged and functional quantum computers
they're incredibly sensitive and they often require very specific and energy intensive
environments in order to maintain coherence this is why initially deep is using a quantum
computer simulator instead of quantum hardware all quantum computers the algorithms that we're
running on them they are universal computations what that means is that we will be able to model
any algorithm we want on quantum computers and so what we can do is if you're smart enough if
you're clever enough you can figure out the right mathematical representation of the many
bodies showing your equation and port it onto a quantum computer simply by the fact that you can
approximate any algorithm you want on a quantum computer so if you have algorithms and mathematical
models that that map right from quantum computing to many bodies showing equations you're in the
money and that's what we do right we do hardcore research into how to map these material science
problems on a quantum computers describe to the audience what a qubit is it's the quantum version
of a bit a bit is the fundamental unit of information for classical computers right one or zero one or
zero exactly but the fundamental smallest unit of information you can have in a quantum system
is a qubit qubits can take on superpositions of states right and so what a lot of people in
popular culture popular science butcher when they describe superpositions is that they say that the
qubit is both one and zero at the same time that's not true it's not in the one state it's not in the
zero state it's not in the one and zero state either it's also not not in the one and not in
the zero state it's in a superposition state but how does that equate to transmitting more information
more information yeah exactly if i were to have let's say just 10 bits right it sounds trivial
but it takes 10 bits to describe the state of 10 bits right but if i have 10 qubits then i need
two to the 10 classical bits to represent the entire quantum state of those 10 qubits because
you can have all the qubits entangled with each other meaning that they can all to describe one
you have to describe what's happening to all the others take a caffeine molecule right the
the caffeine molecule is sesame to have about like 97 electrons right at least and to describe
97 electrons fully like fully entangled 97 electrons right to properly account for that
you would need to to the 97 classical bits and that's more atoms than the surface and
all planet earth right minus the air so even if i took every single atom on planet earth
and convert it into classical bit i wouldn't be able to store the quantum state of a caffeine molecule
for some reason nature is able to do a level of bookkeeping in the background
with quantum states that we don't fully know how it does it nature does this bookkeeping
that's so computationally impossible for us to do today right and that's where like ideas of the
multiverse and into multiverse interpretation comes in and so on right where people will say
well nature's not actually storing it anywhere it's actually just distributed across different
universes we have a sense of where it gets stored so obviously but there's a way in which quantum
computing sort of simulates nature more accurately and so can store more but do we have a sense of
how the computing is storing either that's also somewhat of a black box where complete black box
we can engineer them interesting but we have no fucking clue why it works wow that's pretty nutty
every physical material ever is a quantum system your brain your skin everything is made of atoms
and all atoms are described by quantum mechanical rules it's almost a form of blind exceptionalism
to say that the body is not quantum because everything else is quantum so that how much
quantum sensing is going on that's unclear but exactly it's not like we we came into existence
as giant macroscopic bodies right we literally started from amoeba we were closer than the
quantum scale when we started out so it's hard to imagine that that we didn't evolve even at
the cellular level some ability to use quantum effects for sure do you think your brain is a
quantum sensor like the the penrose argument would be so it's like we don't perceive anything
kind of in its quantum form obviously we perceive you know a bigger proportion kind of classical
stuff right and the penrose argument would be that you know you have a probabilistic universe
you have schrodinger's wave equation and we're collapsing schrodinger's wave into a specific
eigenstate right using you know this some some quantum sensor in our brain maybe microtubules
or maybe something else right do you believe that or the thing is that with our brain there may be
parts of our brain that could behave like a quantum sensor we know that there are birds that can
navigate the earth's magnetic field and sense it right using quantum sensing essentially biological
quantum sensing yeah the body in biology at large is typically warm wet and noisy not conditions
that you think of as conducive to maintaining quantum coherence or exhibiting quantum properties
but scientists now know that there are actually parts of biology that do exhibit quantum effects
for example there are birds called robins that have a specific protein called a crypto chrome
in their eye called cry4 that actually uses quantum effects to sense the magnetic field of
the earth electron pairs in the cry4 protein arrange themselves based on the robin's position
and direct the bird where it needs to go based on the magnetic field of the earth
it's basically biological gps lockheed observed these birds right or like the physics and and they
decided can we replicate this with existing sensors can we create a quantum sensor that does
the same thing yeah that these birds are doing to detect the earth's magnetic field and they
succeeded as of six years ago they created what's called a dark ice magnetometer so with these
magnetometers they can navigate anywhere on earth without a gps with gps precision they don't need
a satellite they can be underwater they can be wherever the hell they want and they can that's
pretty amazing right all sorts of issues national security vulnerabilities with gps satellites for
sure for sure and then if you don't have access to gps for whatever reason and imagine if you're
an extraterrestrial species visiting a new planet and you don't have access to gps magnetometer
that's it as we build more powerful quantum sensors we're going to be able to learn things
about the human body that will actually be medically useful there's already research being
done and devices being built for sensing the heart and like the activity of each you know
basically atom in the heart right so imagine having atomic resolution into the human body
wow these are this is what's going to happen right it's inevitable you see all of la so that's west
hollywood right here downtown all the way east right there and then you can see the beach during
the day all the way what yeah it's beautiful i think your blog is fascinating and i want to
go through some of your blog posts because i think the the titles themselves i think are worthy of
explanation so i'm just going to go through a couple of them and you can sort of give me
the summary if that works sure okay the evolution of science and the interactive universe so
when we look at the modern scientific method right it was invented by the credit gosus or
francis bacon his assumption the scientific method naturally assumes that whatever you
are deriving about the universe should be repeatable right and if it's not repeatable
if it's not testable and controlled then it's not scientific and it's not useful information
the issue with that is that it assumes that the universe is static that if i were to measure a
certain volume of air that it will never change if i measure the the particle composition of this
air nothing ever changes the the repeatability is there because the laws of physics are the same and
so on so forth nothing will ever affect my measurements other than the errors i already
know the the fundamental issue with sir francis bacon is assumption was that as commander favor
flies through the air that air the composition everything about it should be repeatable however
that day something happened that was not repeatable the existence of the tic tac so somewhere in that
air was this anomaly this thing that does not and is not repeatable yet it was clearly something
that needs to be studied so the scientific method needs a modification and that's what
this article is about that yeah it well yeah another model of science and this is maybe like
a kunian model is that there are anomalies that don't go like we're talking about quantum field
theory like you had black body radiation in the 1860s discovered by some german guy and it didn't
make any sense you'd expect sort of you know uh runaway heat in this in this black body or whatever
if you were talking about kind of a typical newtonian system and that wasn't the case we
figured out mathematically why that wasn't the case when max planck figured that out you know
that that that light was actually quantized in the early 20th century right but you have these
things where it's like little little pokes in the formal convention of the time and the standard
paradigm and you're like what is that doesn't quite make sense it doesn't quite make sense
and i love that there's a carl popper line it's called materialist promissory notes and it's you
know all the gaps of materialist reductionism will get filled in inevitably but but um that in
itself takes faith and so i think i think studying anomalies is incredibly important
absolutely and should be should be seen as a possibly a harbinger of the next paradigm
absolutely and and and not shoved away and not i mean i think we're over indexed on like people
like michael schermer like justifying the current paradigm that doesn't move science forward that's
not exciting at all it doesn't it also doesn't face reality i really believe in you know as
cheesy as it sounds facing reality if we're realizing that the scientific method is not
giving us uh the full picture we should be looking at new methods too that complement
right science as well because we know now at least no we have good indications that the universe is
indeed not static as in if i were to measure something there is a non-zero chance some crazy
anomaly that has never been properly characterized will occur in my measurement in my experiment
and we need to be able to quantify that somehow we need to account for it we have to be comfortable
with the fact that maybe when we study the abyss it steadies us back
okay
one of the interesting things we've been talking about like physics with uaps but what i find very
interesting is if you look at all into the subject it's not just new physics or if it is new physics
there's one component that doesn't fit with our current model of physics outside of the
observables of the actual uaps being very weird and that's that certain people see the uaps and
those people see the certain uaps often in various states true and so again the ockham's razor easy
way to explain that away is the person is crazy right but often these people have no mental health
history why do you think certain people see uaps and is there science that we'll discover
that might be able to explain that i have two answers right one is much more rational and
doesn't make me sound crazy the other one makes me sound completely let's start with the second
okay sure my lunatic answer is it's based on cellular automata so cellular automata is a
notion that comes from computer science and mathematics and it's the idea that you can create
highly complex highly emergent systems from very basic cells and very very basic rules right where
you just define um you know a couple cells on a grid and how they'll behave well whether they die
or not right this is where like conway's game of life comes and so on and then we see that if you
let the simulation run and you let the play out you imagine you see this completely different
immersion phenomena right that's so complex my crazy theory is that these uap sightings that
we're seeing and so on are part of the cellular automata where individually they may seem like
one-offs and weird events but what we're experiencing could be part of this
essentially a game or strategy where the end goal is this very very complex emergent phenomenon
that cellular automata leads us to and i think that we're part of a more intelligent organism's
cellular automata game i guess if you will interesting i think that it's the whole point
is that is to change society towards a new state an emergent property like a very complex society
that we don't even have like we're not even near right now like we're we're getting pushed
towards it in ways that we don't even realize that's what's weird is it almost feels like
there's an arc of tech innovation or civilization civilizational progress or something that sure
it's like what you know why are there certain discoveries at the same time in places that
didn't have any contact with one another people were having sort of the same same thoughts at
the same time there's obviously you know esoteric traditions of kind of cyclical civilizations that
you know rose up and then they declined and it's i don't it's all very hard to explain but maybe
maybe tech is more pre-ordained than we than we think it is or maybe per like the william james
transmission theory of consciousness these things are sort of zapped into us and all ideas are kind
of zapped into us okay let's go through some more blogs we have resolving key issues in quantum
mechanics while simultaneously debunking every ufo case in history i love that is that yeah so
that was just an april fools prank okay okay curiosity as a time capsule what is that awesome
so that's where i lay out my predictions for where i think uap research is going that was
my version of a time capsule so that one day the hope is that you know five years 10 years
20 years from now as we develop a deeper understanding of what uaps are and the ecosystem
around it what it means or where that's going to leave us so that's what that yeah what are
your predictions um my prediction is that over the next 10 years i think that we will have
collected enough scientific evidence enough groups will have collaborated and worked together
and also post-scientific groups too right like i mentioned when you make some modifications to
scientific method i think that we're going to be stay in a decade from now where we acknowledge
that we are not the only life forms that are intelligent and super intelligent on this planet
i vaguely believe that failure and that would be an insane thing say we all were like okay so we
have scientific verification that aliens are you know i have a basis somewhere whatever uh all of
a sudden you replace angels and demons in the bible with aliens and you're like okay that was
probably real right and like a lot of that stuff might be happening now and actually my cousin who
had a vision you know or whatever like maybe he really did have a vision and they had something
to tell him and and all of a sudden the world becomes much more magical place totally and it's
not just these like folkloric funny stories that people are telling in the form of religion that
people think you know it's just the sort of garden variety thing that you do you show up it's for the
community whatever but it's ultimately there's no metaphysical truth in it and then there's science
which is like cold and amoral but it's it's real somehow this would marry those two things in this
like freaky way it's amazing it would be kind of crazy but i i don't know if it's happening
it's inevitable it is inevitable there are too many anomalies that are being reported and that
are being measured and observed around the world that for us to ignore you know that relates to
almost religious like experiences right yeah um i think that it's night it would be so painfully
naive of us and it is to conclude that we know everything there is about the universe where
we're so close that we can say that there's no such thing as like you know aliens for example
right like think about our quantum mechanics and general relativity that describes five percent of
the damn universe yeah the other 95 isn't even describable with our physics yeah right like yet
people are so damn confident about their worldview yeah it's crazy i think they mistake the map for
the territory it's because a love it yes that's exactly it that's brilliant what would you be
working on if it wasn't quantum computing if quantum computers didn't exist i would definitely
be an artificial intelligence do you think ai will ever get to a point where it's generative
and a human doesn't need to feed it some ideal end state that it's sort of judging it off yes yes
it will be when our fundamental machine learning models are better and improved and we go beyond
the neural networks of today and when they have their own physical body because that's what
they're missing is the ability to actually interact with the world around them where i
would disagree with like elon musk or nick bostrom or those those that camp of people is like they
seem to have these like doomsday scenarios in their head that are like near term where like
these like sentient killer robots decide that you know human meat space is useless
and you know or they don't fit into some objective function and then we end up getting thrown out
and killed and where we are now which is like statistics on steroids to that just feels like
this insane leap of logic and i actually think the more insidious narrative is that ai is already
killing us but ai is just consumer apps and consumer apps are eating us uh our brains
i think it's brilliant no that's a very very wise insight because most people who
use tiktok for example right yes they have no freaking clue yes how much they are being
manipulated by an artificial intelligence no idea the extent of it why she ain't put the news at
the bottom then that's disgusting so imagine you know we already saw problems with facebook when
people were experimenting with facebook's news feed to see how it affect people's mood and then
you know alleged suicides and deaths would increase during this the results of this
experimentation right how do we know that's not also happening with tiktok and other
outlets and so on yeah so absolutely there's an insidious aspect of ai that we should worry about
that's outside i think so too i think it's killing us with a whimper not with a bang
love it that's just eating eating away at us sort of parasitically
quantum computers in the next like let's say to be conservative 15 years i will i'm being highly
conservative there will become powerful enough to completely make rsa obsolete rsa encryption is
the backbone of society right it's it's what allows you to securely access your bank account
to send messages you could reverse engineer that with quantum computing exactly that will happen
it is not a matter of if but when so you could double spend bitcoin you could double the whole
all of these yeah most of these cryptocurrencies today will become obsolete because of quantum
computing well that's an interesting sort of black swan event around crypto it will happen
yeah totally and it's gonna get a lot of people will get blindsided and caught blindsided in that
absolutely interesting absolutely and so what happens when there are nation-state actors or
people who are intelligent enough that can build quantum computers and suddenly the whole world's
information is exposed right what happens if i can read your facebook messages now that you've
sent throughout your whole life right how disturbing would that be so um i think that
that that event alone will force society the apocalypse exactly or like force us to work
together basically like because like everybody will lose their leverage right at the same time
yeah well dude thank you for doing this this is a lot of fun absolutely likewise jesse yeah
thanks deep it was such a pleasure man we'll do this again sometime we'll definitely do this again
dude in miami absolutely yes