There's something that looks like it has been sliding into the ocean.
So they found this thing that looked like a crashed UFO
or looked like an artificial structure outside the Swedish coast.
They found that it was covered in burned biological material,
which is really weird because we don't have volcanic activity in that area.
We need the actual physical proof.
And I don't think any government is willing to release that.
But the scientists who had claimed it was just a rock never studied the actual samples.
And there's no paper and no open data.
There's just a claim to the media by those scientists.
And I'm just like, this is not a way of analyzing something.
Wow. So if there's there are no samples of that object because it was so hard
so they couldn't get a piece out of it.
So I still think it's something that should be analyzed
because it might be possibly the best candidate
and non-human artifact that you can find. Wow.
And I really believe that we need to seriously study these kind of objects.
Yeah, absolutely.
I'm here with Dr. Beatriz Villarreal, who is a phenomenal astronomer,
both in a conventional sense.
She's conventionally trained, but also I think you are a rare,
kind of very open mind in your field and you found some very interesting things.
And so I'm really excited to speak with you because you're kind of on the frontier.
You're the intersection, I think, between scientific rigor
and this burgeoning field of studying kind of anomalous phenomena in the air and in space.
And so thank you for being here. I really appreciate it.
It's my pleasure. And it's a true honor.
Oh, well, thank you. How did you get in this space to begin with?
Were you always in the space as a kid?
Actually not. So as a kid, I was a very, very curious person.
Well, I am still a very curious person, but of course I was very interested in space.
So I was very curious about a lot of things. And I think already when I was six or seven,
I had written a small little essay about cats in flying saucers.
I still like cats as well.
When you were six or seven, you wrote an essay.
Yeah, I had that essay. I don't remember how long it was.
I had also painted the cats and the flying saucers there.
So I don't think I changed too much.
Oh my God. That's unbelievable.
Anyway, I simply liked probably this topic already since I was very young.
I got interested in molecular biology and DNA.
And I actually started my university studies with an engineering program
in molecular biotechnology. And then I got super bored.
How did you get bored of molecular biotechnology?
Well, it's like we were all the time. I think it was the particular program
I was studying at the university. We were all the time repeating the central dogma
and how DNA turns into a protein over and over.
And I just started wondering about the mysteries of the universe,
galaxies, how are galaxies gaining the shapes that we see,
the spiral form versus the elliptical forms. I wanted to understand all that.
Well, I found myself on a PhD program in astronomy and I started studying active
galactic nuclei, which are galaxies that have lots of light coming from their center.
And I tried to see how different types of active galactic nuclei,
and you could see these different types by looking at the spectra.
Some had broad emission lines, some had narrow. And how are they related?
And I did my PhD on that topic. However, already like in my early years as a PhD student,
was it even maybe in my last year as undergraduate student, I had,
while writing some fable, I had started wondering about if a star could vanish,
or if a galaxy could vanish.
What do you think sparked that question of could a galaxy vanish?
Well, I think I was so influenced and fascinated by Halton Arp's theory.
So Halton Arp was an astronomer who was a super famous astronomer.
For a very long while, who one day observed, he found couples of galaxies that looked like
they were exchanging gas. But if you looked at their redshifts, which are indicators of distance,
they had completely different redshift, which completely went against all the idea of the
expanding universe and how we interpret redshift. So when he said this, all astronomers attacked him.
It was the controversy of what we have today with Avi Loeb and Oumuamua, and in the 80s,
with the non-cosmological redshift or anomalous redshifts, as we call them.
Yeah, so I was fascinated by that thing. And I wrote an essay based on these ideas. And then
somehow I killed off my poor quasar because it was a fable. And it vanished at the end of the story.
And I started wondering, but hey, has anyone ever searched for galaxies or stars that vanish?
Interesting. And so can you explain what a non-cosmological redshift is?
So it would be, so usually when we look at galaxies, we can see the redshift,
and it's a Doppler shift because the universe is expanding and it's moving away from us.
So it's stretching light and you're moving lower down on the electromagnetic wave spectrum towards
the low nanometer range.
Exactly. So what then happens is that people use this redshift to calculate the distance
through a galaxy. Now the problem would be if you have two interacting galaxies that are
completely different redshifts, you wouldn't be able to use that as a distance estimator.
So I was just curious about that.
Why do you think it was so controversial?
Well, because that would question the entire Big Bang idea. So it would completely change
all the fundamentals of physics as we know today, or cosmology rather.
So the verdict on redshifts is still out, but you've moved on.
I moved on.
You might come back at some point.
When I get really bored.
So how did you get into, because I know you through my own interest in UAP,
unidentified anomalous phenomena, how did you get into even believing that that was possible?
So I'm going to show you some like contradictions in how I were thinking when I was younger.
So as an undergraduate student, I was in Sweden and I one day heard about this fascinating discovery
that our team of divers had done called the Baltic Sea Anomaly. So they found this thing
that looked like a crashed UFO or looked like an artificial structure outside the Swedish coast.
What did it look like?
It looked like a Millennium Falcon that had just crashed into the deep seas.
Wow.
I was super fascinated and I was like, oh my God, can there have been aliens coming to visiting on
earth? Later, when I started working with these searches for extraterrestrial intelligence,
which we did through the project by looking for vanishing objects,
that's when I started wondering about the UFO question as well, which I until then didn't want to touch.
And is there any government interest when it comes to this?
Well, I don't know about that, but I know that they did super interesting investigations of it.
I think they found that it was covered in burned biological material, which is really weird because
we don't have volcanic activity in that area. Plus, I don't think they even said it was a
crashed UFO. I think their idea is that this is an artificial structure and they don't know what it
is, but some kind of artificial structure. There's something that looks like it has been sliding into
the ocean. Sadly, Fox News went out with saying that this is just a rock, but the scientist who
had claimed it was just a rock never studied the actual samples. And there's no paper and
no open data. There's just a claim to the media by those scientists. And I'm just like,
this is not a way of analyzing something. So there are no samples of that object because
it was so hard, so they couldn't get a piece out of it. So I still think it's something that
should be analyzed because it might be possibly the best candidate and non-human artifact that
you can find. And I really believe that we need to seriously study these kinds of objects.
HOFFMAN Yeah, absolutely. We should go down there and try to gather resources.
I mean, that's amazing.
LESLIE I hope these two guys will get all the support they can to actually
study it and research it.
So how does looking at vanishing stars then lead you to an interest in UAP or UFOs?
So we were looking for these vanishing stars. And so now people talk about vanishing stars
sometimes in different ways than I talk about them. So we had access to these catalogs,
like lots of imagery from 1950, and also a catalog called the U.S. Navy catalog.
And then we had images of the sky as it looks today. And so we were comparing these images
from the early 50s to images as it looks today. And I was hoping to see this perfect sparkling
star that you can find in multiple images that one day vanishes. But before you find that,
you find lots of candidates and like things that you see in the 50s that have vanished,
but you don't know if it's a beautiful star or if it's something else. I had this image
where you could see multiple stars appearing and vanishing, which is completely crazy. Because
one thing to have one transient, but when we have several of them happening in a small space at the
same time, you really start wondering. So I started studying this phenomenon. I showed it
to my colleagues and we all started investigating it. We had this guy at Gran Telescopio Canaria,
one of my friends, who actually pointed the world's largest optical telescope, a 10.4 meter
telescope, to the positions of all these nine objects or eight of them or something like that.
And there was nothing left. We were really hoping to see some kind of counterpatch there.
And you said, oh, maybe there were nine lasers or whatever. There was nothing like that. And then
we started wondering, so what can actually cause this thing? And there's no astrophysical
explanation. So we started looking at various kind of instrumental explanation and all of them.
And this is not a supernova or like, you know, the heat death of the sun type thing turns into
a black hole or dwarf or something. You're not going to get several of them in a small space
at the same time. Wow. So this just didn't match anything. Just like perfect anomaly basically.
Yeah. Although today you can have that in the sky because today I have lots of satellites
that sometimes are blinking and lots of space garbage. And then short reflections just happen
due to, I mean, because you have solar reflections. The problem is that this is from 1950.
We didn't have any of that technology back then. Yeah. So, and that's how I became interested.
And I got an idea of that one of the ways how I can also search for more such examples by looking
for those that are lying along a line or in a narrow band. So my friend Lars helped me to develop
the statistics to properly see how many do we need at least in a line in order to, or in a narrow
band in order to say that even if you have this kind of transits, also their positioning is
anomalous and that they are kind of not randomly placed, but they are aligned or so. And we had
two such examples that are statistically significant. And one is five objects on a narrow band
and it's from the 27th of July, 1952. My colleague Enrique found these three stars,
triple transients. And this one is from the 19th of July, 1952. And it's super beautiful. And then
my colleague, Dave Altman, who is the manager, a media manager for Vasco, he said, do you know
what happens or what happened on 19th of July, 1952? No, I wasn't around. So he introduced me
to the Washington flap. That's absolutely amazing. I mean, because in UFO lore,
not even lore, this was a national event. It was all over the press. It was in newspapers saying,
saucers on the White House lawn. It prompted a call between Truman and Edward J. Ruppelt,
who was the head of Blue Book at the time. And you had this Washington invasion or DC flyover
where there were saucers all over DC at the time. And it was specifically, it was July of 1952,
but it was specifically two weekends. It was the 19th and 20th and it was the 26th and 27th. So
I find that absolutely remarkable. So these are naval records that you're looking at to see the
stars. We used this naval observatory catalog initially, or I used them initially, but later
we just went directly to the Mount Palomar images. Got it. And so you're seeing images,
you're seeing this three in a row and then five in a row in your case.
The three are just randomly placed and the five are along a narrow band.
Okay, got it. And then they just seemed to vanish. They weren't in the public re-observable data like
a year later or even a week later. Exactly like you said.
That's wild. I mean, that's really fascinating. Is there anything that is distinct about them
when comparing them to other stars in the images or do they look like garden variety stars?
They look like garden variety stars. We actually now are re-exploring whether they look identical
to the garden variety stars or if there might be some small tiny difference because you can
expect slight differences if you have short flashes depending on the shorter they are,
the more they might be concentrated. Interesting. And have you seen any vanishing
stars since 1952? Have you combed through the records since then?
We have a lot of single transients, but what I actually want to do is to look at more cases
of multiple transients. We have some more cases when we were looking for these alignments that
we just ignored because we were looking for alignments. Can you describe the methodology
of Project Vasco? What exactly are you doing? So we take images from Mount Palomar
from the early fifties and then we look at the same positions in new images from pan stars.
And Mount Palomar is an observatory in California?
Exactly. And then we use these images from Hawaii and we compare the same spot just 70 years later
and see how something vanished. It was actually quite fun. There was an expert in satellites that
contacted me when he saw our paper where we were looking for these alignments and I found these
two particularly interesting cases. And he wrote me something like, but come on,
you have just found satellites. Haven't you thought about that? And I wrote back,
did you look at what year these satellites are from? They're kind of before Sputnik.
Yeah. I think that's kind of hard to argue with.
It was quite fun. And you can't imagine how often some astronomers actually make that kind
of comment. Aren't you just having satellite links? Do you remember Don Menzel? Do you know
that name by any chance? Yeah. Famous astronomer. It's my favorite typical
arch villain. He kind of is, right? It was all like, what was it? Like temperature inversion.
He was a Harvard astronomer and I think he was also a cryptographer and kind of deep in the
national security state. And he would just write these kind of naysayer debunking books in the
fifties. And he would describe all the stuff, you know, light reflections or, you know,
temperature inversions and that sort of thing. But yeah, what are your thoughts on it? Why is
he your favorite villain? I mean, I don't think he necessarily is a villain, but there's some very
interesting coincidences around his name that really make me wonder. What are the coincidences?
Well, first, I mean, we all know that he was a super famous UFO debunker, if not the most
famous UFO debunker. Absolutely. And he helped the US Air Force to debunk the Washington 1952 flap.
And two or three months after, he suddenly becomes the director of Harvard Observatory
and he destroys one side of the photographic place. And he doesn't ask, as I understand from
the record, he doesn't ask the astronomers to select the place. No, he asked his secretary
to go and throw away one third of the plates. And there's a woman, Dorit Hofleit, that has been
telling about the story in her memoirs. And kind of he started revenging on her later too for,
as I understood it, for that she tried to protect some of the plates. He also threw away
a number of the blog books that are keeping the observations and what plates exist.
In 1953, Donald Menzel also stopped the astronomers at Harvard to carry out their
very famous sky survey, where they were monitoring the entire sky since already
late 19th century. And he stopped them and they didn't do this survey between 1953 to 1967
for roughly 15 years. So he also had apparently some more later episodes of
plate destruction, I've heard. That is wild. And suddenly you find that his name is famous
for the so-called MJ-12, Majestic 12. And you start wondering, of course, I mean, I can't help
it, but it's a lot of coincidences because we also see things on these dates from Mount Palomar.
Well, the other fascinating thing about Don Menzel is he went on to run the Bureau of Public
Standards, which they're sort of codifying time zones, but also a lot of astronomical data as
well. And so if anybody were to manage our reality, it would be somebody in that position.
And then, I don't know if you know this fact, this is kind of trippy, but he had an understudy,
a PhD at Harvard who studied right under him named Lou Branscombe. Lou Branscombe gave Edward Condon
his clearance back and Edward Condon went on to do a hit job on UFOs with the Condon Committee,
which killed Blue Book. So it was literally Menzel's like protege giving Condon his clearance
so that he could completely kind of put the kibosh once and for all on UFOs and kind of kill the
field. He's my favorite arch villain. Yeah, I think he's an arch villain. I think there's
something going on there. And we were talking in the car earlier about Carl Sagan, who I think is
such a fascinating figure because we were saying in his early diaries, he would write all about
UFOs. He was clearly sort of fascinated by them. It feels like if you read Pale Blue Dot or Watch
Contact, he sort of, it seems like this tongue in cheek reference to actual non-human intelligence
or extraterrestrial visitation. But then publicly, he just seems to dogmatically flip on the topic
and just become this kind of debunker. Actually, right around the time when J. Allen Hynek kind of
goes in the opposite direction, he was running Blue Book and Astronomer and he says, you know,
actually, I played a part in the cover-up. And so it's interesting that Carl Sagan, there seems
to be this kind of split between his private life and beliefs and public life on UFOs.
So do you know that Allen Hynek worked under Menzel at Harvard? So there was this project called
Operation Moonwatch held by Fred Whipple. So Fred Whipple was the PhD student of Donald Menzel.
And so he created this program where they had 12 stations around the Earth with a lot of
citizen scientists that were tracking satellites over the sky. And so Allen Hynek was helping
Whipple in this program. And they actually had 36 UFO reports that I think Jacques Vallée found
that we now also look through. There are some very interesting things there. So astronomers
and amateur astronomers have been seeing UFOs forever. It just has been ignored.
Do you know who's running the Harvard Undersea Observatory at the time?
Galileo Project.
Currently, maybe. But the guy at the time was Robert Sarbacher.
You know those moments in the middle of the day when you feel your energy dipping
and you just need something to help you reset. That's when I grab my greens and it's become
my favorite way to recharge. Greens is a refreshingly delicious blend of 14 essential greens,
adaptogens, antioxidants, and even mushrooms. It's packed with everything your body needs to fill
key nutrient gaps and keep you feeling your best without relying on coffee or sugary snacks.
I personally love the strawberry kiwi flavor. It's tangy, slightly sweet,
and way better than any other green powder I've tried before. Plus it's so easy to make. I just
mix a scoop with water during that midday slump and it's like hitting the refresh button on my day.
Since adding greens to my routine, I've noticed I feel more energized,
less stressed, and just way more balanced. It's a simple step that makes a big difference in how
I feel throughout the day. So prioritize your health this year with up to 35% off bean greens.
Just use code JesseMichaels. That's Michaels with no A. So it's J-E-S-S-E-M-I-C-H-E-L-S at checkout.
This offer is only available for a limited time only. Go to shopbeam.com slash JesseMichaels to
enjoy a refreshing blend of 14 essential greens and use code JesseMichaels at checkout for up to 35%
off. Click the link in the description and use my code to grab your greens now. You're going to love it.
Fellow alchemist, Lucy Breakers are changing the game for nicotine users. If you're looking for
a 100% pure nicotine product that's tobacco free, Lucy Breakers are where it's at. Each
pouch has a cool twist. Inside is a capsule that can pop to release an extra burst of flavor and
hydration. It's a unique experience that makes your nicotine routine more enjoyable and convenient.
As someone who delves into the most heretical thinkers and ideas of our time, I appreciate
products that challenge the norm. Lucy Breakers do just that. My personal go-to flavor is mint.
Whether I'm deep into a podcast discussion, exploring new frontiers, or brainstorming ideas,
throwing in a Lucy is an easy way to keep the day moving. Plus, the flexibility and
strengths lets you choose what suits you best. Let's level up your nicotine routine with Lucy.
Go to lucy.co slash jesse and use promo code jesse to get 20% off your first order.
Lucy has a 30-day refund policy if you change your mind. Again, that's lucy.co and use code
jesse to get 20% off. Here comes the fine print. Lucy products are only for adults of legal age.
Every order is age verified. Warning, this product contains nicotine. Nicotine is an
addictive chemical. Thanks so much to Lucy for sponsoring today's episode.
Who David Grush says went on to basically create UFO secrecy through the Atomic Energy Act of 1954
and was very close confidant with Thomas Townsend Brown who's working on anomalous gravity research.
And so it seems like Harvard was the epicenter of a lot of this interesting work.
It seems so fascinating to have been at Harvard in the 1950s. And actually, the same time as Menzel
was there, JFK was on the board of overseers for the astronomy department.
I didn't know that.
I first found that in Stanton Friedman's notes. So I'm fascinated.
That's amazing. Yeah, I've always wondered how much. Do you think JFK was maybe privy to the UFO?
Because there's this letter.
I don't know anything about JFK. All this is outside my specialty. I'm now wildly speculating.
Really speculating.
That's what we do on my show. But there's a letter that was FOIA'd.
The Freedom of Information Act was used to request it out of the government in 2005.
And it was from JFK to acting director of the CIA, John McCone. It was after JFK had
fired Alan Dulles. And he's asking for data on unknowns because he's worried that the Russians,
the Soviets might view it as a threat if they see the unknowns in their airspace.
And I would think it was fake, but it really dovetails with the language that was used in
the 1971 SALT talks, where on record we're saying that we have to coordinate with the Soviets
on unknowns in their airspace and our airspace, especially around sensitive military installations,
so that these things don't provoke war. And if you're thinking about detente,
that's obviously a really important vector to kind of think about.
And so I always ask myself, you know, this guy, John Greenwald, blackvault.com,
has done a lot of work on this. And he's looked into the veracity of this document.
And the verdict's still out. It's unclear. And I think there are a lot of reasons to think it might
not be real. But it's interesting because there were some people in and around the JFK assassination
that think that maybe it had something to do with his inquiries in the UFOs. I don't know.
There's a lot of fascinating questions to explore for sure.
But that's really interesting. I didn't know he was, I mean, I know he was the Harvard
affiliated. I had no idea he was at all involved in anything they were doing in the world of
astronomy. That's really fascinating and cool. What is the current, so you did Project Vasco,
and now you're onto a new project to get more of a smoking gun possibly around these anomalous
objects. Can you describe what that project is? So we still have Vasco running and we are going
to be looking for more signatures of satellites with the Vasco project. And hopefully also make
a new citizen science project where we look for these signatures. Was that the extent of
the vanishing stars just the 1952 or you found a lot of vanishing? Well, we found a lot of
transients things that appear and vanish. Okay. Okay. So what exactly do you hope to do with
Exoprobe? If you remember with the Vasco project, when we saw these multiple transients, there were
no satellites in the sky. Today there's loads and loads of space debris. So now what we want to do
is that we want to look for these kind of signatures of non-human artifacts in orbit
around the earth, outside the earth's atmosphere. But we also want to remove all this contamination
from human space debris directly when we do our observations so that we get clean data.
So to do that, first we have a method that I cannot discuss how we are removing all this
space debris. But more importantly or equally importantly is that we are hoping to build a
network of telescopes. And by having multiple telescopes, you can determine the distance
to an object. And the more telescopes you have, the more accurately you can actually
determine this distance in three dimensions so that you can actually eventually go there,
pick up the object and bring it down to the earth. Because that's what I would like to do,
to bring down an actual ET probe. So that's what Exoprobe is about. It's about validating a finding,
verifying it, localizing the object and characterizing the nature of it. Since the
1960s, we have developed a new way of imaging the skies, new technology for imaging the skies. We
don't use photo emulsions anymore like was done in the 50s. Our cameras are much more sensitive.
We have also artificial intelligence that can analyze a huge amount of data. We can now digitize
the entire sky. That wasn't possible in the 60s. All that was impossible for them that time
or extremely difficult. And today you have all the methods you need to look for probes.
So now since Radio SETI has failed, why not going back to the second best idea of those times,
which is looking for artifacts and probes from advanced civilizations. And I think that's the
route we have to take. And I also believe that instead of looking for anomalies blindly,
we should look specifically for artificial non-human objects. That's how I'm thinking.
I think it's an error to do UFO projects too open where you look for anything that doesn't match
whatever is natural or earthly. I think we need to be much more concrete with what we
are looking for. If we're looking for metallic orbs, you design a project designed for looking
for metallic orbs. That makes so much sense. We were talking earlier and there are certain
projects out there that kind of just use generic, you know, a lot of sensor modality, kind of
constant observation, and then just the exclusion principle. And it's like, okay, there are all
these objects. We do recognize what lies outside of the scope of what we recognize.
And you presented this really interesting kind of model, which updated me where it was like,
no, you actually need a hypothesis going in. That's actually really good. That's good science.
Having an idea of what you're looking for and then whatever signatures you'd expect to see
from that thing and actually looking for that precisely. And so I guess the question for you
would be in the case of UAP or UFO, do you have specific signatures you might be looking for?
Yes, we are looking for either solar reflections that can be short or it can be streaking or we
look for emissions from artificial objects. We simply want to look for these very distinct
signatures. And like one discussion I have in a new manuscript that we put out is that
I don't like the definition of UAP because it fits almost everything now. It's so broad.
UFO is more limited object.
Yes, but even better is flying saucer. Because when you have flying saucer,
you directly can see the flying saucer in your head. But when you can see it in your imagination,
you can imagine how it would look in your data. That you can directly transfer it to an image
in your mind makes it possible to design a scientific experiment that is very clearly
looking for these flying saucers. Now I'm not saying that you should only look for flying saucers
because we know about the metallic orbs and all these other possible signatures we can look for.
But having it so concrete makes it possible to also not only imagine the experiment,
but also imagine all the ways how it could fail and all the limitations of your design.
While when people work with exclusion principle and look for everything that doesn't fit
the earthly or the natural, you have so many things you have to test.
You can always go on forever and say, and what will you actually prove from that?
You just prove that there's a bunch of stuff outside of what you'd expect, but you're sort
of using process of elimination forever. Exactly. So it's a barely falsifiable
hypothesis. While if you have the flying saucer, it's a very concrete hypothesis.
So I think my feeling is that more science projects have to be working
with very concrete hypothesis around the UFO question.
So when you say you're looking for light reflections and light emissions,
is that specifically like in a specific light wavelength or is it other possible
signatures or is it just light? Well, you can look all over the
electromagnetic spectrum. I'm going to start in the optical, but I think the infrared
might be very, very interesting. I've heard a lot of people commenting on that there are many more
UFOs in the infrared. However, I'm a little bit skeptical because our eyes are trained with the
optical. I mean, we are all the time judging an object, what it is based on optical light.
When people look at infrared imagery, they don't have that same experience.
So I think it's much easier to find a UFO simply by the lack of experience. It doesn't mean that
they are more visible in the infrared. It could just mean that we are worse at identifying objects
in the infrared. Because one example would be, you're familiar with the Nimitz case in 2004,
the Tic Tac. So that was detected right when a forward looking infrared new system from Raytheon
was installed on the Nimitz carrier strike group system or whatever. And so people hypothesized
that that aperture allowed them to see the UFO. And if UFOs are moving like we think they might
move, you'd expect light stretching or light crunching. And so in the light stretching case,
you'd get red shifts and infrared would be probably better. And then in the light crunching case,
if it was moving towards you, you'd see UV. And so maybe these are good detection methods.
I guess we will discover. We have to do more infrared surveys and simply search for UFOs in it
or search for flying saucers in it, like I rather suggest. I think there has been also
a certain misdirection when people try to answer the question, what are UFOs? Because you have all
these UFO reporting groups that spend lots of time trying to say, what are UFOs? And they say,
oh no, 3% of the time it's birds and 10% of the time it's insects. And they go on.
I think it's an irrelevant question. The only question that should matter is like,
are those that would push the edge of science, which is for example,
are there non-human intelligence on our planet? That's the relevant question to answer,
not what are UFOs and what is all falling into that category. So if you say, is there some
non-human technology that we see available? That's a relevant question. The relevant question is of
course also if UFOs have some kind of medical effect on people or are they proposing a hazard
to pilots or to people on the sea. These are relevant questions, but just the question,
what are UFOs? It's too broad. Have you ever experienced, because you are going out on a limb
and even looking into this stuff, you, Avi Loeb, a few other astronomers of serious pedigree
are even entertaining this. Have you experienced any blowback for what you're doing? Yes, I have.
So far not come in the form of direct complaint on my choice of topic from astronomer colleagues.
They have been too busy with attacking me for my choice of collaborator. So in 2021, when we did
this discovery of the nine transients, I published a paper with my colleague, Jeff Marcy. So he had
been canceled in a sexual harassment scandal in 2015. But he kept on publishing papers and
everything kind of, I mean, even if he retired himself, but he still published papers and
collaborated with scientists. Except for that the same week as we got our paper accepted into the
journal, suddenly the national academy of sciences decided to kick him out of the national academy
of sciences. So he was removed from there. And then science and nature published papers about it.
And everyone said, who is still collaborating with Jeff Marcy? And we had the paper already
accepted. And I remember someone like calling me and saying, don't make any press release
because otherwise you're going to get seriously attacked. That's wild. So since then I got kicked
out of conferences. They find all kinds of ways to like not letting me talk, forgetting my
registration. I had social media attacks. I'm going to work with a scientist because he's
fantastic simply. And I believe in human rights. And that's my thing that I don't understand that
people should be like, the idea of that one condemns a person outside of the court in a
public court is for me. He was never convicted. No, nothing like that. So that is for me goes
against the human rights. And the second thing is that even if people do something wrong,
they still should have a chance for rehabilitation. Why is Jeff Marcy suddenly an exception to all
human rights? I cannot accept that. Also, I have no idea what he did in 2015.
I didn't know him back then. I got to know him much later. So not even commenting on
whatever happened then. For me, I care about the truth as far as people's incentives around
attacking the person. Okay, go after the person when they did it, if you really care about the
thing they did. But to go after it right when you publish your paper about these anomalous objects,
that seems to be at least motivated by the anomalous objects and trying to cover that
up and not like the initial grievance. I cannot answer that question. It might
have been a coincidence. But anyway, it happened at the same time. So I have no idea what to answer
on this. But I can say that I had a lot of troubles because of my collaboration with Jeff.
But I will work with him as long as it's productive, as long as it's fun and helps
the science. I will keep working with him. And I simply am not going to allow some peer pressure
to stop me or force me into giving up my belief into human rights. And that's something that is
important to me. Good for you. Do you think we are close to finding anything? I mean,
do you have like an intuitive sense for just the overall dynamic of, you know,
finding kind of more of a smoking gun, more evidence around UAP? I think we have to search
for more. We have to do the best we can with the scientific projects. We have to attack the data
from all directions. And we have to ignore all the setbacks. Because I think, actually,
one of the things that the whole bad episode with all these troubles with the cancel culture
taught me is that one has to develop resistance. One has to develop resistance on peer pressure
and critique. And I think it maybe even helped me. If I wouldn't have that experience, would I dare
to work on UFOs today? It's a question I ask myself. Or did that actually liberate me in some
ways that I said, okay, they're always going to complain. Some of my favorite people have been
unreasonably canceled. And it's weirdly freeing. Because they're just like, when you get crucified
like that, you're just like, whatever, especially when it's completely unwarranted and unreasonable,
you kind of like let go and just, you know, and then you're really, you're kind of free.
You're not bounded by like needing to be liked or validated, which most people are.
So that's, I think that happened to me. I just say, okay, I'm going to do the science I love to do.
I love to work on this topic. I don't care if anyone now thinks that I'm touching forbidden land
or that I'm saying something that I shouldn't be saying. I know some people are uncomfortable
with that I have the European Crash Retrieval Initiative as a hobby project in my free time.
What is that? The European Crash Retrieval Initiative?
Well, it's a private citizen driven crash retrieval team.
How do you go looking for crash retrieval?
Well, we actually are.
How can I get involved?
So we have a small database run by Vasco where we take in all the tips and suggestions for
possible crash retrievals in Europe. We only stay inside Europe because of the,
it's easier from a legal point of view to operate.
And are the databases just like crowd sourced from people saying like online,
I saw a thing crash and that sort of thing?
Yeah, we have gotten lots of suggestions for cold cases.
But we hope to also get some hot case where someone says,
hey, I saw a UFO crash yesterday. Can you come here?
Wow.
That's what we are hoping to get.
Do you have any recent cold cases?
We are working on a cold case that I cannot go into details on, but it's super cool. Super scary.
I want to go. That sounds amazing.
But I can't comment further on that, but there are some really interesting cases.
Yes.
Wow.
Is there a correlation with where the crashes occur? Are they around specific sites?
I cannot answer any questions.
About that?
I cannot comment more on.
Okay. Is it like, it's like a private group or?
It's a private group. So it's led by Thomas Bovinder and Alex Torell in Sweden.
Okay.
So they are the project leaders.
Are you guys, is there like a desire to commercialize this stuff?
We are trying to actually stay as independent as possible so that we cannot get under pressure in
any way. So far we are not funded. We are just putting our own private money into if there's
something fun that we find. We are looking into some interesting cases and we have something
particularly interesting right now. I cannot comment on it. I hope that we will learn more
in the coming year while working on that. And the idea is simply that we don't want to wait
for governments to open up about materials or UFOs. I simply believe that this is a question
everyone can work with. I believe that the only thing you need is some activity that one starts
collecting inquiring about potential UFO crashes and try to see is there anyone who is willing to
share material or willing to share knowledge of such a crash. I suspect that there must be quite
a number of such crashes in Europe also. And not only those that one has discussed regarding United
States. So where is the information and what can we learn about all this?
Is the methodology like scraping the internet for like people writing about this stuff?
We are doing some active investigations of course also looking ourselves for these places but also
hoping that someone will just inform us about something that is new because it's sometimes
maybe easier to go to a newly crashed UFO than to try to find it 50 years after.
Fascinating. Do you have a hypothesis as to you know per our conversation earlier,
do you have a hypothesis as to what you'll find in the form of a crashed UFO?
Well it would be nice to find a flying saucer.
Do you believe most of them are flying saucers or do you think they're you know this Michael
Schellenberger this journalist just testified in front of congress put out this 12 page report
Immaculate Constellation this program that seemed to be some unacknowledged special access program
in the US and in it there are like there's a taxonomy. There are like different descriptions
of crafts. You have flying saucers, you have orbs, you have jellyfish as actually mentioned
in this document. Do you believe in kind of a variety of things or do you think the flying
saucer is the main thing or what do you think? Well my guess is that there would be a variety
of things but I first would like to get confirmed a single object before I could even speculate
further because we need the actual physical proof and I don't think any government is willing to
release that. Why do you think you know like at least not now one if I were playing devil's
advocate and acting skeptical I would say if you really have crashes going on everywhere
they're not just around military installations then like why don't we have a smoking gun yet?
Like if you have plenty of UFO crashes in Europe and other places in remote areas
why don't you have some like Inuit tribe or something just come upon a crashed UFO and then
like you know some anthropologist is visiting and then they see the crash or like I don't know
random explorers or travelers or whatever like not we don't have one case of like somebody you know
having like at least a larger craft Gary Nolan has in his possession because they were mailed
to Jacques Vallee and he did mass spectrometry on them these objects from an uba tuba crash in Brazil
and you know from from Roswell you have bits and pieces of you know possible stuff but you don't
have like the larger objects that you might expect. Well my guess is that if I'm going to
um think about a counter reply to that is that we have been so much as a society
marinated in skepticism and we have been uh let's say if you now would see something that is metallic
and a flying saucer like maybe you'll think this is some waste from industrial waste that is lying
there you will find probably 1 000 ways of dismissing that and if someone would actually
say there seems to be a flying saucer in the garden you will again think that this is some
kind of military project and you shouldn't go to check it out not to get into trouble.
I think we have ways of rationalizing uh and coming up with counter arguments
so so effectively that we wouldn't be able to recognize a flying saucer if it even just lied in
front of us that's what I think that there's some sort of programming as well that has been happening
what drives you on a deeper level do you hope we do make contact and if so how do
how would the best form of that contact look like? Absolutely I really hope we make contact
with a benign kind and nice civilization I don't know how likely this defines such a civilization
but imagine if we find out that we are in touch how much could we learn as species how much could
we learn from them what could we learn what are all the discoveries that we don't have to make
but that we could learn about from them directly I think it's it would be an amazing opportunity
for humanity to actually progress. Amen is there anything on molecular biology which you studied
before or just life in general or religion or anything that you've rethought because of your
current contemporary interest from an astronomical perspective in UAP? That's a very good question
I must say that I don't know the answer to it but I'm definitely open about the idea that
another civilization might have been interacting with us for thousands or
tens of thousands of years or longer and that they could have brought some influence already
into well our development I'm open for that I want to know if it's that way or not
I want clear answers I want clear answers with if there are any UFOs or flying saucers that can be
seen in astronomical data I want simple binary answers to whether they are non-human artificial
objects on the earth or in our oceans or buried underground and I want to know of course if there
is some non-human biologics that has been caught or by the humans that are by the military because
all these questions can change our understanding of our place in the universe my place in the
universe and I would like to get answers within our lifetime I think this is the most pressing
and important question I'm with you it's almost like a governor has been placed on fundamental
physics and religion our understanding of ourselves and the universe we live in and
that governor hopefully it will come off I have a weird feeling it will in our lifetime which is
like wild I mean maybe I'm wrong right like Stan Friedman unfortunately would have been wrong like
I don't think things shifted that much in the last 50 to 70 years but maybe maybe now things
are speeding up it kind of feels like they are it feels that way to me too I just want to know
and I hope that we will get a positive answer soon either through the disclosure process
for the political movement behind or through science if that is the case
I just don't know what will be the implications but I guess we will learn
we'll find out well Dr Vio Royale I appreciate you spending time with me this was really remarkable
to just learn about all the stuff you're doing how can you know is there are you looking for
more funding is that like something that you're always sort of open to or like what how can people
help you you know in your in your efforts well there are several ways that they can help us
one is with the exoprobe project we are always looking for more support to set up more telescopes
in New Mexico where we have our telescope I think I didn't we're in New Mexico so the exoprobe project
that I'm having now we're setting up a network of telescopes because that will allow us to
to look for such a signature from an extraterrestrial probe or non-human artifact
but also confirm it via multiple telescope and once you can see it in at least two telescopes
you can also get the distance to such an object if it's outside the atmosphere where we are looking
so we're looking outside the atmospheres with exoprobe but in order to localize it well you
need to have at least two that are well separated and of course for every additional telescope
there is a running cost coming in and also the cost of the telescope itself so this is one way
that one can be supporting us another thing that I would hope to do in Europe is that we would like
to have at some point a conference completely dedicated to non-human artifacts and how to
search for them in space in the atmosphere underwater on the ground on the ground and
also these are things that are difficult to organize we would where we always can
will appreciate some kind of practical support to organize it if you have a hole in Europe that
we could use for free for the audience and so on so there's lots of ways one can help
awesome well audience help Dr. Virial if you can if any of that applies to you
I really appreciate it was awesome I thought it was fantastic yeah
so