The information density of your channel
is drinking from a fire hose of mind blowing facts.
The Golden Age of Army R&D has a lot
of really interesting research we can parallel today
and talk about later.
But during this time, the foreign technology division
was trying to use recovered technology
to use human brain waves to guide ICBM missiles.
Whoa.
It is not only possible, it is essential.
And then there's also stories about the 1983
strategic defense initiative instituted by Ronald Reagan,
which was to act against Soviet ICBMs.
This is Star Wars.
This likely had a back door to fund UAP programs
and act offensively against UAP.
This technology is obviously not ubiquitous.
There's different types of technology.
There's different craft design.
One could reasonably assume then
there's different types of NHI.
Some man, some not man.
That design actually was featured
in the first ever episode of The X-Files,
which was allegedly based on true stories from John DeSouza.
It's the same design.
Wow.
["Different Parts of the Brain Have Different Activities"]
Different parts of the brain have different activities.
You know that, don't you?
["Different Parts of the Brain Have Different Activities"]
Maybe you should interview me.
I'm here with Sammy UAP Gerb,
who runs, I think, my favorite channel on YouTube
that covers UFOs, literally.
The information density of your channel is second to none.
It's drinking from a fire hose of mind blowing facts.
I think any 15-second clip from any one of your videos
could beget its own entire video
on various other channels that are slower
and less fast-paced.
I'm just so impressed by you
and I'm grateful to call you a friend,
and I'm really excited to have this conversation.
We had another conversation,
and it looks like that might go up on my WAP,
this channel where we're trying to foster
really cool community engagement,
and have conversations that take it to the next level
when it comes to UFOs,
but this follow-up should get crazier
because the UFO world has gone nuts since we last spoke,
so it's an honor to have you here, man.
Yeah, thanks so much, and I'm happy to be back.
We recorded last time in November.
Since then, we had the hearings,
we had the Soul Foundation,
we had Jake coming forward.
We've had so much to touch on,
so like you and I talked about,
got this back together
because a ton of new topics to touch on,
old stuff to revisit, new information.
It's been an exciting time.
It's been a crazy time.
I don't even know where to start.
Maybe we start with the Jake Barber story,
so we're in unprecedented territory
where we have somebody coming out,
a UFO whistleblower claiming firsthand knowledge,
saying that he retrieved an egg-shaped craft,
and then a video coming out
that may have been a little hyped up and anticlimactic,
but if you listen to him,
a lot of what he says
is just extremely internally consistent
with people like Michael Herrera,
who you've done a great piece on,
and a lot of other accounts
when it comes to UFOs and crash retrievals.
It kind of vindicates Stephen Greer as well,
and so it's kind of hard to poke holes
in actually just the core details of the story,
but yeah, what's your take
on this whole Jake Barber phenomena?
To start, the video on the NewsNation special
isn't even, that wasn't taken by Jake,
and I think that was rather rushed and overhyped,
just like you said.
Dr. Nolan came up beforehand,
said people would be very happy with this.
I don't think anybody was happy with that,
but the whole Jake story for me
goes back to investigating Michael Herrera.
Way back in the day,
I think this was like February of 2024,
I made a video on him and Jonathan Wagant,
and anybody unfamiliar with Jonathan Wagant,
he was a Lance Corporal in the Marines
who claimed in 1997 while stationed in Peru
under Operation Laser Strike
that he encountered a crashed UAP.
Kind of large, egg-shaped, featured some ubiquitous features
that we see in other retrievals.
Where's Operation Laser Strike?
Operation Laser Strike was an anti-narco operation in Peru,
so there were ground-based radar systems
from U.S. intelligence to track drug-running planes
and so forth.
And what year was this?
1997.
And so Jonathan Wagant, a Lance Corporal at the time,
basically was sent to kind of investigate a crash
of an unknown, possibly foreign craft,
and he and two other Marines,
one Sergeant Allen and another person,
found a crashed craft.
The story is super interesting
because it features like mother of pearl effect
on the skin of the craft,
liquid coming from the craft.
Explain what mother of pearl effect is.
Kind of like oil on water.
Something that Jake and others also kind of described,
unique features of the shimmering of kind of the craft skin.
And also, Wagant spoke of what he assumed to be bodies
in the craft with kind of an arm hanging out of the craft.
He's only ever done two interviews,
one in 2001 for Stephen Greer,
one in 2023 under, I think, Dan Willis.
And so he is a really interesting person.
Are you in touch with him?
Yes, yes.
Jonathan Wagant is one of the nicest people
I've ever met in my entire life.
Wow.
He's a really good guy.
Do you find him beyond reproach as a person?
Yes, I fully believe Jonathan Wagant's encounter.
Why?
There's small details that kind of
prove to aid in other research.
The reason I covered him and Michael together in a video,
besides just the fact they were Marines,
is they both talked about a team present.
Of course, in Michael's case,
he talked about a human-made craft that he encountered.
Yeah, let's back up.
So you're saying, so Wagant's this Peru case,
and then just for the audience,
Michael Herrera is this case in Indonesia
with this Marine unit, right?
And they see this sort of,
I guess he calls it Vanta Black,
eight-gon shape, which Jake Barber describes as well,
craft hovering above the treetops.
He kind of closes in on it,
and then this really elite paramilitary unit
then basically takes his whole unit into sort of custody
and kind of reprimands them.
And then he thinks that this whole thing
is part of some sort of psionic asset trafficking scheme
where UFO legacy programs are actually taking people
in third world countries like Indonesia back to the US
in order to summon craft.
I mean, the whole thing.
Well, initially he thought it was human trafficking.
And we'll get into this in a few minutes.
It was when he gave his testimony,
when Michael Herrera gave his testimony
at the 2023 Stephen Greer National Press Club show,
that's when Jake Barber was sitting in the audience
and said, I know about this, and contacted Michael.
We backchanneled it, that was us.
We backchanneled that.
That was you.
That was me.
Oh my God.
But in Michael and Jonathan's encounters,
so Jonathan said he saw an extraterrestrial craft
or a non-human intelligence craft.
Michael has stated, unlike the air report,
which lies about this, that he saw a human-made craft.
However, there are some similar elements in both aspects.
The crash recovery team in Jonathan's story,
some of them wore DOE lettered rain jackets,
and there were other seemingly military operators
in black fatigues.
They spoke with American dialect, but featured no insignia.
This was the same thing that Michael described.
Michael described a little further by stating
that these men, back in 2009,
had really advanced M4 rifles
with beautiful range finders.
They had bioscanners.
Yeah, kind of like what he described
to be like a modern cell phone,
to kind of scan their identification and so forth.
So there were some very similar elements,
and that's kind of why I covered
those two people together now.
And that's pretty wild, right?
What was it?
2009.
2009?
Yeah, that's pretty shortly after the iPhone was released.
And then, so do you have any sense
of what these elite paramilitary groups,
who they're working on behalf of?
Is it UFO Legacy Program, is it the Department of Energy?
I know that's been speculated at times.
I've reached, I think they're two different teams,
to be quite honest, because Jonathan,
so Jonathan described a team of guys in camouflage
with weapons, the black fatigue, sorry,
DOE rain jackets, and also men in hazmat suits.
So this must have been a specially designed
crash retrieval team to contain biologics, spillage,
possibly hazardous materials.
If you analyze other cases in history,
the 1974 Koyama alleged crash,
and some of the majestic documents,
there have been occasions where toxic elements
have seeped from crash retrievals and so forth.
But I think this is likely a DOE Nest team,
nuclear emergency search teams.
This is kind of almost semi-private institutions.
I mean, back in the day, these Nest teams,
which were kind of elite operators sent to
deal with anything that involved nuclear technology
or nuclear secrets.
This was comprised of various specialized operators
and also received help from contractors like EG&G.
We know EG&G from the Wilson Davis Memo,
from the story of Bob Lazar, Edgar Fouche,
so forth, seeped in UFO lore.
It seems like Michael, the team he was dealing with,
is the same team that Jake Barber is familiar with,
and this is like a deep, black, former JSOC,
Joint Special Operations Command, Tier One operators,
former Delta, SEAL Team Six, Intelligence Support Activity,
24th STS, and these guys are bad eggs
who are okay with hurting people.
Then this is likely strictly private teams.
And so who does it roll up to?
Because this is, I was trying to talk to Jake about this,
and it's like, there's an ongoing FBI investigation,
so he can't say much.
And then I did get him to say,
well, you could probably guess,
if you had two guesses on the aerospace
prime contractor front, like, you know.
Can you say anything about the companies
that you worked for in the context
of these UFO crash retrievals?
Look, man, if you took two guesses,
you'd get both of them right on the first try.
There you go.
Okay.
And then, so my guess is, this is me talking,
would be like Lockheed and Northrop,
but there's this other element of Department of Energy,
who in the government does this roll up to?
You hear stuff like the CIA's Director
of Science and Technology,
somebody like Glenn Gaffney would be involved,
and back in the day, the CIA's Office
of Scientific Intelligence was probably involved
in this sort of stuff.
But who's in charge from the government perspective now?
That's a great question,
and I think it's probably a very small,
small portion of people, I think,
like you talked about, elements of DOE,
and intelligence, CIA, and I think,
even more so than CIA modern day,
the National Security Agency, NSA.
We know that the CIA deals with humant,
or human intelligence, and we know the NSA
deals with SIGINT, or signals intelligence.
As far as why I also say the NSA,
so in my projects, I use as much publicly available
research as humanly possible.
I don't really like to say,
well, a source told me this, a source told me this,
even though there's quite a bit of people
I talk to that will never make it on a video,
or never reveal their identity public,
but this individual was in US Army Office of Public Affairs.
He served in the mid 2010s, and he said,
I'm not really afraid of the CIA,
but what I'm terrified of is the NSA.
So I think if I had to wager the elements of the NSA
pulling a lot of strings.
Well, the sort of public-facing review group,
the all-domain anomalies, anomalous research organization
or office, or I always screw it up, Aero.
Organization, whatever.
The main sort of outfit studying UFOs
from a public perspective, the new director
was a former director of the National Security
Administration, the NSA, John Kozlowski.
And so it does beg this question,
yeah, how much of this is...
I often think that the overrated elements of UFOs
are just focused on like meta materials.
That's like the tip of the iceberg.
And then actually it's this way deeper sort of thing
around like human signal, like the fact that
we're like probably getting downloads and stuff.
And actually there's a book called Above Black
by a guy named Dan Sherman.
And he goes, he's like sort of recruited
into this like nondescript NSA building.
And I've heard some from an extremely credible source,
high up in government where if I were to give you
this person's title, it's just completely beyond reproach
saying that that program probably existed.
So he's recruited to this like NSA nondescript building
and basically told to do all sorts of weird
mind matter experiments, like collapse a sine wave.
He's given these like binaural beats and then like
basically he's used as like a sort of human antenna
for like alien signals.
And it's part of this thing he calls
project preserved destiny.
And he says that he's genetically been manipulated
in the womb and more and more,
I interviewed yesterday a psionic asset
who was recruited through the GATE program,
through these gifted student programs or whatever.
And so I think more and more is coming out of the woodwork
around like kids and gifted people
and like clairvoyance being approached at a very young age
for downloads and signals that they're getting.
And this guy named Andre Pujaric,
who I believe he wrote a book called The Sacred Mushroom.
And he had this space kids back in the day
where he'd recruit all these kids to upstate New York.
And he had this round table Institute in Maine.
And it was the space kids were meant to
basically get downloads from and Star Trek
came from one of these downloads.
Gene Ronberry was inspired by this woman named
Phyllis Schliemann, I don't know, Phyllis something.
And that sort of inspired all of Star Trek.
And EG&G, I think actually picked up
a lot of the work there.
And so super fascinating.
That's similar to like Tim Taylor, right?
He said some of the ideas for his businesses
came via like unknown downloads to his head.
Isn't that what Diana Pasolka has kind of said around him
and his work?
He engaged in protocols to basically download
all sorts of information.
And he, I believe started a biotech company
called Vivex Biotech and sold it for 88 million bucks
or something crazy like that.
And he claims that a lot of that was derived
from downloads that he got.
And I spoke to him for a very brief period of time
over the phone once he sort of disappeared on me after that.
And his whole thing was like, don't use your phone
and tap in and like, you know,
and it all felt like on the one hand cliche,
but maybe actually really fundamental important advice
as far as being able to gain access to better stuff
or whatever from, I don't know,
the whole thing's really trippy.
Well, it's been an interesting year so far, right?
With all kind of the mention of psionics.
I mean, I'm sure I speak for a lot of people
when I speak for myself here.
I don't really like to use the word nuts and bolts.
I think it's super cliche and overplayed,
but kind of my focus is in legacy program research,
crash retrieval, reverse engineering, stuff like that.
So the whole psionics territory with Jake and stuff
is still uncomfortable territory for me,
but there's still so many lines of research
and stuff I do that harken back to this.
One example is Philip J. Corso.
I recently did a project on Corso.
Corso stated that in 1960,
he was recruited to the US Army's
foreign technology division.
This isn't to be confused
with the Air Force's foreign technology division.
Two separate things under Lieutenant General Arthur Trudeau.
Now, the foreign technology division,
there's no records of it.
It's similar to the Army's interplanetary phenomenon unit
that probably only exists through institutional record.
There's no record, but in Corso's testimony.
Which, by the way, we know that existed.
Correct, yeah.
The interplanetary phenomena unit.
We know that that existed, which is crazy.
We knew that a group named that existed between, what,
47 and 50 or something?
47 to 50, and that was first confirmed in 1986
to UFO researcher William Steinman.
In the majestic documents, there's an IPU report,
interplanetary phenomenon unit report,
and an IPU field order.
Two documents still disputed, but.
So those are disputed, but the Steinman thing,
I believe Steinman contacted somebody
in the federal government to gain more access,
and they basically said the records had been deleted.
Yeah, and that it only existed in institutional memory.
That's right, but it existed.
And so that's just so fascinating.
And I'll get back to Corso, but maybe we'll talk about
the IPU documents later, because that actually talks
about a crash retrieval that killed technicians
at Sandia National Labs because of the danger of the crash.
So Corso worked for the foreign technology division.
This is not in dispute.
You can look through his official military records
that said he was the chief of the foreign technology
division, not out of Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.
But the crux of his testimony is that under Arthur Trudeau
in 1958 to 1962, we saw the golden age of Army R&D.
And this is where materials recovered
from the Roswell crash and possibly other crashes,
maybe Aztec, maybe crash at Corona,
Plains of St. Augustine, and so forth,
that the U.S. Army would partner with the U.S. industry
to figure out how these technologies work
and seed them back primarily to help the U.S. military
and secondly help the American people if necessary.
Well, we know we never saw the American people if necessary,
but it wasn't just to seed the technologies,
it was also to improve upon existing technologies.
You know, there's a lot of contention here
because some of these technologies
were passive night vision systems
and guys like Colonel John B. Alexander,
who has made some lies about the majestic documents
before dispute this and stuff like the transistor
and integrated circuit.
But I like to focus on other stuff
because the golden age of Army R&D
has a lot of really interesting research
we can parallel today and talk about later.
But Corso also states during this time
that the foreign technology division
was trying to use recovered technology
to use human brain waves to guide ICBM missiles
and ballistic missiles.
Whoa, really?
Yeah.
In today's world, staying informed
can feel like navigating a maze of headlines,
each with its own agenda.
That's why I started using Ground News,
a tool designed for skeptics and truth seekers
like many in this community.
It's an app and website created by a former NASA engineer
to tackle a problem we all face,
how the way we consume information
can distort our understanding of the world.
Ground News brings transparency to the news.
It gathers coverage from over 50,000 sources worldwide,
organizes stories by topic,
and even breaks down the bias and ownership
behind each perspective.
With features like the bias distribution bar
and factuality score,
it's easy to see how different outlets
frame the same story.
For example, when I was researching
those mysterious drone sightings,
Ground News gave me instant access to over 200 articles,
helping me uncover every angle,
from the facts to the spin.
For the left, from Radar Online,
Donald Trump says, shoot them down.
But on the right, news refers to it as a rogue loose nuke.
This just goes to show how different the framing can be
based on where you're reading it.
So if you're tired of echo chambers
and one-sided narratives,
Ground News is your ultimate tool
for staying informed and making better decisions.
You can even follow your favorite topics
and compare coverage to find the most credible sources.
And for a limited time,
you can get the same plan I use every day
for nearly half the price.
Just go to ground.news slash Jesse Michaels
or scan this QR code to save 40% off
unlimited access to their Vantage plan
or gift it to someone you know
and have more informed discussions
and hopefully chill out about those drones.
I only promote brands I vet
and I think you'll find them just as valuable as I do.
Ground News, the truth is out there.
You just need the right tools to find it.
Today, I wanna share something
that's become a game changer for me personally,
qualia senolytic.
Have you ever heard about senolytics?
It's a revolutionary class of ingredients
that researchers discovered less than a decade ago
and they're already being hailed
as one of the biggest breakthroughs
in promoting healthy aging.
This is where qualia senolytic shines.
As we age, our bodies accumulate
what scientists call senescent cells,
also known as zombie cells.
These cells just sit there,
hogging resources and dragging down your energy,
recovery, and even mental clarity.
Think of it like pruning a plant.
You've got to remove the dead leaves
to get the rest to thrive.
Since I started taking qualia senolytic,
I've felt a huge boost in energy and productivity.
I'm sharper, more focused,
and genuinely feel like I've rolled the clock back.
And here's the kicker,
you only need to take it two days a month.
This science-backed formula is non-GMO, vegan,
and designed to work synergistically
to help your body shed those zombie cells.
And with a hundred-day money-back guarantee,
there's zero risk in trying it out for yourself.
So resist aging at the cellular level
and try qualia senolytic.
Go to qualialife.com slash Jesse for up to 50% off
and use code Jesse at checkout for an additional 15% off.
For your convenience,
qualia senolytic is also available
at select GNC locations near you.
That's q-u-a-l-i-a-life.com slash Jesse
for an extra 15% off your purchase.
Thanks so much to Qualia for sponsoring today's episode.
That is so interesting.
I didn't know he said that.
That's fascinating.
So this is, Philip J. Corso wrote this book
called The Day After Roswell, and he wrote it in 97?
97, but The Day After Roswell has a bunch of fluff
added by its co-writer.
That's interesting.
That's, and he wasn't super happy about that, right?
No, no, no.
Rumor has it he only had 24 hours to edit it,
and according to his son, he put his hand to his head
and said, I can't believe this.
That's so interesting,
because I was just talking to James Fox,
who has an interview with Philip J. Corso,
and we need to put this out.
It's not public.
No, it is.
It is.
Uh-oh, is it?
Yeah, yeah.
He said he's sitting on three hours,
and maybe part of it's,
Oh, okay, only 20 minutes is public.
I think a little bit's public.
It's published through Greer, weirdly enough.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, so I think more can come out.
And he was like, basically James Fox said,
gun to my head, I get shot if I'm wrong.
I think Philip J. Corso was legit.
And so that's fascinating.
He had a co-writer that might've kind of co-opted
his process in some way,
because there is stuff in that book
that's, I think, clearly false.
Yeah.
Like, if you look at the tech tree
around integrated circuits and semiconductors,
I don't think you need alien intervention to describe.
There's, I think, a Munich-like patent on a transistor
that goes back to the 30s.
Yeah.
But I do think we saw this stepwise leap
in interesting technology around this time,
especially in material science.
And I do believe the basic Roswell story,
that some sort of, this memory metal,
and I believe Jesse Marcel, this Air Force flight surgeon,
that may have handled this memory metal material,
and that it probably did make its way
to Wright Airfield at the time,
which Wright Airfield would've been the place
you would've taken it,
because they were basically reverse engineering
adversary tech.
They had MIGs.
Russian MIGs later on, but.
Well, in 1943, they successfully reverse engineered
a German pulse jet engine.
So they were already successfully reverse engineering
adversary retrieved technology.
So it makes total sense that you'd take something there.
And then basically, to complete the loop on Philip J. Corso,
he says that that material is taken to Roscoe Hill,
or Hill and Coder.
Roscoe Hill and Coder is the first director of the CIA,
makes the call that Corso should be in charge
of doling this out to basically for civil side use cases,
for commercial purposes.
So like Bell Labs would be the main place.
Bell Labs, Sperry Rand, which went to Functon,
its divisions went to Northrop, Lockheed Martin,
Raytheon, and others.
And so Philip Corso actually has a manuscript.
It's called Dawn of a New Age.
And so for my research on Corso,
I read the two side by side
and went through every single difference.
Remarkably different.
For example, in Day After Roswell,
there's a passage about how Corso intimidated
a CIA director to off himself, which is absurd.
And of course you don't see that in the manuscript.
Oh, they just, they Psyoptim, man.
And he had 24 hours to edit it.
And what else, what else?
The first chapter of the book is like
a detailed description of Roswell
as if somebody was there.
Corso never, never talks about that stuff.
He doesn't know what happened at Roswell.
He just takes the materials he's seen.
Another example is continued mentions
to the majestic documents in Day After Roswell.
They're only passively referenced once
in Dawn of a New Age.
However, in Dawn of a New Age,
Corso also states interesting stuff that he found
after his time in the foreign technology division.
And maybe we'll get into that later
because we can circle back to the psionic stuff
with other like really old research we can dig into.
But, you know, Corso would talk about stuff
like a UFO working group, which there's reasons
to suggest maybe the Majestic 12
changed into that along the way.
But what I wanted to say about the psionics as well is,
and just kind of the mental phenomena,
I wanna route this back to three key players,
Dr. Eric A. Walker, Robert Sarbacher,
Dr. Robert Sarbacher, and Wilbert B. Smith.
So this story takes place around 1950.
Wilbert B. Smith was a Canadian radio engineer
who had a huge interest in flying saucers
after reading The Flying Saucer Conspiracy
by author Frank Scully.
Dr. Robert Sarbacher was the scientific advisor
to the research and development board
spearheaded by Vannevar Bush.
Around 1950, Wilbert Smith met with Robert Sarbacher
to talk about flying saucers
because the Canadian government wanted to use
sort of kind of magnetic,
the Earth's magnetic field for propulsion.
And he thought after reading The Flying Saucer Conspiracy,
there may be some sort of connection.
And during this meeting, Robert Sarbacher said stuff like,
well, in the 1950, there were meetings about flying saucers.
The US government studies them.
It's spearheaded by a group of Vannevar Bush.
I can't tell you what they're from or what they're made of,
but we know they're not made by humans.
So Wilbert Smith relayed that in a 1950
Department of Transportation Canada memo
that was then reduced from top secret
to I think restricted access or confidential in 1960 something
and then completely unclassified later.
But so Wilbert B. Smith took that
and met with Sarbacher and these guys again
to really get involved with UFOs.
And Sarbacher basically said,
I can connect you to the proper American authorities
to engage with more UFO research
if you can A, become cleared, and B, give something back.
And so Wilbert B. Smith, he would later on go
to Spearhead Project Magnet,
which was Canada's first UFO investigation group
followed up by Project Second Story.
But when he finally met again with the Americans,
he learned other things such as, you know,
Vannevar Bush spearhead the group.
He knew that.
He had a couple more things, but he also said
that the US authorities studying UFOs
were obsessed with the mental phenomena
that accompanied UFO research.
So later on down the line,
there was also a gentleman, Dr. Eric A. Walker.
This guy is super esteemed.
He was Penn State University's president,
one of the smartest people of the entire 20th century.
He was named in a conversation to William Steinman,
UFO researcher, that one of the attendees
of these meetings in the 1950s about UFO crash retrievals
was Dr. Eric A. Walker.
Dr. Eric A. Walker would stay silent for a long time.
He was first contacted in, I think, 1984 by William Steinman.
He returned William Steinman's letter really cryptically
with a typed thing saying like, go, go, go, leave me alone.
But eventually he would kind of meet with Steinman,
another researcher named Henry Azadahel.
During these meetings, he would say some interesting stuff
like he was present at the 1965 Kexberg UFO crash.
And yes, that he did attend these meetings,
but when William Steinman asked him about,
or maybe it was Henry Azadahel,
asked him about Majestic 12,
he said he knew about Majestic 12,
he'd known about them for 40 years.
And he retorted with a question saying,
what do you know about ESP, extra sensory perception,
unless you know about it.
I think he said the sixth sense specifically.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you would never be let in.
Yes.
Well, it was almost, not only you'd never be let in,
like you can't even comprehend the reality of it.
It was, and I think it was a Don Quixote reference, right?
Yeah, chasing after windmills.
Chasing after windmills.
Which that's always stuck with me.
It's like disclosure isn't this file
that you can just give to somebody.
No.
It's like, I can't even tell you
because you're like, you're literally like unable
to cognize what I might be able to, you know, share.
Yeah.
That's, it's just so fascinating.
And so, and then just to add corroboration
to the first thing you were mentioning
with the Sarabacher-Wilbert-Smith connection,
not only did he run, you know, research and development,
you know, under Vannevar Bush,
he was head of Washington National Labs.
Yeah.
He was like atomic energy expert
at the highest level in the U.S.
And he was kind of scrubbed, this is Robert Sarabacher,
he was kind of scrubbed from the internet as well.
And he was known for having like an IQ of, you know,
200 plus or something. Brilliant person.
He was a brilliant guy.
And so he's just this fascinating character
who is also very close with Thomas Townsend Brown,
who's this anti-gravity inventor at the time.
You know better than anybody.
Well, in 1956, when Thomas Townsend Brown
does his experiment in Paris,
proving the Bifield Brown effect
and that this works in a vacuum,
and I think showing some sort of interesting coupling
between electromagnetism and gravity,
he comes back to the U.S. and he's picked up
in a black Cadillac by Robert Sarabacher,
who he's very, very close to.
And so there's a lot of, you know, connection there.
And so you had a third, so Eric Walker, Robert Sarabacher,
both corroboration for this sort of ESP, psionic thing.
What else?
And then another thing I'm sure many viewers will know,
Leonard Stringfield, who's one of the greatest
crash retrieval researchers,
probably the greatest of all time.
In the 70s and 80s, when nobody was doing this,
he was researching crash retrievals.
He was mainly focusing on witness testimony.
In his file, so in crash retrieval status reports,
one through seven, as well as when he passed on
and Michael Schrat went to his archives in Cincinnati
and read through the rest of his reports,
he found numerous mentions of witnesses
who had observed recovered UFOs
and kind of cutaway diagrams accompanying the UFOs
and how in certain retrieval cases,
there would seem to be like a headband
or a headband transceiver worn by the operators
of the craft that somehow would pilot said craft.
And the same thing Corso said, right?
In interviews with him, he said that the operators
of specifically the Roswell craft
were part of the guidance system.
So it doesn't seem too far-fetched when Jake talks
about an asset, a psionic person being able
to use their mind to commandeer the flight controls
of a craft.
When we look at collecting data,
one of the areas that we look to collect data
is through a psionic asset, which is an individual
who's trained in remote viewing,
psychic abilities, telekinesis, that type of thing.
I'm still unfamiliar with the physics
of really how to wrap my head around this fully,
but it's not out of the question to me.
It's based in a lot of research spanning back to 1960s.
Yeah, no, I think it's the future of physics.
And I think it's just, so like,
when you have an anomaly in physics,
if you can't turn it into math
and you can't instrumentalize it into technology,
I think it goes into this category called an anomaly
and you just don't know what to do with it.
And then the anomaly usually or often
will get vindicated in a new theory.
But until that anomaly gets vindicated in a new theory,
you just have to say it's a weird anomaly
and we don't know what to do with it.
And so parapsychology, I think is,
parapsychology being the psionic sort of mind matter thing
is proven experimentally.
You can't turn it into math.
We're in the Stone Age on it
and it's hard to turn into technology.
Maybe inside government circles
have turned this into technology,
but we haven't civil side.
And so I think because of that, it's totally stigmatized.
But if you look at other examples in the past,
like black body radiation in the 1860s
or the orbit of Mercury,
which was not described well in Newtonian paradigm,
you needed Einstein to describe it.
Until you get the new theory,
you just don't get vindication for the anomaly.
And so that's my take on it.
It's not like physics outside of that branch
has been productive at all in the last 70 years.
It's actually been extremely unproductive.
Well, who knows what sort of progress has been made
that's been kind of kept under wraps.
We have SRI and SAIC with the Stargate program
and you and I have personal experience with Randy,
who as a green beret was at
the Naval Surface Warfare Center crane,
went underground via contractor SAIC
and was shown technology that purportedly
responded to human consciousness.
We get under there, door opens,
we go through a security type checkpoint.
I remember the first thing that stood out to me
was that it was significantly more modern
than everything up top and that was odd.
Now anybody who's saying that the Navy
hasn't studied this stuff is not fully knowledgeable
on the subject.
Going back to 2011 and 2012,
the Navy, the ONR specifically, Office of Naval Research,
was publishing studies on a sixth sense within humans.
So the Navy, SAIC, SRI, Stargate,
all of these guys are pretty interested.
I mean, we have US Army Incom General Albert Stubblebine
who wanted to basically cognitively enhance soldiers.
The movie The Men Who Stare at Goats
is made after Stubblebine.
Yeah, after Stubblebine, Lin B. Cannon,
all the, yeah, the whole Stargate program
which ran from 1972 to 95 and systematically
kind of employed these psychic spies
which would gather intel,
which was hugely consequential for the United,
I just interviewed actually Joseph McMonigal
who figured out this novel Russian submarine,
I think it's 78 or 79 and that was extremely critical
for the US during the Cold War.
And he was thanked at like the highest level.
I think Robert Baker actually was like
sort of very against his intel to begin with.
And then he realized that it was sort of indicated
after McMonigal sort of figured this out.
And he won the Legion of Merit
due to the very productive activity he engaged in.
So I do think the Office of Naval Intelligence
is the oldest intelligence organization in the US.
It goes back to the 1890s way pre National Security Act
and CIA and NSA later, like pre all of that.
So I agree.
And for the audience,
cause they're probably drinking
from a fire hose of facts right now.
Randy Anderson is this amazing Green Beret
who you introduced me to,
who is really just a, I think a war hero.
I think both you and I have heard offline
of stories around his deployments to various countries
that he wants to lay low on
cause it's not the Green Beret way.
He doesn't want to brag about anything.
It's not the SEAL way.
But there's a number of people in his graduating class
who've died.
He's gone through a lot.
And yeah, he was stationed at,
he was an 18 Bravo weapon sergeant,
an expert on various weapons systems.
And he was taken underground
to this deep underground military base,
which we know exists across the country.
That's not a question.
And that's a fascinating topic to get into as well.
Once you talk about Randy,
we can absolutely get into dumbs.
Well, I just want to hear you,
because I got a lot of flack for that video.
And I've spoken to his colleagues.
I've spoken to two of his Green Beret buddies now.
I have their DD-214s.
I know a little bit about them and their background.
And I know that Randy is not lying.
And there are people out there on the internet
questioning his service, which is insane.
And honestly shameful.
Yeah.
If there's anything substantive,
you have to say there or on the testimony, fine.
Because he also has pictures of him at Crane.
It's absurd.
At the year, right when he saw the technology as well.
He's a war hero.
You just don't, that's insane.
And then yeah, there are questions he has
about his experience.
The off-world technologies division,
like he doesn't know what that was,
was that non-human intelligence tech.
After that, we moved on down another hallway
and got into an area that had a marking on the wall
and said off-world technology.
Said off-world technology.
That, yeah, that was where the weird shit started.
So yeah, we go into the room and the one room,
these significantly higher level of technology,
like the lighting even looked,
everything was just, it was more,
everything was, it was just a different vibe, man.
I don't know how else to describe it.
Like I said, the lighting was different.
The walls had like, maybe I would assume
some type of Faraday material.
Everything was just a higher level of detail.
The first object was a metallic basketball-sized sphere
and it was above a podium and it was,
looked like it was just levitating above the podium.
Levitating above the podium.
What makes you think that that was non-human?
Well, A, I don't think it's a valid criticism as well
to say that because there was some sort of sign
that labeled off-world technologies division
that that's completely nonsensical.
Yeah.
I've seen that criticism leveraged around
and how do you, like, that's quite a baseless claim
to make that a division would not be named.
Sure, it may seem a bit strange,
but we're talking about UFO legacy programs
and deep underground military bases
that span the continental United States.
So that's not an accurate criticism to me,
but the technologies Randy saw,
I wanna focus specifically on the sphere
that he said reacted to human consciousness.
There is a mutual friend of ours
that has observed that as well.
Yes.
And that is Jordan of Sky Watchers,
if we can talk about that.
When he was involved in the GATE program as a late teen,
intelligence or military brass and suits
and eggheads brought in a case, opened it up,
and there was the same exact sphere.
That story continues to pop up.
It's either a sphere or a piece of metal,
and they wanna see, I just interviewed somebody yesterday,
and I can talk about this,
because it's gonna come out.
This guy, Shane Frakes, hold that symposium on Twitter,
and he talks about being shown a sphere.
And so it's the same thing,
shown a sphere and seeing how the person would react
and if they have some sort of psionic connection to it.
And it's kind of the same thing as the Jake Barber story,
where he locks on mentally to,
in this case, the Aitgon craft,
but there is a mental connection.
And so that is, and then there's SAIC,
I believe is on record,
studying quote unquote psychotronic technology.
It's like a long history.
They coined their own terms
for like telekinesis and psychokinesis
and bought up the research from SRI.
So SAIC took it and ran with it.
And they were operating Stargate,
the psychic spy program in Palo Alto,
like at the end of its existence.
So yeah, there's a lot of history there
that just corroborates,
where if you don't know the history,
you're gonna hear this Green Beret saying,
I saw a sphere levitating in front of a podium
and I mentally locked onto it.
And you're gonna be like, that's fucking crazy.
But you need to update your priors
and actually dive deep into the history of this stuff,
which, I mean, you're like the tip of the spear on,
but I often feel like I'm out on an island
where you have very few people to talk to
who don't realize that this stuff actually isn't crazy.
If you're engaging in solid Bayesian reasoning,
maybe you have to think probabilistically
and it's not 100%, this is definitely real or whatever,
but your base case is that it actually is real
because there's a lot of evidence around it.
Yeah, and like the other testimonies we mentioned too
are incredibly interesting.
He and I spoke about that long before any research
with Randy was ever made public.
So initially when I made contact with Randy,
I went around kind of looking for any other story
that may involve some sort of sphere,
some sort of basketball sized metal
that might interact with people.
And this also like almost hearkens back even
to how we opened up with the story of Jonathan Wagan.
When he got in close proximity to the crash craft he saw,
whether it was the beans or the craft itself,
he felt an overwhelming sense of calmness
and communication in his head.
And we hear that from Jake Barber as well with the eight gun.
You hear it in pretty much every alien abduction account
is this sort of mental telepathic connection.
And I do find it interesting.
Certain people are down for like breaking exotic,
breaking physics in the form of exotic flight principles
and like metamaterials, but for whatever reason,
so that like breaks our reality there,
but they're not down for the mental thing.
And it's like, why is that a bridge too far?
If you've crossed this bridge, this bridge is crazy.
So you have to open up all possibilities at that point.
And again, think probabilistically.
So maybe that second bridge is slightly lower probability
than the first bridge.
But I think people don't realize just how limited
their thinking is around a lot of this stuff.
Yeah, it's like what we talked about.
Like my research mainly focuses on legacy programs,
but I can't discount the research done at Stargate,
the psionic stuff.
I can't leave that out of the equation.
I still need to study it always when it arises.
Of course, yeah.
And sometimes those bleed over into the realms
I study as well.
Because we were talking about Stubblebine
who was interested in psychic spies.
Then on the other hand, Stubblebine also has
really interesting research into like UFO crash retrieval
and legacy reverse engineering programs.
So on one hand, he's kind of engaging
with the more psychic aspect of the phenomenon.
On the other hand, he's dealing with
the really tangible program level stuff.
I mean, Stubblebine created the U.S. Army
INSCOM Intelligence and Security Command's
Special Operations Unit, the Intelligence Support Activity.
And I think 2002, right around the time the CIA OGA
was created, the Intelligence Support Activity,
which is a really, really clandestine,
secretive combat group, kind of like the CIA soldiers almost,
was brought over to JSOC,
the Joint Special Operations Command.
And if we adhere to some excellent reporting
by Chris Sharpe and others,
the CIA OGA and its creation in 2002 and JSOC
are utilized to perform crash retrievals and so forth.
Yeah, yeah, there's a JSOC continues to come up,
you know, as like they sort of go in, you know.
What's the connection between Delta Force and JSOC?
Delta Force is a unit in JSOC.
I think it's the 24th STS out of the Air Force,
SEAL Team Six out of the Navy, Delta out of Army,
and ISA out of Army as well.
There might be another unit or two,
I don't wanna butcher that,
but those are some of the primary units.
And my buddy Matt Pines made the connection
that Lou Elizondo is actually part of this group
called Grey Fox, which is deep military intelligence,
but specifically it's like going into extremely sensitive
sites for JSOC.
And so, you know, he might know a thing or two
about UFOs from that, not just the ASAP, ATIP,
whatever that experience was around 2007, 2012, so.
Absolutely, and another interesting thing
about Stubblebine, what we're talking about him,
in the memoir, Dawn of a New Age, by Philip J. Corso,
Corso stated he learned that in 1986,
there was a group created called the UFO Working Group,
which was created to study and kind of manipulate UFOs,
reverse engineering, and so forth,
and this was funded by the leader of US Army INSCOM,
which is, of course, Albert Stubblebine.
And to top things off, to make it even more interesting,
so that's 1986, in 1984, Stubblebine left the US Army.
He then went on to serve as like a chairman
or a board member of BDM, which was a defense contractor
bought up by TRW, which was then bought up
by Northrop Grumman.
But in 1985, Albert Stubblebine and BDM
at their corporate headquarters in McLean, Virginia,
created what they called the Advanced Theoretical
Working Group, which was a large kind of,
which was a large event classified with DOE controls
to study UFO reverse engineering and crash retrieval,
and we have the famous notes by Oak Shannon,
which resulted from that.
Oakey Shannon, who was a Los Alamos project manager
very high up, you had, I believe,
like Ferris Williams, Kenneth Shoulders.
John B. Alexander as well.
John B. Alexander, Hal Putoff, guys like that.
Was Eric Davis part of this or later?
I don't know, but I wouldn't be surprised.
He's always popping up in the same circle.
Well, it was clearly this sort of working group
to figure out the physics around UFOs,
and I think, according to Oakey Shannon,
there were some even spookier people
who would never speak, and they'd just sit in the room,
and they'd sort of gather intelligence on this stuff,
and then when Greer started his kind of
whistle-blowing efforts where he started to attract,
this is Stephen Greer, Dr. Stephen Greer,
started to attract all these people
coming out of the government and speaking to him,
and he starts to promote this sort of CE5,
like getting into contact with the UFOs,
attracting them, whatever.
Stubblebine and John Alexander show up around him,
and I believe Stubblebine offers him a big sum of money
to join legacy efforts, or join the program or something,
or what's the story there?
So I think because of Greer's own ego,
and I have my feelings about Greer,
both pros and cons, he likes to frame this as,
oh, Stubblebine offered me $2 billion
to shut up and talk about UFOs,
but I think, according to documents and emails
on the DPI archive, that $2 billion,
which still is an egregious sum of money,
was to purchase Stephen Greer's institution, CSETI,
and integrate it into Stubblebine's work.
So it wasn't just to buy off Stephen Greer,
it was to basically purchase his whole institution,
and this was in 1992.
That's crazy.
So what do you think was so valuable
about what Stephen Greer was doing in 1992 that would,
I mean, maybe that was a fake offer, or like?
I don't know if that's real,
but the real meat of the Greer saga
and the Greer information starts to pick up around 97.
It's really hard to track down
what Greer was doing in pre-1997.
But he was a doctor?
Yeah, he was a practicing trauma doctor,
I think at an ER.
I don't really know how he got interested in the subject,
but he does say at the age of 18,
and he said this in his 2024 September event,
that he was contacted by a cosmic intelligence
and told to basically save the world.
He's brought a lot of exposure to the UFO world,
and he should be really vindicated
and he's worked his ass off,
but yeah, it can be weird vibes, I think, at times.
I think there was a really big shift in Greer.
So he talks about his archive release, the DPI Archive,
Disclosure Project Initiative Archives.
He says it would take somebody two to four years
to go through it, that's nonsense.
I've gone through the whole thing like eight times.
But so in 1997,
I don't know what Greer was doing before that,
but in 1997, UFO researcher Bill Hamilton,
William Hamilton III, who wrote the book Cosmic Top Secret
I talked about in relation to Northrop Grumman,
he had been in contact with Greer,
and this UFO researcher who I think
is one of the most underappreciated people
in the entire realm, he introduced Greer
to various witnesses that would feature
on the 2001 Disclosure Project National Press Club event
where various government and private sector
whistleblowers would speak.
Some of these included some redacted names
who I've come to learn about those people,
they're not public.
And then, Mark McCandlish and Brad Sorensen,
the two primary witnesses,
Brad Sorensen being the primary witness
of the 1988 Northern Air Force show
where an alien reproduction vehicle was shown off
and Mark McCandlish, the person who created
the line art drawings and so forth.
And by the way, the term alien reproduction vehicle
that most people associate with Greer
was coined by Sorensen himself
and relayed in Hamilton's 1992 book Cosmic Top Secret.
He got this wrong, he said alien replicated vehicle,
but even so.
And around the same time, I talked about this
around Northrop as well, Greer met a person named A.H.
He's since spilled the name in his archive,
I just won't repeat it, we'll call it A.H.
But A.H. was, I guess, a former Boeing technician.
And we can see from Hamilton and A.H.,
most of the grounds that Greer operates on today,
including naming sites where programs operated
where it's Air Force Base, not really Wright-Patterson,
China Lake, Dugway Proving Grounds, all of these sites.
And you can see direct quotes from A.H. and Hamilton
that have made their way into Greer's research,
he still is used today.
I mean, Greer's a big proprietor
that Dugway Proving Grounds out in Utah
saw a lot of UFO programs shipped over from Area 51.
And he always quotes that 35 to 40% of programs
at Area 51 were moved to Dugway in Utah.
Well, if you look at A.H.'s testimony
in the year 2000 recorded,
he says the exact same thing.
So Greer has really built upon, like most of us,
like all of us, he stood on the shoulders of giants
and important people before him.
But there seemed to be a real shift
when he gained that sort of popularity
where Greer would really, really focus on the CE5 stuff
which can really rub people the wrong way.
And I think that's really mostly due
to kind of the monetary incentive around it.
Like he's doing CE5 cruises.
And what is CE5 sort of summoning?
It's psionic stuff.
Yeah, psionic stuff, yeah.
But I think a little more spiritual,
like more focused on love and light.
And Greer's also been busted for posting photos
of like cactuses and stuff and saying they're entities.
Yeah, it's this mixed bag
and it's somewhat unfortunate.
But you have to express your sort of gratitude to him,
but then it's also like sometimes you wish
it came in better form.
Yeah, because I've never spoken to Greer,
I've never been in contact with him, I don't plan to.
But I've been bad-mouthed by him, I know that.
What did he say about you?
So when Greer releases DPI archive,
and I went through that
and looked at all the accompanying files
because with each witness ID that's redacted,
a lot of the time there's emails.
I would look through these and I would say like,
why does Greer get to talk to these people
and nobody else does?
So I would spend weeks tracking people down
and finding out who they were and contacting them.
There've been multiple that I have,
but at the tail end of 2024,
there was a recent entry on the archive.
This was a brand new person.
This was the army public affairs person
that I talked about recently.
I contacted this person, we struck up a relationship.
This guy's an amazing person.
But right when we started talking,
he was suspicious of my motives, of course,
because I reach out and I just said,
hi, I found your name this way, this way, this way.
Because whenever I reach out to somebody from the archive,
I say, hey, this is where the breach of security happened.
This is how I found your name.
It will not be shared.
I'm not interested in contacting anybody else.
So this guy and I started talking
and we hung up on the phone one day
and he called me back 10 minutes later.
He said, I need to know what you're doing.
I said, excuse me?
He said, I just talked to Greer
and he said, you're an intelligence asset.
I said, what?
So apparently this guy, when we hung up off the phone,
he then contacted Greer
because he was still in contact with Greer.
And he gave Greer my full name,
which I would prefer if he wouldn't have done that,
but that's okay.
And then Greer said I wasn't an intelligence asset.
So that's my one.
And then he said you were not an intelligence.
He cleared it up.
Or he said you were an intelligence asset.
No, Greer said I was an intelligence asset.
What is he basing that off of?
Nothing.
He's just fucking saying that you're an intelligence.
Yeah.
I've never talked to the guy.
And for the record, on record,
you'll say you don't have a security clearance.
No, I don't have a security clearance.
I've never been in the military.
I've never been in intelligence.
I graduated with a degree in engineering
and I moved to Texas.
What do you do?
Do you have like a day job
or is YouTube your full-time thing?
Yeah, like mechanical engineering, service engineering.
It's very boring.
I'd like to move to this more full-time.
For what, can you say?
Medical devices, formerly renewable energy
like wind turbines and such.
Okay, normal dude.
Yeah, normal dude.
But that's been my work.
But he's gonna have a massive channel
and do this full-time.
I hope so.
I mean, there's a lot of work in this subject
that I think needs to be revisited
because as much as I hate to say it,
and I'm sure you realize it as well,
there has been elements of circular reporting
in this subject.
Tons, tons.
And I'm sure like, you know,
I've been guilty of it at times.
Like I don't think you can thoroughly investigate
all of this stuff and get,
it's all so crazy and weird.
You're gonna get a little bit wrong along the way.
And so like, it's gonna be this dialectical process
where you have to wade through the bullshit
and just have open conversations.
And I think as long as people think
you're a good faith actor
and you're like earnestly showing your thought process
to everybody and you're like getting closer
to an approximation of truth,
that's all you can do.
Yeah.
And so, and then just saying,
like admitting if you're wrong
and like if somebody comes at you with something substantive,
just like accepting that and incorporating it
into your worldview.
And I think the other tricky thing is like,
people can say when you cover this topic
that you are shilling a thing.
And you can be-
Or grifting.
Or grifting, which is absurd.
Like I've, I do have like a company
that like encapsulates my show.
I've never taken money out of the company.
Like I've never like made,
I mean, money has come in through like sponsors
and that sort of thing.
Cause I do want this to be sustainable.
I have costs and like,
I'm down to make money on it long-term.
But like what I was doing before
was definitely more of a clear path
to making like a lot of money than this.
If anything, I've lost a lot of money
in the last couple of years.
It's kind of funny.
Like, but yeah, I don't think you can do anything else
other than like earnestly kind of move forward
and just be humble and cool.
And like people sense that and-
Yeah, I really, from what I try and do,
I see a big gap in modern day
in terms of investigating primarily legacy programs
and witness testimony.
Because historically like wherever you look,
wherever you look in this subject,
Greer kind of has his paws in post like 1995
cause even he is entwined in stuff
like the Wilson Davis memo going back that far and so forth.
And guys like really great researchers today
like Richard Dolan,
he still focuses more on like sightings
and kind of flaps and encounters and so forth.
And what he does, he's almost the best at.
Totally.
Well, that's the beautiful thing about this subject
is I don't view it as zero sum at all.
I actually think you're like best in the world now
and you will be like so much better there
cause how old are you?
You're like 28?
You're 28.
Yeah, so it's like you're like best in the world now
like tracking granular like legacy activity stuff.
I think I'm really good on the theory side.
Like, you know, like inter-domain consilience
between like science and like theory and that sort of thing.
And that's what I love.
And then, you know, we have a buddy, Chris Ramsey,
who has his YouTube channel,
to me, I think he's gonna have like
the biggest YouTube channel on this
just cause he's so,
his like the thoughtfulness that he puts into like
production and storytelling is just next level
and his skill set there is so good
that he's gonna open this topic up
to like a whole new massive swath of people.
And I think we're all like pretty like,
I don't know, we all have egos,
but we're pretty like team players.
And so I love that.
I think that's really cool.
And it's gonna be like a new era of this stuff
where we can just like work together
and like find the truth and complement each other.
It's really refreshing because any,
it's really refreshing to work together
because I'm sure it's like everybody who's done
some research in this subject knows
like any sort of disclosure
is not really gonna come willingly,
especially when it comes to UFO legacy program operations.
So kind of working together and tackling cases
and stuff like that is really brilliant to do.
And Chris is a great guy.
You introduced me to him at the hearings
and the second he and I met,
he and I were talking about Bob Lazar
because he did the interview with Luigi
from Project Gravatar.
He spoke very highly of him.
Luigi is super cool.
I've talked to him and he's awesome.
So this is this new documentary about Bob Lazar.
Bob Lazar is obviously,
if you've made it this far in the interview,
you definitely know Bob Lazar.
Absolutely, yeah.
But he is famous for having claimed
of reverse engineered UFOs at Area 51 S4.
And one of Rogan's biggest episodes,
this wild controversy,
some holes in his background,
but like spoken to Luigi and Chris
and they've actually really helped me update
my take on Bob Lazar to the point where
I think he worked at Area 51 for sure.
Area 51 or S4?
I think he for sure worked at Area 51,
probably worked at S4.
And then I'm not sure that what he was shown
wasn't shown to him deliberately
and he wasn't given high level frameworks
as sort of passage material and recruitment for legacy,
which doesn't make covering his story invalid at all.
It makes it almost more interesting,
but to me it has to be covered through this like meta lens,
if that makes any sense.
Through the skepticism,
but also like there's probably some real stuff.
Yeah, I mean, I've historically stayed away from Bob
because I'm so biased towards wanting to believe him.
Growing up, I would always hear about his testimony.
I was the first to buy Area 51
or UFOs and flying saucers from Jeremy Corbell
and his book, Dreamland.
The more I study other things,
the more interest I find specifically not Bob Lazar,
reverse engineering the sports model, propulsion systems
or reading about the files and bodies and so forth,
but specifically around the facility S4,
which I have good reason to believe
that S4 is just southwest of Papoose Mountain Range,
right by Papoose Lake is a real place.
And what's your good reason to believe that?
So there's a couple of public testimonies around it
that I don't really wanna focus on,
but like Dan Barish, Edward, Edgar Fouche,
who claimed that S4 ran the Defense Advanced Research Center,
the DARS, which was found in a ARPA document in the 70s
to be proposed to exist, which was an underground facility.
Never really proven to exist,
but I've talked to one person who has been to S4,
another person who said they won't comment on if it exists.
The person who had been to S4 said he didn't see anything
like crazy or extraterrestrial,
he was just went in the facility,
but he did say some things that are similar
to what Bob Lazar and others would say,
meaning like colored pathways
to show where you can walk and stuff like that.
Yeah, I think we should all wait
for Luigi's documentary, Project Gravatar,
because he's told me things offline
that out of respect for him, I'm not gonna share,
but that give me conviction that he did work at S4
around stuff that will get corroborated in the documentary,
so it's pretty cool.
So yeah, I'm saying Chris has as well,
and Chris is coming at this whole thing
from an angle of like he's a famous magician
for this, debunking other magicians,
and so he comes at this whole thing
through a more skeptical storytelling lens,
and he thinks that there's definitely something
to the Lazar story and that he worked at S4.
Yeah, I mean, if that story is true,
then that's one example of a deep underground military base
with a hanger built into the side of a mountain,
which is really interesting.
Yep, because deep underground military bases,
a lot of people associate those with conspiracies
for like human trafficking or stuff like that,
but those are a very real concept.
There's like a very rich, rich history
of deep underground military bases
that started in the 1950s and 1960s
out of Air Force Project RAND,
which eventually became the RAND Corporation,
which is a federally funded research and development center
that is likely up to their eyeballs in UFO legacy programs.
Why do you think, there's so many things that like
when you talk, I'm like, we need to query this and this,
and that's like, why is RAND so deep on this stuff?
So one of the things that I talk about all the time
that I think is really overlooked in legacy operations
is everybody likes to talk about the government intelligence
from military and contractors,
Northrup, Lockheed, Battelle.
The piece that's missing, the thing between them,
are the federally funded research and development centers
and the university-affiliated research centers.
These are semi-private, not-for-profit institutions
that are government owned.
Examples of FFRDCs would be places
like the MITRE Corporation, the RAND Corporation,
Sandia National Labs, Lawrence Livermore.
There's one at Penn State where Eric Walker was.
That's a university-affiliated research center.
And those are kind of another side of the same coin,
and we can talk about what I think
based on some good intelligence
what I think these do.
University-affiliated research centers
are like the MIT Soldier Nanotechnology Lab.
Super Soldier Program.
Yeah, the University of Southern California,
a creative research institute.
And that's another really interesting thing
where I think Bob Lazar might have done something
in and around the MIT.
He could have.
Well, whenever he comes up with Rogan,
Rogan always says, I'll tell you something offline
where it would make the MIT records being deleted
make sense.
And then he can never say it off online.
Could be a UARC.
That would be my guess
that there's probably some interesting research
that he was maybe involved in that like,
because that's from way back in the day at MIT was,
Carl Compton, he was president of MIT
who was rumored to be shown the craft at Wright Airfield
with this sort of Anderson Trust, these like CIA guys,
and actually like be very involved in like a CUFO efforts.
It's fascinating.
And now we have this Super Soldier Program.
Yeah, and so with those FFRDCs and UARCs,
what I think based on good intelligence
is that the US military and intelligence sources
split between the Army, Navy, and Air Force
will have a program, whether that be technology exploitation,
materials research, reverse engineering,
or flying of alien reproduction vehicles,
and direct connections will be made with the UARCs
or FFRDCs.
These will serve as the project manager
performing subject matter expertise
and research and development.
And that will bridge the gap to the contractors,
the defense corporations,
because as far as I'm aware,
most of the contractor personnel
will not necessarily know what they're working on.
A famous example is the infographic show whistleblower
where he talks about a guy at Texas Instruments
getting a piece of metal
and not knowing what he's working on.
It's the middle management of these companies
at the contractors that generally know
what they're working on,
like the security directors and so forth.
But the FFRDCs and UARCs allows kind of one step removal
between the military and intelligence and the contractor.
Well, but with MITRE Corporation and RAND,
you would think of them as having kind of the
top of the pyramid view on the technology.
Like, I believe the president of RAND Corporation
for many years was a guy named Michael Rich,
who's Ben Rich.
Ben Rich was the president of Skunk Works
that says we have the power to travel the stars,
take ET home, and made all sorts of interesting comments.
Like at the end of his career,
he also called UFOs unfunded opportunities,
said that we have UFOs and they have UFOs.
So like humans do, and ETs do.
Said there was an international corporate board
controlling a lot of the UFOs,
and that maybe we needed to take it back
into the hands of the US or something.
Said all sorts of interesting stuff.
His son was the president of RAND Corporation for decades.
So I find that somewhat interesting as well.
And Thomas Townsend Brown,
he's doing his anti-gravity experiments.
The RAND Corporation shows up, sees the experiments.
They have this meeting.
Something changes after the meeting.
Townsend Brown, his experiments just fail.
Something sort of nominally like they fail,
even though clearly they hadn't failed.
And then to me, it's clear there's some covert
IP transfer that occurs,
where his anti-gravity technology gets transferred
to Northrop Grumman via his investor,
who's a guy named Floyd Odlum,
who has a majority stake in Northrop.
And so there's, but there's something
around the RAND Corporation there too.
Absolutely, RAND, MITRE, Sandia.
Sandia and Lawrence Livermore were accused by some people
like Edgar Fouche of actually reverse engineering propulsion
for craft that would lead to like triangular ARV.
But you also have to look at the time
when a lot of these were made,
specifically MITRE and the Aerospace Corporation.
They were founded in 1959 and 1960,
the exact time of the golden age of Army R&D under Corso,
who said that there were institutions also created
to study extraterrestrial technology.
And if you look at what's weird
and what parallels to modern day
with the UARCs and FFRDCs,
if you look at US Army research and development,
this is gonna sound so boring to so many people.
But if you look at US Army primers
for research and development from the 1950s and 1960s,
like read through all of their proposals,
you'll see under Trudeau when he was the chief
of research and development for the Army,
he proposed that the Army work
for kind of technology transfer and technology study
with URIs, University Research Institutes,
and IRILs, I think it is like independent research
or something independent research laboratories, similar,
which are similar concepts to the UARCs
and FFRDCs made in the 90s.
So we see these insane parallels to modern day.
And of course, MITRE was made out of Project SAGE,
which was a Lincoln Labs giant project
to like make giant radar systems
to study ballistic missiles and so forth.
Well, it's like, if you were doing any secret,
if we live in the world where any science is classified,
which come on, yeah, of course we,
and now like it's all coming out,
you have people like Mark Andreessen, Ben Horowitz,
go to the White House, they say,
we'll classify math and the AI,
just like we classified physics and like Eric Weinstein,
my former colleague is constantly kind of opining
on like this idea of the secret science branch.
It's, you have to be stupid to not think
that some science isn't classified.
If we live in the world where it is classified,
that stuff is going on in the places
where we uphold the most secrecy,
which is these DOE labs.
And so like, I don't think it's like conspiratorial.
It's like, obviously, if you're doing a high energy,
really intense physics,
you're probably also understanding ontological truths
that the rest of the public don't understand.
That's often the case.
Like you start to understand things about reality
due to some of these experimental effects
where you're breaking the bounds of our reality
in some sense, through these high energy experiments.
Like it makes sense that UFOs
show up around nuclear weapons.
It's high energy output.
And if we live in any sort of like time bound,
you know, 3D bound,
like if there's anything outside of our,
what we perceive, you would be stress testing that
every time you set a nuke off, you just would.
So it's like not that crazy.
And yeah, I'm with you there.
And I just think it's so interesting
to try and investigate how players
and the government and military
package these concepts and these high energy experiments
to classify them and keep them out of public view,
especially when it involves kind of extraterrestrials
or non-human intelligence.
And for the aero disenjoyers out there,
as recently as 2024,
the new aero director, John Kozlowski,
said that aero is working with both EU arcs and FFRDCs.
So that's something to plumb onto.
Yeah, he said that to,
when Susan goes sitting right behind him to Gillibrand
at the 2024 aero hearing.
Whoa.
And then of course, when Sean Kirkpatrick left aero,
he ran off to Oak Ridge,
which go look at the FFRDCs connections there.
Totally.
Yeah, I've been doing a lot of interesting
material science there.
It's not just a nuclear lab.
Like they're doing a lot of frontier science at Oak Ridge.
Many FFRDCs are owned by Battelle Memorial Labs
or Triad National Security LLC,
which one of those three is Battelle.
Battelle's really interesting.
I mean, if there's any group out there
that is studying actual biologics, it's probably Battelle.
They run some sort of biological materials lab
out of Fort Detrick,
and also a lot of really interesting classified work out
at Dugway Proving Grounds.
It's fascinating.
Yeah, and that was always, I believe,
was it the HR Cross, HC Cross?
You know what I'm talking about?
This memo that-
Yeah, Project Stork from Battelle.
Project Stork from Battelle,
it's now clear and retrospective.
I think this is a lot due to Richard Dolan's great research
that you had this cleaving off of the vital study of UFOs.
The public facing stuff was relegated
to Project Blue Book and the Air Force,
and then all the private stuff was managed
by Battelle Memorial Institute,
the CIA's Office of Scientific Intelligence,
and was classified under the Atomic Energy Commission,
which occurred later in 54,
but there was a precursor called the McMahon Secrecy Act.
And so it would totally make sense
that Battelle would have a whole lot to do with this.
I believe Robert Sarebacher also told Whitley Strieber.
So Sarebacher, I just interviewed Whitley Strieber.
He talked to Sarebacher?
He talked to Sarebacher.
Sarebacher took an interest in Strieber.
And when he published Communion?
When he published Communion.
I'll tell you a fairly weird story here.
Stanton gave me Sarebacher's number,
and then he called me back and he said,
Sarebacher is waiting for you to call him.
He's very eager to talk to you.
So I called Sarebacher.
Sarebacher proceeds to tell me all kinds of detail
about the materials that he was working on
at the Battelle Memorial Institute
about how when electron microscopes became operative,
they understood that there was a molecular grid,
a designed grid inside this very thin material,
and that was what made it so strong.
And I think that's probably been extrapolated out
into our military technology in many different ways.
And so you're talking about an extremely advanced scientist
taking an interest in a horror novelist's
abduction account.
And so Sarebacher's working at the highest levels
of American military, and he takes an interest
in Whitley Strieber, reaches out, wants to speak to him.
And Strieber says they're about to meet up,
and Sarebacher dies.
Oh, oh yeah.
And so it's fascinating, and then again,
Sarebacher's just scrubbed from the internet.
But what Sarebacher, I think, told Strieber on the phone
is that you had all this interesting material
that Battelle Memorial Institute was managing back in the day
that Sarebacher was somewhat involved with.
So just another piece of corroboration for this.
And there's research to suggest that Battelle
also studied the really lightweight metals
out of the 1947 Roswell crash.
In 1949, alongside Project Stork,
they started publishing information
on shaped metal alloys, nitinol, nitmols.
There was a nickel alloy or something?
Yeah, titanium nickel alloys.
I used to think that Battelle was phased out of operations.
I'm not quite sure why I thought this.
But recently, I've taken a huge interest
in Battelle being one of the primary contractors out
at Dugway Proving Grounds, which I think
has a massive underground facility.
I've talked to a witness who didn't go on the 2023 career
NPC, but I've talked to him and I've interviewed him.
And he, while working as a contractor for the C. Martin
Company at Dugway at the West Desert Test Wing
in the Avery section, stumbled upon a building
where he saw a craft hovering in the air being tested on.
So fascinating.
And then Battelle runs.
Battelle has a bunch of old contracts
for making enclosed laboratories at Dugway and stuff.
That is really fascinating.
Is there a Mormon connection with Dugway?
Because it's in Utah.
And I think of the CIA as being fed into by a lot of Mormons.
Mormons were surrounding sort of Howard Hughes.
Well, Greer likes to say so, right?
But I don't know.
I haven't been able to make that connection.
But I was able to make a Dugway Proving Ground connection
to one of your recent videos with James Fox.
Oh, tell me.
So I was rewatching your James Fox interview,
and he talks about the 1971 Holloman Air Force base
footage that he talked to filmmaker Alan Sandler, who
said he saw the footage and saw beans in the footage.
Yeah, we showed that conversation
between him and Sandler.
What did you see on the film?
Was it color?
Was it black and white?
It was black and white.
When I saw it, it would be a black and white friend.
But it was nothing other than what we said in the book.
We see this thing, this round thing.
And it wasn't that stable, funny part.
And it landed, and the door opened,
and guys come out looking like they were outer space guys.
So in 1971, Sandler and another filmmaker, Robert Emanager,
or something like that, I think his name was.
Emanager, yeah.
Yeah, they were approached by two US military officials
to make a documentary, and they could include the Holloman Air
Force base footage.
One of these individuals was an Army or Air Force,
I can't remember, a colonel named Weinbrenner.
And Weinbrenner was actually part of the Foreign Technology
Division out of Wright-Patt for a while.
So that occurred in the 80s or the late 70s.
And so time goes on.
Weinbrenner would be asked all the time about UFOs,
because Robert Emanager would go back and ask him,
what did you think?
And there's a story of a conversation where he
and Weinbrenner are speaking.
And Weinbrenner is saying, oh, UFOs don't exist,
blah, blah, blah, while taking a book off his shelf
and giving him a book about UFOs.
But on his deathbed, there's a lot of research
proposed by like Grant Cameron and Anthony Bregalia
and so forth about Weinbrenner on his deathbed
saying that they house dead extraterrestrials at a facility
out in Utah, which, of course, is Dugway Proving Grounds.
Oof, it's really crazy.
I made that connection last night.
It was fun to see, the Sandler to Weinbrenner to Dugway.
Sammy, are you in touch with any UFO whistleblowers,
not whistleblowers yet, people on the inside,
who have firsthand witnessed crafts?
Absolutely, yeah.
And anybody who has witnessed craft in a hangar
in a classified facility in the US,
not just seeing a thing flying in the air.
Yeah.
That's wild, man.
Yeah, but will they talk publicly?
No.
And will they discuss the full extent?
Why won't they talk publicly?
I do think it's important context for the audience.
We're going to get comments, trust me, bro, or whatever.
No, no, I'm not saying that to push a narrative or say,
run with this.
I know people have seen this, not a trust me, bro thing.
But yeah, of course, I've talked to people
I take very seriously, like good friends that I've made
who have said this.
And these people are former military or intelligence.
They're not contractors.
I haven't heard a peep from a contractor.
I think that's a whole nother story
because there's government NDAs and contractor NDAs
and the penalties for violating those are severe.
But these military people are bound by NDAs sometimes,
which usually really long NDAs,
like decades long or lifelong agreements.
And they do not want to be the person to violate this.
Any who've seen bodies?
One of them has talked about a place
in which bodies are stored.
Where they're stored.
We'll say that because that might lead to people
being able to identify that person.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Anything about the bodies and what they look like?
No, nothing about the bodies because I think that is privy
to a lot of their NDAs and so forth.
So they can't talk about that.
How do you think this stuff gets so well-hitted?
I think there are some really important
foundational questions that the Jake Barber story brings up,
which is if you can summon these things on command,
then you probably have a thousand plus.
And if you have a thousand plus,
then you'd expect more leakage.
You'd expect more like I saw the thing in the hangar
and I wasn't supposed to.
I took a photo and it's out.
You hear rumors on the other side of this
that we have 10 to 15 and they're like,
we can only select things.
It's around atomic sites or whatever.
How many do we have?
10 to 15 and a thousand plus.
That's a wide range.
And so clearly we can't fully attract these things
that will would be my guess
because I think if we had a thousand plus,
these things would have leaked.
So do you have kind of like a mental model on that?
That's a good question because if we look at Ryan S. Wood's
Fantastic with Magic Eyes only,
we can find over a hundred cases of UFO crash retrieval.
And even if only 20% of those are true,
that's still above 20.
There's also claims by Greer and others
that at some of these black sites,
one to two craft are brought down a year.
So I have no conceivable notion
of how many craft have been brought down
or why they're brought down.
You know, you got guys like Philip J. Corso
who talk about the initial Roswell crash
being due to kind of conflicting radio signatures,
messing with craft navigation.
You have testimonies like the 1953 Kingman, Arizona crash
where possibly nuclear testing
from Operation Upshot Knothole messed with craft.
And then you have Barbara's testimony
that psionic abilities can forcefully land craft
or bring them down,
or they have EM weapons to target the craft
and bring them down.
And then there's also stories about
the 1983 Strategic Defense Initiative
instituted by Ronald Reagan,
which was to act against Soviet ICDs.
This is Star Wars.
Yeah, this is the Star Wars programs.
I've talked to numerous people
and I talk about this all the time in my projects
that this likely had a back door to both fund UAP programs
and act offensively against UAP.
So there seems to be numerous methods
for them to crash accidentally or be brought down forcefully.
How often is that successful?
I have no idea.
And what sort of technology is being brought down?
In Jake's case, we have the testimony
of the egg and the eight gone.
And there's also the classic saucer and so forth.
And this technology is obviously not ubiquitous.
There's different types of technology.
There's different craft design.
One could reasonably assume then
there's different types of NHI.
Some manned, some not manned.
I often think back to the 2008.
I'll say this slow,
because it's of course very complicated.
But the 2008 contractor that rhymes with Bakkeed Barton
wanting to divest themselves of a craft to-
You could say this.
David Grush said this on Joe Rogan.
Oh, okay, okay.
So in 2008, when Lockheed wanted to get rid of materials
to the OSOT program through the CIA office,
the Directorate of Science and Technology, Glenn Gaffney.
And he blocked that.
Correct, he blocked that, stopped that from happening.
And I have really good reason to believe
that this was materials for the craft
from the 1953 Kingman crash.
And there's also other lines of research-
I believe that too, by the way.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And there's other lines of research to suggest
that Lockheed, the only reason they were able
to give this up is because they were completely comfortable
in the fact that no other contractor,
no other foreign government or no US government
could make any heads or tails of this technology.
And that stands at a huge juxtaposition
from all the other stories of alien reproduction
vehicles being created.
Yeah, so where are you there?
Because I think this is really important,
is how much have we actually reverse engineered,
made progress and made these things flyable?
And you've gone really deep on this interesting story
of Mark McCandless, Brad Sorensen.
But I'd love to hear, let's go over that story
and then I also just want to kind of zoom out
and get your view on like,
have we reverse engineered UFOs effectively?
Okay, so Brad Sorensen, he's an industrial designer
with his friend, aerospace illustrator,
who had worked for defense contractors,
popular science, Mark McCandless,
in either October to December of 1980.
Yeah, so McCandless is a top aviation illustrator,
worked with the biggest contractors,
and you hear him speak and like,
the guy doesn't seem like a liar to me.
He was a genius.
He was super smart and like,
just almost like slightly, I don't want to say autistic,
but like, you just hear him speak and he oozes authenticity.
Yeah, yeah.
So Mark and Brad are to go to an air show
at Norton Air Force Base in 1988.
Mark had to not go to do work for Popular Mechanics.
We can actually see the cover of that magazine
he worked on.
So Brad goes with some former high up official,
I initially at the time thought
it might have been Frank Carlucci,
but it might have been somebody else he went with.
The air shows going on,
there's all types of interesting stuff,
fighters, advanced technologies, and so forth,
and then the person Brad is with brings him
to a classified exhibit at another hangar
and passes Brad off as his aide.
This was a former like, secretary of defense
or really high up person,
and there were other senators there,
Georgie Brown Jr., Cranston, and so forth.
Mark kind of thought this might have been flown down
to Air Force Plant 42 a couple miles away,
but after further research and talking to some people,
I do think this event did occur at Norton.
So Brad Sorensen is brought into a hangar
where all sorts of advanced aerospace vehicles
are shown off.
So this is like a back of the house,
more secret version of the air show,
only for select people.
And so there's like a hovercraft,
there's the losing competitor
to the B2 Spirit bomber race.
There's a craft called the Pulsar,
which is likely a Lockheed Northrop group craft.
It's an unmanned UAV, unmanned aerial vehicle.
And it was designed to go at incredible speeds
with scramjet technology to go super fast.
That could deploy like 120 nuclear warheads
on its underbelly.
Insane piece of technology.
And this whole giant hangar is separated by black curtain.
So eventually they go to the other side of the black curtain
and that's where mama baby and papa bear are.
These are three flying saucers hovering off the ground.
Identical in composition, but scaled to different sizes.
What stood out to me from...
So-
And these look like acorn shaped, is that right?
Yeah, it looks like a jello mold
with half a ping pong ball at the top.
Yep.
And so sort of a typical saucer shape
or maybe what you would see in the Kexberg crash of 1965.
Almost.
It's like a dome on top.
Yeah, like a dome on top.
And I wanna pause here for a second
because historically people have said
that Mark McCandless has relayed this story secondhand,
which he has because he created line art of the craft,
which we'll go into in a second.
But this was not supposed to be published, what I found.
And I was told it wasn't supposed to be published
by a person, but I found an original interview
from I think 1990 with Brad Sorensen and Bill Scott
of Aviation Week and Space Technology.
So no longer is this a secondhand retelling.
No, this is straight from Brad Sorensen, okay?
This is not a secondhand encounter.
This is straight from Brad, who by the way,
gave me death threats.
I don't like Brad, not a nice guy.
Yeah, he sent you some pretty weird shots across the bow
and said something about, so Mark McCandless died
a sort of strange death.
And he said something like I couldn't protect him anymore
or something, and then I believe the filmmaker
who made this documentary, I forget what the name
of the documentary is on Mark McCandless,
which is called Zero Point, something about Zero Point.
It's not the hunt for Zero Point,
but something about-
Zero Point is like the story of Mark McCandless.
That's right, something like that.
I think James Allen, he died in a weird way.
In his autopsy report, it showed evidence
of heavy metal poisoning.
Right.
I've actually talked to the editor of that interview since
and he said that they had received kind of threats
like men in black type encounters and so forth.
So somebody did not want this out.
Yeah.
And so, okay, Brad Sorensen actually has a firsthand
interview with Bill Scott of Aviation Week.
Goes back to the early 90s.
What is he, when was it?
1990.
Was it 1990?
Yeah.
So what does he say?
So he said he saw these three craft.
There was a demonstration by like cats in suits
with kind of a VCR and a video showing the craft
over a dry lake bed, hopping, hopping, hopping,
shooting up into the air.
And there were some panels pulled off of the craft
and essentially the bottom portion had
what looked like a giant Tesla coil almost,
like copper plates and a rotary arm to reach out.
The top part looked like a removable crew cabin.
This had F4 Phantom jump seats, super crap,
like a handball control mechanism, which by the way,
that was the control mechanism for the Triangular Craft
and Secret Machines by Tom DeLong.
But that's a whole other story.
And the thing looked like, all three looked like crap.
Sorensen said that it looked like it was made
by scientists, not engineers.
There was no beauty in design.
There was no streamlining of features.
There was slag on it, chips.
These things looked like they had beaten up.
There were rivets on the outside.
And so eventually during, the pitch for this
was to garner funding because Reagan had put a lot of effort
into this project with Star Wars and so forth
and the incoming administration, they wanted to see
just as much advanced aerospace money put in.
And so the story behind this by the men in charge
was that these craft were created, were copied
from technology found in a crash in 47.
The technology was not given to us.
It was forcibly taken.
It was never meant to be had.
The people who it was taken from or the things
that it was taken from, it was taken forcefully.
And that this was our poor man's interpretation
of how this technology worked.
So interesting, because yeah, that's the rumor
about Roswell, it was high powered radar
that we sort of, you know, that messed with,
interfered with the flight patterns of these UFOs
and then they come down and we weren't meant
to have this stuff.
And then you hear rumors in and around legacy programs
of like whatever beings are in control of the UFOs
like want their stuff back and are extremely angry
at the legacy UFO programs.
And so that begets all sorts of weird ontological
questions there, but I wanna stick with the core details.
So what else gives you conviction that this is true
and that we do have flyable UFOs because I just think,
you know, so many people are gonna sort of be skeptical.
Right.
I completely understand.
It's such a crazy topic, but this was the birthplace
of what we'll call ARV, alien reproduction vehicle.
This was kind of the first ever big testimony of it.
And Mark McCandless, before he passed in 2020
due to a self-inflicted gunshot wound that, you know,
who knows, he investigated the flux liner,
what it was called ARV multiple times.
He talked to an individual named Kent Sellen,
who said he saw this over Edwards Air Force Base
in the 70s.
He has an image taken by a pilot Harvey something,
I can't quite remember, over Provo, Utah,
right by Dugway Proving Grounds in the 60s.
And that looks identical down to the synthetic vision system
on the outside, which was an array of cameras
to kind of point to a location and-
That's what's so interesting about this.
It's as if we were given this sort of intact shell
and then we retroactively patchworked on like,
kind of low tech.
Yeah, like the jump seats.
The jump seats and the cameras,
and then you kind of like make this thing work,
but like it's this really low tech combined
with the really high tech that we were given or something.
But this isn't the only example.
You know, there's the controversial account
of Edgar Fouche.
A lot of people like to discount,
especially because they like to say that Fouche
has been debunked due to a lot of controversy
with the alien scientist that I still think
is it's really worth revisiting.
I talked about it a little bit,
but-
The alien scientist is a YouTuber named Jeremy Reece.
Yeah, yeah, and he had a relationship with Fouche.
Okay, oh, interesting.
I've talked to the guy.
He's a nice guy.
Yeah, yeah, he's cool.
But he's pretty critical of Fouche.
So what's up with Edgar Fouche and-
So Fouche was a USAAF master sergeant
that actually has-
USAAF is United States Air Force, yeah.
He has verifiable work at Area 51 in the 70s.
Okay.
And he said whilst at Area 51,
he would work on like advanced satellite uplinks
and so forth, but he would come to learn
from various friends he knew,
including some NSA officials of the TR-3B,
reverse engineered flying triangle.
Yep.
Weirdly enough, I've talked to a guy,
former Army in the mid 2010s,
who said he saw a triangle craft
jut off of an airway in Area 51.
That's pretty interesting.
Well, we can say this now,
because I said this in my piece with Randy Anderson.
Randy Anderson, who you introduced me to,
this Green Beret, amazing guy,
who claimed to be taken to this
off-world technologies division,
Naval Surface Warfare crane,
also occasionally does contractor work at Area 51,
and he's told both of us now,
and I've said this publicly,
that he has seen triangle craft
that he can only presume uses electrogravitic propulsion
because it's not using normal flight principles,
at least observably to him, take off at Area 51.
Yeah.
Well, this is even a separate guy too.
Okay, so then you have another guy.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, he said that this took off during a,
in the Chao Hall at A51,
during classified takeoffs of aircraft,
the windows are supposed to be lowered,
and nobody looks outside,
but because he was with a colonel,
they just kind of looked outside,
and a craft took up,
it didn't disturb any of the dust around it,
shot up silently, just vertically straight up.
And this is-
There's so many stories about this,
even Paul Benowitz,
who was totally mentally screwed up with,
and PsiOpt by Rick Doty,
Air Force Officer Special Investigations,
and Project Beta's great book by Greg Bishop
documents all of this.
You know, like, even,
like the reason that he got onto the radar
of all these kind of like counter-intel people
was because he saw this craft,
you know, vertically taking off
and landing at Kirtland Air Force Base
that looked to be like it was employing
exotic flight principles.
Right.
And we know from William Steinman,
this great researcher, UFO researcher,
that this guy, Eric Henry Wang,
who ran special projects at Wright-Patterson,
or Wright Airfield at the time,
was taken to Kirtland Air Force Base
to work probably on some of this exotic flight stuff.
Yeah, and Wang was also talked about
by my primary Kingman witness, Arthur Stancel Jr.
Yep.
So that's funny too,
but this craft, the TR-3B,
there were allegedly multiple versions,
a prototype and operational version
ranging from 200 to 600 feet in diameter,
crewing four, serving as logistics and transportation
for what could only be known as a secret space fleet.
The propulsion device for the system
was reverse engineered by Sandia and Livermore,
two FFRDCs.
The program was ran by the NSA, CIA, and NRO,
and the contractors at work were Northrop Grumman,
Lockheed Martin, Boeing, a couple others.
But here's what's-
I hate to say this, this all makes so much sense,
but it just fits so well with all the other stuff you learned.
This is the most interesting part to me
about the whole TR-3B thing.
Yeah.
Fouchet says the pilots for this were plucked
from the Air Force Test Pilot School,
which takes place at Edwards,
which is the 412th test wing.
There's a witness that contacted Greer in 2023
that I found his name, investigated him thoroughly
in an Edwards piece that claimed he operated out
of Edwards Air Force Base in Nellis and Area 51
on testing reverse engineered vehicles.
I have shown you a little bit about this guy, right,
including like the work he did at the Pentagon,
and Nellis, and Edwards,
and he was a director of an electronic,
or kind of an electronics warfare group at Edwards
under the 412th test wing,
which is exactly what Fouchet said
tested the TR-3B vehicles.
That is a phenomenal case.
So what does he say exactly?
So he said he tested reverse engineered vehicles.
At Area 51.
At Area 51, and Edwards.
So he said in 1998 to 2002,
this guy, Ed, was briefed into programs
while he was at Nellis under the 98th range wing,
which became the Nevada Test and Training Range,
which is pretty interesting in itself,
but that then in about 2006 he was sent to Edwards
to actually work and set programs
as a director of an electronics warfare group.
And like I vetted this guy quite well.
I've tried to contact him in numerous ways.
Would you ever put out a story with him, or?
If he would talk to me, I would instantly.
Okay. Instantly.
So you just know about, you're not in contact with him?
My number is blocked by him.
I've tried to call him, I've tried to email him.
You've told me about him, yeah, yeah.
I've tried to message him on social media.
Funny enough, one time he accepted a Snapchat request,
and I messaged him, but he never got back.
He never got back?
No.
So this is what I think
of the most consequential untapped testimonies there is.
So many of these guys, as soon as you initiate contact,
they say a little thing, and they say a thing,
and they get kind of excited, and then they get spooked.
Well, Greer did the right thing with this witness, Ed.
He was gonna bring him in front of
Senate Select Committee on Intelligence to testify.
The guy got cold feet right beforehand.
And I had this confirmed to me
by elements of Senate and so forth,
so this isn't just Greer saying that.
But this guy was supposed to testify.
By like a Senate aide, or like?
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, and this guy was supposed to speak,
but got cold feet.
Why?
Is that because he was threatened?
I don't know.
There's other, if you look through the Greer archive,
there's other witnesses.
It's actually really interesting to see witnesses
who are going to talk to Greer and so forth,
but then say they've been threatened
with some really horrible crimes, like really gross stuff.
So messed up.
Yeah, that if they continue to talk will happen.
I just don't understand why there isn't
some sort of limited disclosure around these things existing.
Because it's like in the event in which,
we're at par with China and Russia,
why wouldn't you let out some like basic surface area
that this stuff exists?
Like that's what, is it just this bureaucratic
bullshit overhang?
Or are there real national security reasons
for not letting this stuff out?
And not letting it fully out,
but like nuclear physics is not classified.
Nuclear trade secrets are.
Why is that not fully analogous to this?
I mean, it must be, even looking at the testimony of Ed,
he said 2009 to 2010,
he was part of an Air Force going public plan
that was called off by a two-star general.
Why?
Yeah, there are all these,
well, it's like you had under the Bush White House,
Bush 43, they were gonna do this sort of possible,
they were thinking about disclosure
and Hal Puthoff was part of this advisory group
and they were talking about it.
And anyways, Bush 43, so Hal Puthoff is on record
saying that Bush 43 contemplated disclosure
with Stephen Hadley, National Security Advisor,
and Dick Cheney who David Grush is on record saying
was one of the gatekeepers for the program.
And they decided that it was too ontologically shocking
to let this out
and that we couldn't publicly disclose about UFOs.
And I think that turned into a group
where they were reading about,
like they're reading the three body problem
and other things like that.
So super interesting.
I mean, this could also boil down to.
And the three body problem for people that don't know
is a Chinese science fiction novel.
It's a great series.
It involves basically like aliens controlling
almost all frontier science and sort of reality itself
and being able to stagnate but also upstart physics.
And yeah, reality being sort of information theoretic
in nature and the whole thing is so fascinating.
And this could all deal with the subject of ARVs
but real quick, you mentioned Dick Cheney,
a little interesting factoid
is there is a supposed S4 whistleblower
named Derek Hennessey who claimed he was a Navy SEAL.
He wasn't a Navy SEAL, I had this confirmed.
So already not off to a good start.
But he claimed he worked at S4
and sometime in the mid 90s that Dick Cheney came into S4.
But the funny connection there is that,
I can't remember the exact year
but Dick Cheney was actually going around to air bases
around the US to close up what he didn't think
was operating efficiently.
So that's kind of a funny connection.
So we know that he was going around to air force bases.
That's fascinating.
But Derek Hennessey lied about being a SEAL
so we don't know.
So we don't know what's up there.
I mean, yeah, the Dick Cheney thing,
I don't know what to think about it
but if there was a government behind our government,
Dick Cheney would be the tip of the spear of that thing.
Like if you read the Spartan Gelman biography of him,
his called The Engler.
And it's like that dude single-handedly architected
the Iraq war based on like false intelligence.
And he was a representative of a lot of oligarchic
sort of corporate interests.
And then Hal Burton gets the contract
once we go kind of screw up Iraq
and then he gets the contract.
It's like, there's something to that guy
where you even read George W. Bush's book, Decision Points.
And you're like, yeah, your decisions locally
are being made based on certain intelligence
being given to you.
And those decisions actually don't seem
extremely irrational at each moment.
And then it's like, who's giving you the intel
and it's fucking Dick Cheney.
And like, there's some other guys like Wolfowitz
and sort of cast of Neocon characters,
but like Cheney's at the heart of it.
Yeah, I mean, he would make sense as a person
at the top of the pyramid like Grush is.
Yes, yeah, person at the top of the pyramid
and maybe of a lineage.
I'm about to do a piece on Henry Kissinger in UFOs.
And I think there's some connections there.
And it's like, if you pick a modern Henry Kissinger,
it would be Dick Cheney.
It's like this guy is the man behind the man.
Right, so we were talking about the ARV and the TR-3B.
And according to Fouche and so forth,
that's not the only triangular alien reproduction vehicle
that's in kind of UFO lore.
There's also, if you reference forensic artists,
I've talked about this a few times,
Bill McDonald, who's done a lot of work
on drawing the Roswell craft.
He actually worked with Robert and Ryan Wood
to create the two extraterrestrial biological entities
mentioned in the majestic document,
the Special Operations Manual.
In 1992, McDonald met with two Northrop
and two Lockheed engineers who were fed up with the secrecy
and classification of their work,
who kind of dictated a drawing of a triangular ARV
called the XF-131 Super Sentinel
that operated off of like RCS,
Radar Cross-Section Facilities in the Mojave Desert.
And I've talked to McDonald about this
and he maintains the secrecy of these engineers
to this day, because I said,
hey, can I talk to these people?
But that design actually was featured
in the first ever episode of the X-Files
because I can't, Chris, or Curtis?
Chris Carr.
Yeah, Chris, yeah.
Contracted Bill McDonald to put that in the.
Chris Carr is the creator of the X-Files.
Right, Bill McDonald was contracted to put that
in the first ever episode of the X-Files,
which was allegedly based on true stories from John DeSouza.
And that episode is about a triangular alien reproduction,
triangular alien reproduction vehicle
that's seen over an Air Force base.
And it's the same design.
I've featured some clips of that.
That's so interesting.
I think Hollywood has been engaging
in soft UFO disclosure for 30 or 40 years
through these CAA liaisons.
We have Spielberg's new movie Disclosure.
It's now called Disclosure.
And I was talking to Chris Ramsey again,
great YouTube channel, go follow at area52.
And he was like, what if a UFO is shown
as part of that movie?
Would that not be the best way to disclose?
And like, I'm kind of, I'm on his side.
And maybe that happens.
And then historically too, you've had, you know,
close encounters with the third kind,
which involves Jacques Vallee and Jalen Hynek.
Jacques Vallee is played as a character by Francois Truffaut.
You see crates that say Lockheed in Northrop.
Don't they say TRW?
The skunk works in TRW.
TRW.
If they say that, then you're like, okay,
they're talking about next level knowledge.
Then they really know.
Because TRW was bought by Northrop in 2002.
Right.
And TRW was the contractor behind the Zodiac story,
which was an alleged crash.
So I think they do say skunk works in,
because close encounters with the third kind was,
they do?
Okay, I don't know.
Interesting fact about TRW.
Jacques Vallee has talked about Dr. Eric A. Walker.
We talked about earlier being on the board of directors
or a chairman of TRW as well.
Oh, wow.
Fascinating.
Yeah, I mean, Spielberg was dialed in with,
you have to go deep to talk about skunk works in TRW
in the film.
Yeah.
Well, let's look up, you know, at some point,
whether it's Lockheed and Northrop.
It's skunk works.
You're sure?
Yeah, skunk works in TRW.
Well, that's next level.
Then yeah, he knows a lot of knowledge.
Also on the Townsend Brown,
who I am sure discovered some interesting effects
in the world of gravity.
I'm sure of that.
I feel very high conviction in that.
And I just interviewed Carl Nell,
who's the deputy CTO of Northrop Grumman,
where I'm saying again,
that this gravity technology got probably implemented
in the B2 stealth bomber.
And he's the deputy CTO of Northrop Grumman.
And he goes, go watch Jesse's video
on Thomas Townsend Brown.
When I ask him, is there anything sort of useful
or applicable in the UFO story?
Jesse's done a number of podcasts
looking into Taylor Townsend Brown
and some other very interesting like heretical technologies.
So I'd invite people, an unsolicited plug
to check out some of Jesse's podcasts.
So there's more corroboration beyond that
on the T.T. Brown stuff.
But where was I going with?
What were you just saying?
TRW, Close to Cutters of the Third Kind before that.
Oh, okay.
So Steven Spielberg,
executive produced Back to the Future.
And the subplot of the whole Thomas Townsend Brown story
is that gravity affects time.
In general relativity,
gravity and time are tightly coupled and they're related.
And he talks about time travel constantly with his family.
Like that's something that's really,
and if you think about it,
if we were to ever engage in effective interstellar travel,
it would involve space-time metric engineering inherently.
You can't get around that.
Even with nuclear thermal propulsion,
you get to the closest star system in 40,000 years.
Biologically, that does not work, right?
So he's super into time travel.
And then you have Back to the Future come out,
which is a Steven Spielberg executive produced movie.
The guy's name is Doc Brown,
which everybody called Thomas Townsend Brown.
His name is Emmett Brown, E-M-E-T-T Brown.
Thomas Townsend Brown is in the name.
He uses his flux capacitor.
Thomas Townsend Brown's experiments
are capacitor experiments.
And he goes back in time in 1985,
which is the year Thomas Townsend Brown dies to 1957,
which is when I think his experiment
was first experimentally proven around that time
at the Bonson Labs.
It's the time that physics sort of went astray
in the wrong direction
when I think the anti-gravity stuff went black.
And so it's just, I don't know.
There's so much there that I think begets this like greater.
And then E-T even is extremely interesting.
E-T and the kid like lock it,
like they have some sort of weird psionic connection.
And you remember they're in the hospital together.
And E-T's like heart rate
is matching the kid's heart rate.
And you have all this stuff around the psionic connection
that's now coming out.
You also have the consciousness connection there
where the mother is walking around the kitchen.
And like these kids have taken,
these kids see the E-Ts, but the mother doesn't.
And like the E-T is sort of like walking around the fridge
and the mother doesn't see it.
Cause like her perceptive,
she's closed off to these realities.
So like I think Steven Spielberg definitely has been fed
some really interesting UFO stuff over the years.
And was it Spielberg or Cameron
that created the film The Abyss?
That was James Cameron.
Okay, cause that's also an interesting one about USO.
Totally.
It's interesting to see these concepts
relate in Hollywood cause.
James Cameron, Steven Spielberg and Christopher Nolan
are definitely fed intense secret shit.
Yeah.
They have to be, I'm sorry.
Cause on one hand you have films like Independence Day,
which is just a bombastic action film glorified.
But then on the other hand, you have very thoughtful projects
like Close Encounters of the Third Kind
and to an extent E-T and as we know now.
But even like where does the concept of men in black get to?
Men in black sounds quacky.
Yeah.
But like if you go talk to Richard Dolan,
he's a super deep UFO researcher.
Men in black, they are this thing.
They're in these suits and they show up
after UFO abduction experiences, UFO sightings.
And they often take people's footage
or like, you know, swear them to secrecy.
And he thinks, Dolan thinks they're almost like
the counter intel group of the aliens themselves.
They erase your memory.
And so it's turned into this like kind of jokey, funny,
you know, movie with Will Smith.
But like even that,
like where is that derived to begin with?
Right.
It's just so fascinating, you know.
That's interesting that,
cause I've heard that idea floated around before
that the like colloquial men in black
are almost like a non-human entity.
Cause I almost, I'd like to hear more about that
cause I almost stand on the other side.
I straight up think that the men in black
in a sense are NSA spooks.
So I would say the same thing,
but like how do you meet with certain people
like Whitley Strieber and other just experiencers
and like these guys seem to like
have technology available to them
that's not available to the general public.
And maybe that is just like, okay,
so it's like Occam's razor, it's like NSA or something,
but it's weird technology.
It's like implants that involve technological mediumship
as Whitley Strieber.
I felt his implant in his ear.
Really?
Yeah, I felt it.
And it's the weirdest thing I've ever heard.
And he says it moves with his own metabolism.
I haven't verified that, but like.
Has he ever thought about getting that cut out?
He wants to get it cut out,
but he says it moves every time.
And I felt the thing and it's not natural.
So unless he's totally grifting
and putting the thing in his ear,
even though he's not really like making that much money now
off of UFOs and it happened after he wrote Communion
and like, it's like, I don't know, man.
The whole thing's so strange.
That is interesting.
You know, perhaps the two are not mutually exclusive
cause there's also stories like, have you heard of TREAT?
It's the supposed men in black unit out of the NSA
called the Tactical Reconnaissance
Engineering Assessment Search Team,
which was created by Stubblebine.
Ah.
And it's only ever been talked about by Fouche
and Hans Adams, the Crown Prince of Liechtenstein.
So that's come up for me and I've never brought that up,
but yeah.
Well, how do you think that the Crown Prince of Liechtenstein,
cause I've heard some very interesting things about him.
He seems like a really cool guy,
but like really interested in the spooky science stuff.
I've only ever seen his discussions with like Greer
in the emails on the DPI archive
and looked up a few things about him
and him mentioning TREAT.
Besides that, I have no idea because I would see that.
And I said, Crown Prince of Liechtenstein,
a small central European company.
What have you found out about him?
Cause that's pretty interesting.
I don't, you know, I don't know.
I probably shouldn't say
because the conversations I've had are in confidence,
but he seems very interesting
and interested in sort of secret science.
One more piece of possible corroboration of, you know,
maybe it being a combo as far as the men in black
is I did speak to Hal Puthoff recently
and I was trying to figure out, I was like,
is it their program?
You know, is it the NHI program or is it our program?
And he goes, what if it's a joint space program?
He goes, I might believe that.
Maybe there's something in where we're in.
He did, yeah.
To me.
Jeez.
Yeah, so and Hal Puthoff is, I think as deep as it gets
when it comes to sort of outside the Overton window science,
which is now being vindicated.
I mean, he was just on a podcast in December,
which is co-sponsored by National Science Foundation.
And like you had like pretty high up DOE people
on the podcast and all these amazing people
with pretty impressive credentials.
The former head of revolutionary tech at Skunk Works
are all in this podcast.
And he's talking about extended electrodynamics
and gravity manipulation.
And I think it's clearly this sort of limited hangout
where it's like, let's partially expose some things
so that people can, you know, learn a little bit more
about some science that we've been sitting on,
especially again, if China has caught up,
you can't just, you know,
throw people off the trail constantly.
You need some limited surface area around it.
But yeah, Hal Puthoff did say,
and you know, it's always, I love Hal,
but it's always this sort of like, you know,
tongue in cheek, like half speculating.
So you never quite know.
Yeah, because he never commits to,
he never commits to something.
He always goes, the whole zoo of possibilities.
And it's like A, B, C, and D,
and then you have to decide, you know.
I, sometimes I wonder about Hal
and how much he'll commit to subjects.
Because under his tutelage and good friend,
of course, is Eric Davis.
And recently, like, as you know,
Missile Man, myself, and others talking to Eric Davis.
You did a great interview with Eric Davis.
He said a lot of interesting things,
but he also said some, a couple of things I disagree with.
One, he said that the only FFRDC he knew of
was the Aerospace Corporation, which I disagree with,
but I think that's because he was only read
into a sub selection of legacy programs under OSAP.
But he also said that
alien reproduction vehicles don't exist.
Do you think there's aircraft systems
that have kind of leveraged technologies?
Definitely no aircraft systems that have leveraged anything.
And there's been no one-to-one reproduction.
A lot of that fell into the psyche of the UFO community
because of Bob Lazar and then Brad Sorensen
and Mark McCandless.
So, I don't know where they're coming from.
And then other people kind of came out of the woodwork
saying the same thing, but no proof.
Right, and I'm only left with two possibilities
when I think about that.
One is that he's lying.
Two is that he was only read
into a select subsection of programs
that only overlapped Lockheed
trying to get rid of Kingman materials,
and thus he would not know about ARV
because those weren't part of the program.
And I kind of lean towards that explanation
because I really don't agree with that assessment.
And at the end of the interview,
I had a little notebook with the flux liner on it,
and I said, you know, Dr. Davis,
you really haven't even considered this testimony
of Mark McCandless and the flux liner.
And he said, but right before we cut off,
well, Hal Puthoff interviewed Brad Sorensen,
and we never got to talk about that more.
And to this day, I want to ask him so badly
about how that went because Hal has spoken to Sorensen.
Wow.
And I just need to know how that goes.
I wish Hal could speak a little bit more candidly
in an open setting because he's also super cagey
in the program with James Fox,
and he's also kind of integral to the story of Zodiac,
the alleged crash retrieval program
first introduced in UFO Magazine in 1998.
What is Zodiac?
God, that's a really interesting one.
So in 1998, UFO Magazine published a story
by pseudonym Greg Halifax about Sedge Masters,
a story about somebody who is brought
into a UFO crash retrieval program called Zodiac.
This occurred in 1988, 2001 or 2002,
there's an email chain with Hal Puthoff,
Kit Green, and Eric Davis talking about
the Santilli alien autopsy film and so forth,
and Kit Green saying he saw different pictures
of an alien autopsy.
But then in a later thread in that email,
somebody, one of the three brings up Zodiac
in the Sedge Masters story.
And most of this work needs to be credited
to, of course, Richard Dolan,
who actually tracked down the very likely author
of the Zodiac story and puts a lot of faith
that the Zodiac was indeed a crash retrieval program
and it was operated by TRW.
So that's just a fascinating story
how even it seems like everything kind of post 2000
or post 1995, Hal, Eric, and Kit.
What is the core story of Zodiac?
Like what is?
It's essentially the Majestic 12 by another name.
Because the Majestic 12, for people who don't know,
was introduced under, the Majestic 12 documents
first appeared in 1984 in a film canister
to TV producer Jamie Chanderay,
and this included the Eisenhower briefing document
and later the special operations manual
and then a whole host of other documents.
And this details the Majestic 12,
a supposed UFO crash retrieval and reverse engineering group
spearheaded by Vannevar Bush, including Dr. Ross,
or including Roscoe Hillencoder, Dr. Donald Menzel,
I think his name is, Von Neumann.
Von Neumann, Jerome Hunsaker, who else?
Denzel Ward.
Vandenberg.
Yeah.
Hoyt Vandenberg, Nathan Twining.
You have a bunch of head honchos
in military intelligence science.
And so, you know, Majestic 12, Zodiac 12, 12 signs.
Some might suggest in the realm of UFO study
that Zodiac is another name for Majestic 12,
just like Majestic 12 has been called other names,
like the Working Group, the PI-40,
by that guy A.H. we talked about with Greer.
So it's a super interesting story
that I hope sees more coverage,
because Richard Dolan has been a true trailblazer
in the Zodiac story,
and it's just kind of like the secret retrieval team.
So to be quite plain after talking with Ryan Wood,
I think the Majestic 12 did exist in a capacity
and probably still exists today,
but I am hesitant to think about
like a very ubiquitous crash retrieval team.
I think that there's a very wide swath
of retrieval teams and retrieval operations.
Well, there are people who I think are pretty credible
who talk about this,
like these continuity of government programs.
Yeah.
So the 5412 committee, you know,
national security committee, you know,
back in the 50s and 60s,
that turned into the 303 committee,
which turned into the committee of 40.
Do you have anything to say about that
as far as they're kind of, you know,
interested in UFOs?
Only thing I know is that Colonel John B. Alexander
said that the Majestic 12 was specifically
a continuity of government program.
Right.
But I hasten to adhere to what he says,
because he lied about the special operations manual.
He lied about a bunch of stuff.
Yeah.
And even in the Wilson memo, you know,
where they said that, you know, the Wilson,
of course, you know, the Wilson memo.
Yeah, absolutely.
So this is, was it 1997?
1997 was when the Greer, Will Miller,
Thomas Wilson, Stephen Lovekin meeting took place.
The briefing took place.
Okay, interesting.
But when was, and then-
2002.
2002 is this meeting between Eric Davis,
who's again, this HAL put off protege,
propulsions expert, and like exotic physics expert.
It's in the parking lot of EG&G,
and he's meeting with Admiral Thomas Wilson,
who's head of joint chiefs, joint chiefs J2,
you know-
He was like intelligence for JCS at the time.
So he should have like all exotic tech under his purview,
and he's extremely,
he's basically expressing extreme dissatisfaction
that you had these rogue groups working on purportedly UFOs,
who he met with, and it's out of his jurisdiction.
And in that document,
that I believe was found in the Edgar Mitchell estate,
in that document, it says JA is a liar,
and I think JA is John Alexander.
Yeah.
Yeah, cause John Alexander has been publicly said,
oh, majestic 12 exists that had nothing to do with UFOs,
and kind of all of that before.
And of course, he kind of said myths, truths
about what Dr. Ryan Wood said
about the special operations manual.
Ryan Wood and Robert Wood did a ton of provenance research
on the majestic documents,
getting the physical onion skin documents,
putting them through rigorous testing of materials.
So what do you think about these documents?
Cause they're popular view,
like with those kind of old school,
like UFO researchers, like Robert Hastings,
you know, who wrote UFOs and nukes,
this was passage material.
So it was like meant to detect spies,
it contained all sorts of falsities.
You're giving it to this film producer
who's friends with all these UFO researchers,
Jamie Chandra.
And then I think other versions of the majestic 12
were then doled out in packages to other UFO researchers.
Cause there's a whole host of documents,
and the source cannot be all from the same person.
And a bunch of varying quality documents.
I tend to adhere to the work of Stanton Friedman,
who spent a bunch of time authenticating
these special operations manual
and Eisenhower briefing document with the woods.
I think those two probably have the strongest claims
of real documents, as well as the two
IPU interplanetary phenomenon unit reports.
One of them is a seven page report
that sounds very similar to the Eisenhower briefing document
and talks about the Roswell crash retrieval and so forth.
Later on down the line,
you get a lot of other documents like the burned memo
and the project Aquarius document from Lee Graham.
The burned memo or the project Aquarius,
one of them I can't remember,
which actually makes reference to project Zodiac,
by the way, and like project Jehovah and MKUltra.
But a lot of the earlier documents
like the Eisenhower briefing document,
a lot of the dates and specific discussions
line up with real events.
For example, James Forrestal meeting with Truman,
dates are mentioned when those two met
and kind of discuss the future
or the inception of majestic 12 and so forth.
If you look in the library of Truman,
library of Eisenhower when he supposedly briefed,
these presidents and president incumbents
had these meetings.
I believe Dulles' diary recently came out
and it showed a meeting with him and Eisenhower
or something and that was like a real meeting.
And his diary came out
after the majestic 12 documents obviously had come out
and they corroborated the information
in the majestic 12 documents.
So it's probably similar to the Lazar stuff
where it's like some of the stuff is just true.
And then maybe true and under a different name
and maybe they were looking for spies
and there was some passage material involved,
but yeah, it is interesting.
And then there were other documents
like the Cutler-Twining memo
that is really difficult to dispute and so forth.
I was actually reading on the plane over here,
different validation of majestic documents
and there's just been a lot of mentions
of majestic documents before,
including, I can't remember the general's name,
but a four-star general who was asked about the documents.
He said they're real.
The majestic 12 is real.
I can't tell you any more than that
because I know that the majestic 12
to many sort of hobbyists in this subject
is nothing more than kind of conspiracy material, right?
They just think majestic 12 may not true, just.
But if you were to simulate back then,
if a UFO issue were a thing and we had exotic materials
and we were in contact with an extraterrestrial
or interdimensional intelligence,
you would need our best and brightest on it.
And if you look at that list of people,
those would be the people on it.
Vannevar Bush would be heading it up.
And then of course, Vannevar Bush is completely
unconnected with Robert Zarbacher and Dr. Eric A. Walker
as also mentioned as the head of UFO research.
That's right.
And then you have Gordon Gray, who was also on the majestic.
Don Menzel, who admitted,
he was super read in on Navy, CIA,
a bunch of pretty classified info
and admitted as much actually to Kennedy.
And Sam Friedman actually writes about this,
was sort of in charge of disinfo and debunking,
which he was debunking a lot of it.
And there's this amazing Swedish astronomer,
Beatriz Villarreal.
And she talks about Menzel having like deleted
like all this astronomical information from like 1953
and onwards in, from the Harvard Observatory.
And at the Harvard undersea observatory
at the time you had Robert Zarbacher, he was working there.
And then the number, I think James Conant
was the president of Harvard.
And he was like the number two guy, you know,
the Manhattan project at the time.
So yeah, I don't know.
It's hard to say, but it sort of makes sense.
It's directionally correct.
Yeah.
And you know, it's not unreasonable to think
that the group evolved over time, changed names and so forth.
I mean, you have in 1987 or 86 or 87
when Eric Walker is asked by Steinman
about the majestic 12,
and he gives the Don Quixote impersonation.
You're chasing after windmills.
It's impossible to chase after the majestic 12.
The majestic documents were first delivered
to Chanderay and Friedman and so forth in 1984.
That's when the first documents were actually kind of received
but weren't given to like a Muffin Symposium until 87.
What's interesting is the documents were kind of mailed out
in 84.
And then if we look at the manuscript of Corso,
it kind of seems like around 86,
the majestic 12 took on a new name,
the UFO working group and got new blood
like Albert Stubblebine and some NSA people
and some CIA people.
So it's interesting to think how this group
may have evolved over time.
Possibly it changed its name to the working group
because it was aware of the leaks at the time.
The whole history is fascinating.
I think maybe one of the tip of the spear frontier
longitudinal timeline assessments of like,
all UFO oversight is this great article by Chris Sharpe
at the Liberation Times.
Oh yeah.
It's really interesting stuff.
And there's some connections you've made
between Woods Hole and like,
some of the- Crane?
Yeah, Crane, exactly. Crane and SAIC, yeah.
And Randy Anderson's story.
But I also just wanna touch on,
he talks about how it was the OSS,
the Office of Strategic Services,
which was before the National Security Act,
before the CIA was formed.
They were sort of in charge of the initial UFO custody.
And I think we have a decent map of actually what occurred.
So David Grush says that there's this magenta crash
in Lombardy in Italy in 1933, exactly.
I've now made the connection through some people
this woman, Pippa Malmgren, who's amazing.
She's really interested in the UFO thing,
but she was actually special assistant to George W. Bush.
She made it clear to me that James Jesus Engleton
was the US like OSS person involved in Italy at the time.
And so rumors are that you have this magenta crash
and then Mussolini goes to Hitler and says,
is this yours to the Nazis?
And then they end up working together on it.
And so this magenta crash ends up
probably being worked on by the Nazis,
which explains these like Deglaca rumors
and Komlerstab and sort of modern Czechoslovakia and Poland
where they're working on these flying saucers.
You have tons of reports around this
from Rudolf Schreiber, Richard Mita,
a bunch of guys at the time,
along with Paul Mellon and Alan Dulles.
There's a story of Paul Mellon kind of spilling the beans
to his grandson who's alive now, John Warner IV,
sitting, standing over a UFO
that can employ exotic flight principles
in modern day Czechoslovakia.
And so you kind of can come up with this thread
of like the Lombardy magenta crash happens.
It goes to the Nazis.
Maybe there's some custody
where the Vatican is involved as well.
I've heard that from Grush.
And then it goes over to the US
and then it's worked on at Wright Airfield.
And you have all these Operation Overcast
paperclip Nazi scientists who then,
that's part of the rush to get the Nazi scientists
is to get the ones who are like this deep
on like really exotic flight principles and UFO stuff.
We now know Hans Kammler himself
who was in charge of the blackest of the black
Wunderwaffe programs for the Nazis made his way to the US.
And so you kind of have this somewhat consistent narrative
of like what happened with this early UFO crash
and how the US started to get involved with this stuff.
And all the guys who were involved
in the early Marshall Plan and tech transfer programs,
Kissinger was an army counterintel guy
who was doing tech retrieval at the time.
And you have other examples.
You mentioned Forrestal.
Forrestal was as well and he was secretary of the Navy.
So-
He threw himself out of the Naval Hospital in Bethesda.
Yeah, exactly.
Mid-Sophocles poem, yeah.
And the Magenta case is so interesting
because Mussolini thought it was a Nazi advanced craft
or a British or American advanced craft
when he had his own special investigation group, the RS-33,
who was like really keen on the fact
this wasn't human technology
and then likely worked with the Nazis.
Yeah, and apparently Marconi's grandson
might be like on the verge of saying something
of this Pinotti, this Italian UFO researcher
who's like really on that trail.
I'd love to hear more of a description
because the only real description we have
is from the RS-33 like a disc
and then crushed like a lenticular shape.
And that begs the question
when we brought over operation paperclip scientists,
so Nazi scientists,
if there's kind of a collaboration
in crash retrieval groups today.
Even in 2023, you had a Canadian Parliament member,
Larry Maguire, who wrote to the head of Canadian Defense
wanting to bring the Canadian people up to speed
on UFO programs because there was an active Five Eyes nation
that was working together on material exploitation
and so forth.
Well, there's a scientific principle
called the Kiwanda effect
and it involves stabilizing basically a saucer-like craft
and there's a, this guy, Henry Kiwanda was this guy,
he's a Romanian scientist.
He has a patent on this from 1936
and I think at points he was in Vichy, France,
but he basically was forced to work under the Nazis
and then he was taken to Wright-Patterson
to work on Project Y,
which was an extension of the Avrocar project,
which is trying to get flying saucers to work.
And so, and then William Steinman connects this
with Thomas Townsend Brown and his gravity experiments
where they were coordinating with Thomas Townsend Brown
and wanted to see if the gravity stuff worked
so they could incorporate it into these saucers
or whatever that they had.
I wonder how much that collaboration takes place
because you know, in Grush's News Nation interview,
he talks about like a multi-decade Cold War
with our adversaries we can assume is Russia and China.
I think back to Jonathan Wagan's encounter in 97 in Peru.
Once he sees the UFO,
he's taken in by these guys in DOE rain jackets.
He's flown to a place on a CH-47, interrogated for days.
When he's brought to this location,
this like obscure military base,
there's not only Americans there, but there's Chinese,
there's Germans.
And so who else is collaborating on these projects
if there's a multi-decade Cold War?
Well, that's the Lazar rumor as well,
which is that like Russians were at Area 51-2
and there was sort of this co-space program.
And that was always, there's, you know,
SALT, this is even public, this is open source.
In the SALT-1 negotiations, I think it was a 1971 treaty,
we're talking about coordinating with the Russians
on the UFO question because we were worried
that they'd mistake it for American acts of aggression.
That's what Kennedy probably wanted to do as well.
So maybe there is some sort of international space program
around the UFO thing, I don't know.
Yeah, and then we look at, you know,
of course there's a lot of drama about this,
but the Immaculate Constellation Report
that talks about alien reproduction vehicles
seen over Indo-PACCOM,
which is obviously Chinese territory,
like equilateral triangles with three lights
seen over Chinese territory of adversarial ARV.
So it's like clear, there's similar programs going on
if we have similar triangles,
what sort of collaboration is occurring?
It feels hard for me to believe that like
the surface level geopolitics that we see is totally fake.
I do think we are, you know,
tensions are at an all-time high with China.
But it is interesting, I think in the Lazar account,
it's like the Russians started to get kicked out
as tensions rose around the development of these ARVs.
And so it brings up, it harkens back to this Carl Nell quote,
Carl Nell, who was part of the UAP task force
with David Grush, was also deputy CTO of Northrop Grumman
and I believe was stationed at Wright-Patterson Airfield.
Yeah, and he was also Army Futures Command.
And he says there's this sub Rosa secret conflict,
arms race going on between us and other countries
that's been going on for decades.
Yeah, for feudalistic dominance.
So that begs the question,
is the ultimate pursuit mastery of ARV?
Because with ARV might not just be the vehicle,
but it might be any sort of weapon or technology
that can be exploited as weaponry.
Remember what Randy said when he was taken to crane
that the technology was considered weaponry
due to an electronic discharge during retrieval.
Well, if you think about what the Manhattan project was,
it was all about payload potency and magnitude.
And it's like, how can you create a bigger bomb?
And then at a certain point,
when you're at the Tsar Bomb level or whatever,
you're at 80 megatons plus, it doesn't matter.
That's too big for any target.
You have tons of Tsar Bombs.
It's like, it's game over for the world.
At that point it becomes,
the second Manhattan project becomes about payload delivery
and it becomes like,
who can deliver this payload faster and stealthier?
It was ICBMs and then it was stealth fighters.
And so it's a scary world.
And I almost don't even love talking about UFOs
in this context,
because I think it's the sacred,
ontological, metaphysical thing,
which should really drive people.
I'm talking about weapons.
But I do think that that might be a reality
driving some of this stuff.
Yeah, and I completely agree.
I think back to the 1988 Norton show as well,
when Brad saw the pulsar craft with 121 nuclear warheads,
the guys were raving on about how this could destroy Russia
in like 20 minutes, raving on about that.
Then on the other side of the curtain,
you have saucers that utilize zero point energy systems.
That could drop a nuclear payload
in a quarter of a second,
or the zero point energy systems can be harnessed
to create more devastating effects
than even nuclear warheads.
Given that, that this technology
is probably a forcing function
for extreme good or extreme evil.
Think about nuclear fusion.
It could destroy the world or it could save the world.
That's what Ed, Witness Ed out of Edwards said,
part of the reason he reached out to Greer
is because zero point energy systems
were being harnessed and repressed.
Do you believe,
because that is part of the Stephen Greer narrative,
the lost century.
I'm not convinced that,
I believe that we displayed some local effects
around over unity, free energy,
lower energy, nuclear reaction, whatever.
But the idea that we have scalable free energy
that we're hiding in black compartments
feels hard for me to believe,
but I'm open.
What do you think?
I'm not sure because I don't understand the physics enough.
Yeah, I don't either.
There's always a world in which these energy systems
could be powering deep underground military bases
and we just don't know about it,
that it's already employed on the system at large.
But my knowledge is we need to call it Missile Man
and ask him his advice on this part
because I just don't know enough.
Yeah, yeah, no, totally.
I can't say I'm a high conviction in any direction there.
But how do you,
what's the thrust,
what's the motivation for your research?
Is it just truth seeking?
Or do you have a hope for how this UFO thing ends?
Because it seems like we've crossed a Rubicon of late
as far as people's acceptance of these things.
Yeah, but not enough.
I've just been interested in this subject all of my life
and my goal really is just the work.
I would like to, in a responsible manner,
help disclose UAP legacy programs
and bring a larger truth about what the craft are,
what, not just what they look like,
but where they're from, what they do, why they're here,
and how the programs that study
and exploit these technologies have been constructed
because there's a lot of very dark things in that aspect.
Not only just the decades of secrecy,
but also just the exploitation of possible sentient beings
and technology that is not ours.
And exploitation of humans?
Yeah, that's the contentious thing we talked about as well
with Jake and Michael in that testimony with the psionics
because we have historical testimony
that these psionic assets used to summon craft
are treated like crap,
given drug cocktails and so forth to perform efficiently
and that could result in danger or death.
And we also have Jake and the psionics team
saying they take quite a bit of pride in those actions.
So there's a discrepancy there
that there's people being hurt
or being given drugs forcibly.
That's bad.
It's very bad.
It's definitely bad.
Yeah, it's not cool.
And then the idea too,
where I don't feel like I have probably the most concrete
and good orientation towards this
and it's something I struggle with
because it's like you cover some of this stuff
and it just leads you into dark territory.
And it leads you into the territory of like,
yeah, I want people to know that reality
is more expanded than we realize.
But the only way to do that
is to uncover some pretty gnarly messed up truths
around how this stuff has become operationalized.
And the government's orientation towards this
is how can this confer a tactical advantage for us?
And I think the orientation should be,
how can this beget more meaning for people
in civil side infrastructure updates?
And then great,
if there are derivative technologies
that allow us to protect the free world
in a more effective way, of course,
they should be funneled to like the right thing.
But it feels like the impetus,
like the sole impetus is weaponization of this stuff.
And I don't think that ends well
if there's an intelligence on the other side of it,
which I think there is,
I don't think that ends well for us.
If that continues to be our orientation towards this topic,
we're dealing with forces way greater than us.
And I don't think it's a coincidence
that ASAP and a lot of these programs,
the people come out and they're kind of haunted.
They have these hitchhiker effects.
I think it's sort of,
the two sort of mantras in UFO research world
are like seek and ye shall find
and fuck around and find out.
Look into the, stare into the void and it stares back.
Stares right back.
And it's a mirror of what you feel.
And people, the description of the sphere,
often when people are looking for the psionic connection
between less participant and these materials,
they're often, what's inside of them gets excavated
and mirrored in this technology.
I mean, it's almost, it's also very poignant
like looking at the testimony of Corso as well.
He said that the purpose of giving this technology
to US industry was A, to bolster the US war machine
and B, benefit the American people if necessary.
These technologies clearly have not been used
to benefit the American people.
But if they're used to create alien reproduction vehicles,
which I believe they are,
and possibly service an unidentified space program
or in near earth orbit defense capabilities
or payload delivery or human relocation as Michael saw
with the large football field sized eight gun craft
or operate underground and deep underground military bases.
It's clear that that's a very disturbing reality
in which we live.
Because that's 80 years of programs, right?
Have had time to flourish and hide themselves
and like layer on themselves.
That's a very frightening world.
It is a very frightening world.
I just retweeted Scott Adams, the Dilbert creator
and he said, wherever there is complexity, there is fraud.
And I just thought that was so applicable
to the UFO question.
There is an absurd amount of complexity
to the point where disclosure has taken a quantum leap
around this Jake Barber story and some of the other stories
and like mainstream media could not give less of a shit.
They don't understand.
It was horrible timing around the inauguration,
like peak news mania.
And then that's when you release this thing
that's beyond the pale for most people
and you're piecemealing in psionics
and all these other things.
And I love Ross Coulter.
I think he's an amazing investigative reporter.
And I think Jake is beyond reproach as well.
So it's not a knock on either of them.
It's a knock on the timing
and maybe NewsNation's editing team.
Yeah, for the 45 minute special,
that had to be like on the editing team.
That was not good.
And then everybody started, it started to be vindicated
when Ross did this amazing follow-up with Jake.
Yeah, the two hour, 47 minute.
And then with, of course, I thought one of the most
underappreciated testimonies was Don Paul Bales as well.
Oh yeah.
Works closely with Jake.
He talked very poignantly on retrieval
and implications of crash retrieval.
And so that started to kind of refocus the conversation
with that, with Fred Baker, with Dr. John Blitch.
Yep.
Yeah, you're right.
Mainstream media could not care less.
It can care less.
And it's wild to see realities just diverge so starkly
where it's like UFO world is on,
it's on another planet, literally.
And then there's also a big pickup
in social media categories of kind of discrediting
all the stories coming out and whistleblowers so forth.
Like I've even noticed a larger concentration of revisiting
and kind of discrediting Grush as well,
who I find beyond reproach
probably more than anybody else.
Yeah, dude, that guy is like motivated by the right stuff.
Yeah.
He's pieced together so much.
And he's been treated like shit.
And I think his disclosure was done in the,
his disclosures were done in the greatest manner possible
where if you have disclosures
but can't necessarily provide firsthand evidence,
he provided so much actionable intelligence.
Yes.
Whether to pursue IRAD contracts, IDIQ contracts,
embedding of programs, history of programs,
certain retrieval incidents,
mounds from Air Force Base incidents,
he provided so much actionable intelligence.
Hundreds of documents, I think maybe a thousand pages plus
to the IC Inspector General, Thomas Meinheim,
who's now out and they haven't done anything about it.
No, nothing.
And unless you can look at those documents,
and all we have is that,
Thomas Meinheim said it was urgent and credible,
and nobody has debunked anything in those documents.
So unless you can debunk stuff in those documents,
then you need to take action on what this guy is saying.
It's absurd.
The only knocks people have against Grush
is the Ken Clipstein hit piece,
or the fact his op-ed didn't come out.
Where Ken Clipstein,
basically, Klippenstein,
he admitted to Cigar and Crystal,
Crystal and Cigar, the breaking points.
Yeah.
He admitted that the DOD and IC
tipped him off on the story, basically.
Yeah.
It's just crazy.
And then the USAID, we now know,
was funding the Intercept.
I don't know how much of that specifically
made its way to Ken Clipstein,
but the dude has all these secret sources from the USAID.
So he's a bad faith actor, I'm sorry.
Yeah, absolutely.
And I made a tweet to that effect,
and somebody threatened to sue me,
and I'm not gonna say their name,
because I don't wanna amplify them.
They're really bad actors.
And they've also questioned the service records
of Randy Anderson and Jake Barber,
which is just, I think, disgusting, to be honest.
Don't go after that.
There was a lot of talk about
the combat controller pipeline,
even though Jake has said numerous times
he was in the pipeline for combat controller,
but then was diverted elsewhere.
These guys just,
and one of them specifically has a clearance,
and it's like, I don't know what he's up to.
I don't know if he's a bad,
I don't know if he's actually acting
he wants to be a paid disinfo agent,
but he hasn't gotten the contract yet,
and he's actually just this small-time guy.
I think part of this is, as well,
there's some popularity to go against
kind of the disclosure movement,
and there's a couple prominent channels
that really base their entire fame
off of just debunking everything,
almost pre-debunking stuff.
Like a teaser of Jake Barber would come out,
and they'd already be debunking stuff.
Yeah, totally, and they don't listen to any of the details,
and their priors are entirely off,
because they take nothing seriously.
So their Occam's razor is it's all mass hysteria,
which if you look at the levels of government
that are now saying that this is real,
your Occam's razor,
this is like a cabal controlling all these people.
It's the greatest mass hysteria in the history of,
it's the best PSYOP in the world by standard deviations,
if that's your claim,
which is itself a fantastical null hypothesis.
So these people are, they suck, honestly.
The cabal stuff is nonsense,
because it's all talked about in the frame of ATIP and OSAP,
which as we've talked about
throughout this whole conversation,
there's going back to Robert Zarbacher in 1950,
and even before in 1933 with Mussolini,
there are so many other players involved.
There is not, there might be a lot of reoccurring players
that we've also talked about as well in recent disclosures,
but the circular reporting,
it's crash retrieval and reverse engineering
is not isolated to a small group of people.
No, it's not at all.
If anything, the intelligence community tactic
to kind of repress this stuff has been flood the zone.
So there's too much snake oil to sift through
for the average person.
I think it moved from secrecy under Blue Book
in the 50s and 60s, and then the 80s at some point
around the Majestic 12 stuff,
this stuff started to get promoted,
but with all sorts of quackery,
and you have Air Force Office of Special Investigations agent
and other counter intel people like Rick Doty being like,
there are six alien beings,
and like John Lear saying,
there's a soul catcher on the moon or whatever.
And that's starting to pop back up
with some of Rick Doty's disciples,
I think he's in prison, who tweets all the time,
like, let me show you a photo of an extraterrestrial
and it'll just be a random image.
Right, I don't know.
So that's starting to pop back up.
Yeah, so it's just, yeah, I don't know.
I'd love to,
because I think earnest debate is always good.
In McWest, people say he's like a paid asset or whatever.
I enjoyed having him on to debate Merrick,
and we debated all the top UFO videos,
and I thought that was fun and good.
He's like, I want more light shown on this.
I think he could be a little more earnestly open
to some of this stuff,
but some of these other guys are just like bad vibes,
and it's all ad hominem,
and they threaten lawfare and stuff,
and it's whack.
It's like, I hope you, I don't know,
just introspect a little bit if,
I mean, again, read between the lines,
see if this applies to you,
because I don't wanna mention anybody,
but it's like, just think about what you're doing.
Are you really on the right side of history?
Well, also step back and study the subject a little more,
because even if you're not ready to make the jump
into crash retrievals and reverse engineering yet,
go back, look at the history of Cyangrudge,
Blue Book, OSAP.
Go look at numerous sightings, mass sightings.
Just go through a long list of UFO sightings
and projects in the 20th century, and start there.
I mean, there's the, not the Condon committee,
but the Condon report from England,
Project Magnet, Project Second Story,
Grudge, Cyan, Blue Book,
all sorts of UFO programs around the world.
Numerous sightings, private corporations contracted
to look at UFOs and Battelle.
Well, go watch your channel too, UAPGIRB,
because it's, like I said, it's literally a fire hose.
It's a cannon of absurd amounts of information
to the point where you can't just dismiss it all.
There's something going on.
Even if that something is slightly adjacent
to the consensus truth we all think on aliens, UFOs,
maybe the rest of the iceberg doesn't look like
the tip of the iceberg, that's fine.
I don't think anybody on the pro-UFO side
is dogmatic about that.
I think it's just, this stuff is worthy of investigation,
which clearly it is.
And if you're still just trying to figure out,
do UFOs exist, just go look at all the dang
military reports of pilots and so forth, sighting UFOs.
Like the Malmstrom case, people dismissed that,
but that's a great one to study.
The Minot Air Force Base in which I think a C-1,
sorry, a B-2 bomber encountered a saucer flying around
at de-elevating, there's so many stories.
Just go read through the Blue Book files
of the unexplained cases.
Yeah, no, they're an enormous, and anybody
in the government capacity looking at this sort of,
earnestly, always comes to the same conclusion,
which is there's something probably here.
Yeah, as Eric Davis says, there's a there there.
Clearly.
Well, Sami, UAP Grubb, this has been an absolute honor.
Is there anything else you wanted to cover?
I mean, there are probably a hundred other things
you could talk about, but.
Yeah, nothing really.
There's so much stuff we could talk about.
I just say to everybody, keep investigating
crash retrievals and reverse engineering.
There's a ton of interesting cases and interesting studies
and corporations and military requirements.
And send out FOIA requests as well, a no answer
and a denial is always an answer within itself.
We didn't even get to that story of the whistleblower
who talked about, was it an egg-shaped craft
like off on the Azores, like off of Portugal?
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, we'll save that
because I plan to talk to that guy soon,
but it's a person who was stationed with the USAF
who claimed to see a Tic Tac.
A Tic Tac, that's right.
Unloaded from a C-130 Hercules.
Yep.
And there's a lot of good research there as well.
That C-130s are often transport,
what do you mean, good research?
Oh, just that this incident?
Yeah, because of course this guy, when I studied this case,
he doesn't have photos or reports on the actual craft,
but the information he can share,
which is like the insignia on the C-130
and on the nearby vans.
Just even just the C-130 that unloads the Tic Tac
and knowing what military wing that's from
can lead to such bountiful research
because then you can look where the C-130 is from,
you can look at nearby contractors,
you can look at nearby air wings,
you can look at nearby FFRDCs
and start to piece together some interesting stuff
based off the testimony.
I love it, man.
Well, go subscribe to UAPGIRB.
Check out, you're doing a follow-up with Randy Anderson.
It'll probably be out or around out
when we put this out.
And I know you're gonna do an amazing job there
and you're not only gonna talk to him,
corroborate his story,
but also, or try to stress test it, whatever,
but also go really deep into the specific contractor SAIC
which was likely involved in this sort of
psychotronic or psionic research.
So yeah, it's been an honor, Sam.
We really appreciate you stopping by, man.
Thanks for having me, man.
Yeah. Appreciate it.
Absolutely.
All right.