I think, oh my God, I have a shotgun under the bed and a pistol in the side table.
I'm from Texas and I'm going to be gunned up at all times.
At some point I was standing in front of the bookstore and that book just stood out for
me and it was something about seeing the eyes again that almost created a moment of regression.
It might be that this is a time right now where we have to be very careful about preserving
our dominion of our reality.
There's something in your body that you believe is an implant.
I feel it right here.
Can we see it?
If you touch it, you can't, I don't, you touch it if you want to.
I feel like two years I can give you a CT scan, I would agree.
Is it okay?
Was it weird if I touch it or is it okay?
No, it's fine.
Doesn't matter.
But I feel like it might be a little hot because it's been working.
Two, three years ago?
Two, three years ago if you had...
If you had told someone.
Go ahead, touch it.
I'm scared.
Here, here.
I'm kind of scared.
It's right under my finger now.
Oh my god.
We are here with the legendary Whitley Strieber outside of writing maybe the archetypal alien
abduction book Communion in 1987, which sold an incredible amount of copies, inspired a
Christopher Walken movie and has started all sorts of mythological lore and really made
it acceptable for other direct experiencers to come out along with doing so many other
things.
I just bought a book by Stanton Friedman called Top Secret.
It's about the majestic 12 and you wrote the foreword to it and so you seem to kind of
pop up everywhere and I'm also joined by the amazing Amar Kandeel who is the number one
supporter of American Alchemy, is one third or one fourth of Yes Theory, founder of Yes
Theory and I'm always so honored to be graced by his presence at our very small humble operation
at American Alchemy.
It's my favorite operation on YouTube that's for sure and it's always an honor to just
do this together and meet all the amazing people that you just brought into my life
over the past three years.
Appreciate you man.
Well you've been really pushing me to do this.
You and Whitley met, we all met actually at the Soul Conference.
We got lunch before that but we kind of reconvened at the Soul Conference which was held by Gary
Nolan at Stanford last year and you guys really hit it off and since then Amar has been like
you got to interview Whitley, you got to interview Whitley.
Yeah well I'm glad you're doing it.
Adding to Jesse's intro and even emphasizing the title Legendary, I mean you know I put
this on, it's my first time wearing it and I think about like it's just this figure,
our modern depiction of the grace and how much that was massively influenced by you
and the book and Communion and you being able to have the sketch be so accurate that
it just awakens something in millions.
Yeah it was the eyes mainly that awakened something in people.
I have to say though if they finally land and come out and they don't look like that
I will experience the most profound embarrassment in human history in my opinion.
Because you think that they will look slightly different.
No I don't think they'll look different.
Well they're not going to look exactly like they cover but they're going to have those
big eyes I'm pretty sure.
You're responsible for the emoji we all use while texting.
No and it's been such a theme over the past you know four years of looking into this topic
and meeting people with Jesse and without Jesse, constantly come back to in the 90s
at some point I was standing in front of a bookstore and that book just like stood out
for me and something about seeing the eyes again that almost created like a moment of
regression for so many experiencers and I almost reflect now you know this is the end
of 2024 the entire country seems to be talking about drones and UFOs and it's like the most
in the zeitgeist that's been in my lifetime and yeah and I think about like the other
moment that you know before the 2000 where that happened was when Communion came out.
But there's a significant difference between the two times because when Communion came
out it's very interesting I was told a publication date and then all of a sudden the books were
in bookstores and my editor was very coy about I said what you jumped it in other words books
boxes of books appeared without warning at bookstores all over the country and he said
well we felt like there was some kind of resistance I said what do you mean he said I'm not sure and
I don't know whether he meant I'm not sure I should tell you or I'm not sure of the resistance
but for some reason they jumped the book about two weeks and it showed up you know when I was
writing that book it crossed my mind that it was going to initiate contact for the ordinary people
which is exactly what it did I don't know I might have frozen up I mean it never occurred to me
never even crossed my mind I was aware by then that there were people inside the government who
had had a certain amount of contact because I had met a space scientist David W. Webb who
had come into our lives I think through Stanton Friedman the UFO researcher and he was very well
connected in the intelligence community and very supportive and very friendly and he met
us for dinner and came and stayed at the cabin and said it was I was doing a wonderful thing
and so forth and so on he's very sweet so I knew the government was aware of this of this whole
abduction scenario and I think now that they've understood the full extent of it they might not
be so willing to say they were aware of it then but in any case the fact that this period this
thing that happened in 85 initiated contact is still sort of surprises me because I don't feel
like this sort of person I don't feel like I don't see how it could be me that did it and that's
exactly why I felt like we needed to have a conversation with you because now that just
people are more accepting of the idea that the NHI is most likely involved with disclosure and
things moving in the way they have been I often think I'm like well something was very specific
about choosing you to have this experience knowing your background successful writer we know could
deliver an experience and articulate what you went through in a way that can make other people
connect with that and I often come back to like how do you make sense of that today?
Oh I know exactly why they chose me I can tell you precisely well they chose me for a number of
reasons first it's a family affair my one of my uncles was heavily involved in this at right
path no he's my uncle Mickey and General Exxon were worked at the Air Materiel Command in 47
and my father was apparently involved but he was so secretive I I have no idea whether or not he
was no no he was he was in the well he was in the army during the war and then there were a couple
of incidents in childhood that seemed to me in retrospect to involve this but I'm that's not
where I want to go right now where where I'd like to go right now is into this this issue of
why me and that was part of it I mean I don't want to go down the road of the details about
the family connection but the most important part is and I have come to an awareness and I'm pretty
sure I'm right that they are very concerned about something called cultural colonization in other
words if they show up with this amazing array of being skills technology mind they're gonna
overwhelm us and make us feel completely disempowered and they don't want that they're
not looking for slaves they're looking for friends and they don't want us to be running
around behind them begging for their cell phones or whatever their cell phones to the beyond or
whatever they have and so the choice of this guy I can tell a good story I'm an efficient writer
but I don't come from authority I'm not a scientist I'm not Carl Sagan I'm not I don't
have I can't you you you can take my work and you can say he was a horror novelist and he maybe
he wasn't making as much money as he wanted on his horror novel so he wrote a horror novel and
called it real in other words you can just opt out if you want to with me if it was a scientist
with a big PhD and a lot of authority you couldn't opt out so with me it's take it or leave it you
can take it it's accurate the story is real and especially if it happened to you you're gonna be
able to you're gonna say wow this is deeply empowering to me and that's this is what they
wanted and I think that's why I ended up where I was Wow that's amazing so you were kind of chosen
I mean something that you've talked about as well as the great John von Neumann who is known for
being an absolute genius in his time smarter than all of the other incredibly smart scientists in
the US Hungarian and studied at a very you know actually notorious school in Hungary with along
with his colleague Jonathan Wigner and was just known as you know laid the mathematical foundations
for quantum mechanics a lot of modern computational principles he has said and you've cited he's
written a paper on the aliens possibly needing to be believed into existence and if they do exist
in some sort of parallel timeline or dimension that human consensus belief needs to shift into
kind of actually manifesting them and so you would be an incredibly important kind of first node of
creating that sort of belief well yeah and that has been the source of a lot of friction for me
in my life internal friction and friction with people on the inside who are aware of what you
just said now as far as this goes let's go back and let's explore von Neumann a little bit very
interesting he came up with he was involved in this I think that we're past the point of saying
oh these scientists who were supposedly in the majestic 12 group if that was even its real name
if that's all nonsense it's just sand Friedman made the whole thing up that's not true they were
involved a couple of data points to support you before you go on is Robert Sarebacher said
John von Neumann was directly involved right and von Neumann died of a really kind of gnarly form
of cancer and he had circuit secret service outside of the Naval Hospital that he that he was in
because they were afraid of what he might say that's exactly right yeah well you know I knew
Robert Sarebacher you knew Sarebacher oh absolutely no way Stan Friedman was a was a catalyst and he
introduced me to Robert Sarebacher and to other people you think Sarebacher was involved and then
we'll get back to yeah I knew Sarebacher was involved in fact I'll tell you a fairly weird
story here Stanton gave me Sarebacher's number and then he called me back and he said Sarebacher is
waiting for you to call him he's very eager to talk to you so I call Sarebacher Sarebacher
proceeds to tell me all kinds of detail about the materials that he was this was working on at the
Battelle Memorial Institute about how when when electron microscopes became operative he they
understood that there was a molecular grid a designed grid inside the inside this very thin
material and that was what made it so strong and I think that's probably been extrapolated out into
our military technology in many different ways and possibly civilian as well and he asked me I
narrated my experience to him this is before commune was even written how'd you meet him
through San Friedman okay so and I narrated it to him and he said I want you to write it all down
and send it to me so the next day I sat at my typewriter wrote the whole story out I put it
in an envelope and we weren't near we were I was at my cabin in upstate New York and we were not
near FedEx but UPS had just started overnighting and so they were willing to come pick it up so I
called the UPS office and they came along and they picked it up to take it to Sarebacher the
next morning I get a call from the UPS guy on the scene saying we can't deliver it the recipient
has expired he's dead he died Sarebacher yeah that came to him the night he died but that
was after commune this must have been 80 no it was 86 I believe it was 86 yeah he died right
around then I thought he wrote to William Stein oh well it was it was while commune at that point
was being created and then I'm quite sure of that I'm quite sure of the day Wow that's Chris it was
very scary and I think it was related to your course I have no idea he was I was told later
that he fell off his boat and another UPS guy said he fell off his boat and the death certificate
says natural causes well the context around what was happening at this time is Sarebacher had just
written a letter to William Steinman who's another UFO researcher who was actually an
employee of skunkworks who got basically fired over his research around UFOs and he was saying
you know yes there was a program and von Neumann Vannevar Bush Oppenheimer were all involved and
he says these beings are like insects you know they're very lightweight and he talks about crafts
and stuff so maybe he was killed for you're running his mouth or something I don't know he
was head of Washington National Labs and David Grush has said on record that he set up UFO
secrecy in 1954 and I know he was very close with Thomas Townsend Brown who was a mid-century
anti-gravity who set up UFO secrecy of Sarebacher along with Oppenheimer well what's so fascinating
about that is Sarebacher would he talked about it very openly well that's the thing he was then I
didn't realize he died like that he was scrubbed from the internet there is nothing on Sarebacher
now all you can see is a little memorial from you know I think it's some Florida local magazine
I know other people who are deep inside who are like that who were extraordinary had extraordinary
lives and now you can barely find them on the internet like who well we're not gonna joke
on that let's keep talking about Sarebacher do you think well maybe and maybe maybe talking to me
was a mistake I was very frightened by it I'll tell you that and if you read communion you'll
see my references to this but I don't mention his name in communion because I was scared to
that was Sarebacher well Sarebacher's son has now gone on record saying my father told me that he
used to put cameras on you know modified versions of VT rockets in order to chase UFOs so sound has
a familiar ring he might have said that to me actually really I don't remember directly but
it does have a familiar ring well that was more and more is coming out about Sarebacher and Ross
Colthard has some interesting data points around some of the nuclear engineers old-timers that
he's met with in Australia knowing who Sarebacher was I think Sarebacher even taking a trip out
there because they had their Wumara nuclear test site right and so there being some correspondence
there and so that's fascinating you didn't realize when we when we did the documentary
with Rush last year I asked him there is one person that you can ask questions that can lay
out that can allow you to understand the architecture of the program who would it be and he said it was
Sarebacher how fascinating because Sarebacher spent a couple hours on the phone with me
so they knew they knew what was happening to me they had to have known or he wouldn't have done
that well when when Townsend Brown finally achieved a positive result with his anti-gravity
experiments this was in Paris he flies back to the US and Robert Sarebacher picks him up in his in
his big Cadillac and you know that's that's a noted by his daughter Linda and and and his historian
Paul Schatzkin and so I think you know he was he seemed deeply involved in all this stuff and he's
written big textbooks he was known for having you know an IQ of 200 plus and I think having
some correspondence with Sarebacher oh yeah yeah he was obviously extremely smart very quick
yeah and uh full of insight either way and uh really I think he did a lot of good that must
have been encouraging for you before community was made to just know that you were well the first
time I wrote it down was for him oh and the ups said we'll we'll send the thing back to you but
I never received it he's written a book too about ultra high frequency physics which is basically
if you think about what happens at ultra high frequencies that's the stuff that the National
Science Foundation is now quietly admitting unfortunately the necessary and only impetus
that will allow us to release suppressed science is kind of game theory vis-a-vis other countries
and national security but they're now releasing this overt model of extended electrodynamics
which you could say people like Sarebacher were probably looking into in the 50s because
these are sort of microwave microwave really extremely you know high up the the electromagnetic
scale you know uh very short wavelengths um that it may have all sorts of weird effects you know
and uh explain a lot of the biological effects as well when it comes to UFOs so well that's
very interesting I haven't kept up with that right I want to get let's get back though to
um von Neumann yeah because and parenthetically on the way back to von Neumann
uh he didn't tell me personally but he told a member of my family uh uh not von Neumann
uh general Exon if he had held when the debris and bodies were brought into
air material he had held one of the bodies and he said this is from the Roswell crash
yeah he had said he said it was like a big insect yes and that's certainly my impression of them
only they're not big I mean they're some of them are very small some of them are bigger but that
was that night when I woke up in that room my immediate thought was my god
bugs huge bugs and I thought that's why I thought I was having a nightmare because I came to this
with no idea it could happen now let's get back to von Neumann uh von Neumann there's two things is
the von Neumann machine which is he postulated a machine that would replicate
the species that built it and would then move around the galaxy looking for planets that it
could seed what if that's what we have here only von Neumann in in his I don't recall if it's
in very much detail in the writings he did about this but he does mention that something
like that over vast amounts of time would inevitably have a certain amount of deterioration
of its its uh memory what if what we have here is something that was programmed to
uh seed planets like this but not programmed to find someone else because they had as much
trouble as we're having finding other people and decided there weren't any and so it arrives it
finds us and doesn't know what to do and that's why we have this bizarre situation that if you
look step back from the whole thing it could be it looks a little bit like an AI that has gone
berserk von Neumann the von Neumann machine could be an explanation for why this is so
peculiar let me put it that way but the other thing that von Neumann and you referenced briefly
this paper earlier there is supposedly a paper and general Exon who was no scientist but had
been exposed to a lot of scientists involved in this and was very smart it tried to explain this
to me and of all the scientists who were involved in it I thought he was most likely talking about
something that von Neumann would have thought of would have conceived there could have been
other scientists involved in it that I don't know about but the paper supposedly is just a
couple of pages long and it if it even still exists because a lot of this stuff was gone with
the wind I'm sure by now and what it postulates is that if this presence is not from this physical
universe or even if possibly even if it is in order to become part of our reality where
it does not exist in any way it has to gain a deeper within us we have to come to a deeper
realization of its reality it has to be as real for us as we are to each other as this is to
it's us as this is to us as our world is if it's not from our world it has to break
through into our reality by taking us not just to a level of belief in its presence
but to an assumption about its presence that is as basic as our assumption about the rest of the
reality that we know fascinating how do we get our hands on that paper because we know on record
that von neumann I mean no scientist would dispute this he entertained this idea that
the mind is responsible for wave function collapse yeah that's exactly why I think he
wrote the paper precisely and he he explored that idea extensively and so it would be something he
would think of definitely and it is what he's talking about in the paper I would assume
is an intervention in the process of the collapse of wave function by this other
presence that alters the way the wave function function collapses when we perceive so fascinating
yeah now that would also explain and I take this extremely seriously because I think we're talking
about something real you understand I respect this this belief I think this paper existed
maybe it still does and it's why when people are all angry about you know the government won't
disclose and so forth I say wait a minute and they say well we're ready and I say no we're not
we don't because you say we're ready for it but we don't know what it is that's right therefore
we are not ready and here's the problem I wrote a short story about this about von neumann's death
called the open doors about his fear that this is a door
which opens in the mind and in the perceptual system and can never be closed so once the door
is open once we have accepted them into our reality we can never get rid of them we can never tell
them no it turns out we don't want you here because we don't like you and we don't like what
you're doing to us we can't do that the door opens only once and only in one direction and forever
now if that isn't a motive to hide this to keep it secret people scorn the collins leaf they say
well they think it's demons and we're supposed to ignore demons and that's why they do
it might go a little deeper than that it might be that this is a time right now where we have
to be very careful about preserving our dominion of our reality and to think of this in some new
ways what do we do right now if we are going to let them into our reality and I think ultimately
we have to but on our terms they cannot come into and take our reality with we must not lose
dominion this is what my new book is basically about and I don't want to I'm not flacking my
book here but it does it has come up well how do we maintain sovereignty while letting them in
because we have to understand their motives and their functionality their physical functionality
their motives their understanding of themselves and we have to even if it's not necessarily a
completely correct conclusion factually we have to come to a decision about what we want them to be
in our reality and this has got to be a decision that is so deep that it is below the level of
ordinary discourse in a deeper level of consciousness which is the level of consciousness
which von neumann was talking about when he was talking about the way perception collapses the
wave function it's at that point that we control this fascinating that's right yeah I mean so this
brings this interesting question up philosophically of like we all three of us probably at this table
like are somewhat more pro the re-enchantment of the world or anti kind of materialist reductionism
this idea that you know everything's kind of happening randomly and lacks meaning but once
you kind of let that in your life the idea that you know maybe there is a hierarchy of being maybe
humans aren't at the top of it maybe things are way more magical than they seem it is a pandora's
box and the farther and deeper you get kind of ontologically you know as far as kind of chasing
truth the more evil you have to face and fight as well and so how do you ensure that human
consciousness raises kind of commensurately with our you know unveiling you know epistemologically
well that gets me to a story of something that happened to me in the 1970s
before any of this was in my life but that was other people already knew it would be apparently
I went but my wife was a very social person and she had lots of friends in New York
and we went to a lot of parties I was even invited to some of the parties but told
don't be depressing or I'll throw you out and you'll have to go them all in any case
at this party there was this lady who wanted to sit with me and talk with me she said Mr
Whitley she talked with an accent let's sit down over here and we sat down and she said
I want to tell you my story my story is this I was working I was doing the magical working she said
in a shtetl in Poland in the 1930s and we pushed away the dark side we had made extraordinary
progress in animating a glam but we absolutely walled off the dark side which kept trying to
enter our working in different ways suddenly across the river there burst tanks
with its men in them in black uniforms with death's heads on their on their caps and we realized
that we had forced the dark side to come in on its own and it had broken down the door
this woman walked from Poland to China over the next six years and there was still an American
presence in China when she arrived and General Stillwell got her to the United States where she
rejoined the same community that she was in in Poland which had moved to United States
it is terribly important that we understand what the dark side is and not say it's demons and we
don't want it we push it away we have to understand that it's the wellspring of knowledge
and we have to we have to take care with it I mean you you don't you do not dance with the tiger
but you respect the tiger's presence in the world so how do you do that because you've said on record
many times you think you are where you are as far as your worldview because your curiosity
trumps your fear it does I know that for sure on the one hand you have all these myths like
you know the philosopher's stone or the holy grail or you know you're seeking truth and you find it
and you realize it's within or something and the outer is the inner you know the uh uh Siddhartha
you know you have all these stories like that kind of hero's journey and then you also have stories
like Faust and Prometheus of going for the forbidden truth for for the knowledge and then
getting burned and so how do you toe that line well the first thing we have to do is to understand
that all of us contain Faust all of us are Prometheus and we always will be that's called
being human and the best way to do this is to fully embrace in our deepest hearts the honest
truth about our humanity its dark side and its light side we all want to be good people
but that's not all we are not one of us that's not our nature our nature is to
a nature is to be sentimental about the good but enjoy the bad and the dark and that is it look
the whole the whole expression of rock and roll is about that it is an incredibly important
expression a new kind of expression of the human spirit so i love it so much although i don't have
the ears for it anymore unfortunately i have to ear plugs when i go to concerts i hate it who's
your favorite i'm not going to get into that i don't i don't want to go down to the rock and
roll road you'll be here doing that all day and your your your your fans will sing why is
you talking about rock and roll for two hours come on they want to know the real Whitley
well no the real Whitley is actually also a huge classical music fan and an opera fan
okay so i'm a real culture vulture on many different levels amazing yeah what do you
think speaking of the dark side you obviously experienced this famous you know abduction if
you will in 1985 prior to that you had a very interesting childhood and you hint at possibly
having undergone secret experiments you grew up next to Randolph air force base oh yeah well
something happened i i know let's go back to that in i mean let's go back there in time i'm not
saying let's return to it later i'm sorry here's what happened as far as i can put it together
first of all i was seven years old when this happened so therefore my memories of it are
very confused and very sparse but i have a very close friend who grew we grew up together in
texas and like a lot of texas families our family connection probably goes back to before the civil
war family friendships and the south are quite common and we're still closest friends he's my
closest friend in the world he is very high up in this world in a completely different area from
anything remotely connected is it science or is it no it's it's another another area
it's something to do with government interesting and but we are you know we we spend every new
years together i'll be with him enough and his wife in a few weeks and every week and a half
he was also recruited and when i told him the story he's known all of he's read all my books
and manuscripts he knows all the story backwards and forwards and you'd laugh if you saw how very
different his place in the world is from mine and we keep our friendship secret i'm not going to
don't bother or probe about it because i won't i won't go there because we have to not because
we want to because we have to so in any case he remembers he was nine and i was seven i don't
remember anything about that recruiting me he was recruited and he was in the living room when
the air force people came and they knew them we knew a lot of air force but i'm sure my parents
knew them too and they said to the parents that it was an accelerated learning program with
for children with very very high iqs and there would only be three or four children in the program
in san antonio but the implication was was nationwide and maybe i'm saying a little more
than he said but that was this is i think it's logical extrapolation and they asked about the
program and he remembers them saying that it involved the use of a skinner box which i would
assume my parents had no idea what that was but his parents did know and they said no this was a
box that a person was put in so the real for the context for the audience the bf skinner was a
mid-century psychologist that worked on kind of behavioral conditioning so you know how do you
honestly often manipulate biological systems to like do certain things over and over you
ring a bell or what it's kind of like avlov's dog sort of thing yeah well it was repetitive learning
is what it was trapped in a room in the little box with a repetitive learning all i remember is
a dark place i couldn't get out of and noise horrible noise i don't remember any repetitive
learning that's all i remember in any case come october this started in august of 1952
come october i began to get sick constant i couldn't i was getting one cold and so my mother
takes me to the doctor it turns out i have no immune system it's broken gone it's broken down
so they take me out of the program i don't even remember any of this i was told this i didn't i
wasn't told my mother never told me anything about the program but i surmise i was taken out of it
because the next thing i do remember very vividly is i end up at brig general hospital a little
seven-year-old thin little seven-year-old boys being in an isolated in a room and given gamma
globulin shots and by these doctors who you know these huge needles i mean this is the early 50s
right needles are like gigantic and these huge needles are coming at me and they would get so
nervous the needle would go through my arm and the stuff would drip down my chest
it was just awful and then after a few days i'm taken home i can't see anybody i'm fed separately
i'm i can't i'm isolated until after christmas i go back to school finally in january my mother
kept my report card it said absent due to illness absent due to illness semester
month after month all of her life and we found it in their personal effects after she passed
and i said to my sister i want that report and she said sure i'll give it to you she destroyed
it instead and i said why did you do that i wanted them and she wouldn't say anything
about it she said quickly i just did it what does your instinct tell you on
what the skinner box and these experiments were for were they to make you a high performer no
they were to crack the cosmic egg i think so kind of liberate the soul from the body and
light astral travel or no because the visitors showed up a couple of years later
or right then maybe right even then and i think that that's the was the purpose to and i think
that to make you a receptor yeah i think that this started now i'll tell you what i have surmised and
i can't prove this i think it started at dachau i think it started in the camps and i think that
children who were being gassed sometimes after the gassing they weren't there anymore everyone
you know the people would all rush into the center of the thing and try to go up because the gas was
low and they would die in these pyramids of humanity uh all of them clawing for the ceiling
and the children would always be at the bottom crushed flat like bugs and um
um sometimes you know the the nazis kept extremely careful records and sometimes i suspect
some of those children weren't there and that noise i remember from those box that box i think
that's the sound a recorded of the screaming from inside the they were trying to duplicate the
conditions of the gas chamber to see if they could induce this power in another in in highly
intelligent what's the so the kids weren't there after i don't know they disappeared they went into
another reality so i know you've worked with peter lavenda yes he wrote a book called unholy alliance
right it's getting into really speculative territory that i i don't i don't personally
feel high conviction in but i'm curious to get your take on which is that you know the nazis
somehow allied themselves with an unholy force of non-human intelligence i don't even want to go
down that path i don't feel a level of conviction about it either i think the nazis were just shits
but lavenda also helped you uncover that some of these experiments might have been post operation
paperclip secret nazi experiments of some of these germans coming over a lot of the operation paperclip
people apparently lived in my neighborhood yep and my father was on a big house on the hill and
then across the street a couple houses down is an fbi agent and his wife and then the street over
there's these scientists so god knows what that's all about right no idea and then i'm going out to
randolph every thursday night for um for these things and uh and then that ends and you know i
sort of go back to living a normal kid life i have a wonderful childhood it's almost that made me
think is there something about inducing such a high state of human suffering that opens a crack
in the same way that an immense amount of love and like focused intention can also open you know
cracks open something and in our fields that allows you know someone who's thinking of you
with a lot of love allows you to maybe feel that yeah i think you might be on the right track
i think that's exactly what it was about and even when i think about idea of angels and demons
for one force is like exploiting human potential and humanity to like them the most that they can
and then the other forces there's like a levitate like a they're trying to levitate levitate or
or elevate the the the just the way we think and the way we act and uh maybe the extremes do
do something to our reality that then brings in things today i want to share something that's
become a game changer for me personally qualia senelitic have you ever heard about senelitics
it's a revolutionary class of ingredients that researchers discovered less than a decade ago
and they're already being hailed as one of the biggest breakthroughs in promoting healthy aging
this is where qualia senelitic shines as we age our bodies accumulate what scientists call
senescent cells also known as zombie cells these cells just sit there hogging resources
and dragging down your energy recovery and even mental clarity think of it like pruning a plant
you've got to remove the dead leaves to get the rest to thrive since i started taking qualia
senelitic i felt a huge boost in energy and productivity i'm sharper more focused and
genuinely feel like i've rolled the clock back and here's the kicker you only need to take it
two days a month this science-backed formula is non-gmo vegan and designed to work synergistically
to help your body shed those zombie cells and with a hundred day money back guarantee there's
zero risk in trying it out for yourself so resist aging at the cellular level and try qualia senelitic
go to qualia life.com slash jesse for up to 50% off and use code jesse at checkout for an additional
15% off for your convenience qualia senelitic is also available at select gnc locations near you
that's q u a l i a life.com slash jesse for an extra 15% off your purchase thanks so much to
qualia for sponsoring today's episode all right imagine this you're crushing it all day feeling
confident and suddenly it hits you a little boost of freshness that keeps you in your zone
that's exactly what mando does for me it's not just deodorant it's a game changer for your entire
routine i've been using mando everywhere even places you normally don't think about and let me
tell you this is not your average deodorant it's designed for your whole body and delivers freshness
like nothing else plus i love the scents bourbon leather that is sophistication in a stick what
makes mando different it's safe effective and works wherever you need it baking soda free paraben
free and clinically proven to block odor for up to 72 hours it's like confidence in a bottle
mando's starter pack is perfect for new customers it comes with a solid stick deodorant cream tube
deodorant two free products of your choice like mini body wash and deodorant wipes and free
shipping as a special offer for listeners new customers get five dollars off a starter pack
with our exclusive code that equates to over 40 off your starter pack so use code cosmic
at shopmando.com again that's s-h-o-p-m-a-n-d-o.com please support our show and tell them we sent you
smell fresher stay drier and boost your confidence from head to toe with mando again get five dollars
off a starter pack with our exclusive code use code cosmic at shopmando.com thanks again
to mando for sponsoring today's episode of american algorithm well i started to have
weird experiences in my childhood after this and uh i had a normal childhood and the weird
experiences were very compartmentalized i remember an incident two incidents i remember an incident
of my father taking me out to the country house and in the middle of the night it was cold so
it must have been the winter and um this strange car showed up with these glowing lights that
didn't shine and came rushing down the road and stopped in front of the house very abruptly like
it was not a normal car and then the next thing i knew this object that was squared off came tumbling
across the sky and went into the back pasture behind the house and it was back there glowing
and i tried to talk to my dad and he was just standing there he wouldn't he couldn't move or
didn't move her and then i felt like i needed to go find out what was going on and i went out toward
the back pasture and that's all i remember and then the other incident was very weird
suddenly one afternoon my mother and father gathered up my then baby brother and my sister
and they all went to the country house leaving me at home with my dog alone at an age of 11
without ex you know mother said well just call us if you need anything
you know yeah i needed a lot of things like a dinner and you know a life and
you know not being left in the house alone in a scary night by myself yeah so after a while i
eventually i mean i made a dinner probably peanut butter sandwich or something
and i went to watch the little tv and then went up to bed to find i had an air conditioner this is
house was too old to have been centrally air-conditioned and there was a window
air conditioner that looked out on a window and there was a lower roof behind that beyond that
window and the window above the sash above the air conditioner was sealed and it had been pulled
down and the seal was all hanging loose and i could see it was obvious that it was just
little past dusk there was someone on the roof and so i went down and called the country house
and my mother answered and she said well if there's someone on the roof telephone the police
does you see how strange this all is yeah she didn't come rushing home exactly or why did they
go in the first place so your dad must have had some involvement and i mean he must have so we do
you must have speculated you know if he was this high ranking army officer who he probably had
clearances right i don't know i know he listen he would tell you mother said well he found
apartments for uh or uh gi uh uh the wives of gis who were abroad and then he if you asked him
what he did during the war he said well i just used to pick up cigarette butts at fort sam used
to keep the keep the place clean and so you know i have no idea what he did you're pretty sure
that's not true i have a feeling somehow i didn't pick up cigarette butts yeah yeah
and and what was his name his first is carl streber k a r l okay and um
so but getting back to this uh the the um
i went downstairs to call the police but i you know there's no 9-eleven in those days i didn't
know how i called so i'm got the phone book there's a man in the house upstairs get coming
to the house in any moment and i'm looking in the front of the phone book for the local the
tarot hills the local police i finally find the number i call and the lady answers and you know
we only had like three cops it was a small community a bedroom suburb of san antonio but
an independent city save on taxes and uh a cop comes i know the cop i know all the cops
all the kids do it's not you know it's a very small scale deal he he parks it down at the front of
the half it's a half acre front lawn with big huge hedge like 60 feet tall augustum hedge
and a bower kind of it and he comes through and i see him coming out coming up out of the shadows
and he's got his gun out like this he's coming to the house with his gun in his hands
and it scared the hell out of me you know what did he know that i didn't know
and so he comes in the house and i say he's up on the roof and he goes running upstairs
seconds later he comes running down just yelling there's no one there
there's no one there he runs down into his car gets in it and drives off
that was it then what happens to me i actually don't know the rest of the night i don't remember
a thing about it i remember my parents and my sister coming home the next morning it was a
beautiful morning i came home about 11 o'clock 12 o'clock before noon because i had a lunch with
them i'd made my own breakfast i remember that that's the story and you're still in communication
with the nhi is that right as of today yes it's part of my it's a it's my life non-human
intelligence i am in communication with something do they manifest themselves as grays for you or
still no not often once in a coon's age i about a year ago i'm pleading i want you to a come in
front of the cameras i've got two different camera systems in the house i've been i've
been trying to get pictures of them since the 80s do you have any no i do i have very little stuff
a few things they got pissed off at me a couple of years ago and they all these
explosions strange explosions got picked up as a result of that and on the cameras and i've got
that and they like me to wake up at three o'clock in the morning to immune i guess yeah and uh
i know is it at a specific time well it's an hour according if it's if i'm right about what it is
there's a an ancient yogic tradition of brahman muhurtha time the time you're looking at in your
head yeah yeah because in islam it's also you there's like a in a lot of religions that time
is is is like very sacred you do commune with god like the highest the the highest um yeah in
islam the prayer that you do around that time is the one where where you're supposedly closest
to god and i think it has something to do with actually like uh having done to joe dispense a
retreat he there's a whole thing around like a melatonin being uh there's something mystical
about that we still don't understand about how melatonin makes the uh makes the brand makes the
brain act when we're asleep and that's why some of his meditation you'd make you wake up during
that time well i wake up during that time every night every every single night and in fact for
years after my wife passed away back in the 90s well what is between three and four or well it's
supposed you know the interesting thing was that it is supposed to be an hour and a half or an hour
and 30 minutes before dawn and so that's why i you know at first they would wake me up physically
they would blow in my face i would get a little kiss um i wrote a poem i have a book of poems
out called the hidden garden which uh has been read by i think 12 people and another 14 people
listen to the audiobook but you know poetry is not go out and check out whitley's poetry come on
yeah do it folks they do check out it's nice anyway i wrote a poem about this experience and
and uh and it was not an unpleasant experience you know you get to the point where you have to
learn something about sleep healthy sleep you're going to go crazy getting waked up at that hour
every night and you know they do not they do not stop uh so after she passes back in the 90s
there was a period of time where they're waking me up at that hour
then we lost the cabin we leave the cabin uh and that doesn't happen then she gets ill
and she passes on and a few days after she passes on it starts again they start waking me up at
three o'clock around that time and it becomes a very big part of my life very important because
i can feel the communing going on i can feel it really intensely and part of it is involved
seems to be involved with my wife and other dead people and the dead and the aliens it kind of all
do you think you know we talk about the communion of the saints in christianity
do you think that it's somewhat similar where where you're commuting with feels incredibly
sacred it's something i would not every once in a while i don't do it because what happened
at first for the first five years from 19 2015 until 2020 they woke me up religiously every
night then they began to not necessarily wake me up every night but i was expected to wake myself
up and i found that out the hard way as i decided well they're not waking me up so i can sleep all
night that wasn't the idea do you get any messages from them oh god i've written all my books since
2015 have been written based on this what are some what are some big recurring themes as far as
messages you're supposed to get out to humanity from them
well if you look across the books what you see are two things one is we are more than physical
creatures and two is we have value more value than we ourselves recognize we are very very valuable
very very valuable and extraordinary beings we're not the lesser we are our own in our own way we
are another masterpiece of the universe and you can see that that's the arc if there's any arc
and that in those books that's the arc and it comes up very strongly in the new book which
is basically about empowerment do you because i've read your book on jesus actually it did
yeah yeah yeah oh thank you yeah of course i thought it was great and it definitely has like
gnostic underpinnings around your view of jesus that he uh ascended to you know in traditional
christianity he he was the son of god he was also godlike but i think you view him as possibly one
of many and so going to your point about humans generically speaking being more special or more
godlike is that would that be your sort of worldview that we're capable of coming to deity
that because we are we're not like the angels and the perhaps the demons uh we don't have to be
anything we can take a journey we have that freedom to take a journey and the grays do not
have that freedom they know too much to have that kind of freedom but we they see too far ahead in
time and too far back in time too clearly to really have free will they don't have free will
that's interesting so you're like if they're because i remember one part of communion it's
like this kind of joke but it's twisted and it's so visceral and and the the the being says uh soon
my dear you'll you'll be one of us or something just like us yeah and so it's like they're they're
almost they've moved so far down this path that they've hit this sort of cul-de-sac and so they
know too much and they're trying to come back to warn us to inflect in some sort of more godly way
or something and to also enjoy communing with us because when they are in communion with you they
are experiencing time the same way you do everything is new how do you discern between
good and bad in that scenario where if you do think that this is some sort of parallel or alternate
timeline what if it's bad entities and they're trying to ensure that their own sustenance and
through trickery and deception you have to you have to be your own best best
counsel your own wisest counsel you have to live a good life a kindness and not lying are two very
important things of course we all lie and we're all unkind and everyone sees says that he's we say
that and they immediately go to all the things they did all the unkind things they did and all
the lies they've told and so do i the same thing but we have these choices if human beings can make
choices that they can't make it's too late for the grace they know too much they can't make choices
do you think they do exist on some sort of timeline or something happen like the classic
speculation about the grace would be like they are the victims of some sort of nuclear holocaust or
cataclysm cataclysm they've lost the melanin in their skin because the atmosphere is sort of you
know blocking the sun you know due to due to nuclear debris or whatever do you believe that
or or any sort of specific version of who they are where they're coming from
well i know now that we have bodies here that we have biologists have studied here and that those
studies are ended i don't know if they i hope they still have the bodies because you know they those
studies were never released and they're done in secret and there's probably a lot of biology still
to be done on those bodies if they would ever be brought out into the public space in science which
would be wonderful but so we have bodies but but i'll tell you a few things about these bodies one
is they are a mix of biology and not exactly machinery that's too putting it too far but they
they they um like biological replicas of some sort they're like something somebody built
somebody with a certain amount of skill in in in genetics built these but not not unlimited skill
because they're not uh all that you know there's things about them that don't work very well yeah
i mean and then i also thought that like if you're gonna if you're gonna engineer a being
that kind of looks like like it's very grail small like well you you you get back to the hybrids
which are they are they are engineered and they are very fluently telepathic but they are also
unvoiced and they are extremely autistic and if you go online and spotify or apple
podcasts or somewhere you can find a a podcast called the telepathy tapes thinking over by storm
right now yeah it's amazing i just interviewed kai and dr powell actually oh you did i'm going
to interview kai in a few a few days actually amazing i discovered this in the second i discovered
it i realized how important it was i'm glad it's come up but these people are unvoiced and autistic
yes now i have friends who are telepathic and are not unvoiced and i think there may be some people in
working with the in the ic and probably other intelligent communities around the world who are
telepathic and not un and not and voiced yeah but in any case uh one of the my friends who's
telepathic recently had a contact with an unvoiced person who was shocked because she
she he wasn't used to having a you know another telepath around and he and she had to really calm
him down they were but uh and said don't worry about it i'm i'm not going to do anything i'm
just here you know i can't help it either so um but i kai is a lovely person yeah she's awesome
yeah and i think really in this for the right reasons and uh for context for the audience
the number four podcast in the country right now which is absolutely wild kai dickens is this
amazing filmmaker she was rejected by all these you know production houses as far as making this
into a you know larger documentary and just kind of diy style recorded this it's she's found all
these non-verbal autistic children who were formally being studied by this harvard
neuroscientist a woman named dr diane powell and it's really remarkable you have these kids being
put in you know their parents are put in one room kid is put in the other room the parent sees a
random image generated on ipad or tv or whatever out of you know a thousand or ten thousand images
and the kid guesses what their parent is looking at with almost 100 accuracy 95 plus accuracy
and so it's it moves because all of these studies in the parapsychology world of mind never matter
or whatever have traditionally been super weak you need extremely large amounts of data and cohorts
and you end up in these endless arguments because people are too lazy to actually look at the data
right and in this case you have conclusive data and all these kids are spiritually while
physically they're you know non-verbal they're seen as totally maladjusted you know whatever
spiritually they seem far more evolved than all of us they meet up on the hill together
and they hang out and they talk about god constantly in the kingdom of heaven
and they seem to have faith in some sort of higher world that that we all just they do
have limited access to and kindness and truth-telling are essential in that
and they're savants they know everything they know languages better than the Spanish teacher
without having learned it it's a it's absolutely amazing sorry they yeah they are and it's you know
it gets me to the hybrids who are i don't know i know a few of them and i are there some that
are functional are there aliens walking among us well okay here's the functionality issue
you the ones i know are not voiced which immediately makes them essentially profoundly
crippled in this society also they're non-verbal that's what i'm saying they're not they're non-voiced
they can't talk and they often have to use techniques this one called rpm to type right
what they feel but they they know they live in an article they don't do that i mean they're not
they're not in they're not interfacing with the world around them which is a huge problem i've
talked to kai about it we're going to get together and try to figure out can we help them because
they're very they're very autistic and they are fluently telepathic and you know i'm i'm telepathic
but passive telepathic another sense in the sense that if i'm around a telepath i can have telepathy
with them very easily and i will pick them if i'm near someone who's telepathic i'll pick it up right
away should we try to do like uh you think about a color oh no i can't i can't project it in other
words i can't read your mind in your mind but if someone who is telepathic was in the room we could
converse that's that's that that so i was walking in the grocery store the other day that i'm
lived fairly near some of them i think i don't know where they live exactly but i do see them
around and of course i pick it up immediately this woman was walking in in front of me and i hit i'm
i realized oh shit it's one of them and she goes oh yeah she runs looks around she's got a skateboard
and she starts to come after me with a skateboard and i think holy shit what if i'm going to be
beaten to death by one of the hybrids because she's scared of me and so she can't she wants
to leave the store she wants to run out of the store but i'm in the doorway so she turns around
and runs off into the store and i think just calm down witty let her go i'm not going to
follow anything and so i just go and concentrate on what i'm looking for i do not put my mind on
her in any way i get my stuff and i go out and there's often somebody waiting another one will
waiting you know they have these old cars they're not having they don't have much money and so the
other one that's waiting outside is there and i come out and go into my car and he looks at me
and he goes like that and i know i'm good i've passed they're not going to be pissed off
but that's reality it's a reality and i'm sorry it's real it's real the telepathy is very real
do you think any of the hybrids are functional human beings that are walking around not that i
have met uh and and they also all smoke all the time and why do they do that well i i went to
this into this very extensively i spoke to a psychiatrist who specializes in treating
schizophrenics and he really solved it for me he said schizophrenics smoke not to suppress the
voices in their heads but to smooth out the the nicotine smooths out the the uh emotions it it
calms you and the hybrids smoke all the time they never stop all the time and you know in this
society you know at santa monica is practically has a no smoking sign on the city on the boundaries
of the city i mean this is not a place where you smoke very comfortably anywhere and so you know
they're very isolated and they're very unhappy and they're not they're poor and i'm hoping and this
seems to me to be completely impossible i'm hoping that we will be able to reach out to them
in some way and bring them into society because we've got wonderful people human regular people
caring good people who can help them have you ever read the sci-fi novel childhoods end i certainly
have so in that book as you know there are the overlords these sort of cosmic hosts if you will
that are attempting to make contact with mankind right they do it through this cadre of telepathic
children and these telepathic children are sort of the paul reveres if you will of humanity
that are starting you know this this communications channel to this higher higher kind
of borg-like being what do you think of that do you think that's that that that's a case of fiction
becoming reality or he he was obviously a very extraordinary man he was arthur c clark was
fascinating fascinating man he's probably mi6 oh probably yeah he lived in sri lanka he he wrote
a book about a portal in sri lanka on the top of a mountain and now it's you have to speculate that
he actually thought that there was one or something well of course he did i'm sure he did yeah i had
this strangest experience with him um i had a friend uh mike smith when i was living in london
he was also an american he was a very good artist and in those days the english were easily fooled
by fake credentials so he made some fake credentials for a paper called the chicago
citizen which didn't even exist and we used to use these credentials to get into places we
didn't belong like ask at opening day and the premiere of of uh which what is 2001 was space
odyssey yeah yeah arthur c clark's the movie the earth okay yeah arthur c clark sanly cubrick based
on actually a novel by arthur c clark called the sentinel right so arthur c clark is there i end
up sitting beside arthur c clark in the in the movie no way i'm telling you the truth that's crazy
and so you know i'm very quiet of course because i don't want to i don't want to get thrown out and
i don't think it'd be too long before another american's gonna understand realize that i'm
there based on complete bullshit and so so i'm sitting there you were meant to be there baby
and i asked afterwards he turns to me and he introduces himself as if he didn't know who he
was and i tell him my name and he said well why are you here and he said i said well i'm from the
chicago citizen the chicago citizen he says i said yeah it's a new paper oh he says well what do you
think you're going to write a review he says i said yes i'm going to write a review and i'm
in the review i'm going to say that you are a genius and he says well you better say stanley's
a genius too wow so that was my contact with arthur c clark both of those guys were truly
geniuses they were great geniuses and yeah god i have a feeling there's not too many places in
the universe to create geniuses that are scot-free yeah in the world like we are
in moments like this i just often remember a specific interview that dr john mack did with
one of the one of the kids from the aerial school and he asks her why she thought the
visitors were there and she goes in space there is no love but down here there is and i i remember
so viscerally watching that for the first time and that resonating on such a deep soul level
that and and of course you can make the case that it's wishful faking of course i want to
feel special as a human and i want to feel like we have something here that doesn't exist elsewhere
in the universe but there is something so profound that anybody that has experienced like a
love and and a sense of yeah it's anyone that that just experienced love you can really
feel the transcendence of that i mean the most popular filmed for the past past decade was about
like transcendence of love interstellar so like the whole thing is about was it was about that so
and and it and you could see how like it's almost like uh it right now is the 10th it's the 10th
year anniversary and the people are talking back about the film because we're watching for the
first time big fans are watching again and and it and the convergence of even that i was talking
to jesse about a couple days ago it feels so every just everything feels like it's making sense for
the moment that we're living right now unlike uh in the way people are in the the drones popping
up on people's thinking more about space with space x landing you know a tower from coming
coming from space background to onto earth i really do think that we have something so
profound here that we have to preserve that we have to gather around to like as you said really
understand what is it that makes us who we are what it makes it what is it that makes us makes
them who they are and uh and so that they are here based on our terms we know that we're not
they're not going to be the overlords that we have to like that's exactly what we have to submit our
entire sovereignty to just because they're a higher form of intelligence 2025 is about figuring out
how to live together and that does not mean we are going to have to accept overlords if that's all
we can manage they don't want to be here maybe our current reality is more governed by entities
than we realize like where do thoughts even come from and so i do i think there's kind of this
perspective of like you know one of my favorite quotes is this eden phil potts uh the universe
is full of magical things waiting patiently waiting for our wits to grow sharper now and um
that's a wonderful quote it's a wonderful quote and there's maybe some strata of beings that are
waiting for us to ascend in to their level to truly you know communicate at parity with them
and then there may be some other beings that if you're not aware of them probably have more
insidious control of your life right now yeah and so like it brings up all these sort of kind of
epistemic ontological questions when you're daydreaming why are you thinking what you're
thinking you're not consciously constructing those thoughts they're sort of entering your
mind as if it's this antenna receptacle and so then then you have to ask what's on the you know
sending end of that and you know well on that point i feel like we jumped straight into
the communication with dana chai but we're not we we missed we didn't talk about the implant
and the fact that there's something in your body that you uh believe is an implant i feel like
right here if you yeah can we see it you can touch it you can't i don't think you touch it if you
want to i feel like two years i can give you a ct scan of it if you want that is it weird if i
touch it is it oh it's fine doesn't matter it might be a little hot because it's been working
right here uh two three years ago if you had if you had told someone go ahead and touch it don't
be scared here here it's right under my finger now oh my god yeah that is well can you touch it
i'll i'll come to you but i want to finish this point because if you like that's also the normal
tissue yeah no no i mean there's the ct scan a video of there's a video of the surgeon trying
to remove it and the thing fucking moving at its own like it's going down into my earlobe
yeah and it just like goes down and i remember watching that
i guess it went under but that's the hard part
it's actually moving now it went under uh it's on the run
okay yes because i could see it just bright as day and now it's uh i don't see it am i going to
have weird effects now that i know not at all listen it's been in this whole it's part of this
conversation it you know it's been it years gotten hot and cold hot and cold all through the
conversations the implant really yeah it's so you think it's how you communicate with the
beans no no it's it's i work with it in other words i can interrogate the implant while i'm
talking but you've had it was humans gave you the implements yeah and this is this is something
like men in black style we this is something we haven't touched on yet is the human level of
this and i can tell you a lot about the implant and a um and and what it does because i've learned
about this from i was taught this by a couple of people who came into the house but let me
just back up to the time it was put in somewhere in one of my books it says it was 1992 it was
put in that's a copy editing error it was may of 1989 and i was in bed in the cabin and and was
asleep at about 11 o'clock at night i was still reading it just about to go to sleep
the cabin is looks out on the swimming pool in the back i had so much money then i really wish
i hadn't been destroyed what happened uh did you see beyond the mgm thing the part of that is
episode three it goes into south park slampooning me and all that oh they eating up i took and
eventually people people will buy a book from somebody who's controversial but they're not
gonna it's easier now but in those days when you had to go into a bookstore to buy a book
you're not gonna buy a book by somebody who's laughing stock and being laughed at
and it torpedoed my career wiped me out and i went on this long agonizing decline it ended with the
loss of the cabin and eventual bankruptcy and it was just a disaster so i'm sort of sort of knocking
along right now i don't have much money but you know i don't need much money and i'm i can't
i don't trust the publishing industry not to get into bed with the defense department and i'm
well aware of the fact that there are people in the defense department who do not like me and do
not want my work out there why don't they like you ask them ask the collins elite why they're
scared of which they really don't like you the collins elites they do not they think i'm in
league with demons because they are simple people who are way behind them they're behind the eight
bowl and behind the times i want to get back to your implant but really quick with the consulate
this is this evangelical christian group that like is cited by luil azondo and other kind of
disclosure advocates as being anti-disclosure because they think this is all demonic and so
it can't be scientifically studied we shouldn't even look at it and a lot of them were actually
looking at the phenomenon and i think is a part of this program called stack five at right airfield
and then they came out of that study with the conclusion this is written about by nick redfern
in his book final events that this is all demonic we shouldn't look at it we should look away but i
i've never heard the collins elite well characterized by anybody like who are they are they they're
still operational and like what do they what do they want to do i well they were early in the cia
right they were sort of no it was air force air force i know yeah okay and um i i don't want to
go down that path because um if you look at beyond and episode three and you see what happened to me
and what it did to my life and it's got something to do with them i'm convinced
and uh because they they there's a lot those intelligence community does way more social
engineering in this country than you can then it should or should even be legally allowed to do
the cia stays out of that because it's not allowed to propagandize the american people but i think
there's lots of workarounds with other alphabet agencies air force office special investigations
right and yeah and the connection between some important aspects of the of the old media and
those uh organizations is very profound absolutely very dangerous so it's 1989
okay yeah let's get back to the fun stuff i don't like to talk about that other stuff because
there's not a lot i can do about it and i have been beaten to death by them so and maybe i'll
just finish the point when you were touching the empire now people can accept that stories given
you know lou's uh lou alessandro's uh testimony and him even bringing it on on news nation and
talking about it but i feel like uh yeah probably the time you were telling people they have an
implant people probably thought you were just not because like well not really because actually
you had a video yeah well no initially anybody can if they were in this room and feel your ear
i don't know what that is man i mean that is like not you can look at the video and uh it's in a
number of documentaries and somewhere on my website too my website's too big and i can't
honestly say where very easily but uh you see the doctor try to remove it you see says my wife sees
it she's right there she says it's a white disc because one like a little tiny white disc
that's it i mean i got i got a little piece of and the doctor doctor was such a cute sweet guy
but he didn't know anything about any of the implants and i i and it said to me from the
beginning you're not getting it removed you're not getting it removed then it's 1994 or six i
believe it was and we lost the cabin we're living in a little condo in san jose and we meet this guy
and we talk and you know he's interested in community and stuff and i decide i'm going to
see if i can get around and and see because i'm very curious about i'd love to see this implant
it's not really working at that time it's not essential to me at all so i say to him by the way
i've got this little cyst and she bristles i said on my ear would you feel that he feels it says
yeah it's just a little cyst you want me to pull it off pop it off i said yeah i would
said sure come over to my office tomorrow morning at saturday morning at 10 and i'll do it
at home and says you know i'm sick and tired you you this is your chance we're going to have a big
fight unless you promise me absolutely on your honor never to try again i say okay i figured
i've got her i'm going to get the implant out take it to la and we're going to study it with
roger lear and you know we finally figured out what this thing is so we go into the doctor's
office and he's got his nurse there and he's opens up the slit and he and there and there
ann's videotaping it she says it's a white disc and the doctor touches it with a scalpel or
something a probe of some kind and it goes down into my earlobe at that point and if you look
carefully at the video you can see it gets sort of still and it's real he's realizing he said later
that i realized i was trying to take out an alien implant and he says um well i gotta have
to take your whole ear off i'm pulling out whoa it was been two days past and the ear burns like
hell i think and my ears caught on fire and it goes up back under the skin to this place
do you have any sense of what it's made out of
they got a sliver at the doctor's office he sent it to the lab in under ordinary circumstances
i receive a telephone call from dr william mallow the head of material science
at southwest research in san antonio which was founded by a family friend is that that's texas
a and m or now that's no it's not a and m no this is different okay this is a private foundation
founded by tom slick san antonio plan in back in the 50s and bill is his head of material science
and has been since the beginning of the foundation at that point and somehow or another it went to a
lab to a regular ordinary lab the doctor just sent it to a lab but i don't get he doesn't get a
report from the lab i get a call from bill mallow about it so that's gone from the lab
to southwest research which is 50 50 or 45 funded by the cia bill says i've got your
piece of your sliver of the implant and he says
it is a metal metallic base with febrile motion moving uh cilia coming off of it
and then the doctor calls me all excited because it's the uh lab tech has seen it and told him the
same thing and i guess the lab tech sent it to southwest for that reason because it was so
unusual a lot of these things are reported as moving under their own metabolism or containing
some sort of cilia i studied a lot of them with bill i mean bill and i became close friends and
we studied lots of the ones that roger lear was producing from here in la from the surgeries he
did and we found one that was remarkable when it was in situ in the person's neck it was emitting
an a radio signal and i'll get to the radio signal in this in a minute you think that so yours it
doesn't know i can tell you about it can you measure the radio signal because i just interviewed bob
mcguire his girlfriend uh has an implant and he put like an rf detector over her head and can like
measure the frequency coming out and so do you do do you ever do things like that okay let's not
forget uh what i was just gonna say yeah uh but yeah here's what happened at one point it used
to in the old days when it turned on my ear would turn bright red it was very noticeable i'm gonna
hear a noise in my head it was trying to to reach to to communicate with me and failing and that's
why it was like that but i didn't know that at the time so i'm in bill's office we're talking
about and suddenly he says your ear is turning bright red i said i hear it bill it's on he said
let's go we run across the campus to a signals acquisition lab we get in the lab i sit on a
stool in the middle in there got all this stuff going on and after about 10 minutes it's cold
now it turns off and the lab guys say we've got a signal but we can't tell you anything about it
because the lab's classified so i think shit i you know i say to bill i want to know the signal he
said well we'll send you some information of course they never do um then the piece of the
implant disappears from his office or is sent off to some other lab i mean i don't they were they
were about 60 they were not totally reliable let me put it that way for me they were not telling
me everything by any means 20 plus years pass i'm doing a book signing in san antonio all of a
sudden two guys walk up they say we want you to know whitley i one of them says i was one of the
technicians who was who acquired the signal and it is the strangest signal we've ever acquired
and it's still under study and they turn around and walk out gone i never see them again i have
tried every kind of rf meter there is to get that pick up that signal i've had ham operators and
all kinds of people try to we can't pick up a signal you know what you should do use a quantum
interferometer i wonder if that's what they used at that lab i i don't know what they have in a
classified signals acquisition well the reason i say that is yeah maybe i don't know if i'm allowed
to say this i don't know maybe we should change the subject so in 1989 in 1989 um this implant is
is put in your ear okay here's what happens i'm lying in bed i'm breathing the windows are open
it's a may night it's a very pleasant night so there's no air conditioning is on the windows
are open and just going to sleep and suddenly i hear the crunching of gravel in the driveway
okay i do not see any lights there's a big gate the place is pretty secure it's a shale driveway
so crunching grab tie that means tires and nothing else i think oh my god i have a shotgun
under the bed and a pistol in the side table i'm from texas and i'm going to be gunned up
at all times i mean just face it uh so uh i start to go for the i have a bank of switches on the
on the bedside that i can turn them all on at once and completely flood the whole area with
floodlights they're still on the cabin by the way that's all still there all i don't own the
cabin is owned by a wonderful family thank god and they let me come up so and bring friends
occasionally anyway i go for the switches but as i'm turning i see a woman standing at near the
foot of the bed she's already in the room and a man beside her and i hear a voice in the backyard
male voice go condition red and then they run forward and instead of going for the lights i
don't care about the lights anymore i'm going for the shotgun the next thing i know i'm lying on my
right side in the bed i cannot see i cannot move and powerful hand is pushing my head down into the
pillow in kind of wave motion and the woman's voice is speaking very gently and softly like
you know it's okay it's okay just relax and etc and so forth a moment after this happens the
pressure is off i start to turn get out of the bed as i do that there's a big flash of light
crashing in the woods and i end up sitting on the bedside there's nobody in the room anymore
the leds on the arm system are still armed red so i grab the pistol i go around the whole house
even up in the attic in the basement everywhere looking for a point of entry and there isn't
i end up sitting on the bedside what the shit
and i knew all about lucid dreams and i could hardly believe that was a lucid dream it was too
lucid so finally i sort of lie in bed all night kind of like this you know waiting for the dawn
and i tell him the story and i said i just don't know what to make of it because there's no evidence
whatsoever of this then i go out to get the paper which entails going out opening the door into the
garage turning off the alarm system which is still on and getting in the car opening the garage door
and driving down about a mile away to get the paper i love the paper i still i still read actual
physical papers in fact the times in the new york times and when i open the door into the garage
the garage door is wide open but it's alarmed it's part of the system and the switch is obviously
completely tripped and the leds are right there bright red and so i disarm it and i keep going
i get into the car and i'm starting to go down anyway to get them sort of on semi-automatic
pilot i'm just getting out of bed i haven't slept the car is full of static it's like you know
shocking my hands when i tried it as a steering wheel i think holy god the cars are kind of blow
up i jump out of the car and i go in i said and there's something's going on it was real
they someone came into the house and they didn't trip the alarm system and she says well
that i'd explain about the garage she said well call the guy i forgot his name the alarm guy so
i call him he comes over and he says there was a very strong magnetic field there and it's not my
equipment all i can do is it the field was still there he could he measured i saw him measuring
with a gauss meter it would gauss meter would go all just the needle would disappear he said all
i can do is replace my switches which he did and we tried to get some information off of the alarm
system's records but they were all garbled so a couple days later it hurt starts to hurt and i
realized i have this implant ann's fascinated she says listen let's see what it's there for i said
i want to get it taken out i'm going out to la to roger she says forget it you're not getting it
taken out i want to find out what it is what it does i said well it's tracking me she says nobody
cares that you go down to the get the newspaper nobody cares about anything you do you're
uninteresting i said well yeah i'm true i mean i don't i mean i'm not a criminal or anything so
i leave it in and it turns on every once in a while i was with a why do you think it turns on
what is it trying to communicate oh at the time i didn't know there was no connection what do you
think now now it turns on when at the 3 a.m. meeting and i go into this semi-meditative state
and um i um and it i can feel it turns on i and and i i interrogate it i say i'm writing on this
i'm working on that it doesn't answer me in words but it answers me in all kinds of different ways
including synchronicities where i will ask it for something you know when it first started
sounds kind of awesome you know it's fabulous i would i i have to tell you it's like an upgraded
human exactly i that my wife was a very wise woman and i thank god she did not let me get that
taken out it's the best thing i have in my life right now but anyway and who do you have any
speculation on who the two people were that let me let me finish and i don't know who they were
but i do know some other people that are involved with this implant this is a very surprising and
fascinating story uh i'm um uh i have obviously got people in my life who are on the inside
and i'm going to respect their privacy i don't agree with their secrecy but i respect their
privacy and you think they take a special interest in you they do definitely absolutely
they have for a long but a lot of them have known for a long time i'm getting back to all the way
back to dr web yeah they knew what was going on they know some of them still do anyway i think
sarbacher had interest in what you went was it was it was sarbacher i mean it was like it goes so
that organic or was that did you have an interest specifically in you oh specifically that's why you
asked sarbacher wanted me to write it all out oh wow yeah yeah something fascinating so yeah
so anyway this gentleman it's a wonderful gentleman you both know his name and i'm
not going to say it because he also has a horrible temper and now you know exactly you're thinking
you know who it is and i'm if you say his name i'm going to deny it plausible deniability okay
anyway i can look at your facial gestures anyway he wants me to get a ct scan of the implant
and i'm eager to do this of course i said well how am i going to do it he says i say because i
can't go to my doctor and say i want a ct scan of my ear for no apparent reason and he says well i'll
call him so i call the doc the doctor i he says and then he calls me back just make an appointment
with him i make an appointment with him and he's all excited he says it's all set up you just have
to go over the blood go to the get and they'll do a ct scan of your ear and i go over to the power
medical lab or wherever it was and they they're very confused a ct scan of your ear and then there's
a person who comes there who they don't know who wants to be there and there's a little confusion
and that's resolved finally and so they do it and i get it back and it's a wonderful i've got images
of it it's a wonderfully clear perfect scan and you see the thing clearly however two days before
this after i have agreed to do it someone somewhere got the idea apparently that i might
get it agreed to have it taken out because i'm sure that's where from the ct scan the next step
was going to be well we've got a ct scan we want to look at it now there is a certain knock on my
door which i am not going to duplicate it's immediately recognizable and it's unusual
i know this knock and it's come to me a few times both here in california and in other places
i know that when that happens i'm going to open the door and i'm going to have a conversation
with human beings with some people it happens i open the door two men are there one of whom i
have met a number of times one of whom i did not know who i suppose i always there's always a second
one there and i always think to myself he needs a guard for some reason is it because he's being
watched or because they're scared i'll go crazy or what is it but anyway they come in he proceeds
to explain to me how the implant works very nice man he explains that it that it can can pick up
and needed information and find it and draw me to it i said it's like synchronicities he says it's
not a synchronicity it's actually guiding you to where you need to go to get the information
and it's wonderful in that respect all i have to do is think of something i need what information
is anything anything i need anything you want anything i need when you read the new book you're
going to see a lot of stuff about genetics and stuff in it that i have no idea about before i
started writing the book but it's all there now do you think the two people who implanted it were
human or non-human they looked like people that's all i know i cannot tell you anything else about
i don't know clearly there was no there was no surgery it was just like no there was no
yeah there was no surgery there it just went through the skin so if they were people they were
and end this business with this super high intensity free-floating magnetic field we
can't do that we can now but we couldn't then you know i wonder if these are the
the agents that tim taylor was talking about in that in his high dry beings or that if you
talk to like people like richard dolan you know he'll say like they're the men in black
phenomena is actually very real and that's like counterintelligence for the nhi for the aliens or
something there's something there's some kind of there's some kind of bleeding off there between
the the presence yeah and the and us and it it's got something to do with the dod i'm sure
i'm sure it does but let's go back now to the incident to the two men coming into the apartment
this was a just a few years ago so they explained to me the man explains to me
that part of it and a few other things about how it works and then he says it was invented by a
man named constantin rodive and they leave and of course i immediately google the name
and i realize as i'm googling the name it's not rodive he mispronounces it's rhodovay
constantin rhodovay was an expert in electronic voice phenomena and electronic voice communication
with the dead no way with the dead with the dead so like it's a technological version of mediumship
exactly it's technological mediumship and it's he said that he designed it am i wearing something
that was designed by someone who was dead and on the other side when he designed it or he did he
design it before he died i don't know when did he live he died in the 70s i think but there's
lots of on the internet about it but actually it's r-a-u-d-i-v-e have you tried to match up
his patents or pictures from his work too and does it look similar no i didn't i couldn't
find anything didn't find anything no but i did find this but that's fascinating that you describe
your your you know this heating up at night at this specific hour that's known historically
to be when you commune yeah and it's it's communion for you you're seeing that there's a there's a
there's a there's a structure here it's not random also the other thing the implant does
is opens up a slit in this eye really it's more in this eye now but it opens up a slit and you
can see words racing through the slit too fast for you to read except occasionally and they all seem
to be kind of nonsense words i mean they're words they're english words for the most part but they're
not relevant to anything and i asked him about that and he said the man he said that's drawing
up material from your unconscious that's relevant to what you're doing what you're working on and
this is why when i'm writing i can remember incredible detail about all kinds of stuff
you've written 40 books yeah but this is this is recent this is after 2015 and i'm only written
about six books since then so the thing came on starting 2015 in 20 no it came on in 1989 and it
started working in oh it started activating in 2015 but there's let's keep going here but how
does this guy know this about how it works though how does the guy who knocks on your door come in
because he is obviously part of the same world we're sort of talking about that i think richard
dolan who is a lovely brilliant guy has got something i think there is a breakaway civilization
and we're talking about it right now interesting so breakaway human civilization that is systematically
in touch sure look human to me it's fascinating now then what happens is i start telling my
friends this story and i'm talking about it i tell one friend and he's asked me not to use his name
i've specifically asked him if i could who says well yeah oddly enough i've had a slit like that
in my eye uh for years i've often wondered and the words go through and you can't quite read them
i said you know i know what that is now and i explain it to him i said and he says well that's
extraordinary because you know i he's written some books also but here's the weirdest thing he's one
of the world's leading experts on constantine rotevei no way yeah what yes what are the chances
that gave me no there's not chances it's an experiment it was been in him for longer than
mine has been in me yeah where's rotevei what where is he from he was from uh rumania or okay
lithuania or somewhere like that i don't recall off the off hand but there's a lot and this did
this guy live in your vicinity at all or is there you know any through line between you and him as
to like why he received this as well outside of i guess being connected to rotevei there might be
some kind of a through line i can't see it he lives up in uh up in marin county why do you think yours
activated in 2015 why the delay i'll tell you why i can tell you precisely and this was this is
just stunning but it's all part of this and i'm you know we're dealing here with something that
causes on a logical shock okay so let's just suck it up uh after annie passed away it began
is when it began to work and i began to notice the slit and i was walking across the street one day
and in bright sunlight the slit's very obvious you can see it and i'm i think to myself who are
you and the words slow down and it says very clearly coming across it's me and whoa wow so your
wife when she passed on you think she activated this she activated it and i think that woman may
be new all along i do not and is a mystery wrapped in an enigma she is she is so yeah
let's go into that you know can i just say something on since i came up like i remember
the first thing i ever watched on you and communion i remember like after i prayed for her
because i just i could feel how incredible of a soul she was and i prayed that i promised you this
happened i prayed that one day i find love like like whitley's oh man you know when one of the
visitors when i was in the abduction experience said to me you're the luckiest of the lucky i
thought what crap and and then later i thought well i must be i written communion and now i'm
a big name but that wasn't it it was her it was finding ann why and i'll tell you how i found
how'd you find her well i was living in london and i like england i spent a lot of time there
i came back to the states daddy got mad at me because i was supposed to go to the london school
of economics and instead matriculated the london film school and a year later he found this out
figured this out and got all pissed off and made me come home and so i'm back in the states and
i'm in new york and i'm trying to i want girls i mean i'm here on 23 or something
and i want a girlfriend and i had girls in you in london now i don't have any girls
so i go to singles bars and i've gotten a job dad said well if you're on your own now you've
got to find your work do your thing and don't come back to san antonio do your thing and so
uh i um got a job as a media planner in an advertising bentman bowls advertising
and i'm looking for girls i'm going to singles bars and stuff and all the guys in the singles
bars they're airline pilots lawyers doctors they're all media planners probably too it's
the lowest of the low in the advertising business at least it was in those days
so i come from a father who's never lie never lie it's basic it's in your my blood
so i'm not going to say i'm a doctor or a lawyer i said i'm a media planner i was getting nowhere
because i'm not the prettiest thing that ever walked yours come on whitley and no no i mean
you know don't sell yourself you've been this you've been this you guys have been you might
do better in singles bars than i did i did not do what so i see in the village voices now amara
and i just bring up aliens because you know we met it's actually alien yeah sorry um so you had
to go into the single bars in new york so i i i give up on that because i'm wasting my money clearly
and um i see this thing in the village voice for something called mind mates and i think great my
main problem has always been i want really smart girls because i want a girl i want someone who's
really really really smart preferably smarter than me i figure i'll try this so i try mind mates i
they send this packet with i spend like two or three hours writing essays and filling out
forms it's a very serious deal i mean they're really into this and then my stuff in a couple
weeks later a list comes back and it's got like five names on it all of the names are the last
names of fish are close to it like salmon uh salomon and there's a trout and all is
what the hell is this and there's one name on it maddox which is not a fish and i think is it
the fish are all fake and i actually was only sent one name when i was supposed to be sent five
so i call one of the fish and she's real she is a fish i mean she is trout or whatever it was
so i can't just hang up on her so i we have a date doesn't work i figure no more fish i'm going to
call the one that's not a fish so i call maddox she's the receptionist or she's at she says she
works at a certain place and as an avenue not far from where i was advertising so i go there
and this receptionist is sitting there with excellent various things about her
and she looks up at me with these big brown eyes and i think oh god if only ann maddox looks like
this girl and i say i'm here to meet ann maddox she says i'm ann we were not part again
um for more than two weeks for the next 45 years wow my best friend who i talked about earlier the
first thing i did was take her down to washington to meet him and his wife and he says to me quit
don't let this one go and ann always said i got the informant when he said that when i told her
he had said it and i said she said when i heard that i knew i was in and i said you were in before
that baby i was no way i was ever going to let you go she became my wife and ann went back to
school and got a degree in english literature to be my editor and you know i wrote seven novels
before i published the wolf and and i got close with some of them one of them was so annoying that
this agent calls me and says i'd like you to come over i'd like to talk about your book
and i thought i said to ann it's a big agent candida nanadia or something jeff brown i think
his name was he was a big agent so i'm very excited i think finally i've got an agent
he go over to his office sits down across from me at his desk and he says i just want to tell you
that book was the most annoying thing i've ever read in my life it was called the searchlight horror
and it's about this town where nobody can leave and everybody gets killed and everything in these
bizarre accidents and every time you get into a character they get killed and that's what
makes the book so annoying and ann read it and she said yeah whitley he's right this is infuriating
in fact i'm not going to finish it because i'm going to beat you up if i finish it wow so and
but you're almost implying before getting into describing her that uh there's something very
special about ann as far as her role in your life above and beyond a romantic one
weird stuff started to happen as soon as we were together like what well the first i'm not sure
this was the first thing that happened uh hey here i'll give you a couple of examples
there was a we lived on west 55th street in manhattan on between eighth and ninth you cross
eighth and then you get to seventh avenue and there's a little distance between
seventh avenue and broadway and in that little area there was a place we laughingly would call
the whore store it was a little uh storefront it's probably not there anymore and um you would see
every once in a while a attractive looking young woman sitting in the storefront in a skimpy dress
with her legs crossed and a green curtain behind her and we would pass it back and forth because
we haunted the bookstores that were then lined madison avenue and we would laugh and say the
whore store is open tonight one night we're we're going home and the chair is on its side the
curtains flying back and forth in there and there's a guy trying in a brown suit trying to get out and
he's being pulled back by these blue dwarfs and we watched this for a second what the hell
and i say to ann we've got to call the police and you know there's no cell phones so we're not far
from home so we run home we're going to call the police and she says what do we tell them
and i think to myself we're going to tell them that there's this place where these blue dwarfs
are trying to kidnap some guy and drag him behind a curtain then that is not going to work i mean
this is new york city i thought i thought to myself the police will come here they're not going there
so we don't call the police we also didn't go by the whore store at night again
that's one of the many things that happened many some of them were hilarious it's almost like uh
your local shared reality with ann was sort of divergent from the consensus reality that we
all precisely precisely because you know later these blue figures which played a i didn't remember
at the time they played a role in my childhood they've played a role in the whole experience
in my life i'll tell you something else about lori barnes was our secretary and was reading
she was getting heaps and heaps of letters and i was saying you know we can't throw them out
because they're very private many of them they got people's names and addresses what are we going
to do yeah and just for context after community came out tens of thousands if not hundreds of
thousands of people were sending letters to whaley's home because he left he left his address
being like expecting you know maybe 10 20 people to send ends up shutting down the whole the the
post office in there in his town the abduction researcher the pioneering abduction researcher
bud hopkins who i pissed off unfortunately um but you know that's the story of my life a good man
was the one who said i should do that and it was very important very important so i want to just
honor bud for that uh anyway uh we've got these heaps of letters coming in and and i said i can't
what are we going to do i mean they're literally pouring them on the on the living room floor in
heaps and um uh she's i said i can't read these she said well i can read them and she gets a she
gets her letter when she starts she was a speed reader she could sit down and she could literally
read a big complex novel in two hours easily she was really smart she was smarter than me and that's
exactly what i was looking for as i wanted to marry a genius and i did so uh anyway she's reading
these letters she hires a secretary and they'll come back into it and say we're gonna get him
back to the blue guys at or burns and they're working on the letters and they're all
four or five thousand of them are now at rice university in a in an archive called the archives
of the impossible founded by jeff kreipel and uh so they're beautifully beautifully uh uh uh
uh curated now they're so it's wonderful that they're there
so she comes out of her office one day he says whitley this has something to do with what we call
death and the letters again and again will mention the dead in connection with the visitors
and when we would have she would choose people to come up to the cabin don't worry i haven't
forgotten the blue guys yet uh and she would say this letter should this person we're gonna
have them up to the cabin and when she would get these groups up at the cabin the visitors
would show up wow she knew who to get sounds like ann was and did this and named the book communion
wow and ann ann said things like i asked ann what is enlightened she says enlightenment is what
happens when there's nothing left of you but love kind of the opposite of today's day well
nowadays we think of it very intellectually yes you know it's it's informational that's so wild
like one of my favorite quotes that drive this quest is the highest form of knowledge is empathy
segues back to the telepaths you're not going to the hill unless you are kind and you do not lie
that that's the those are essential criteria so um she hires the secretary lori barnes and
they're working on the letters here is lori's story and now we're getting back to the blue guys
in this long complicated segue uh lori's story is this is back in the 50s 54 i think it was
she's lying in bed at night alone her husband's they were they were show people and he was on a
gig and she notices movement out of the corner of her eye she's reading it's about 11 o'clock
12 o'clock at night she's waiting for her husband to come home she's pregnant and
she looks up and there standing beside the bed is this horrible looking blue dwarf
and behind it are the line of others just like it and of course she recoils
and it says to her do not be afraid we're not here for you
we're interested in the girl child you're carrying and of course she's not not made any
more calm by that and of course it's the 50s so we don't know what the boy or girl turned out to
be a girl she i know her we've talked she's a very nice person she has a lovely career there's
nothing about her it would say she's in any way an unusual human being except she's a very good
sweet person and it does a lot of good in the world
okay so this happens and she recoils from the creature at that point and it says to her
why do you fear us so and she says you're so ugly and it says something now
it gets to the way deep into the heart of this whole thing says one day my dear you will look
just like us oof lori has passed on i have wondered if the little blue guy is going to show up in my
life with but so far i haven't heard any scent any sense of her presence at all i do get the
presence of a lot of dead people but i haven't heard from lori what were john mac stanton
friedman these sort of legendary figures in the ufo world what were they like because you knew
both personally yeah uh well stanton was stanton died basically running through an airport i mean
stanton was the most driven human being i've ever known he would go anywhere he would do anything
he would not stop and he was very coy about whether or not he had been activated by activated i
mean you see a ufo up close or you have a close encounter experience you're activated
most people who that happens to they a lot of people don't remember it a lot of people can blow
it off but there are certain people who just will not stop they will not stop and so the ufo almost
installs in them some sort of drive or mission to for disclosure or like an
insatiable curiosity or it installs within them a burning question and they can't let that go
it's a wonderful a lot of the people in this field are much more wonderful than the outside world
realizes that you like you get a room full of close encounter witnesses together they're all
incredibly sweet and mild you think to yourself well agrees they're little and they're fragile
of course they abduct people who are mild-mannered right and children and children and i'm very mild
i should be i'm be as mild-mannered as i am but i am very mild-mannered um and was the one with
the temper she could blow up in your face very easily and but stan friedman's to me always stood
out along with john mack is these guys who are extremely rigorous smart and accomplished in
their sort of day job roles you know john mack was obviously head of the harvard psychiatry
department and stan friedman was like this westinghouse nuclear engineer right you know
laurence rockefeller who was passed on sadly and was very interested in as much the annoyance of
other members of his family not all but some um invited me and uh john mack and edgar mitchell
and uh joe rules who's a ufo investigator from el paso to his medway plantation in uh south carolina
to just sit together and have a you know with our wives and significant others and just spend a
weekend together and it was wonderful time and i got to know jack john better than than i had before
what was that group like and what was laurence rockefeller like and john was a laurence was a
very he was a good man he had a good heart and he was very curious and for whatever reason
he knew this was real yeah i find that so fascinating that some of these elite families
have such a deep interest in laurence rockefeller specifically in the 90s was trying to get hillary
interested in this like right yeah the photo of her holding are we alone by paul davies right and
it's a gift from laurence rockefeller who was trying to get her more into disclosure and
understand kind of the reality of of non-human intelligence so so you got the sense that he
he knew like it's like he didn't use something laurence knew something and uh uh bootsie galbraith
uh was also a friend of laurence's and you know i tried to warm out a bootsie of what uh laurence
knew and what they knew but she was quite coy about it she'd been turned on in an interesting
way she was in mexico with steven greer and he called in the ufo and they all saw it so didn't
didn't the rockefellers both on john mack and steven greer as well in the 90s i believe yeah
and they funded the princeton parapsychology lab which was studying mind over matter so
okay so what was john mack like was he he was well first of all we were both cut ups when we were
kids and played a lot of practical jokes and made bombs and did all kinds of crazy things you can't
do anymore and uh so we had a lot to talk about we had loads of fun talking about our childhoods
and uh he was a very very smart man he was too smart to be deceived by assumptions
that defines his mind better in fewer words than any i can think of
he was too smart to be deceived by assumptions i will never forget the day
i got a call and he is practically in tears he just had the ambush and he said they're going to
try a harvard take at harvard yeah he was invited to a meeting it was actually an ambush
and they're going to try to take away my license to practice psychiatry
and they're going to try to take away my tenure and i said john what are you going to do
there was a silence on i never would forget that was hard
it was broody what they did to him they went after him roger leer had the same thing happen
they get went after him they tried to get get rid of him get take away his license practice
it's these show trials and dr diane powell of the telepathy tapes i was just gonna mention
new john mack when they were at harvard together they had offices down the hall from one another
her medical license got revoked for studying his telepathic children well you know there's two
sides here the side of Galileo and the side of the inquisition and let's face it it's very obvious
that dr powell dr mack the others dr leer are on the side of Galileo and these other
creeps are on the side of the inquisition and they function like inquisitors yeah i always wonder
it's 100 amar and i were at the dc hearings you know a few weeks ago and this just straight up
spook came up to us and in the hotel that we were staying at yells at us from across the hall
our friend chris ramsey who's an amazing magician from canada who's gotten super interested in the
ufo thing he's actually a world famous magician kind of knows when people have tricks up their
sleeves because a lot of you know the name he's made as a magician is actually debunking other
magician's tricks or elucidating them and showing how they work and so this guy is provoking us
trying to get basically get us to say that we're cynical about disclosure and like don't believe
in ufos and aliens by saying asking these leading questions saying you know it's all
bullshit right you know you guys are just doing for content right you want clicks you want likes
whatever and then chris after he leaves it's like that guy had his hand in his right pocket
the whole time and was definitely trying to record you and anyways going back to this kind of
establishment you know scapegoater role versus the truth seeker innocent truth seeker
i think about people on that side like that guy like what's your psychology like do you do you
have any historical context for what you're doing like if you if you're if you're just persecuting
people earnestly looking into you know truth like how do you live with yourself and do you have zero
like metaphysical understanding like you don't think any of your earthly actions have any
implications for what you do in the futures all just you're expedient expediently aligning
yourself with establishment forces you just want a promotion like like what do you think is going
to happen to you you know you don't want to do that because you don't want we have souls
and we're anesthetized to our souls for a reason so that we can live free but
no you definitely don't want to live a lie in lies and you don't want to hurt other people
you have to um like and another thing ann said it's so powerful i asked her what compassion was
because i'm really interested in compassion i want to be a compassionate man i want to be a good man
and she says to me she didn't answer the question directly she says each of us is all we have
and that really went through me because you know when i'm on the street and i'm
someone's pissing me off or i'm i'm i'm a driver in la and there are there's the odd three-minute
period when i'm not pissed off uh and i always think of this these words and i'm face to face
with someone i really don't like and don't want to be with this person is all they have
it changes everything it's incredibly powerful it makes you into a better person just by knowing
those few words and keeping them in your it's amazing you know that's power that's word power
of the first order yeah and we are all on a journey and i think it's some you know there's
evil is typically depicted as being consciously tyrannical evil you know sort of like mastermind
evil often it's just being unconscious it's just you know acting on sort of these primitive
instincts that are is often the default and and emerges if you don't kind of consciously override
it or seek virtue and uh yeah i think uh y'all just need to look at ourselves and she would always
engage with homeless people and stuff and and and what yeah and i i would say you know uh
how can you know whether or not you know i always would she said just don't judge them
you'll feel which ones can use your help and which ones can't just don't judge them don't
don't go there witley don't go to that part of your head you don't know why they're there out
in the street and you never will it's not your business speaking of which given that you wrote
a book on jesus jesus has been sort of rewritten by the likes of thomas jefferson steven mitchell
all sorts of writers yourself now what do you think most people misunderstand about him
and they misunderstand
well a lot of things but the most misunderstood thing is in modern times is the resurrection
of a jefferson bible takes it out it should not be taken out in jesus in new vision i go into exactly
why it actually happened and this gets way back to the beginning of our conversation when you
mentioned that suffering has something to do with these extraordinarily powerful states it
activates something that happened to jesus what happened in the tomb was a real thing and the
book lays out exactly what happened because there's been magnificent research done on it that's
ignored because it doesn't fit the paradigm but in fact he did come out of the tomb the tomb was
empty when mary came back yeah as a light being and and the shroud remember he said if you do not
follow me i will return as a thief in the night and then and in jesus a new vision i point out
the time of that return it was 1898 when the first photograph was taken of the shroud
that was the moment he returned and we saw him on the shroud the shroud is amazing and i think it
was studied by like nasa yeah well it was studied by a group of group of air force guys air force
yeah yeah and they claimed to debunk it but they only took a little piece of it or something oh no
i'll tell you the story i'm very close to this story yeah uh father peter rinaldi was a friend
of ann's she had you know if you ever go to new york when you go to new york go down to laguardia
place and between laguardia and uh right off of right uh immediately north of uh of uh howston
street and rather at bleaker street is 520 laguardia on one side and there's this beautiful
park on the other side called laguardia park if you go you'll see a statue of laguardia in there
and you look down at the bottom of the statue and there's a plaque and all these famous
social people are on the plaque and so are the names ann and whitley streiber and one day we
lived in the building 520 laguardia place she was looking down there and she said you know i'm going
to turn that into a park it was just a place you know it was a druggie hangout and stuff
and she said i said how can you do that i visualized her going down there with a shovel
she said well i'm gonna do it and she called got all her friends going and got them networking
and soon they had millions of dollars to build this park and to create the statue and permission
from the city and there's the plaque there's the statue it's a wonderful statue of laguardia the
park is so verdant and full of birds and that's ann i'll go i will go there don't miss it it's
like it's a pilgrimage place next time i'll definitely be too yeah yeah i love to meditate
in that park now so what happens to jesus is this in at least i understand it he goes to egypt
he understands the resurrection technique there and he sets out to do this
in i retranslated the sayings gospel of thomas it's easy i mean it's very simple
the gospel of thomas is remarkable it's absolutely extraordinary but what do you say to the people
because i'll argue all day with like conventional christians where i'm like
i think that book is really special and then they say oh it was found you know it was first of all
it was written 150 years later after his death and it was found you know 1948 in this sort of
you know pile of the you know the nakamati or whatever the sayings gospel of thomas according
to the the q scholars is the oldest gospel and they're probably right okay so it's the oldest
gospel right it was the beginning of the of the story let's go to the thread of you saying that
jesus went to egypt he learned this technique in egypt and the technique is sort of the mystery
ritual resurrection total ego death and we're going to get back to the part about the the
discovery of the shroud and the work that was done on it in a minute i don't want to forget that and
we could quit yeah uh he then in effect becomes a magician at a time where in the roman empire
the cornelian laws are in effect and they will kill you in all kinds of very very depressing ways
if they catch you being a magician so he's very careful that's why he tells people don't tell
anyone that i'm doing this he understands something about the mind and my new book is
all about this it's about recovering this power yeah because we can all do this i believe that
and this is where i differ from the conventional christians jesus is in all of us that power is in
all of us he wasn't here to put himself on a peasant pedestal he was here to say i am the son
of man i am a human being well in the in the gospel of thomas doesn't he take thomas who's
typically depicted as you know this judas judas says this like betrayer he takes thomas aside
and he whispers secret words to him yes and so what are those what are those secret words
well he doesn't tell but they the other disciples ask him what did he say and he says
they say thomas says if i told you you would stone him to death in the sayings gospel he says
don't believe me i'm not a teacher he says go out among the gentiles and eat the food you're given
violate the law to a total revolutionary what he's saying is leave your ego behind
and be you your real self and it doesn't matter everything depends on this do anything to find
yourself it goes all the way back to the delphic oracle know thyself and this is also the word the
core word of jesus know thyself and the kingdom of heaven is within you and all around you
and all around you but find it be as little children what's the other gospel thomas quote
it's um if you look up the birds will precede you if you look to the sea the fish will precede you
the kingdom of heaven is within you right and the great poetry of being is there yes it's a
poetry of being it's so it's fascinating and and we you know i just interviewed doc uh colonel
carl now who he kind of traces back the origins of these sort of esoteric versions of religion
that he thinks all kind of bounds together in this kind of hermetic lineage and he talks about the
festival of said and the egyptian magical papyri where you have these sort of you know secret
brotherhoods in egypt that's very interesting i did not know that i want to talk to curl about
that i know don't know him well i sent him an arc of my new book and that's an advanced reading
copy of my new book i haven't heard back yet from anyone i sent all my friends that arc i sent it
i even sent it to robert bigelow who i don't i know but not well and uh uh i sent it to jacques
valet and leslie cain who is a close friend and of course jeff kreipel and hal puthoff has been a
friend since forever i mean we've been friends since i was a since i was up we've been friends
for over 30 years since how old were you well since the communion experience since community
okay so so um let's go to the shroud of turenne because i have a friend named randall carlson
works a lot with graham hankock incredibly smart just super rigorous i would not do justice to his
work on this topic but he has all sorts of prince first principles arguments as to why
the shroud of turenne is absolutely real it is he's probably right okay here's what happened
a father peter rinaldi who and knew uh calls us up one day calls her up one day and says i want
you to come to a meeting we're having a meeting about the shroud of turenne would you be interested
and she of course says yes we'll come and i said what is the shroud of turenne
she said well let's go to the meeting we'll find out we go to the meeting and it's with
jackson and jumper the two guys who were they're fundraising for the initial studies
and um i never meet them i mean i talk like you know in a fundraiser context but i never
like become friends or anything with them so we contributed as much money as we could afford to
it a few thousand dollars and we follow it and they do their stuff and it's all in the papers
and then i hear that material has been taken from the shroud and it's going to be sent to
oxford and i write father rinaldi a letter do not do this they have to defend their paradigm
they will lie without knowing it and they do very that very thing they say the shroud is from the
middle ages they destroy the research but it doesn't end because this is humanity and there
are other people in the world who have a better grasp of the truth here they can feel the energy
and other scientists and now jesus in new vision sums up where they are and where they are as you
can't deny it anymore if you're a real scientist the shroud is the single strangest thing on planet
earth and it is that way because it records the moment a human being whose body had expired
transformed into a being of light what makes you think it's real
uh the weave of the cloth the pollens found on it all place it in exactly that place yeah and time
the uh uh image itself could not have been produced by almost anything except a sudden
burst of neurons and remember the rending of the of the curtain in the temple in the earthquake
that was the moment of the resurrection it's a tremendously powerful event a burst of neurons
burst of of energy that involves uh a neutron neutrons involves a it involves an expression
of a burst of neutrons and that's what burned the image into the shroud and that's the whole
thing of like maybe that intense suffering it cracked all the way back to the in that
kind of electromagnetic the neutron burst and then you're in there are all these ancient art
depictions of like saints and holy figures traveling up in this kind of cobalistic like
bubble envelope thing like this yes celestial ascents vehicle maricaba vehicle or what a wheel
of ezekiel you know the whole theme of this conversation it goes back to what you just said
we've been talking about the power of suffering in all kinds of different ways over the course of
this conversation and now here we are coming to the end of it and we're talking about the ultimate
moment that the power of human suffering was expressed into the world by jesus
in his resurrection and this is where we have to go we have to go back to an understanding of that
which is also an understanding of ourselves and face the hardest thing of all which is this place
is a miracle it is a whole this whole planet is a miracle and that's why all of these
un-miraculous but fascinated creatures are going around here and why they do not want us to kill
ourselves off on that note i just makes me want to go pray on it like that's definitely what i'm
gonna go do but like yeah oh we should do a prayer session after that yeah for sure i can't think of
a better note to end on yeah willie we really appreciate your time this was awesome oh thank
you i'm so glad it was such a pleasure to be here you guys were really fun to be with thank you so
right back at you man you got a lot to say and i hope the the world understands how profound
your messages your experiences are well in time i probably i probably have become a shade by then
but nevertheless they will well you look great now so i feel great too i biked 10 miles this morning
oh that's incredible yeah i do it i do it three times a week or swim or go to the gym i'm a very
active guy physically good for you man well okay well thank you willie appreciate it man
pleasure huge news everyone we've been sitting on a ton of unreleased footage that we will now be
releasing weekly in our new WAP our first episode is a completely uncut heated discussion between
hal puthoff and eric weinstein on remote viewing yeah you heard that right i still can't believe
i experienced that firsthand and now i'm happy to share it with you all as our first exclusive
video on WAP head over to wap.com slash american alchemy premium to become a premium member today
by becoming a member you'll gain access to weekly premium videos behind the scenes footage and
monthly group calls where we discuss the ideas we love most plus you'll get early access to
merchandise drops and be the first to know about the upcoming conference we'll be holding later
in 2025 our WAP community will serve as a private space where curious individuals
and tech enthusiasts can come together to challenge the status quo and explore ideas
shaping our future if you're passionate about exploring unconventional ideas and want to dive
even deeper into our content i invite you to join our WAP today head over to wap.com
slash american alchemy premium to become a premium member today thank you so much
and enjoy the rest of today's episode