This story will challenge your understanding of reality.
I've never had this conversation publicly, literally a game changer.
The mainstream media wouldn't touch it.
We are at a turning point in human history.
People's right to know.
There is a real phenomenon here, there's no question about that.
It's the biggest story ever, really, isn't it?
It is, it absolutely is, there's no doubt about that.
Good evening and welcome to this special edition of Spotlight with breaking news from the stars.
Tonight we bring you critical new witnesses and revelations in our ongoing investigation
into the UFO phenomenon.
And we'll reveal startling information about an Australian cover-up sanctioned by the highest
levels of government.
Shortly I'll be joined by investigative journalist Ross Coulthart, who for the past three years
has traversed this planet in a search for evidence of life on others.
What he's about to reveal will stun even the sternest of sceptics.
This is a very real phenomenon.
This is coming directly from the pinnacle.
This nut of this earth.
We have no idea its intent.
What?
You know, it was absolutely mind-blowing.
You don't know where these things are coming from?
We are well beyond reasonable doubt.
High level officials are acknowledging this.
They are focused on our nuclear weapons.
Highly trained observers.
I was stunned to my core.
Fighter pilots.
Circular.
Radar.
So extraordinary.
Iranian UFOs at the same time, at the same place.
Choo, choo, choo, choo.
The object knew where they were going.
I want to know the truth, Ross.
This is real.
Really good to have you here.
Ross, you've just published a book and documentary, they've been watched and read millions of
times.
Huge interest.
How do you describe that interest?
What is it?
Well, it's one of the biggest questions.
Are we alone in this universe?
And what's happened is the United States government has come out publicly now, officially, and
admitted that there is a possibility that the explanation for the phenomenon that they
acknowledge now is real.
The possibility that that explanation is extraterrestrial.
As recently as last week in Washington, the director of national intelligence conceded
the possibility that this was extraterrestrial phenomena.
Have you unearthed new leads?
The number of calls that I've had, particularly from people in Australia and overseas military
intelligence is phenomenal.
Extraordinary things about sightings, mainly linked with nuclear facilities like Pine Gap
in Australia, North West Cape in far Western Australia.
Every day you wake up and you are intrigued with the emails and the contacts you're receiving.
Absolutely.
And I think the days where this needs to be stigmatized and ridiculed are long over because
the Americans have now conceded this is real.
Let's pause for a moment.
We'll look back at some of the revelations in your initial documentary.
We're in a really interesting time in history here, where I think for the first time since
World War II, the US military is actually quite openly admitting that there's a mystery
it can't explain.
What we know is that there's a UAP task force, an Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force,
which quite incredibly has been operating in secret inside the Pentagon, apparently
for years investigating the phenomena of UFOs, flying saucers, strange craft in our skies.
We may be looking at a situation where we've got to consider the possibility of intelligent
non-human life for the first time on this planet.
We have the sensing apparatus to detect objects, and as we found with the recent DoD videos,
we are detecting objects and they are highly anomalous in nature.
And they're not any known human technology.
That we know of.
We see this hyper acceleration with complete absence of a sonic boom.
We see the objects have the ability to hover and then rapidly accelerate in the blink of
an eye.
We used to hear these stories within UFO circles by UFO nutters, but we're hearing this from
credible senior level government and military officials that are all basically telling us
the same story.
And to what end?
Why would they lie?
So who are the officials that you attach most credibility to by reputation, who you think
have said interesting things in recent months?
I would have to say Chris Mellon.
So let's go through it very carefully.
Are these objects intelligently controlled?
Some of them clearly are, yeah.
Could they be Russian, Chinese, or any other attestation?
Conceivably.
We're entertaining that possibility, sure.
What do you think?
The problem with that is that in some cases the performance of these vehicles is so extraordinary,
it's so radical, that we don't understand how it's possible even.
And so it's difficult for us to imagine how our terrestrial rivals could master that kind
of technology.
In April last year here at the Pentagon, the US Department of Defence made an unprecedented
admission.
It acknowledged that the videos taken by their fighter pilots of unidentified objects
are real.
So if they're not ours, if they're probably not Russian or Chinese or any other potential
adversaries, does that mean they're alien?
I think that we have to entertain that possibility.
Now you realise that is just mind-blowing in its immensity.
It is.
The implications of that are extraordinary.
We're talking about the possibility of alien life visiting this planet.
It is, and it is mind-boggling, it's hard to process, it's hard to digest, and yet as
a matter of integrity, scientific integrity, we have to be able to look at the facts and
follow them wherever they lead.
When we look at decades-long denials on the part of the US government and military forces
with regard to UFOs, they denied, they denied, they denied.
Then in December 2017, everything changed.
One of the world's greatest newspapers, the New York Times, revealed the existence of
a Pentagon unit secretly investigating UFOs, and even more extraordinary, it had the videos
to prove it.
He saw this white oblong object, which he said looked like a tic-tac, kind of zigzagging
around over the surface of the water.
What were the primary revelations in that story that made people, probably for the first
time, sit up and say, wow, UFOs are real?
Well I think there were two.
The first revelation was that there was a secret program within the Pentagon that had
started in 2007 that had been studying these objects.
So this had been for 10 years secretly being studied.
Now you don't have a program studying UFOs if there's nothing to them.
The second revelation was the Nimitz case that happened in 2004.
There's a lot more to that case than we were able to report, but we got that case out there
in the public.
We were going to do high fidelity air defense training.
We launched the good guys off the Nimitz, launched the notional bad guys off the beach,
and they go at it.
The captain comes down to the combat and says, hey sir, you know we've been tracking these
objects for days now.
If we launch aircraft and we hit one of these, someone's going to ask you and me both why
we were so damn curious.
That's a very persuasive argument.
What did the captain say?
He looks at me sternly, you're right, senior chief, intercept and V.I.D., visually ID it,
Commander Fravor happened to be airborne, top gun training guy.
And as he began to close the gap, the tic tac recognized and began to react to his movements.
It sees him and he recognizes as a fighter pilot that it's engaging with him.
And so he's spiraling down like this, it's coming up to him and he's in a dogfight and
he screams out to his colleagues, I'm engaged.
So it's intelligently responding.
It is absolutely intelligent responding to his actions.
That's very important.
It is.
It's not a dumb object.
Correct.
And it began to take evasive maneuvers to counter and maintain distance between his
aircraft that was closing in, by the way, an F-18 at the time, Super Hornet, one of
the most premier aircraft on the planet at the time, and this thing had no problem keeping
pace.
You're seeing whatever this object was.
Yeah, I'm seeing it on radar.
Are you picking it up on radar?
Yeah, I'm seeing him do the intercept and as soon as he's at the merge plot, that object
went from 28,000 feet to the surface of the ocean in .78 seconds.
And then all of a sudden, bam, it's gone.
Bing, disappears instantaneously.
The accelerations that were observed would destroy five or ten times over any craft that
we can design or build today.
No visible propulsion system.
No visible propulsion.
No obvious signs of lift.
No wings.
No rudders.
No control surface.
No ailerons.
No elevators.
No cockpit.
No rivets.
My gosh.
All right, Ross, since then, a lot has happened.
There's been quite a few developments.
What's been the most significant development?
The biggest thing is that the Congress is now taking this seriously.
They're demanding reports from all of the intelligence agencies, from the defence departments
on the phenomena.
They're demanding transparency.
There's even a request in a new amendment that's very likely now to go through for any
disclosures to be made of recovered craft and even organic matter bodies.
Believe it or not, this is being seriously discussed in the Congress.
Those videos from America, they have changed the game.
They have.
The New York Times, when those videos were published four years ago this year in December,
they changed everything.
It was a totally new paradigm, especially when the United States government was forced
to admit that it couldn't explain the phenomena.
And Mike, there are so many more videos.
There are 144 sightings that were investigated by the United States Pentagon UFO investigators.
And literally all of them, except for one, couldn't be explained.
And I've been told the videos in them are incredible, identifiable, metallic, silvery
objects, disc-shaped craft, clearly visible, flying within 50 metres of a jet fighter.
And Ross, the biggest mystery centres around are mass sighting in suburban Melbourne.
That's right.
It's the biggest mass sighting in the world.
Hundreds of Melbourne school children, along with their teachers, witnessing an event so
strange and implausible it would change them for life.
Officially, the dazzling silver UFOs seen hovering above the school oval that April
Day in 1966 never existed.
But for those who were there, it was real, terrifyingly real.
Ross Westall appears to be sighting on such a grand scale that it can't be denied, yet
it has been.
It has been.
And in fact, the real situation is the government's basically ignored it.
Even though these people, 180 to 200 plus people, have said they saw these elliptical
disc-shaped objects hovering over a school in broad daylight 55 years ago, no government
official has ever provided any explanation for what happened.
There's one guy who's done a very thorough investigation tracking down those witnesses.
His name is Shane Ryan.
This is his story.
I've spent far too long going through National Archives documents, but they represent a fascinating
counterfactual history to the history that we've been presented in public by our defence
department for the last 50 to 60 years.
The Australian Government holds thousands of UFO sightings reports going back decades,
many of them once classified secret or top secret.
It might surprise a lot of people to know just how seriously those sightings were taken
by military investigators, even though some of those sightings describe crazy things
like hovering craft, flying saucers, black triangles.
But there's one very secret report, which I know exists because I've spoken to someone
who saw it being prepared, which isn't in these archives, and it should be.
It's perhaps Australia's greatest UFO mystery of all.
This is Australia's, possibly one of the world's biggest UFO mysteries, isn't it?
It is.
I think it's time to put Australia on the UFO map, because of this incident, certainly
in terms of Australia, maybe internationally, was the largest daylight mass sighting of
at least one, possibly up to three, flying saucers, UFOs, that has ever happened.
Melbourne, in the sunny suburban swinging 60s.
What a time to be stuck at school. Westall High School, a college of about 600 pupils
in Melbourne's South East.
I was a very young man in those days. I was teaching, I was teaching a year nine, I think
it was, class, teaching science. Just before morning tea, the door flung open,
a young girl rushed in.
Mr. Greenwood, Mr. Greenwood, there's a flying saucer.
The bell went, and I can remember running out into the oval, looking into the sky, and
seeing these things, and just standing there absolutely transfixed.
When I looked up, I could see this object in the sky. It was directly over the far side
of the oval.
Never seen anything like it before in my life, haven't seen anything like it since. Trying
to absorb what we were looking at because it was just something so unusual.
Shane, take me back to the 6th of April, 1966, at the Westall High School. What happened?
So on that day, something very unusual, something that the kids had never seen before, flew
into their view. It flew silently, it flew unexpectedly, and according to the witnesses
who were there, it looked like a bowl, turned upside down, sitting on something like a plate
or a saucer. It was silver looking, metallic looking, and it flew in ways that they'd never
seen an object fly before. These kids were very used to aircraft. Moorabbin Airport was
only a few kilometres away, a very busy airport. But this object, apart from being silent or
virtually silent, it flew very quickly. It would stop in midair, it would hover, and
then it would flick off and then flick on again on the other side of the sky.
It was a classic cigar shaped object that looked like grey metal. That's what it looked
like.
I actually headed over to the corner of the school and jumped the fence and went into
a place called the Grange, which is an area where we used to do our cross country exercises,
and ran towards where we had seen one appear to come down and land.
What do you think it was?
I'd love to know what it was. After 16 years of researching this story and talking to hundreds
of witnesses, literally hundreds of witnesses, people who saw the object, some as close as
a few metres away, I still don't know, but I feel as though I can say what it wasn't.
I feel as though I can say it wasn't an aircraft, it wasn't a balloon, it wasn't a kite, it
wasn't a drone, but it was something that, in a way, shouldn't have been there that day.
You actually saw one of the objects land?
Yes. Well, I didn't see it land, but I did see it on the ground in front of me. I could
feel a heat and hear this buzzing sound, and I could see purple lights all around it. I
know soon it got there, and within, I'd say, a minute, it just raised up off the ground
really slowly, just kept on rising to probably about three or four metres, maybe a bit higher,
and then it turned on its side and just almost just disappeared, just went straight up like
that, and I looked up in the sky and I could see the other two. So it appeared to just
disappear.
According to the witnesses, the people who were there, it left at least one, some say
several, rather large, perfectly round-shaped circles in the grass with a very definite
indentation, a very definite perimeter to the grass, as if the perimeter had somehow
been singed or discoloured.
What I want you all to do is to try and draw as best as you can what you saw that day.
And no peeking.
The witnesses gave descriptions that were pretty consistent. You have to remember people
were standing in different places at different times, but for the most part, they gave descriptions
that tallied with each other.
And what did they say they saw?
They say they saw a flying saucer.
It's like a silvery thing, like this, and it had like little lights around it, all lights,
underneath it, around here, around the edges.
It gave a lot of witnesses the sense that there was some intelligence behind it. They
say that because it flew effortlessly, it flew virtually silently, it could go wherever
it wanted. And for the witnesses who saw five very regular-looking aircraft like Cessnas
flying close to the object, as if it was trying to, the planes were trying to chase
the object and catch up to it, the craft very easily, completely out flew those aeroplanes.
How many witnesses have you interviewed in the 16 years that you've been researching
this who actually saw the craft?
I think at last count, because I've had a few witnesses come forward just in the last
few weeks, and I get new witnesses coming forward, probably one every couple of months.
But at the moment, I think I'm up to somewhere around 180.
180 people?
Something like that, very similar number to that, and more who saw the traces that were
left behind, apparently, by the craft on the ground.
What did you see?
It's circular. The area, the trampled grass, and there were guards around it, and there
were people in there with equipment.
Do you believe the witnesses?
I absolutely believe them.
What do you believe happened that day?
Well, I've spoken to so many of the witnesses over these years, and they're very ordinary
people who tell an extraordinary story at no particular gain to themselves, and often
at some cost to themselves, because people often don't believe other people when they
tell extraordinary stories.
Let's talk about that. There's been a lot of ridicule, hasn't there, directed at the
whole issue of flying saucers, UFOs, generally. Is it deserved in the West Auckland?
It's absolutely undeserved.
Within 40 minutes of the sighting, Air Force and Army personnel, Alec and their trucks,
they were there.
You saw this?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Military turned up for sure. You're very sure about that?
Yeah, definitely. Yeah.
They saw them there with lorries, with Land Rovers. They saw people getting equipment
out of their vehicles, equipment like metal detectors, Geiger counters, shovels and spades,
and they were apparently busily inspecting the site of these ground marks.
We know that two separate fire brigades were called. We know the Civil Defence Organisation
was called. We know the police attended both to the school and to the site at the Grange.
And the military.
For 55 years, Tanya Vassy, who was 12 at the time, has been afraid to speak publicly about
what she saw that day. Afraid because she was warned off. Soon you'll hear from her,
but first let's look at the extreme steps taken by sinister figures to shut the news
down and shut eyewitnesses up.
What do you say to the fact that officially there is no government report into this matter?
Well, because they buried it, you know, they hid it.
Two weeks later, a knock on the door, and when I answered it, there were two people
there, one in plain clothes and then the other one, Senior Air Force. Obviously Senior had
a good many rings on his sleeve, and they told me that I was wrong, that I hadn't seen
anything. And when I tried to explain to them that they weren't there, I was, and I knew
what I saw, and well, I think the first suggestion was that you'd be ill-advised to go on saying
that because clearly you were drunk on duty and that would have to be reported to the
Education Department and of course you'll lose your job.
They were threatening you?
Oh, absolutely. I was threatened.
You're describing officials from our government, trying to gag you from telling the truth
about what you saw.
Which is quite interesting when you realise that officials from another government, twelve
months later, beg me to speak about it. The Office of the President, saying that...
Let's be clear here, this is the President of the United States.
Yes, the President of the United States.
President of the United States.
The President had authorised the establishment of a board of inquiry or an inquiry to inquire
into issues of unidentified flying objects and that they were sending out somebody who
I believe turned out to be a Mr...
I think it might have been a Professor James MacDonald.
James MacDonald, that's the one.
Officially, he was working for the US Navy, but in his spare time he's checking many Australian
reports of UFOs and comparing them with American reports. His aim is to see if the reports
tally, in short, whether UFOs constitute a global phenomenon. In Melbourne, he's talking
with Brian King.
Professor MacDonald, what have you found here that's been of use to you?
I've investigated about 50 or 60 cases since I came down to New Zealand and Australia.
Extremely interesting UFO sightings, essentially similar to those in the United States.
What are the main similarities?
The reasons of really quite high credibility, reporting unconventional objects, discs,
cigar-shaped objects, frequently at very low elevation, hovering over sometimes urban areas,
sometimes over cars, following cars.
I met this Professor MacDonald. Basically, we did the same as I'm doing with you now.
Just went through the story.
And did he treat you respectfully?
Oh, absolutely. Absolutely. There is a recording of the interview.
You saw it. There was a hovering motionless when you saw it?
Well, it did several things. It did hover at different times. It seemed to be able to
accelerate and disappear out of sight and then someone would see it over another part
of the sky. It moved a considerable distance, but rapidly. And then it would move back again.
My recollection is that it was very much he asked some prompting questions and that's
all. It was basically for me to speak.
And why would it disappear?
Well, this is one thing we just don't know. It didn't just vanish.
All of a sudden while you were all looking at it?
No, it did one of these, you know, seven accelerations and nobody could figure it out again. Darn.
There clearly is a report somewhere.
You think there was a cover-up?
I think there was a cover-up of sorts. I'd love to know why there was such pressure applied
to some of the witnesses to keep the story under wraps. But for someone at some level
in government, they didn't want this story to get out.
This is the largest group sighting of a UFO, the largest one in the Southern Hemisphere.
And it's got a whole credibility because it's not as if just one person saw it. There
were over 200 people saw it.
What official explanation, if any, has ever been given by the government or any agency
to explain what happened at Westall?
There's never been any.
I mean the silence is deafening, isn't it?
It's deafening and it's perplexing and very, very frustrating.
It was something incredibly unusual, unexpected, that came from somewhere else. And I don't
know where that somewhere else is.
And it happened here in Australia.
In Australia's second largest city, in the suburban outskirts of that city.
In broad daylight.
In broad daylight, in front of hundreds.
Joining Ross and I now is former Westall student Tanya Vassie. You've never spoken before about
this. This is the first time. You were one of the first to see that UFO hovering that
day. What did you see?
I saw a shiny two-story disk. It certainly wasn't anything that we'd ever seen.
So you had an incident that took place two days later where the headmaster came into
the classroom and took you away. What happened?
Well, he took me to a room which I presume was a parent-teacher interview little office.
And there were two gentlemen waiting there and I was with them probably for about 15
minutes, being questioned.
Did they say who they were?
No.
What nationality were they?
Definitely American.
Americans?
Yeah. They didn't want me to speak of the incident to absolutely anybody and because
it was in the interest of national security. So we want you to keep this under your belt
and not discuss it with anybody.
Did they try and explain to you what it was?
Yes, they did. One of them actually told me that it was a very special weather balloon.
Did you believe that?
No. Not at the age of 12. I knew better. I know what I saw and it was definitely not
a balloon.
Can I ask you this? Do you think it was something not of this world?
As an adult now, yes I do. Yes I do. Definitely. I no longer care what people think. I saw
what I saw. I know what I saw. I was not the only one.
Yeah. Ross, how significant is it that Tanya is coming forward with her story?
It's very significant. The thing that really comes home to me, Tanya, is the fact that
you corroborate that American officials were there trying to shut this story down.
Absolutely.
And it suggests there really was a cover-up and it was international. What is it that
the Australian and American government had to hide in 1966 that 55 years later we still
don't know what it was?
It's fascinating. Well, Tanya, thank you so much for sharing your story with us as well.
Just as a matter of interest, what questions did you think I was going to ask?
I thought you were going to ask some questions about aircraft. It sounds like you're going
to ask questions about UFOs.
Well, it would be very interesting to hear your views on this.
You heard it there, Ross. I mean, when Peter Wish-Wilson raised this in Parliament only
last month, the topic of UFOs, I think it's fair to say that he was met with a lot of
mirth. He's insisting, though, that this is no laughing matter. Why is he passionate
about this?
Because he's hearing what I'm hearing from military personnel, not just in Australia
but all over the world. They're seeing these things and whether it's being reported up
the line or not, I think our Air Force, our military commanders need to start taking it
seriously because if, as the Americans have discovered, this is a threat to flight safety,
this is a potential national security issue, we need to engage with it. We need to study
it. We need to understand it, whatever it is.
It's concerning that we actually don't understand what these things are. We don't know anything
really about them at all. I probably couldn't have justified asking this question at Senate
estimates or using the Senate's resources if it hadn't been for these extraordinary
revelations that we've seen in recent months, including the Pentagon saying this is very
real.
I got the impression that when you asked questions about UFOs, UAPs at Senate estimates, neither
the Air Marshal nor the Minister were prepared for your question.
No, they certainly didn't appear to be around their brief, which surprised me considering
we saw a significant report released by our close friend and ally, the United States,
only four months prior to that.
This will certainly be having a round two. It will be interesting to see if their attitudes
change when we ask them more questions in the future.
You've spoken to people, I understand, in our military services who've seen these objects.
After I left school, I joined the Army. One of my lifelong friends joined the Navy and
we hooked up nearly 20 years ago after we both got out of the services. He just came
out with this bizarre story of a close encounter he'd had while on operation. I've been intrigued
ever since.
Do you think he would be willing to speak to us?
Look, he may be willing to speak to you, but I got a sense from him that he was almost
a little bit embarrassed about his confession.
I remember asking him, you're in the Navy, you're obviously out at sea, surely there
was technology there, this thing would have been detected and other people saw it. And
his view was, yes, other people did see it, but no one really wanted to talk about it.
The astonishing thing, Michael, is that we've been able to track down the person who Senator
Wishwilson's speaking about. The story he has to tell of what he saw on a Navy vessel
in waters around Australia is quite extraordinary, and this is what he saw.
The vessel I was on was a patrol boat based out of Cairns. It was about two o'clock in
the morning. It was just myself and an officer of the watch. We were in cruise control heading
west, clear night sky, very little cloud. And then all of a sudden it was a white light
and it moved. If you held out your hand with your index finger and your pinky directly
up, that's the kind of distance it moved. And it moved once, twice, and the third time
it just took off and the light was gone. I've seen aircraft do manoeuvres and I've seen
helicopters do manoeuvres. This is something that's not explained. Definitely a UFO or
something out of this world.
Is it fair to say that what you saw must have been intelligently controlled?
Yes. It wasn't space junk hitting other space junk. It was a steady white light that just
changed. I know it in my soul. Deep down I know, okay, that's unexplainable. It changed
me as knowing that, okay, we're not it. We're not it. Maybe they're watching, watching
what we're doing, laughing at us, thinking we're ants. I don't know, but we're out there
to intercept illegal immigrants at this stage. And it made me think, wow, if we're this
small, what are we doing?
Tonight we've been exposing the secrets, cover-ups and conspiracies of the UFO phenomenon. Before
we leave you, not many people know this, but on the far western tip of our continent is
Australia's very own answer to Roswell. And Ross, you went there as part of your investigation.
And if we are being watched from above, then it may provide the answer as to why.
I think that something extremely anomalous and unusual is still happening up at North
West Cape.
Dear sir, I hereby wish to report a most unusual sighting.
You couldn't pick a more remote part of Australia to locate this extremely secret military base
that was doing communications with America's most dangerous nuclear submarines at the height
of the Cold War. It's one of the last places in the country to see the light every day.
And one dark night, 30 years ago, a young Australian who was living here, called Annie,
had an experience that was to change her life forever.
And what do you see?
I see a craft. I see a diamond-shaped craft hovering literally straight above the vehicle.
Are there lights?
Yes, there's lights on the bottom of it.
How big is it?
I would say two to three cars in length.
Any noise?
Nothing. There wasn't a single sound coming from this.
Within seconds it shoots up, straight up in the sky, like faster than you could watch
it. And then it comes down over here.
When I was doing my preliminary research, when I went up there the first time, I had
people walk up to me at the table when I was having dinner one night. They said, are
you that journo that's investigating the flying saucers? And I went, well, not quite,
but I'm looking at the phenomenon. He went, well, good, because we've all seen it.
It was very early in the morning. No one else was on the road. I was completely by myself.
And I saw this light on top of a hill. It was pure, bright, white light.
The only thing I could think of like that was if it was to do with the military.
I have absolute clarity of that memory. It was definitely solid, definitely solid. An
oval the size of a car.
Forgive me, why didn't you stop?
I think something was just telling me to keep going.
No, Exmouth is a place where it seems to occur.
What we saw was not of this world.
We are still transmitting on behalf of the Americans from North West Cape. And what happens
there is cloaked in secrecy. When we tried to go there and film around the base, the
Defence Department kicked us off.
They told us that we weren't allowed to film certain aspects of the base. It remains highly
confidential to this day. In fact, I think we had to pull back to a hill which was about
10 kilometres distant.
Is there a link between nuclear weapons, do you think, and these craft?
Yes, there seems to be a strong correlation between nuclear weapons, nuclear storage sites
and UFOs.
No question they are focused on our nuclear weapons.
And you believe they're trying to send a message?
I do. I think the message is get rid of your nuclear weapons.
Why would these objects, these craft, be taking an interest in a place like Harold Holt Naval
Communication Station?
Well, you know, these craft have shown the ability to disrupt communications. And so
if it came to the point where we had to use communications from that facility, they could
have disrupted those communications. I think this is simply a message to us humans to deactivate
all of our nuclear weapons and basically go another direction. And also to learn how to
live with each other in peace.
Regardless of whether you believe in aliens or not, that is a fine sentiment to end on.
Ross, thank you so much for your time tonight and all of your revelations from what we have
seen. I have no doubt there's many more to come.
I'm sure there will be, Michael, and thanks for the privilege. And good night.
Thanks so much for your company. Have a good night.
I have more questions for you. Let's go and talk about it.