Well, I am very interested in the subject of human misjudgment, and Lord knows I've
created my, well, a good bit of it.
I don't think I've created my full statistical share.
And I think that one of the reasons was I tried to do something about this terrible
ignorance I left the Harvard Law School with when I saw this patterned irrationality which
was so extreme.
And I had no theory or anything to deal with it, but I could see that it was extreme and
I could see that it was patterned.
I just started to create my own system of psychology, partly by casual reading, but
largely from personal experience.
And I used that pattern to help me get through life.
Fairly late in life, I stumbled into this book, Influence, by a psychologist named
Bob Cialdini, who became a super tenured hotshot on the 2000 person faculty at a very young
age.
And he wrote this book, which is now sold 300,000 copies, which is remarkable for semi
well, it's an academic book aimed at a popular audience.
And that filled in a lot of holes in my crude system.
And when those holes had filled in, I thought I had a system that was a good working tool
and I'd like to share that one with you.
And I came here because behavioral economics, how could economics not be behavioral?
If it isn't behavioral, what the hell is it?
And I think it's fairly clear that all reality has to respect all other reality.
If you come to inconsistencies, they have to be resolved.
And so the idea of if there's anything valid in psychology, economics has to recognize
it and vice versa.
So I think the people that are working on this fringe between economics and psychology
are absolutely right to be there.
And I think there's been plenty wrong over the years.
Well, let me romp through my as much of this list as I have time to get through 24 standard
causes of human misjudgment.
First, under recognition of the power of what psychologists call reinforcement and economic
and economists call incentives.
Well, you say everybody knows that.
Well, I think I've been in the top five percent of my age cohort all my life and understanding
the power of incentives and all my life I underestimated it and never a year passes.
But what I get some surprise that pushes my limit a little farther.
So one of my favorite cases about the power of incentives is the Federal Express case
where heart and soul of the integrity of the system is that all the packages have to be
shifted rapidly in one central location each night.
And the system has no integrity if the whole shift can't be done fast.
And Federal Express had one hell of a time getting the thing to work.
And they tried moral suasion.
They tried everything in the world.
And finally, somebody got the happy thought that they were paying the night shift by the
hour and that maybe if they paid them by the shift, the system would work better.
And lo and behold, that solution worked.
Early in the history of Xerox, Joe Wilson, who was then in the government, had to go
back to Xerox because he couldn't understand how their better new machine was selling so
poorly in relation to their older and inferior machine.
Of course, when he got there, he found out that the commission arrangement with the salesman
gave a tremendous incentive to the inferior machine.
And here at Harvard in the shadow of B.F.
There was a man who really was in the reinforcement as a powerful thought.
And you know, Skinner has lost his reputation in a lot of places.
But if you were to analyze the entire history of experimental science at Harvard, he'd be
in the top handful.
His experiments were very ingenious.
The results were counterintuitive and they were important.
It is not given to experimental science to do better.
What gummed up Skinner's reputation is that he developed a case of what I always call
man with a hammer syndrome.
To the man with a hammer, every problem tends to look pretty much like a nail.
And Skinner had one of the more extreme cases in the history of academia.
And this syndrome doesn't exempt right people.
It's just a man with a hammer and Skinner is an extreme example of that.
And later, as I get on my list, let's go back and try and figure out why people like Skinner
get man with a hammer syndrome.
Incidentally, when I was at the Harvard Law School, there was a professor naturally at
Yale who was derisively discussed at Harvard and they used to say, poor old Blanchard,
he thinks declaratory judgments will cure cancer.
And that's the way Skinner got.
And not only that, he was literary and he scorned opponents who had any different way
of thinking or thought anything else was important.
This is not a way to make a lasting reputation if the other people turn out to also be doing
something important.
My second factor is simple psychological denial.
This first really hit me between the eyes when a friend of our family had a super athlete
super student son who flew off a carrier in the North Atlantic and never came back.
And his mother, who was a very sane woman, just never believed that he was dead.
And of course, if you turn on the television, you find the mothers of the most obvious
premises man could ever diagnose and they all think their sons are innocent.
Simple psychological denial.
The reality is too painful to bear, so you just distort it until it's bearable.
We all do that to some extent, and it's a common psychological misjudgment that causes
terrible problems.
Third, incentive-caused bias, both in one's own mind and that of one's trusted advisor,
where it creates what economists call agency costs.
Here my early experience was a doctor who sent bushel baskets full of normal gallbladders
down to the pathology lab in a leading hospital in Lincoln, Nebraska.
With that quality control, for which community hospitals are famous, about five years after
he should have been removed from the staff, he was.
And one of the old doctors who participated in the removal was also a family friend.
And I asked him, I said, tell me, did he think here's a way for me to exercise my talents?
This guy was very skilled, technically, and make a high living by doing a few maimings
and murders every year, along with some frauds.
He said, hell no, Charlie.
He thought that the gallbladder was the source of all medical evil, and if you really loved
your patients, you couldn't get that organ out rapidly enough.
Now, that's an extreme case, but in lesser strength, it's present in every profession
and in every human being, and it causes perfectly terrible behavior.
If you take sales presentations of brokers of commercial real estate and businesses,
I'm 70 years old.
I've never seen one, I thought was even within hailing distance of objective truth.
And you want to talk about the power of incentives and the power to rationalize terrible behavior.
After the Defense Department had had enough experience with cost plus percentage of cost
contracts, the reaction of our republic was to make it a crime for the federal government
to write one, and not only a crime, but a felony.
And by the way, the government's right, but a lot of the way the world is run, including
most law firms and a lot of other places, they've still got a cost plus percentage of
cost system, and human nature, with its version of what I call incentive-caused bias, causes
this terrible abuse.
And many of the people who are doing it, you would be glad to have Mary into your family
compared to what you're otherwise going to get.
Now, there are huge implications from the fact that human mind is put together this
way.
And the idea is that people who create things like cash registers, which make misbehavior
hard, are some of the effective saints of our civilization.
And the cash register was a great moral instrument when it was created.
And Patterson knew that, by the way.
He had a little store, and the people were stealing him blind and never made any money,
and people sold him a couple of cash registers, and it went to profit immediately.
And of course, he closed the store and went into the cash register business, with results
So this is a huge, important thing.
If you read the psychology text, you will find that if they're a thousand pages long,
there's one sentence, somehow incentive-caused bias has escaped the standard survey course
in psychology.
Fourth, and this is a superpower in error-causing psychological tendency, bias from consistency
and commitment tendency, including the tendency to avoid or promptly resolve cognitive dissonance,
is the self-confirmation tendency of all conclusions, particularly expressed conclusions
and with a special persistence for conclusions that are hard won.
But what I'm saying here is that the human mind is a lot like the human egg, and the
human egg has a shutoff device.
When the sperm gets in, it shuts down, so the next one can't get in.
The human mind has a big tendency of the same sort.
And here again, it doesn't just catch ordinary mortals, it catches the deans of physics.
According to Max Planck, the really innovative, important new physics was never really accepted
by the old guard.
Instead, a new guard came along that was less brain blocked by its previous conclusions.
And if Max Planck's crowd had this consistency and commitment tendency that kept their old
conclusions intact in spite of disconfirming evidence, you can imagine what the crowd that
you and I are part of behaves like.
And of course, if you make a public disclosure of your conclusion, you're pounding it in
to your own head.
Many of these students that are screaming at us, you know, they aren't convincing us,
but they're forming mental chains for themselves because what they're shouting out, they're
pounding in.
And I think educational institutions that create a climate where too much of that goes
on are, in a fundamental sense, they're irresponsible institutions.
It's very important to not put your brain in chains too young by what you shout out.
And all these things like painful qualifying and initiation rituals, all those things pound
in your commitments and your ideas.
The Chinese brainwashing system, which was for war prisoners, which was way better than
anybody else's, they maneuvered people into making tiny little commitments and declarations.
And then they'd slowly build.
That worked way better than torture.
Sixth, bias from Pavlovian association, misconstruing past correlation as a reliable basis for decision
making.
I never took a course in psychology or economics either, for that matter, but I did learn about
Pavlovian high school biology and the way they taught it.
So the dog salivated when the bell rang.
So what?
Nobody made the least effort to tie that to the wide world.
The truth of the matter is that Pavlovian association is an enormously powerful psychological
force in the daily life of all of us.
And indeed in economics, we wouldn't have money without the role of so-called secondary
reinforcement, which is a pure psychological phenomenon demonstrated in the laboratory.
Practically, I'd say three quarters of advertising works on pure Pavlov.
Think how association, pure association works.
Take Coca-Cola Company, we're the biggest shareholder.
They want to be associated with every wonderful image, heroics in the Olympics, wonderful
music, you name it.
They don't want to be associated with president's funerals and so forth.
When have you seen a Coca-Cola ad?
And the association really works.
And all these psychological tendencies work largely or entirely on a subconscious level,
which makes them very insidious.
Then you've got Persian messenger syndrome.
The Persians really did kill the messenger who brought the bad news.
You think that is dead?
I mean, you should have seen Bill Paley in his last 20 years.
He didn't hear one damn thing.
He didn't want to hear.
People knew that it was bad for the messenger to bring Bill Paley things he didn't want
to hear.
Well, that means that the leader gets in a cocoon of unreality and is a great big enterprise.
And boy, did he make some dumb decisions in the last 20 years.
And Persian messenger syndrome is alive and well.
When I saw some years ago, ARCO and Exxon arguing over a few hundred millions of ambiguity
in their North Slope treaties, before a Superior Court judge in Texas with armies of lawyers
and experts on each side, this is a Mad Hatter's Tea Party.
Two engineering style companies can't resolve some ambiguity without spending tens of millions
of dollars in some Texas Superior Court.
In my opinion, what happens is that nobody wants to bring the bad news to the executives
up the line.
That here's a few hundred million dollars you thought you had that you don't, and it's
much safer to act like the Persian messenger who goes away to hide rather than bring home
the news of the battle lost.
Talking about economics, you get a very interesting phenomenon that I've seen over and over again
in a long life.
You've got two products, suppose they're complex technical product.
Now you think under the laws of economics that if product A costs X, if product Y costs
X minus something, it will sell better than if it sells at X plus something.
But that's not so.
In many cases, when you raise the price of the alternative product, it'll get a larger
market share than it would when you make it lower than your competitor's product.
That's because the bell, a Pavlovian bell, ordinarily there's a correlation between price
and value.
You have an information inefficiency.
When you raise the price, the sales go up relative to your competitor.
That happens again and again and again.
It's a pure Pavlovian phenomenon.
You can say, well, the economists have figured this sort of thing out when they started talking
about information inefficiencies, but that was fairly late in economics that they found
such an obvious thing.
Of course, most of them don't ask what causes the information inefficiencies.
One of the things that causes it is pure old Pavlov and his dog.
Now you've got bias from Skinnerian Association, operant conditioning, where you give the dog
a reward and pound in the behavior that preceded the dogs getting the award.
Of course, Skinner was able to create superstitious pigeons by having rewards come by accident
with certain occurrences.
Of course, we all know people who are the human equivalents of superstitious pigeons.
That's a very powerful phenomenon.
Of course, operant conditioning really works.
The people in the center who think that operant conditioning is important are very much right.
It's just that Skinner overdid it a little.
Where you see in business just perfectly horrible results from psychologically rooted tendencies
is in accounting.
If you take Westinghouse, which blew what?
$2 or $3 billion pre-tax at least, loaning developers to build hotels and virtually 100%
loans.
Now you say any idiot knows that there's one thing you don't like, it's a developer, another
you don't like, it's a hotel.
To make 100% loans, the developer is going to build a hotel.
But this guy, he probably was an engineer or something and he didn't take psychology
anymore and I did.
He got out there in the hands of these slick salesmen operating under their version of
incentive cost bias or any damn way of getting Westinghouse to do what was considered normal
business and they just blew it.
That would never have been possible if the accounting system hadn't been such that for
the initial phase of every transaction, it showed wonderful financial results.
So people who have loose accounting standards are just inviting perfectly horrible behavior
in other people and it's a sin.
It's an absolute sin.
If you carried bushel baskets full of money through the ghetto and made it easy to steal,
that would be a considerable human sin because you'd be causing a lot of bad behavior and
the bad behavior would spread.
Similarly, an institution that gets sloppy accounting commits a real human sin and it's
also a dumb way to do business as Westinghouse is so wonderfully prude.
Oddly enough, nobody mentions, at least nobody I've seen, what happened with Joe Jets and
Kidder Peabody.
The truth of the matter is the accounting system was such that by punching a few buttons,
the Joe Jets of the world could show profits and profits that showed up and things that
resulted in rewards and esteem and every other thing that human be.
Well, the Joe Jets are always with us and they're not really to blame in my judgment
at least, but that bastard who created that foolish accounting system, who so far as I
know has not been played alive, ought to be.
Seventh, bias from reciprocation tendency, including the tendency of one in a role to
act as other persons expect.
Well here again, Sealdini does a magnificent job at this and you're all going to be given
a copy of Sealdini's book and if you have half as much sense as I think you do, you
will immediately order copies for all of your children and several of your friends.
You will never make a better investment.
It is so easy to be a patsy for what he calls the compliance practitioners of this life.
But at any rate, reciprocation tendency is a very, very powerful phenomenon and Sealdini
demonstrated this by running around the campus and he asked people to take juvenile delinquents
to the zoo and it was a campus and so one in six actually agreed to do it.
And after he'd accumulated the statistical output, he went around on the same campus
and he asked other people, he said, Jay, would you devote two afternoons a week to taking
juvenile delinquents somewhere and suffering greatly yourself to help them?
And there he got 100% of the people to say no.
But after he'd made the first request, he backed off a little and he said, well, would
you at least take them to the zoo one afternoon?
He raised the compliance rate from a third to a half.
He got three times the success by just going through the little ask for a lot and back
off.
Now, the human mind on a subconscious level can be manipulated that way and you don't
know it.
I always use the phrase, you're like a one legged man in an ass kicking contest and you
are, I mean, you are really giving a lot of quarter to the external world that you you
can't afford to give and on this so-called role theory where you tend to act in the way
that other people expect.
That's reciprocation.
If you think about the way society is organized and a guy named Zimbardo had people at
Stanford divide into two pieces.
One were the guards and the other were the prisoners.
And they started acting out roles as people expected.
He had to stop the experiment after about five days.
He was getting into human misery and breakdown and pathological behavior.
I mean, it was it was it was awesome.
However, Zimbardo was greatly misinterpreted.
It's not just reciprocation, tendency and role theory that caused that.
It's consistency and commitment tendency.
Each person, as he acted as a guard or a prisoner, the action itself was pounding in.
The idea wherever you turn this consistency and commitment tendency is is affecting you.
In other words, what you think may change what you do, but perhaps even more important,
what you do will change what you think.
And you can say everybody knows that.
I want to tell you, I didn't know it well enough early enough.
Eight. Now, this is a lullabaloo, and Henry Kaufman wisely talked about this bias from
over influenced by social proof, that is the conclusions of others, particularly under
conditions of natural uncertainty and stress.
And here, one of the cases the psychologists use is Kitty Genovese, where all these people,
50, 60, 70 of them just sort of sat and did nothing while she was slowly murdered.
Now, one of the explanations is that everybody looked at everybody else and nobody else was
doing anything. And so there's automatic social proof that the right thing to do is nothing.
That's not a good enough explanation for Kitty Genovese in my judgment.
That's only part of it.
There are microeconomic ideas and gain loss ratios and so forth that also come into play.
I think time and time again, in reality, psychological notions and economic notions
interplay. And the man who doesn't understand both is a damn fool.
Big shot businessmen get into these waves of social proof.
You remember some years ago when one oil company bought a fertilizer company and every
other major oil company practically ran out and bought a fertilizer company.
And there was no more damn reason for all these oil companies to buy fertilizer companies.
But they didn't know exactly what to do.
And if Exxon was doing it, it was good enough for mobile or vice versa.
And of course, I think they're all gone now.
It was a total disaster.
Now, let's talk about efficient market theory, a wonderful economic doctrine that had a long
vogue in spite of the experience of Berkshire Hathaway.
In fact, one of the economists who won, he shared a Nobel Prize.
And as he looked at Berkshire Hathaway year after year, which people would throw in his
face as saying, maybe the market isn't quite as efficient as you think.
He said, well, it's a two sigma event.
And then he said we were a three sigma event.
And then he said we were a four sigma event.
And he finally got up to six segments.
Better to add a sigma than change the theory just because the evidence comes in differently.
And of course, when there's a share of a Nobel Prize winner, the money management himself,
he sank like a stone.
If you if you think about the doctrines I've talked about, namely one, the power of
reinforcement.
After all, you do something and the market goes up and you get paid and rewarded and
applauded and what have you getting a lot of reinforcement if you make a bet on a lot of
reinforcement, if you make a bet on a market and the market goes with you.
Also, there's social proof.
I mean, the the prices in the market are the ultimate form of social proof, reflecting
what other people think.
And so the combination is very powerful.
Why would you expect general market levels to always be totally efficient, say even in
1973, four at the pith or in 1972 or whatever it was when the nifty fifty were in their
heyday? If these psychological notions are correct, you would affect you would expect
some waves of irrationality, which which carry general levels to to to.
So they're inconsistent with with reason.
Nine, what made these economists love the efficient market theory is the math was
elegant. And after all, math is what they've learned to do.
The man with a hammer, every problem tends to look pretty much like a nail.
The alternative truth was a little messy and they'd forgotten the great economist Cain's,
whom I think said better to be roughly right than precisely wrong.
Nine bias from contrast caused distortions of sensation, perception and cognition.
Here, the great experiment that Sealdini does in his class, he takes three buckets of water,
one's hot, one's cold and one's room temperature.
He has the students stick his left hand in the hot water and his right hand in the cold
water. Then he has them remove the hands and put them both in the room temperature
bucket. And of course, with both hands in the same bucket of water, one seems hot and other seems
cold because the sensation apparatus of man is over influenced by contrast.
It has no absolute scale. It's got a contrast scale in it.
And it's a scale with quantum effects in it, too.
It takes a certain percentage change before it's noticed.
Maybe you've had a magician remove your watch.
I certainly have without your noticing it.
It's the same thing. He's taking advantage of your contrast type troubles in your sensory apparatus.
But here, the great truth is that cognition mimics sensation
and the cognition manipulators mimic the watch removing magician.
In other words, people are manipulating you all day long on this contrast phenomenon.
Cialdini cites the case of the real estate broker.
And you've got the room that's been transferred into your town.
And the first thing you do is you take the room out of the two of the most awful overpriced houses
you've ever seen. And then you take the room to some moderately overpriced house and then you
stick them. And it works pretty well, which is why the real estate salesmen do it.
And it's always going to work. And the accidents of life can do this to you and it can ruin your
life. In my generation, when women lived at home until they got married, I saw some perfectly
terrible marriages made by highly desirable women because they lived in terrible homes.
And I've seen some terrible second marriages which were made because there were slight
improvements over an even worse first marriage. And you think you're immune from these things and
you laugh and I want to tell you, you aren't. And my favorite analogy, I can't vouch for the
accuracy of. I have this worthless friend I like to play bridge with and he's a total intellectual
amateur that lives on inherited money. But he told me once something I really enjoyed hearing.
He said, Charlie, he says, if you throw a frog into very hot water, the frog will jump out.
But if you put the frog in room temperature water and just slowly heat the water up,
the frog will die there. Now, I don't know whether that's true about a frog,
but it sure as hell true about many of the businessmen I know. And there again,
it is the contrast phenomenon. These are hotshot high powered people. I mean, these are not
not fools. If it comes to you in small pieces, you're likely to miss. So you have to,
if you're going to be a person of good judgment, you have to do something about this warp in your
head where it's so misled by by mere contrast bias from over influenced by authority. Well,
here are the Milgram experiment as it's caused. I think there've been 1600 psychological papers
written about Milgram. And he had a person posing as an authority figure,
trick ordinary people into giving what they had every reason to expect was heavy torture by
electric shock to perfectly innocent fellow citizens. And the experiment has been he was
trying to show that why Hitler succeeded in a few other things. And, and so this really caught the
fancy of the world. They partly it's so politically correct. And, and, and
over influenced by authority as another very useful. You'll like this one. You got a pilot
and a co pilot. The pilot is the authority figure. They don't do this in airplanes,
but they've done it in simulators. They have the pilot do something where the co pilot who's
been trained in simulators a long time, he knows he's not to allow the plane to crash.
They have a pilot to do something where an idiot co pilot would know the plane was going to crash,
but the pilot's doing it and the co pilot is sitting there and the pilot is the authority figure
25% of the time the plane crashes. I mean, this is a very powerful psychological tendency.
It's not quite as powerful as some people think. And I'll get to that later. 11 bias from deprival
super reaction syndrome, including bias caused by present or threatened scarcity, including
threatened removal of something almost possessed, but never possessed. Here I took the monger dog,
lovely harmless dog. The one way, the only way to get that dog to bite you was to try and take
something out of its mouth after it was already there. And any of you who've tried to do tests
there and any of you who've tried to do takeaways and labor negotiations will know that the human
version of that dog is there in all of us. And I have a neighbor, a neighbor, a predecessor on a
little island where I have a house and his next door neighbor put a little pine tree on that was
about three feet high and it turned his 180 degree view of the harbor into 179 and three quarters.
Well, they had a blood feud like the Hatfields and McCoys and it went on and on and on.
I mean, people are really crazy about minor decrements down. And then if you act on them,
you get into reciprocation tendency because you don't just reciprocate affection, you reciprocate
animosity and the whole thing can escalate. And so huge insanities can come from just subconsciously
overweighing the importance of what you're losing or almost getting and not getting.
And the extreme business case here was New Coke.
Now, Coca-Cola has the most valuable trademark in the world.
We're the major shareholder. I mean, I think we understand that trademark.
Coke has armies of brilliant engineers, lawyers, psychologists, advertising executives, and so
forth. And they had a trademark on a flavor and they'd spent a better part of 100 years
getting people to believe that trademark had all these intangible values too.
And people associated it with a flavor. And so they were going to tell people not that it was
improved because you can't improve a flavor. If a flavor is a matter of taste, I mean,
you may improve a detergent or something, but telling you you're going to make a major change
in a flavor. I mean, so they got this huge depriveable super reaction syndrome. Pepsi was
within weeks of coming out with old Coke in a Pepsi bottle, which would have been
the biggest fiasco in modern times. Perfect, co-perfect insanity. And by the way,
both Goizuara and Kiyo are just wonderful about it. I mean, they just joke. I mean,
Kiyo always says, I must have been away on vacation. He participated in every single...
He's a wonderful guy. And by the way, Goizuara is a wonderful, smart guy, an engineer.
Smart people make these terrible boners. How can you not understand depriveable super reaction syndrome?
But people, I mean, people do not react symmetrically to loss and gain. Now, maybe
you have a great bridge player like Zekha, but that's a trained response. Ordinary people
subconsciously affected by their inborn tendencies.
Bias from envy jealousy. Well, envy jealousy made what? Two out of the ten commandments.
Those of you who have raised siblings, you know about, or tried to run a law firm or
investment bank or even a faculty. I've heard Warren say a half a dozen times,
it's not greed that drives the world, but envy. Here again, you go through the psychology survey
courses and you go to the index, envy, jealousy, thousand page book. It's blank.
There's some blind spots in academia, but it's an enormously powerful
thing and it operates to a considerable extent on a subconscious level.
And anybody who doesn't understand it is taking on defects he shouldn't have.
Bias from chemical dependency. Well, we don't have to talk about that. We've all seen so much
of it, but it's interesting how it always causes moral breakdown if there's any need
and always involves massive denial. See, it's just, it aggravates what we talked about earlier
in the aviator case, the tendency to distort reality so that it's endurable.
Bias from misgambling compulsion. Well, here Skinner made the only explanation you'll find in the
standard psychology survey course. He, of course, created a variable reinforcement
rate for his pigeons, his mice, and he found that that would pound in the behavior better
than any other enforcement pattern. And he says, aha, I've explained why gambling is such a powerful
addictive force in a civilization. I think that is to a very considerable extent true,
but being Skinner, he seemed to think that was the only explanation. But the truth of the matter is
that the divisors of these modern machines and techniques know a lot of things that Skinner didn't
know. For instance, a lottery. You have a lottery where you get your number by lot and then somebody
draws a number by lot. It gets lousy play. You get a lottery where people get to pick their number,
get big play. Again, it's this consistency and commitment thing. People think that if they
have committed to it, it has to be good. And the minute they've picked it themselves, it gets an
extra validity. After all, they thought it and they acted on it. And then you take slot machines,
you get bar, bar, lemon. That happens again and again and again. You get all these near misses.
Well, that's Deprival Super Reaction Central. And boy, do the people who create the machines
understand human psychology. And if you got to the high IQ crowd, they've got poker machines
where you make choices. So you can play blackjack, so to speak, with the machine.
It's wonderful what we've done with our computers to ruin a civilization.
But at any rate, misgambling compulsion is a very, very powerful and important thing. Look at what's
happening to our country. Every Indian has a reservation, every river town. And look at the
people who were ruined by it with the aid of their stockbrokers and others. And again, if you look in
the standard textbook of psychology, you'll find practically nothing on it except maybe one's
sentence talking about Skinner's rats. That is not an adequate coverage of the subject.
Bias from liking distortion, including the tendency to especially like oneself,
one's own kind and one's own idea structures, and the tendency to be especially susceptible
to being misled by someone like. Disliking distortion, bias from that. The reciprocal of
liking distortion and the tendency not to learn appropriately from someone disliked.
Well, here again, we've got hugely powerful tendencies. And if you look at the wars
in part of the Harvard Law School, as we say here, you can see the very brilliant people get into
this almost pathological behavior. And these are very, very powerful, basic, subconscious,
psychological tendencies, or at least partly subconscious. Now let's get back to B.F. Skinner,
man with a hammer syndrome revisited. Why is man with the hammer syndrome always present?
Well, he stopped to think about it. He's had caused bias. His professional reputation is all
tied up with what he knows. He likes himself and he likes his own ideas. And he's expressed them to
other people, consistency and commitment tendency. I mean, you have four or five of these elementary
psychological tendencies combining to create this man with a hammer syndrome.
Once you realize that you can't really buy your thinking done,
partly you can, but largely you can't in this world, you've learned a lesson that's very useful
in life. George Leonard Shaw said and had a character say in The Doctor's Dilemma,
in the last analysis, every profession is a conspiracy against the laity. But he didn't
have it quite right because he's not so much conspiracy as it is a subconscious psychological
tendency. The guy tells you what is good for him. He doesn't recognize that he's doing anything
wrong any more than that doctor did when he was pulling out all those normal gall waters.
And he believes that his own idea structures will cure cancer. And he believes that
the demons that he's the guardian against are the biggest demons and the most important ones. And
in fact, they may be very small demons compared to the demons that you face. So you're getting
your advice in this world from your paid advisor with this huge load of ghastly bias.
And woe to you. There are only two ways to handle it. You can hire your advisor and then just apply
a windage factor like I used to do when I was a rifle shooter. I just adjust for so many miles
an hour of wind. Or you can learn the basic elements of your advisor's trade. You don't
have to learn very much, by the way, because you learn just a little and then you can make him
explain why he's right. And those two tendencies will take part of the warp of the thinking you've
tried to hire done. By and large, it works terribly. I have never seen a management consults
report in my long life that didn't end with the following paragraph. What this situation really
needs is more management consulting. Never once. I always turn to the last page.
Of course, Mercher Hathaway doesn't hire them, so I only do this on sort of a voyeuristic basis.
Sometimes I'm in a non-profit where some idiot hires one.
17.
Bias from the non-mathematical nature of the human brain in its natural state
as it deals with probabilities employing crude heuristics and is often misled by
mere contrast, a tendency to overweigh conveniently available information
and other psychologically rooted misthinking tendencies on this list. When the brain should
be using the sample probability mathematics of Fermat and Pascal applied to all reasonably
obtainable and correctly weighted items of information that are of value in predicting
outcomes, the right way to think is the way Zach Houser plays bridge. It's just that simple.
And your brain doesn't naturally know how to think the way Zach Houser knows how to play bridge.
Now, you notice I put in that availability thing and there I'm mimicking some very
eminent psychologists on the like, I hope I pronounced that right, and diversity,
who raised the idea of availability to a whole heuristic of misjudgment.
And, you know, they are very substantially right. I mean, ask the Coca-Cola Company,
which has raised availability to a secular religion, if availability changes behavior.
You will drink a hell of a lot more Coke if it's always available.
I mean, availability does change behavior and cognition.
Nonetheless, even though I recognize that and applaud diversity in common,
I don't like it for my personal system, except as part of a greater subsystem,
which is, you got to think the way Zach Houser plays the bridge. It isn't just the lack of
availability that distorts your judgment. All the things on this list distort judgment.
And I want to train myself to kind of mentally run down the list instead of just jumping on
availability. So that's why I stated the way I do. In a sense, these psychological tendencies
make things unavailable. Because if you quickly jump to one thing and then because you've jumped
to it, the consistency and commitment tendency makes you lock in. Boom, that's error number one.
Or if something is very vivid, which I'm going to come to next, that will really pound in.
And the reason that the thing that really matters is now unavailable and what's extra vivid wins is,
I mean, the extra vividness creates the unavailability. So I think it's much better
to have a whole list of things that cause you to be less like Zach Houser than it is just to jump
on one factor. Here, I think we should discuss John Gutfrid. This is a very interesting human
example which will be taught in every decent professional school for at least a full generation.
Gutfrid has a trusted employee and it comes to light, not through confession but
by accident, that the trusted employee is lied like hell to the government and manipulated the
accounting system and it was really equivalent to forgery. And the man immediately says,
I've never done it before, I'll never do it again. It was an isolated example. And of course,
it was obvious that he was trying to help the government as well as himself because he thought
the government had been dumb enough to pass a rule that he'd spoken against. And after all,
if the government's not going to pay attention to a bond trader at Solomon, what kind of a
government is it going to be? But at any rate, and this guy has been part of a little clique
that has made, well, way over a billion dollars for Solomon in the very recent past
and it's a little handful of people. And so there are a lot of psychological forces
at work and you know the guy's wife and he's right in front of you and there's human sympathy and he's
sort of asking for your help, which is a form which encourages reciprocation and there are
all these psychological tendencies that are working. Plus the fact he's part of a group
that'll pay a lot of money for it. At any rate, Good Friend does not cashier the man.
And of course, he had done it before and he did do it again. Well, now you look as though
you almost wanted him to do it again. Or God knows what you look like, but it isn't good.
And that simple decision destroyed John Good Friend. And it's so easy to do. Now let's think
it through like the Bridge Flare, like Zekhauser. You find an isolated example of a little old lady
in the Seas Candy Company, one of our subsidiaries, getting into the till. And what does she say?
I never did it before. I'll never do it again. This is going to ruin my life. Please help me.
And you know her children and her friends and she's been around 30 years and standing behind
the candy counter with swollen ankles. And you're an old lady, isn't that glorious a life?
And you're rich and powerful and there she is. I never did it before. I'll never do it again.
Well, how likely is it that she never did it before? If you're going to catch
10 embezzlements a year, what are the chances that any one of them, applying what Tversky and
Kahneman call baseline information, will be somebody who only did it this once?
And the people who have done it before and are going to do it again, what are they all going to
say? Well, in the history of the Seas Candy Company, they always say, I never did it before.
I'm never going to do it again. And we cashier them. It would be evil not to
do. Because terribly behavior spreads. Remember, what was it, Serbco?
I mean, you let that stuff, you got social proof, you got
incentive-caused bias, you got a whole lot of psychological factors
that will cause the evil behavior to spread. And pretty soon the whole damn,
your place is rotten, the civilization is rotten. It's not the right way to behave. And
I will admit that I have, when I knew the wife and children, I have paid severance pay when I fire
somebody for taking a mistress on an extended foreign trip. It's not the adultery, I find,
it's the embezzlement. But there, I wouldn't do it where a good friend did it, where they've been
cheating somebody else on my behalf. There, I think you have to cashier. But if they're
just stealing from you and you get rid of them, I don't think you need the last ounce of vengeance.
But I don't think you need any vengeance. I don't think vengeance is much good.
Now we come bias from over-influence by extra evidence. Here's one, I'm at least $30 million
poorer as I sit here giving this little talk because I once bought 300 shares of a stock
and the guy called me back and said, I've got 1500 more. I said, will you hold it for 15 minutes
while I think about it? The CEO of this company, I have seen a lot of vivid peculiarities in a long
life, but this guy set a world record. I'm talking about the CEO and I just misweighed it. But two of
the matters, his situation was foolproof, he was soon going to be dead. I turned down the extra
1500 shares and that's now cost me $30 million and that's life in the big city. It wasn't something
where stock was generally available. So it's very easy to misweigh the vivid evidence and a good
friend did that when he looked into the man's eyes and forgave the colleague.
And 22, stress-induced mental changes, small and large, temporary and permanent.
Oh no, no, no, I've skipped one. Mental confusion caused by information not arrayed in the mind in
theory structures creating sound generalizations developed in response to the question why. Also
misinfluence from information that apparently but not really answers the question why. Also
failure to obtain deserved influence caused by not properly explaining why. But we all know people
who flunk and they try and memorize and they try and spout back and they just doesn't work. The
brain doesn't work that way. You've got to array facts on theory structures answering the question
why. If you don't do that, you just, you cannot handle the world. And now we get to Forstein,
who was the general counsel of Salomon when Goodfriend made his big error and Forstein knew
better. He told Goodfriend, you have to report this as a matter of morality and prudent business
judgment. He said, it's probably not illegal. There's probably no legal duty to do it, but you
have to do it as a matter of prudent conduct and proper dealing with your main customer.
And he said that to Goodfriend on at least two or three occasions and he stopped. And of course,
the persuasion failed. And when Goodfriend went down, Forstein went with him and ruined
a considerable part of Forstein's life. Well, Forstein was a member of the Harvard Law Review,
made an elementary psychological mistake. You want to persuade somebody, you really tell them why.
And what did we learn in lesson one? Insanities really matter.
He should have told Goodfriend, you are likely to ruin your life and disgrace your family and lose
your money. And is Mosher worth this? I know both men, that would have worked. So Forstein flunked
elementary psychology, this very sophisticated, brilliant lawyer. Don't you do that. It's not
very hard to do, you know, just do. Remember that why is terribly important. Other normal
limitations of sensation, memory, cognition and knowledge. Well, I don't have time for that.
Stress induced mental changes. Here, my favorite example is, is the great Pavlov and the LA's dogs
and cages, which had all been conditioned into change behavior. And he said, well,
the great Pavlov and the LA's dogs and cages, which had all been conditioned into change
behaviors. And the great Leningrad flood came and the just went right up and the dogs in a cage.
And the dog was had as much stress as you can imagine a dog ever having. And the water receded
in time to save some of the dogs. And Pavlov noted that they'd had a total reversal of their
conditioned personality. Being a great scientist, he was he spent the rest of his life giving
nervous breakdowns to dogs. And he learned a hell of a lot that I regarded. It's very interesting.
I have never known any Freudian analysts to do anything about the last work of Pavlov. And I
never met a lawyer who understood that what Pavlov found out with those dogs had anything to do with
programming and deprogramming and cults and so forth. I mean, the amount of elementary
psychological ignorance is out there in high levels is very significant. Then we've got other
common mental illnesses and declines temporary and permanent, including the tendency to lose
ability through disuse. And I've got mental and organizational confusion from say something
syndrome. And here my favorite thing is the honeybee. And honeybee goes out and finds the
nectar and he comes back. He does a dance that communicates to the other bees where the nectar
is and they go out and get it. Well, some scientists who was clever like B.F. Skinner
decided to do an experiment. He put the nectar straight up, way up. Well, in a natural setting,
there is no nectar way the hell straight up. And the poor honeybee doesn't have a genetic program
that is adequate to handle what he now has to communicate. And you'd think the honeybee would
come back to the hive and slink into a corner, but he doesn't. He comes into the hive and does
this incoherent dance. And all my life I've been dealing with the human equivalent of that honeybee.
And it's a very important part of human organization to set things up so the noise
and the reciprocation and so forth of all these people who have what I call say something syndrome
don't really affect the decisions. Now, the time has come to ask two or three questions.
This is the most important question in this whole talk. What happens when these standard
psychological tendencies combine? What happens when the situation or the artful manipulation of
man causes several of these tendencies to operate on a person toward the same end at the same time?
The clear answer is the combination greatly increases power to change behavior compared
to the power of merely one tendency acting alone. Examples are Tupperware parties.
Tupperware has now made billions of dollars out of a few manipulative psychological tricks.
It was so schlock that directors of Justin Dart's company resigned when he crammed it down his
board's throat. And he was totally right, by the way, judged by economic outcomes.
Mooney conversion methods. Boy, do they work. He just combines four or five of these things together.
The system of Alcoholics Anonymous, a 50% no drinking rate outcome when everything else fails.
It's a very clever system that uses four or five psychological systems at once toward,
I might say, a very good end. The Milgram experiment. See, Milgram, it's been widely
interpreted as mere obedience. But the truth of the matter is that the experimenter who got
the students to give the heavy shocks in Milgram, he explained why was a false explanation. We need
this to look for scientific truth and so on. That greatly changed the behavior of the people.
And number two, he worked them up. Tiny shock, little larger, little larger. So commitment
and consistency tendency and the contrast principle were both working in favor of this
behavior. So again, it's four different psychological tendencies. That's when you
get these Lollapalooza effects. You will almost always find four or five of these things working
together. When I was young, there was a whodunit hero who always said, share sale a family.
What you should search for in life is the combination. The combination is likely to do you
in. Or if you're the inventor of Tupperware parties, it's likely to make you enormously rich
if you can stand shaving when you do it. Then one of my favorite cases is the McDonald Douglas
airliner evacuation disaster. The government requires that airliners pass a bunch of tests,
one of them is evacuation. Get everybody out, I think 90 seconds or something like that. It's
some short period of time. The government has rules, make it very realistic, so on and so on.
You can't select nothing but 20-year-old athletes to evacuate your airliner. So
McDonald Douglas schedules one of these things on a hanger and they make the hanger dark
and the concrete floor is 25 feet down and they got these little rubber shoots and they got all
these old people and they ring the bell and they all rush out and in the morning when the first
test is done, they create, I don't know, 20 terrible injuries before they go off to hospitals.
Of course, they scheduled another one for the afternoon.
By the way, they didn't meet the time schedule either in addition to causing all the injuries.
Well, so what do they do? They do it again in the afternoon. Now they create 20 more injuries
and one case of a severed spinal column with permanent unfixable paralysis. These are engineers,
these are brilliant people, this is thought over through in a big bureaucracy. Again,
it's a combination of attendance. Authorities told you to do it. They told you to make it
realistic. You've decided to do it. You've decided to do it twice. Incentive cost bias.
If you pass, you save a lot of money. You've got to jump this hurdle before you can sell your new
airliner. Again, three, four, five of these things work together and it turns human brains into mush
and maybe you think this doesn't happen in picking investments.
If so, you're living in a different world than I am. Finally, the open outcry auction.
The open outcry auction is just made to turn the brain into mush.
You get social proof, the other guy is bidding, you get reciprocation tendency,
you get deprival super reaction syndrome, the thing is going away. I mean, it's just absolutely
designed to manipulate people into idiotic behavior. Finally, the institution of the
board of directors of the major human American company. Well, the top guy is sitting there,
he's an authority figure. He's doing asinine things. You look around the board,
nobody else is objecting social proof. It's okay. Reciprocation tendency. He's raising the
director's fees every year. He's flying you around in the corporate airplane to look at
interesting plants or whatever in hell they do and you go and you really get extreme dysfunction
as a corrective decision-making body in the typical American board of directors. They only act,
again, the power of incentives. They only act when it gets so bad that it starts reflecting,
making them look foolish or threatening legal liability to them. That's Munger's rule.
I mean, they're occasional things that don't follow Munger's rule, but by and large,
the board of directors is a very ineffective corrector if the top guy is a little nuts,
which of course frequently happens. The second question, isn't this list of standard psychological
tendencies improperly tautological compared with a system with Euclid? That is, aren't there
overlaps and can't some items on the list be derived from combinations of other items?
The answer to that is plainly yes. Three, what good is in the practical world is the thought
system indicated by the list? Isn't practical benefit prevented because these psychological
tendencies are programmed into the human mind by broad evolution, so we can't get rid of broad
evolution. I mean, the combination of genetic and cultural evolution, but mostly genetic.
Well, the answer is the tendencies are partly good and indeed probably much more good than bad,
otherwise they wouldn't be there. By and large, these rules have worked pretty well for man given
his limited mental capacity and that's why they were programmed in by broad evolution.
At any rate, they can't be simply washed out automatically and they shouldn't be. Nonetheless,
the psychological thought system described is very useful in spreading wisdom and good conduct
and when one understands it and uses it constructively. Here's some examples.
Carl Braun's communication practices. He designed oil refineries with spectacular skill and integrity.
He had a very simple rule. Remember I said why is important? You got fired in the Braun company.
You had to have five doubles. You had to tell who, what you wanted to do, where and when,
and you had to tell him why. If you wrote a communication and left out the why, you got fired
because Braun knew it's complicated building an oil refiner and it can blow up. All kinds of things
can blow up. All kinds of things happen. He knew that his communication system worked better
if you always told him why. That's a simple discipline and boy does it work. Two, the use
of simulators in pilot training. Here again, abilities attenuate with disuse. The simulator
is God's gift because you can keep them fresh. The system of alcoholics anonymous. That's certainly
a constructive use of somebody understanding psychological tendencies. I think they just
blundered into it as a matter of fact. So you can regard it as kind of an evolutionary outcome,
but just because they blundered into it doesn't mean you can't invent its equivalent when you
need it for a good purpose. Clinical training in medical schools. Here's a profoundly correct way
of understanding psychology. The standard practice is watch one, do one, teach one.
Boy, does that pound in what you want pounded in. Again, the consistency and commitment tendency
and that is a profoundly correct way to teach clinical medicine. The rules of the U.S.
Constitutional Convention. Totally secret, no vote until the final vote, then just one vote on the
whole constitution. Very clever psychological rules and if they had a different procedure,
everybody would have been pushed into a corner by his own pronouncements and his own oratory
and his own and no recorded votes until the last one and they got it through by a whisker
with those wise rules. They wouldn't have had the constitution if our forefathers hadn't been so
psychologically acute and look at the crowd we've got now. Six, the use of granny's rule.
I love this. One of the psychologists who works with the Senate gets paid a fortune running around
America and he teaches executives to manipulate themselves. Now granny's rule is you don't get
the ice cream unless you eat your carrots. Well granny was a very wise woman. That is a very good
system and so this guy, very eminent psychologist, he runs around the country telling executives
to organize their day so they force themselves to do what's unpleasant and important
by doing that first and then rewarding themselves with something they really like doing. He is
profoundly correct. Seven, the Harvard Business School's emphasis on decision trees. When I was
young and foolish, I used to laugh at the Harvard Business School. I said they're teaching 28 year
old people that high school algebra works in real life. We're talking about elementary probability.
But later I wised up and I realized that it was very important and they do that and better late
than never. Eight, the use of postmortems at Johnson & Johnson. At most corporations if you
make an acquisition and it works out to be a disaster, all the paperwork and presentations
that cause the dumb acquisition to be made are quickly forgotten. You got denial, you got
everything in the world. You got Pavlovian association tenants and nobody wants to be
associated with the damn thing or even mention it. Johnson & Johnson, they make everybody revisit
their old acquisitions and wade through the presentations. That is a very smart thing to do
and by the way, I do the same thing routinely. Nine, the great example of Charles Darwin is he
avoided confirmation bias. Darwin probably changed my life because I'm a biography nut.
Darwin probably changed my life because I'm a biography nut. When I found out the way he
always paid extra attention to the disconfirming evidence and all these little psychological
tricks, I also found out that he wasn't very smart by the standards, the ordinary standards
of human acuity, yet there he is buried in Westminster Abbey. That's not where I'm going,
I'll tell you. I said my God, here's a guy that by all objective evidence is not nearly as smart
as I am and he's in Westminster Abbey. He must have tricks I should learn and I started wearing
little hair shirts like Darwin to try and train myself out of these subconscious psychological
tendencies that cause so many errors. It didn't work perfectly as you can tell from listening to
this talk but it would have been even worse if I hadn't done what I did and you can know these
psychological tendencies and avoid being the patsy of all the people that are trying to manipulate
you to your disadvantage like Sam Walton. Sam Walton will let a purchasing agent take a
handkerchief from a salesman. He knows how powerful the subconscious reciprocation tendency is.
That is a profoundly correct way for Sam Walton to behave. Then there's the Warren-Buffett rule
for open outcry auctions. Don't go. We don't go to the closed bid auctions too because they,
that's a counterproductive way to do things ordinarily for a different reason
which Zechauser would understand. Four, what special knowledge problems lie buried in the
thought system indicated by the list? Well one is paradox. Now we're talking about a type of
human wisdom that the more people learn about it the more attenuated the wisdom gets.
That's an intrinsically paradoxical kind of wisdom but we have paradox in mathematics and
we don't give up mathematics. I say damn the paradox. This stuff is wonderfully useful
and by the way the granny's rule when you apply it to yourself is sort of a paradox in a paradox.
The manipulation still works even though you know you're doing it and I've seen that done
by one person to another. I drew this beautiful woman as my dinner partner
a few years ago and I'd never seen her before. Well she's married to a prominent Angelino and
she sat down next to me and she turned her beautiful face up and she said
Charlie she said what one word accounts for your remarkable success in life. Now I knew I was being
manipulated and that she'd done this before and I just loved it. I never see this woman without a
little lift in my spirits and by the way I told her I was rational.
You'll have to judge yourself whether that's true. I may be demonstrating some psychological
tendency I hadn't planned on demonstrating. How should the best parts of psychology and economics
interrelate in an enlightened economist's mind? Two views. That's the thermodynamics model.
You know you can't derive thermodynamics from Newtonian gravity and laws of mechanics
even though it's a lot of little particles interacting. Here's this wonderful truth that
you can sort of develop on your own which is thermodynamics and some economists and I think
Milton Friedman is in this group but I may be wrong on that sort of like the thermodynamics model.
I think Milton Friedman who has a Nobel Prize is probably a little wrong on that.
I think the thermodynamics analogy is over strained. I think knowledge from these different
soft sciences have to be reconciled to eliminate conflict. After all there's
nothing in thermodynamics that's inconsistent with Newtonian mechanics and gravity and I think that
some of these economic theories are not totally consistent with other knowledge and they have
to be bent and I think that these behavioral economics or economists are probably the ones
that are bending them in a correct direction. Now my prediction is when the economists take a
little psychology into account that the reconciliation will be quite endurable and here my model is the
procession of the equinoxes. The world would be simpler for a long-term climatologist if the
angle of the axis of the earth's rotation compared to the plane of the eucliptic were absolutely
fixed but it isn't fixed. Over every 40,000 years or so there's this little wobble
and that has pronounced long-term effects. Well in many cases what psychology is going to add is
just a little wobble and it will be endurable. Here I quote another hero of mine who of course
is Einstein where he said the Lord is subtle but not malicious and I don't think it's going to be
that hard to bend economics a little to accommodate what's right in psychology. The
final question is if the thought system indicated by this list of psychological tendencies has great
value not widely recognized and employed what should the educational system do about it? I am
not going to answer that one now. I like leaving a little mystery. Have I used up all the time so
there's no time for questions? By the way the dean of the Stanford Law School is here today
Paul Bress and he is trying to create a course at the Stanford Law School that tries to work
stuff similar to this into worldly wisdom for lawyers which I regard as a profoundly good idea
and he wrote an article about it and you'll be given a copy along with Sealdini's book. Questions?
Yes, I presumed I would be one curious man
and I haven't. I'll put it over there on the table but don't take more than one because I
didn't anticipate such a big crowd and if we run short I'm sure the center is up to making
other copies and
you told us how you would have dealt with one of these issues for example with the
unfortunate lady from seas but you didn't tell us how these tendencies affected you and what's
probably the most important one of the most important elements of your success which was
deciding where to invest your money and I'm wondering if you might relate some of these
principles to some of your past decisions that way. Well of course an investment decision
in the common stock of a company frequently involves a whole lot of factors interacting
usually of course there's one big simple model and a lot of those models are
are microeconomic and I have a little list of it wouldn't be nearly 24
of those but I don't have time for for that one and I
I don't have too much interest in teaching other people how to get rich
my personal and that isn't because I fear the competition
or anything like that Warren has always been very open about
about what he's learned and I share that ethos my personal behavior model is Lord Keynes
I wanted to get rich so I could be independent and so I could do other things like give talks on the
intersection of psychology and economics I didn't want to turn it into a total obsession yeah
I would say the one thing that causes the most trouble is when you combine a bunch of these
together you get this Lollapalooza effect and if you again if you read the psychology textbooks
they don't discuss how these things combine at least not very much do they multiply do they add
what how does it work I think would be just an automatic subject for for research but it doesn't
seem to turn the psychology establishment on I think this is a like this is a man for Mars
approach to psychology I just reached in and took what I thought I had to have
that is a different set of incentives from rising in an economic establishment where the rewards
where the reward system again the reinforcement comes from being a truffle hound that's what
Jacob Viner the great economist called it the truffle hound an animal so bred and trained for
one narrow purpose that he wasn't much good at anything else and that is the reward system
in a lot of academic departments it is not necessarily pretty good it may be fine if you
want new drugs or something you want people stunted in a lot of different directions so
they can grow in one narrow direction but I don't think it's good teaching psychology to
them the masses in fact I think it's terrible